<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-9.2">

  <info>
    <title>Release 9.2</title>
    <pubdate>xx Jan 2016</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
<section>
  <title>Assessment tasks</title>
  <para>A new feature for onCourse has been added to allow you to create assessment tasks.
        Assessment tasks have a name description and attached documents. This is the beginning of a
        series of development work scheduled for assessment.</para>
</section>
    <section>
      <title>Audit Logging</title>
      <para>A new table for audit logging was added to the onCourse user application.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>The AVETMISS data checking export 'Extended outcomes CSV' has been added to the enrolment window, and includes the additional field 'Do no report for AVETMISS' 
        <systemitem>OD-9894</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>A new email template has been added to the waiting list cogwheel option to allow you to manually notify students when a last minute place becomes available in a class
        <systemitem>OD-9895</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>VET Fee Help Provider code added to the AVETMISS general preferences tab, to export this code during the VFH export file process 
        <systemitem>OD-9584</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Invoice window quick search now allows for search on invoice number or debtor name 
        <systemitem>OD-9841</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Update to merge student default message to include the student number of the record that was merged
        <systemitem>OD-9844</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Using the AVETMISS reporting code '66 - Did not start' will export two blank spaces for NSW Smart and Skilled enrolments. This is of particular use for Training Not Complete (TNC) student records.
        <systemitem>OD-9864</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Vouchers with a dollar value for redemption can now be used as payment method after the enrolment has been processed in Payment In / Quick Enrol
        <systemitem>OD-9877</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Site columns added to class list view, to allow by simple sorting by class location
            <systemitem>OD-9891</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem>Add the following automatic data export rules to AVETMISS to assist with managing
        CSO enrolments: When 'Funding source – state training authority' state begins with CS or TSS
        then Fee exemption/concession type identifier = Y, Funding source – national = 11, When
        'Funding source – state training authority' is equal to CSO, then export CSD
          <systemitem>OD-9945</systemitem></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Check all units/ uncheck all units option added to session training plan view
        <systemitem>OD-9890</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>A new status of 'in progress' has been added to applications, to differentiate between new and
          un-actioned items, and those that have been followed up
          <systemitem>OD-9892</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvements to tutor records with 'date finished' in their record, to show their record in a
          greyed out font in the tutor list view and stop them from being looked up by the
          clairvoyance when adding tutors to classes <systemitem>OD-8336</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Addition of 'active' flag to tutor roles, to allow old roles to be disabled and not available to select in the drop down list when adding a tutor to a class
        <systemitem>OD-9941</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Allow tutor payable time to be edited for all attendance time, so payable time can be
          increased or decreased per tutor per session <systemitem>OD-9944</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Scrolling added to Quick Enrol related contact record list
        <systemitem>OD-9847</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Outcomes not editable in the contact edit view
        <systemitem>OD-9983</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Delivery mode would show "not set" when in fact they were inherited from the class. This was a cosmetic bug only.
        <systemitem>OD-9984</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Financial record sorting in the contact financial tab adjusted to allow for modified invoice dates, to ensure running totals by date remain accurate
        <systemitem>OD-9789</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improved AVETMISS calculation of  '3 - New Enrolment' or '4 - Continuing enrolment' to take into consideration students enrolling in pathway programs that require the completion of multiple short courses
        <systemitem>OD-9903</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix typo in payment in process <systemitem>OD-9990</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Hide the 'USI required' portal dashboard widget for students who have not enrolled in a
          vocational courses <systemitem>OD-1993</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improve the layout of the portal dashboard resources display <systemitem>OD-1987</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improve the layout of the portal dashboard next class block display <systemitem>OD-1988 and OD-1989</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Auto complete Country of Birth country name in the portal and USI portal process
            <systemitem>OD-9959</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to the layout of portal related contacts UI to allow better scrolling and navigation <systemitem>OD-9988 and OD-1961</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
