<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-2.1">

  <info>
    <title>Release 2.1</title>
    <pubdate>31 Mar 2011</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>AVETMISS: Add additional field and change to export to meet 2011 NSWAPL
            requirements. ‘Training plan developed’ field added to enrolment window.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Message controller: GUI refresh to show in a single list users receiving email, SMS
            or post, including manual deselect options and ability to open list view of
            un-contactable students.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Messaging improvement: Add ‘including people who are emailed’ to postal option.
            Allow users not to post marketing material to people who have been emailed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Private booking: Auto populate class fee, account code and GST status from last
            instance of class, auto populate next available class code and auto populate the
            enrolment for all students in the quick enrol instance.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tutors: Added Legal name option to differ payroll from publicity</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Outcome list: display unit National code column</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enrolment list: Add date column to Enrolment list view</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Database constraints: added a range of protection in the back end database to
            prevent null and corrupt or broken records</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Copy &amp; paste list view records into excel. Run your desired query, highlight the
            records you want in the list window and copy. Open excel to paste records.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sales by Course location. Available from the enrolments menu, groups sales for
            onCourse software users by their administrative location. Useful for calculating sales
            commissions.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Room Details Report. Available from room menu, shows all sessions running in a room
            in a given date range, including details of the tutor(s) assigned and no. of
            enrolments.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Class Timetable Report. Available from the class menu. Shows all sessions for a
            given range of classes in a specified date range. Useful for providing detailed
            timetables for students or tutors enrolled in multiple classes at once.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Class invoice record. Available from the class menu. Shows the related invoices for
            all students enrolled in a given class and the payment status of those invoices.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Single session class roll: Available from the class menu. Designed for sessions
            where the students are required to sign the roll and return the completed roll to the
            administrative centre after each class session.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <section>
      <title>Important fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Timetable display: fixed instances where timetable display would not show the tutor
            name or venue as selected</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Greatly improved tags and timetables component speed for editing</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed tutor window where some record edits prevented save</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved sending speed large volumes of messages (email/SMS/post)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tags: couldn’t save records were tag type was defined as mandatory. Mandatory tags
            now allowed again.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tags: unexpected results were displayed when tags applied to multiple record types.
            Expected results now display.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Payment out: Certain user settings prevented contact record credit notes loading
            into payment out window so a refund could be processed.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Report fixed: Invoice: Total invoice amounts incorrectly calculated to $0</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Report fixed: Class tutor reports: Shows class date range again in report</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section>
        <title>Minor fixes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Label “Per hour” budget cost -> Per unit”</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Fix class cog -> select ‘create certificates’ – print dialogue to display correct
              options for VET certificates and non-VET certificates of attendance</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add better exception handling and user messages for server start up fail</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enrolment confirmation: remove details from the enrolment confirmation when ‘in
              publicity’ is unchecked</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>AVETMISS: Training Contract ID and Training Contract Client ID validation, if one
              field is completed, the other must be also.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Could not send messages to contacts marked as companies</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Custom filters by active enrolments didn’t return expected results. Query
              fixed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enrolments all search for students enrolled in multiple classes didn’t return
              expected results. Query fixed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>‘Display only sessions for current classes’ check box in Timetable tab of Contact
              window did not function as intended</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Display enrolled class sessions in students timetable</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Course status ‘enabled and visible online’ did not always properly update the
              database values correctly, making the course unavailable in quick enrol</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Prevent total message failure where bad contact validation stops email
              sending</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Reverted quick enrol to open into class enrolment option first, instead of contact
              details</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Windows 7 &amp; Vista incorrectly reported that onCourse was not correctly
              installed due to lack of registry changes</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
