<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-0.8b2">

  <info>
    <title>Release 0.8b2</title>
    <pubdate>08 Feb 2008</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>Course search</title>
      <para>Replaced “Course code” and “Class code” search. Functionality has now been combined in
        the “Code” search. Searching on “begins with” will search on the Course code. Searching with
        “ends with” will search on the class code. Note: As an example “ARC134B-0023” is the full
        course-class code where “ARC134B” is the course code, and “0023” is the class code.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Messaging</title>
      <para>We’ve now included the ability to untick message recipients from a list of
        contacts.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>XML exporting</title>
      <para>Significant enhancements to the Indesign and XML export.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <section>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <para>We have enhanced and added new reports such as:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Statement</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Class by Subject</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Class rolls</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Reconcile</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Banking</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Qualifications</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enrolment confirmation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Profit and Loss for classes, Profit and Loss for courses</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improved merging of students.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes to the reconcile screen: the checkboxes are appearing and the payments can be
          selected.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Set date banked for on payments in performed through the credit card gateway.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed problem with concession not being applied.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Added further validation for student AVETMISS fields</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Set default paper size to A4</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enrolment list shows status, better formatted name</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed printing exception when select multi line classes to print class roll or
          schedule by printer.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed the banking view: contact name displays correctly, report is printed</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Cancelling class now allows you to refund enrolments automatically</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>assuring the daylight savings does not affect the times of sessions/classes when: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>creating session across daylight savings</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>duplicating classes with sessions</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>duplicating classes without sessions</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>when using “message students for class” action only currently enrolled students should
          receive the message.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>added ability to traverse the records while printing: allows to print the student
          reports from courseclass list</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>discount combobox and field is only editable when class is selected (QE screen)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>allocating money to paymentin fixed there was a bug when allocating big credit
          notes</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>validation messages and rules updated for payment out</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>changes in paymentIn status cause all the invoices for this payment to update
          calculated field “amountOwing”</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>changes in paymentIn status cause all the invoices for this payer to update calculated
          field “amountOwing”</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>allowing users to search for the cc transaction number with or without prefix
          “W”</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>enrolment cancellation dialog improved: strings more meaningful, layout cleaned up,
          default button highlighted.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>when cancelling the enrolment the “refund” is now ticked by default</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Improved merging of students.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Fixes to the reconcile screen: the checkboxes are appearing and the payments can be selected.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Set date banked for on payments in performed through the credit card gateway.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Fixed problem with concession not being applied.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Added further validation for student AVETMISS fields</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Set default paper size to A4</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Enrolment list shows status, better formatted name</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Fixed printing exception when select multi line classes to print class roll or schedule by printer.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Fixed the banking view: contact name displays correctly, report is printed</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Cancelling class now allows you to refund enrolments automatically</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Assuring the daylight savings does not affect the times of sessions/classes when:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>creating session across daylight savings</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>duplicating classes with sessions</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>duplicating classes without sessions</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</listitem>
<listitem><para>When using "message students for class" action only currently enrolled students should receive the message.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Added ability to traverse the records while printing: allows to print the student reports from courseclass list</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Discount combobox and field is only editable when class is selected (QE screen)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Allocating money to paymentin fixed  there was a bug when allocating big credit notes</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Validation messages and rules updated for payment out </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Changes in paymentIn status cause all the invoices for this payment to update calculated field "amountOwing"</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Changes in paymentIn status cause all the invoices for this payer to update calculated field "amountOwing"</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Allowing users to search for the cc transaction number with or without prefix "W" </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Enrolment cancellation dialog improved: strings more meaningful, layout cleaned up, default button highlighted.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>When cancelling the enrolment the "refund" is now ticked by default</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
