<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="accounting">
	<title>Accounting</title>
	<para>The following chapter provides an overview of the principles of the onCourse financial
		process, as well as clear explanations as to how you get the information you need from
		onCourse in order to obtain your monthly / weekly reports. </para>
	<section xml:id="accounting-Relationship">
		<title>Relationship between the Student and the Debtor within onCourse</title>
		<para>onCourse has a clear separation between financial data and enrolment data. Students
			enrol in classes. Students may not be a company, since only natural people can enrol in
			a class. The contact linked to an invoice (the debtor) may however be a company or a
			natural person. The student and the debtor may be the same person; this often happens
			for a simple enrolment of one person into one class. The student and the debtor could be
			two different people, or in fact a debtor could pay for the enrolment of multiple
			students on one invoice.</para>
		<para>In the following example of a basic enrolment, there are 2 students Peter and Amy, and the
			invoice is issued to the debtor Geoff (1). Geoff then pays the full amount (2).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Student_and_Debtor_Simple_Enrolment.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Simple Enrolment for Student and Debtor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If an enrolment needs to be cancelled for whatever reason, the cancellation process
			will generate a credit note to the debtor. It is important to note that although Peter
			might phone to cancel his enrolment, the credit can only be issued back to Geoff in
			onCourse.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Student_and_Debtor_Refund_Process.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Student and Debtor refund process</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>As the credit note is attached to the debtor, it can be applied to another enrolment
			for the same student or a different student. In the following example, Peter wishes to
			cancel his enrolment so the credit note is issued to Geoff as the debtor. Geoff is then
			able to enrol another person (Sue) into another course using the credit note that has
			been issued. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Student_and_Debtor_Cancellation_and_New_Enrolment.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Original student cancels, allowing the credit note to be applied by the debtor
					(Geoff) to a new student (Sue)</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-principles">
		<title>Principles of Accrual Accounting</title>
		<para>onCourse works on the principle of accrual accounting, which means that the income is
			recorded to the General Ledger (GL) at the point the invoice has been generated,
			irrespective of when the payment is received. The following diagrams illustrate the
			difference between accrual accounting and cash accounting and the point at which income
			is recorded against the GL.</para>
		<para> You will note also that the income that is received will initially be assigned to a
			liability account, then transferred to the income account once the class commences. For
			further information see the Unearned Income section of the user handbook.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Updated_Accrual_vs_Cash_Accounting.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Comparison of accrual and cash accounting standards</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-financialTransactions">
		<title>Explanation of Financial Transactions Generated by the System</title>
		<para>onCourse follows the basic concepts of double-entry accounting: all financial
			transactions are written to the general ledger in balanced pairs. Asset and expense sit
			on the left, and liability and income on the right. So an increase in Asset could be
			matched with an equal decrease in another Asset. An increase in Expense might be matched
			by an equal increase in Liability.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Basics_of_onCourse_Accounting.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Basic principles of double-entry accounting</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Financial Transactions generated by Enrolment and Payment Process</title>
			<para>Within the Transaction window of onCourse, you can clearly see the individual
				transaction lines that are generated by an enrolment. In this first example, a user
				creates an enrolment for one student into a class with no GST.<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $300 is added to the Pre Paid Fees Liability Account linked to the
						Class being enrolled in,</member>
					<member>(2) $300 is added to Trade Debtors which is a record of the money owed
						to the college.</member>
					<member>(3) Now the payment reverses the $300 in Trade Debtors,</member>
					<member>(4) and $300 is credited to the cheque account, also known as the deposited funds
						account, where your income is receipted</member>
					<member>(5) unearned income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account
						to Income account once the Class commences</member>
				</simplelist></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/simple_enrol_pymt_with_deferred_income_non_gst.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment Non GST Class including
						unearned income</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>For a class fee that includes GST, this would add 2 x additional transaction lines
				for the GST component of the class fee as shown.<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $350 is added to the liability account linked to the Class being
						enrolled in,</member>
					<member>(2) $350 is added to Trade Debtors which is a record of the money owed
						to the college. </member>
					<member>(3) $35 is added to Trade Debtor which is a record of the GST amount
						owing,</member>
					<member>(4) $35 is the GST amount to be received from the Customer (shown as a
						liability)</member>
					<member>(5) Now the payment reverses the total amount owing (Fee + GST
						component) in Trade Debtors</member>
					<member>(6) and $385 is credited to the cheque account, also known as the deposited funds
						account, where your income is receipted </member>
					<member>(7) unearned income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account
						to Income account once Class commences</member>
				</simplelist></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/simple_enrol_pymt_with_deferred_income_gst_inc.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment GST Class including unearned
						income</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Transactions created when a COS discount is applied</title>
				<para>For each discount created, you can choose to either charge the discount to a Cost of Sale
					(COS) account so you can track the discount as a business expense, or to allow
					the discount to reduce the income received. Manual discounts given at the point
					of sale, by overriding the class fee in Quick Enrol, are always posted as
					reduced income, and will not post to the COS account(s)</para>
				<para>Generally, discounts like promotional codes are better set up as COS discounts, while
					variable course fees for differently funded students are better set up as
					discounts which reduce income. Discounts which aren't linked to a COS post the
					reduced income as per the standard liability > income processes.</para>
				<para>By default, Discounts linked to a COS account are charged to an account called Discounts
					Given. You can also create additional COS accounts as needed for different
					departments or promotional types. The transactions processed to this account,
					and balance of this account allow you to keep an accurate track of the cost to
					the business of the discounts given during the sales process. To determine the
					income earned, you can deduct the balance of the COS accounts(s) from the
					appropriate income account(s).</para>
				<para>Discounts work in conjunctions with the standard enrolment transaction posting process,
					and the unearned income posting for income.</para>
				<para>For example, for a $300 (GST free) enrolment fee, with a $100 COS discount applied at time
					of enrolment, the student owes and pays the balance of $200 in full during
					enrolment. </para>
				<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $200 is recorded as pre-paid fees liability. This is the income for
						the full enrolment, excluding the discounted amount</member>
					<member>(2) $200 is recorded as owing in the trade debtors account. </member>
					<member> (3) $100, the value of the discount, is posted to the classes set
						income account </member>
					<member> (4) $100, the value of the discount is posted to the COS sale account
						Discounts Given </member>
					<member> (5) The student pays the balance of the enrolment fee, $200 and the cheque account,
						also known as the deposited funds account, is credited with the Trade Debtor
						account is debited. The student has now paid in full and owes no further
						money.</member>
					<member> (6) When the class commences (or other choice of setting) the remaining
						income, $200, from the enrolment is debited from the pre-paid fees liability
						and credited to the income account set for the class. </member>
				</simplelist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Invoice_and_Discount_transactions.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment GST Class including
							unearned income</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Financial Transactions Generated by Enrolment Cancellation Process</title>
			<para>When canceling an enrolment a credit note is issued, this results in the opposite
				effect to the original invoice. Note that this does not automatically generate a
				payment out to the student since they might use that credit against a further
				enrolment or choose to have it paid to them in one of a number of ways.</para>
			<para>If you need to cancel an enrolment or enrolments for a Class that has not yet
				commenced, the cancellation process will trigger the deferred income held in the
				Prepaid Fees Liability Account to be transferred to the income account. This
				transfer is the first part of the cancellation process. </para>
			<tip>
				<para>If an enrolment or enrolments are cancelled after the Class has commenced, the
					remainder / balance of funds will be transferred from the Prepaid Fees Liability
					Account to the Income account, this is triggered by the cancellation
					process.</para>
			</tip>
			<simplelist>
				<member>(1) Unearned income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account to
					Income account </member>
				<member>(2) $300 is removed from your income</member>
				<member>(3) and $300 is deducted from the trade debtor account since you are
					reversing the debt this person had to you</member>
			</simplelist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/class_cancellation_non_gst_with_deferred_income.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by the cancellation of a GST free enrolment
						including transfer of unearned income</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If a refund is to be given to the original debtor, the resulting financial
				transactions are as follows.</para>
			<simplelist>
				<member>(1) When you pay the debtor their refund, $300 goes out of the cheque account, also
					known as the deposited funds account, and</member>
				<member>(2) $300 of trade debtors is removed</member>
			</simplelist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/simple_refund_non_gst.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by refund for a non GST Class</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Here is an example of the transactions generated for an enrolment cancellation and
				refund for a class with GST.<simplelist>
					<member>(1) Unearned income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account
						to Income account</member>
					<member>(2) $350 is deducted from the trade debtors account since you are
						reversing the debt this person had to you,</member>
					<member>(3) and $350 is removed from your income.</member>
					<member>(4) The $35 GST portion of the debt is expunged and</member>
					<member>(5) your $35 debt to the ATO for this GST is also removed.</member>
					<member>(6) When you pay the debtor their refund, $385 goes out of the cheque account, also
						known as the deposited funds account, and</member>
					<member>(7) $385 of trade debtors is removed.</member>
				</simplelist></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/cancellation_refund_with_deferred_income_gst_inc.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by a GST inclusive class cancellation and refund
						including unearned income</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Transactions created when a COS discount is reversed</title>
				<para>For example, for a $300 (GST free) enrolment fee, with a $100 COS discount applied at time
					of enrolment, the student owes and pays the balance of $200 in full during
					enrolment. When this enrolment is cancelled and the student is refunded, the
					following transactions are processed:</para>
				<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $200 is reversed from the income account. This is the income for the
						full enrolment, excluding the discounted amount</member>
					<member>(2) $200 is recorded as owing to the student/payer in the trade debtors
						account. </member>
					<member> (3) $100, the value of the discount, is also reversed from the classes
						set income account </member>
					<member> (4) $100, the value of the discount is reversed from the COS sale
						account Discounts Given </member>
					<member> (5) The student is refunded $200 and the cheque account, also known as the deposited
						funds account, is debited and the Trade Debtor account is credited. The
						student has now been paid in full and the college owes them no further
						money.</member>
				</simplelist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Reverse_Invoice_and_Discount_transactions.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment GST Class including
							unearned income</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Vouchers and Financial Transactions </title>
			<para>Vouchers are a mechanism to pre-purchase access to training before the user has
				selected a product and in effect, have credit available to redeem at a point of
				their choosing up until the voucher automatically expires. For more information on
				creating and selling vouchers, refer to the <link xlink:href="vouchers.html">Vouchers chapter.</link></para>
			<para>All voucher sales are non-taxable supply, as the GST component can not be
				determined until the voucher is redeemed and onCourse knows if the product chosen
				has GST applied or is GST free. Voucher sales are grouped on invoices under the
				heading 'The following items are not a taxable supply'. </para>
			<para>When a voucher is purchased, the purchase price of the voucher is held in a
				liability account until such time as the voucher is redeemed or expired. The choice
				of liability account is set in your financial preferences, but by default will be
				called Voucher Liability.</para>
			<para>As a voucher can be sold for less than it's redemption value, or given away for
				free, the difference between the sale cost and the redemption cost will be
				calculated as a Cost of Sale and charge to your chosen account for Voucher
				Underpayment. </para>
			<para>At the point of redemption, a voucher acts as a payment in method, and behaves
				like cash, cheque or card. Mixed payments can be made during redemption if the
				voucher balance doesn't cover the full cost of sale.</para>
			<simplelist>
				<member> (1) In this example a voucher is sold for $200 with a redemption value of
					$200. When the voucher is purchased, an invoice is raised for the sale price.
					The Trade Debtors account is increased.</member>
				<member> (2) The sale price of the voucher increases the Voucher Liability account
					by the same amount. If the voucher was given away for free, the sale price would
					be $0.</member>
				<member> (3) When the invoice for the voucher is paid for, the Cheque Account, also known as the
					deposited funds account, is increased by the value of the payment made.</member>
				<member> (4) The Trade Debtors account is reversed by the value of the payment in
					for the invoice. Vouchers do not have to be 'paid for' to be redeemable. Your
					invoice payment terms for vouchers can be negotiable as per all your invoice
					terms.</member>
				<member> (5) A student enrols in a class and the cost of the enrolment fee is posted
					to the Trade Debtors account as per any other invoice created</member>
				<member> (6) The income component of the class fee is posted to the Prepaid Fees
					Liability account if the class has not yet commenced, as per all
					enrolments</member>
				<member> (7) The voucher is used as a payment method. In this example, the total
					invoice balance outstanding is $264, but the voucher is only valid for $200. The
					Trade Debtors account is debited by the value of the voucher.</member>
				<member> (8) The Voucher Liability account is debited by the sale price of the
					voucher. There is no Voucher Liability (or credit available to the voucher
					holder) remaining.</member>
				<member> (9) The balance outstanding of the invoice is paid by another payment
					method such as cash or credit card</member>
				<member> (10) The Trade Debtors asset is reduced by the amount paid in the previous
					step. The amount payable on the invoice created on enrolment is now $0.</member>
			</simplelist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/voucher_sale_redeem_simple.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by creating and redeeming a voucher for the same
						purchase and redemption price</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<simplelist>
				<member> (1) In this second example a voucher is sold for $300 with an open ended
					redemption value of one enrolment (from a pre-approved list of courses). The
					actual dollar value of the redemption value will depend on what class is chosen.
					When the voucher is purchased, an invoice is raised for the sale price. The
					Trade Debtors account is increased by the sale price.</member>
				<member> (2) The sale price of the voucher increases the Voucher Liability account
					by the same amount. </member>
				<member> (3) When the invoice for the voucher is paid for, the Cheque Account, also known as the
					deposited funds account, is increased by the value of the payment made.</member>
				<member> (4) The Trade Debtors account is reversed by the value of the payment in
					for the invoice. </member>
				<member> (5) A student enrols in a class and the cost of the enrolment fee is posted
					to the Trade Debtors account as per any other invoice created. In this example
					the class fee is $5,200, which is significantly more than the purchase price of
					the voucher.</member>
				<member> (6) The income component of the class fee is posted to the Prepaid Fees
					Liability account if the class has not yet commenced, as per all
					enrolments</member>
				<member> (7) The voucher is used as a payment method. In this example, the total
					invoice balance outstanding is $5,200, but the voucher is only cost $300. The
					Trade Debtors account is debited by the purchase price of the voucher.</member>
				<member> (8) The Voucher Liability account is debited by the original sale price of
					the voucher. There is no Voucher Liability (or credit available to the voucher
					holder) remaining.</member>
				<member> (9) The balance outstanding of the invoice is 'paid for' by charging the
					difference to the Cost of Sale account for Voucher Underpayment, in this case
					$4,900.</member>
				<member> (10) The Trade Debtors asset is reduced by the amount charged in the
					previous step. The amount payable on the invoice created on enrolment is now
					$0.</member>
			</simplelist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/voucher_sale_redeem_COS.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by creating and redeeming a voucher for a higher
						value than the purchase price</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Unlike in these examples, the entirety of the Voucher redemption value does not
				need to be used in a single enrolment for a single student. The voucher credit can
				be redeemed over time or can be used to pay for multiple invoices and/or
				enrolments.</para>
			<para>If a voucher expires before it's value is fully redeemed, any remaining credit in
				the Voucher Liability general ledger account will be transferred to the Vouchers
				Expired income account.</para>
			<para>You can manually extend voucher expiry dates prior to them expiring, but they can
				not be adjusted after the expiry date.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-contraPaymentTypes"><title>Contra Payment Types for invoice
			reversals</title><para>A contra payment is a special type of payment that debits the
			balance outstanding on an invoice with the balance of an available credit note. It saves
			you from having to look at the total balance of a student's debits and credits and works
			out what their end position is. It may be especially useful for companies who process
			multiple students in an invoice and have some students cancel and credited.</para>
		<para>Contra payments are processed automatically for a credit note that is created through the
			enrolment cancellation process. For example, if the student had enrolled, but not paid
			their class, which was later cancelled and you issued them a credit note, automatically
			both the credit note and their original invoice would have a $0 balance, as they would
			cancel each other out. The credit note will 'contra pay' the unpaid invoice.</para>
		<para>In the enrolment transfer process, a credit note created from the original enrolment
			invoice cancellation will be used to contra pay the new enrolment invoice being created
			during the transfer process.</para>
		<para>These are the only two instances where contra payments will apply automatically. In
			other situations, you will need to decide how to apply the credit as a contra
			payment.</para><mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/create_contra_via_invoice_window.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Create a contra invoice via the invoice window advanced function
					cogwheel</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>When a cancellation or transfer takes place and the student has credit remaining, as
			well as other unpaid invoices, you can choose to manually apply the credit as a contra
			payment against the invoice of your choice.</para>
		<para>For example, if a student had an invoice for $100 for an enrolment that they have not made a
			payment against, so have a balance outstanding of $100, and there then issued a credit
			note for $70 for a different class that they had paid for, you could choose to 'contra'
			the $70 credit note balance against the $100 outstanding balance on the invoice. This
			would then show their credit note as having a $0 balance (as though you had refunded
			them, or they had used the credit note for another enrolment) and their invoice as
			having a balance of $30 outstanding that they need to pay. </para>
		<para>To manually contra a credit note against and unpaid invoice, do the following:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Locate the credit note in the invoice / credit note list view and single click on it to
					highlight it</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the cogwheel, select 'contra invoice'</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A new window will open showing all the invoices for the contact with balances
					outstanding</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In this window tick the invoice or invoices you want the credit note to contra
					pay against and save.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/contraPayInvoice.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Choosing an invoice to contra pay a credit against</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist><para>You can only use credit notes to contra invoices for the
			same contact. You can't take a credit note from Student A and use it to 'pay off' an
			invoice that was issued to Student B.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/invoice_detail_showing_contra_payment.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Invoice detail showing a contra payment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject></section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-deferredIncome">
		<title>Unearned Income</title>
		<para>In this section we provide an overview of how unearned income works within onCourse
			and how the system deals with adjustments and or cancellations to a Class.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Deferred_Income_Diagram.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transfer of funds from Liability Account to Income Account at time of
						Course Delivery</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<section>
			<title>How Unearned Incomes Works</title>
			<para>Unearned income is income received before goods are sold or a service is provided. When you enrol students, you collect the fees for the class. When the class is delievered, the income is then 'earned' by the provider. This is sometimes called deferred accural accouting.</para>
			<para>When an invoice is generated within onCourse, those funds are initially listed
				within the GL against the Pre Paid Fees (Liability account). These funds are then
				transferred to the income account of the GL at the commencement of the Class. </para>
			<para>As you can see from the above diagram, the method by which onCourse determines how
				the unearned income is transferred across from the Pre Paid Fees (liability) account
				is as follows.<simplelist>
					<member>(1) First session of class is run</member>
					<member>(2) At approximately 1am the following morning, the system will run a
						comparison between the amount of funds in the liability account and the
						amount of funds in the income account for that Class. It will also check how
						many hours of the overall Class have been run and how many are yet to be
						run</member>
					<member>(3) Based on the above comparison, onCourse automatically transfers an
						instalment of funds from the Pre Paid Fees account to the Income
						account.</member>
					<member>(4) This nightly comparison will continue for the duration of the Class
						until all remaining funds are transferred from the Pre Paid Fees account to
						the Income account.</member>
				</simplelist></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>What Happens If I have to Cancel or Add a Session to a Class? </title>
			<para>As you would have noted within the previous section, onCourse runs a nightly
				comparison of the amount of funds in the Pre Paid Fees account against the amount of
				funds in the Income account.</para>
			<para>If for example you have to cancel a session within a given Class, the next time
				the system does an overnight check of the status, it will allow for this
				cancellation and transfer all remaining funds to the Income account. </para>
			<para>Alternatively, if you have to add additional sessions to a Class, the system will
				adjust the nightly installment of funds being transferred to allow for the increased
				number of total hours in the given Class. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>What if I want all funds to be transferred at the commencement of the
				Class?</title>
			<para>A College may decide that they do not wish to transfer income incrementally across
				the duration of a given Class.</para>
			<para>If you don't want to use this feature within onCourse, you can easily deactivate
				this within the Financial Preferences of your onCourse client.</para>
			<para>By choosing to not assign funds from liability to income in nightly increments,
				the system will instead transfer all funds from the Pre Paid Fees account to the
				Income account the night after the first session of the Class is run. </para>
			<para>Please note that this setting is universal, so all Classes are either assigned
				funds incrementally across the duration of the Class, or the funds are transferred
				in one installment after the first session of the Class is completed. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-accountCodes">
		<title>Creating additional income accounts</title>
		<para>onCourse set up comes with a number of general ledger accounts preconfigured. These accounts
			are used by onCourse during standard system transactions and can be renamed or recoded
			as needed. In the general preferences, financial, the default system accounts are
			nominated and can be changed as needed.</para>
		<para>You can also add additional accounts to match your general ledger requirements of your
			primary accounting software. Only accounts onCourse will post to need to be
			added.</para>
		<para>Each class in onCourse is assigned to an income account. Some organisations have a single
			income account, while others have multiple income accounts. For each income account, you
			can select it's default tax setting. This tax setting can be overridden at the class
			level when the account is selected, or when creating a manual invoice line joined to
			this income account.</para>
		<para>You can add to the standard list of accounts, or edit existing accounts, via the Financial
			menu of onCourse</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Account_Code_Menu.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select Accounts from the onCourse Financial menu</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Within the accounts list view, use the + on the bottom hand corner to add a new account.
			When adding the new account code, you will need to stipulate what type of account it
			will be, either asset, liability, equity, income, COS or expense.</para>
		<para>If the account is type income, you will have the choice of setting a default tax. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/Create_New_Account_Code.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Create a new income account and select the default tax (two-column view)</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once you have set up all your income accounts, you can then assign those accounts to
			individual classes via the budget tab class. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Assign_Account_Code_to_Class.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select the required income account code for the given Class</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-financialInformation">
		<title>Accessing Financial Information from onCourse</title>
		<para>When running any kind of query against onCourse to extract financial information, keep
			in mind that enrolment information is attached to the student and all financial
			information (such as invoices / payments / credit notes) are attached to the debtor
			within the system. Therefore there is no direct data relationship between the student
			and the debtor.</para>
		<para>There are multiple methods you can use to extract / examine financial information
			within onCourse;</para>
		<section>
			<title>Automated reporting from scripts</title>
			<para>An automated weekly or monthly Trial Balance report from onCourse is available by enabling
				the script 'send weekly finance summary report'.</para>
			<para>By default, this script is set up to run every Monday morning. It prints to PDF and emails
				the Trial Balance report for the previous 7 days to the default system administrator
				email address. You can make the following changes in the script to meet your
				requirements:</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Change the email address receiving the report</emphasis> The
				default system administrator email address is the one you have set in General
				Preferences > Messaging. If this is not the email address you want to use, change
				the reference in the script that says</para>
			
			<para><programlisting language="groovy">smtp {
			from preference.email.from
			to preference.email.admin</programlisting></para>
						<para>to say:</para>
			<para><programlisting language="groovy">smtp {
			from preference.email.from
			to "accounts@mycollege.com.au"</programlisting></para>
			<para>Where "accounts@mycollege.com.au" is the email address of the person who should receive the
				report, being sure to include the speech marks. </para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Change from weekly to monthly automated reports</emphasis> To make
				this change you need to make some changes to the code in the script, and also the
				CRON. The CRON is the scheduler that defines how often the script runs. By default
				the CRON is 3am every Monday morning:</para>
			<para><programlisting language="groovy">0 0 3 ? * MON</programlisting></para>
			<para>Change it to 3am the 1st of every month:</para>
			<para><programlisting language="groovy">0 0 3 1 1/1 ? *</programlisting></para>
			<para>And then inside the body of the script, you need to change which actions are commented out.
				Lines of code which are comments and not run by the software begin with //. Change
				the script from:</para>
			<para><programlisting language="groovy">    //If you want to change date period use one of the sections below:

    //set period in number of days (e.g. for the last 7 days)
    def endDate = Calendar.getInstance().getTime()
    endDate.set(hourOfDay: 0, minute: 0, second: 0)
    def startDate = endDate - 7

    
//    set period in calendar months (e.g. for the last month)
    
//    def endDate = Calendar.getInstance().getTime()
//    endDate.set(dayOfMonth: 1,hourOfDay: 0, minute: 0, second: 0)
//    println endDate
//    def startDate = DateUtils.addMonths(endDate, -1)</programlisting></para>
			<para>To:</para>
			<para><programlisting language="groovy">    //If you want to change date period use one of the sections below:

    //set period in number of days (e.g. for the last 7 days)
    //def endDate = Calendar.getInstance().getTime()
    //endDate.set(hourOfDay: 0, minute: 0, second: 0)
    //def startDate = endDate - 7

    
//    set period in calendar months (e.g. for the last month)
    
   def endDate = Calendar.getInstance().getTime()
   endDate.set(dayOfMonth: 1,hourOfDay: 0, minute: 0, second: 0)
    println endDate
    def startDate = DateUtils.addMonths(endDate, -1) </programlisting></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Locating data using related records</title>
			<para>In all onCourse windows, you can track through the relationships between the data
				using the 'Find related' function in the cogwheel in the top right hand corner. For
				example, if you wanted to find all the invoices related to the payments in taken on
				a given day, you can select all the payment in records for the day, go to the
				cogwheel, selected 'Find related...' and select invoices. This will open all the
				related invoices in a new window.</para>
			<para>In the new Invoices window, you can run additional queries and or print reports.
				This window has opened in a special state that only ever shows the maximum set of
				results as being the list the generated from your original find related search, so
				all your searches, filters and reports will only relate to this subset of data until
				you close the Invoice list window.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Printed Financial Reports</title>
			<para>onCourse comes with a number of different Financial Reports and each of these are
				looking at one particular aspect or area of the database such as Invoices. You may
				also wish to analyze the financial information that is being generated and you can
				do this by comparing information from one report to the next. </para>
			<para>For example, a data comparison that will enable you to verify the accuracy of the financial
				information is the deposited funds account,balance = Payment in - Payment out for
				the same time period.</para>
			<para>New Custom Reports can be developed upon request, just bear in mind the rules of
				how the data is structured within onCourse when considering what kind of information
				you want to have appear on the Report.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Copying info within list view windows to Excel</title>
			<para>Copy and paste list view records into excel. Run your desired query within a given
				window, hi-light the records you want in the list window and copy. Open excel to
				paste records.</para>
			<para>The benefit of this approach is that it allows you to copy information from a
				number of different windows on to the same excel worksheet in order to better
				compare and verify the data.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>CSV Exports</title>
			<para>onCourse enables you to export data directly from onCourse. As is the case with
				the printed reports, these exports are essentially flat tables of data, which means
				that you are only looking at one specific area such as invoices .</para>
			<para>For more information regarding exporting financial data from onCourse, refer to
				the chapter on <link xlink:href="importExport.html">Importing and
				Exporting</link>.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Exporting to MYOB</title>
			<para>onCourse allows you to generate a text file export of your Financial Data in order
				to import this information directly into MYOB. For more information regarding
				exporting data for MYOB, refer to the following section of the Import Export Chapter
				on <link xlink:href="importExport.html#importExport-MYOB">Exporting to
				MYOB.</link></para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-Deposit">
		<title>Banking and Reconciliation</title>
		<para>In the onCourse preferences, multiple payment types can be created, in addition to the
			system payment types already defined by onCourse.</para>
		<para>For each payment type, you can define if the payment type is banked automatically or
			manually, and if the payment type is reconcilable, and which asset account the payment
			is deposited into prior to banking, and moved to after banking.</para>
		<para>By default, an asset account named 'undeposited funds' is where all manually banked payments
			are deposited on creation. The asset account 'deposited funds' is where all
			automatically banked payments are deposited on creation, and where all manually banked
			payments are moved to when they are banked.</para>
		<para>Automatically and manually banked payments are grouped where possible into daily totals.
			These banking deposits can then be reconciled as a group, or where needed, transaction
			by transaction.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Banking</title>
			<para>As onCourse is integrated with a credit card payment gateway, the system will automatically
				settle payments in and payments out received via the credit card gateway, whether
				these payments are processed through your office or via website enrolments. This
				settlement process is automatically done between 7pm and 9pm each evening and will
				be deposited into your nominated merchant account the following business day as a
				single sum. If a payment is processed into onCourse after the nightly settlement cut
				off time, the payment will not be banked or appear in your nominated account until
				the day after. The grouping of the deposited credit card bankings in onCourse will
				match the batching of the deposits processed by your bank.</para>
			<para>If you accept AMEX credit cards, these payment types will be grouped and deposited in a
				separate banking deposit in onCourse. This is because the AMEX settlement process
				works differently to Mastercard &amp; Visa, and does not always settle on a daily
				basis. Instead it is dependent on the value of the transactions you have
				processed.</para>
			<para>If you have an EFTPOS terminal that you use in conjunction with, or instead of the onCourse
				credit card gateway, ensure you select EFTPOS, rather than EFT or credit card, as
				the payment in type, even if you have processed a credit card through the terminal.
				EFTPOS transactions will be marked as banked on creation, and like your onCourse
				credit card gateway, will be settled automatically into your bank account
				overnight.</para>
			<para>For payments received via Cheque, Electronic Funds Transfer (EFT), Money Order or Cash, a
				manual banking process will group and deposit these transactions. The 'Deposit
				Banking' function within the onCourse client allows you to track the date of
				settlement, method of payment, payment amount and staff member who performs this
				function. It also ensures that you do not 'double count' any funds to your nominated
				bank account.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/onCourse_Deposit_Banking_Window.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Deposit Banking Window within Accounts tab of onCourse Client</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<example>
				<title>How to manually deposit banking</title>
				<para>Manual banking is done a site by site basis. As in, each physical site where manual
					payment types are collected should run it's own banking process. You can see the
					site you are logged in to as user in the onCourse dashboard. If you wish to
					process the banking for an alternate site, you need to change your location on
					the dashboard first. Usually, an administration manager at each site would be
					responsible for running the bank process at their site.</para>
				<para>You should collect all your payments received and confirm you have the same
					cash balance and cheques indicated in the bank deposit window as you complete
					this process.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem><para>From the Financial menu, select Banking Deposits and click the plus button, or from the
							accounts tab choose the option 'Deposit banking'</para></listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you only have one 'Deposited funds' asset account, then you will not need to make a
							choice of bank account. However, if you have multiple accounts, you will
							need to bank to each bank account as a separate process.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>This will open a window showing all the payments that have been receipted for that bank
							account at the site you are logged in at, that are not yet banked, since
							the last time the banking process was run</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>By default all payments are selected, however you can choose to untick
							some payments if you do not wish to bank them at this time.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>By default, the banking deposit date will be today. You can change
							this to a date of your choice, in the future or in the past.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>By default, a printed report will be created as you choose to bank
							these amounts. This printed report can be taken to the bank with the
							cash and cheques needing to be deposited.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
			<para>If an onCourse user has reversed a payment in prior to banking because they recorded the
				payment in error, you will see both the original payment in and the reversal of that
				payment in the banking window.</para>
			<para>It is generally recommended you bank both the payment and reversal together, so
				they cancel each other out, in a single banking process. However, if the reversal is
				processed due to a bounced cheque, you may wish to deposit the original payment on
				the day it was received and banked, and the reversal on the day it bounced.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/reversed_payments_in_bank.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reversed cash payments displaying in the banking deposit window, awaiting banking.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Viewing and adjusting banking records</title>

			<para>You can see a list of your banking history, including transactions banked automatically, by
					clicking on the 'Banking deposits' option in the Financial menu. In this list
					view you will be able to see the following information:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>The date that each amount of money is banked - The date will have been set by a user as
							they manually banked the money e.g. cash or cheques. Alternatively if
							the deposit is automatically banked, the settlement date will be
							automatically set as the date the funds should be received into your
							bank account.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
						<para>The type or the method of how these funds got banked - The method could be MANUAL
							(banked via a manual process), AUTO_MCVISA (Visa and Mastercard credit
							cards banked automatically by the onCourse credit card gateway),
							AUTO_AMEX (American Express credit cards banked by the onCourse credit
							card gateway) or AUTO_OTHER (non-credit card payments banked
							automatically). Prior to the 8.20 upgrade, Amex, Mastercard and Visa
							were banked together in a grouping type called GATEWAY.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The site and user - This information is only displayed when the
							banking is type MANUAL. The site is the office location where the
							banking process was run, and the user is the staff member who ran the
							process.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Reconciled - this check box shows as ticked if the whole banking deposit record has been
							reconciled.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/banking_3column.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Banking Deposits list in 3-column view</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
						<para>You can double click on a banking deposit record from this list view to adjust deposit
							dates or unbank transactions as required. You can alter the deposit date
							of the entire deposit grouping, or for individual transactions. Altering
							the deposit date for an individual transaction will move it from this
							deposit group to the deposit group of the new date. If there isn't a
							deposit group for that date, a new group will be created.</para>
						<para>Should you wish to reprint the banking report, usually created during
							a manual banking deposit process, you can do this from the window by
							selecting one or more banking deposit records and choosing 'banking
							report' from the print menu option.</para>
						<para>You can also 'unbank' a transaction by highlighting the payment in the banking list and
							clicking on the delete icon in the top right hand corner of the window.
							This will change journal the transaction from the 'deposited funds'
							asset account to the 'undeposited funds' asset account. The payment can
							be banked again using the manual banking deposit process as needed, or
							if it was processed in error, reversed.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/changing_settlement_date_manual.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Changing the settlement date for a banking deposit record</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
						<para>To change the deposit date of a payment in or payment out record, double click on an
							individual payment in record and change it's date banked. It is common
							in the case of EFT payments for the date banked to be changed to the
							date the payment appeared in the bank account - often a date prior to
							the payment in being created, and banked, in onCourse.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/edit_deposited_payment.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Changing the settlement date for a single payment record within a bank deposit</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
						
						

					</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Reconciliation</title>
			<para>Reconciliation is a process you may optionally undertake within onCourse to
				confirm your banking deposits match the amounts listed on your bank
				statement.</para>
			<para>Reconciliation can be done on a whole of deposit basis, which is preferable for grouped
				automatically deposited payments, like onCourse gateway credit card payments, or a
				payment by payment basis, which is preferable for payment types like cheque
				deposits, or EFT.</para>
			<para>In the Financial menu, select the option 'Banking deposits'. This lists all the
				grouped banking deposits recorded. You can double click on one of these entries and
				reconcile the whole deposit by ticking 'reconcile this banking deposit', or tick
				individual payment records as reconciled within the transaction. When all the
				payments have been ticked, the whole banking deposit will be ticked as reconciled
				automatically.</para>
			<para>If you prefer to reconcile from a printed report, you can also select a range of banking
				deposit records e.g. the complete calendar month, matching your bank account
				statement, and from the share menu, select the option 'cash movements detail
				report'. The PDF this creates can also be ticked off onscreen (although this will
				not update the reconciled value in onCourse) if you prefer not to print the report
				to hard copy.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" 
						fileref="images/onCourse_Reconciliation_Statement_Window.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reconciling a banking deposit</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" 
						fileref="images/cash_movements_reconciliation.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reconciling a series of bank deposits from the PDF cash movements details report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finalising periods</title>
			<para>When you wish to lock a financial period from any further adjustments in onCourse,
				you can close and finalise that period.</para>
			<para>Once a period is closed, no payments, banking records, invoices, journals or other
				transaction data can be added to that period, or adjusted within this period.</para>
			<para>This process is final, and can not be undone. Proceed with caution.</para>
			<para>This feature is available from: Financial > Summary Extracts> Finalise Period</para>
			<para>When the window opens, it will display the current locked until date, and allow you to
				enter the date you wish to finalise until. This date must be in the past.</para>
			<para>After entering the date, onCourse will check for any financial records that may
				need your attention before the finalisation process should proceed.</para>
			<para>Records that should be addressed include unreconciled payments and unbanked
				payments.</para>
			<para>You can print the Trial Balance for this period by clicking on the share icon in this
				window.</para>
			<para>You can export a daily grouped set of journal transactions for the period by
				clicking on the export icon in this window.</para>
			<para>By opening the banking deposit records for the period, you can also quickly print
				standard banking and reconciliation reports.</para>
			<para>When you finalise and close the period, any banked but unreconciled payments will be banked
				automatically. And unbanked payments will remain unbanked. If you bank these
				payments in the future, they can only be banked on dates after the finalised
				period.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/finalisePeriod.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Warnings and report options before finalising period</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>General Ledger Journals</title>
			<para>On occasion, you may find income in onCourse has been posted to the wrong account, due to the error in a class set up.</para>
			<para>This can be resolved by journalling amounts from one account to another.</para>
			<para>To do this, navigate to Transactions (Financial > Transactions) then click the +
				button.</para>
			<para>This will open a simple window where you can choose what account you want to journal money
				from, to and the value. You can also choose to process the journal into the past,
				provided the period hasn't been locked.</para>
			<para>Journals processed in onCourse will be visible in the transactions window by
				selecting the core filter 'other' i.e. they are transactions in the database that
				were not created by either invoices or payments.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/transactionJournals.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Journal transactions shown by choosing 'Other'</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If you use an accounting system external to onCourse, you may decide to do your
				journalling there instead.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting-cash">
		<title>FAQ: I want cash accounting</title>
		<para>We are asked for this a lot by colleges who migrate to onCourse. Often it is because that's
			how they did things in their old accounting system or on bits of paper. Usually the
			conversation starts like this:</para>
		<para><quote>I get how onCourse works, and it looks great, but I really want to report the class
				name, code and income account alongside every payment. Surely onCourse can tell me
				what every payment was for!</quote></para>
		<para>In a <emphasis role="bold">Cash Accounting</emphasis> system, this is slightly easier. You
			only assign income to your general ledger once you receipt payment. And at that point
			you decide where to post that income in your P&amp;L, breaking it up by account code as
			required. An <emphasis role="bold">Accrual Accounting</emphasis> system is more complex
			but also much more accurate. onCourse goes a step further and can be described as a 
				<emphasis role="bold">Deferred Accrual Accounting</emphasis> system. Let's look at
			what that means.</para>
		<para>Jane enrols in a class with you for $500 plus $50 GST. Her friend Bob enrols in
			another class for $435 with no GST. They enrol together on the same invoice under Jane's
			name. First, that $50 immediately goes to a liability since it is payable immediately to
			the tax office. Even before you receipt the payment. That's a nuisance for your cash
			flow, but at least the ATO gives you 22-50 days to pay. At the same time you have an
			asset (Jane owes you $985) and a liability ($935 worth of training needs to be
			delivered).</para>
		<para>Now Jane pays you $130 first installment. So if you wanted your 'cash payment income'
			report what would go on it? What happens if they $130 payment also finished paying off a
			previous invoice for $17.50 and only $112.50 was toward the new invoice?</para>
		<para>Now you might cry "Oh, that never happens. Our accounts are simpler than that." But
			onCourse can't make those assumptions and we certainly can't generate reports and
			exports which are sometimes wrong because of assumptions that no one ever partially pays
			an invoice or pays two invoices at once or invoices only ever have one invoice
			line.</para>
		<para>So how do you solve this? Separate your financial management reporting from your cash
			reconciliation audit. Don't mix them up. Look at your trial balance in onCourse to make
			management decisions. Look at detailed budget reports from the class list to analyse
			which classes have problems and which areas are doing well. Then look at the banking
			list and associated reports to balance the cash in your bank against what should be
			there. But don't try and do management high level analysis of the money landing in your
			bank. It will not end well.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
