<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="assessment">
    <title>Assessment</title>
    <section xml:id="assesment-whatIs">
        <title>Assessment in onCourse</title>
        <para>Assessments are tasks that you create and assign to classes in onCourse. When an
            assessment task is assigned to a class, it has a release date, due date and assessor nominated.</para>
        <para>An assessment comprises of a name, description and attached documents, and is designed
            to:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Instruct the candidate, or student, of the assessment activity they are required to
                complete for the assessment task</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Instruct the assessor, or tutor, of the marking guidelines and criteria for the assessment</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>        
    </section>
    <section xml:id="assesment-creating">
    <title>Creating an Assessment task</title>
    <para>Assessments can be set as 'active' or 'not active'. Only active assessments can be assigned to classes.</para>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem><para>Go to the menu item 'Training' and select 'Assessment tasks' to open the Assessment tasks list view</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>In the top right hand corner, click the plus button to create a new assessment task</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Give your assessment task a name and code you will remember. This is how you will look up the task later.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Add a description to the General tab that describes the overall assessment task and it's
                    requirements. This will be visible to candidates and assessors in their web
                    portal. The description field allows for rich text entry so you can format your
                    text with headings and other elements to make the content easy to read.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/assessment/assessment_task_general.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The general tab of an assessment task</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para>Any content added to the notes tab is internal, and will not be visible to candidates or assessors.</para></listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Before you can add any documents to the assessment task, you need to save it
                    first.</para>
            </listitem>
        <listitem><para>Reopen the assessment task, and on the documents tab, add any assessment documents to
                    distribute to the candidates or assessors. Be sure to set the appropriate
                    permission for each document attached e.g. 'Tutors and enrolled students' for
                    documents that the candidates and assessors can access like the assessment task
                    instructions, and 'Tutors only' for documents that only the assessors can
                    access, such as marking guides.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/assessment/assessment_task_documents.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>An assessment task with documents for candidates and assessors</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para>Save and close the assessment task. By default, it will be set as 'Active' so you can add it
                    to classes.</para></listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="assesment-class">
        <title>Assigning an Assessment task to a class</title>
        <para>After you have created your assessment tasks in onCourse, you can assign them to
            classes. </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem><para>Open an existing class and click on the 'Assessments' tab.</para></listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Click on the plus button in the top right hand corner.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Type in the code or name of the assessment task to look it up and add it to
                    the class.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Select from the existing class tutor list who will be set as the assessor
                    responsible for marking this assessment task for the class group. You can select
                    multiple assessors.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Enter an optional release date. The release date is when the assessment task
                    is made visible to students enrolled in this class through the portal. You may
                    choose to make this a date prior to the class commencement, on commencement,
                    during or after training. If you do not set a date here, the assessment task
                    will be available on enrolment.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Enter a due date. This is when the students are required to submit their
                    completed assessment task.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Click OK to save and close the assessment sheet. You can repeat this process
                    to add multiple assessments to a class as needed.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>During the class duplication process your assigned assessments will be
                duplicated also, and moved forward by the same date schedule, unless you uncheck
                this option.</listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/assessment/add_assessment_to_class.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Adding an assessment task to the class and setting the due date and time</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
