<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="AVETMISS8">
	<title>AVETMISS</title>
	<section>
		<title>Before taking enrolments</title>
		<para>xxx</para>
		<section>
			<title>General preferences</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Course setup</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Class setup</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Site setup</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Training package components</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>During delivery</title>
		<para/>
		<section>
			<title>Marking attendance</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Marking outcomes</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating certificates</title>
			<para/>
		</section>
	</section>
<section>
	<title>VET Provider Collection Specifications</title>
		<section>
			<title>Training Organisation (NAT00010) file</title>
			<para>This file is quite short, only consisting of one row of data. </para>
			<para>All the data in this file is collected in the onCourse general preferences window. Go to
				File > Preferences > General. Select the AVETMISS tab and enter the contact details
				of your business. It is important your RTO Identifier and name match the details
				recorded on training.gov.au</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Training Organisation Delivery Location (NAT00020) File</title>
			<para>These are your onCourse sites. Set up each site where you deliver training and
				enter the address details. You can ignore the latitude and longitude fields.
				onCourse will require you to create at least one room for each site (this has
				nothing to do with AVETMISS, it is part of our timetabling feature) so to make it
				simple, give each site a room with a generic name like 'default'.</para>
			<para>It is important that each Australian site you create has an address with a State, Suburb
				and Postcode that matches a value in the Australian Postcode data file. Sites in
				other countries will automatically export OSPC for the postcode value.</para>
			<para>The site you have designated as your Admin site in onCourse will be the site any
				self paced classes will be reported at.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Program (NAT00030) File </title>
			<para>This information comes from the Qualification data entered into the Course VET tab where
				the option 'Satisfies complete qualification or skill set' is ticked. Qualification
				Certificates you create in onCourse also will add records to the NAT00030 file. Each
				Qualification or Skill Set will only be added once.</para>
			<para>When you create a new course in onCourse, go to the VET tab and add the Qualification or
				Skills Set you are delivering as part of this program. All the TGA (training.gov.au)
				data is built in so when you start typing the code, the rest of the unit information
				will appear to select from the list. You can set up full qualification courses,
				skills set courses, or short courses with one or more units. </para>
			<para>The nominal hours information needs to be manually added to the qualification or
				skills set as it is not automatically supplied from training.gov.au. You only need
				to do this once for each qualification or skill set you deliver, either by opening
				the related Qualification record after adding it to the course, or by finding the
				qualification under Training > Qualifications.</para>
			<para>Courses do not have to have Qualification or Skill Set assigned. If you add the code, but
				don't tick the 'Satisfies complete qualification or skill set' option, then the
				information will not be added to the NAT00030 file, or the associated NAT00120
				records, but the information will be added to the student's Statement of Attainment.
				You can add this information or tick the checkbox after you have created the course
				and enrolled students. </para>
			<para>If your delivery includes any locally recognised skill sets, qualifications or
				courses (i.e. not from training.gov.au) then a NAT00030A file will be generated
				instead of a NAT00030. This file contains the same rows, but each record has
				additional fields. If you are delivery includes a Smart and Skilled Skills Group,
				for instance, you will generate a NAT00030A file.</para>
		</section>
	<section>
		<title>Subject (NAT00060) File</title>
			<para>Records that form this AVETMISS file are collected from the units or modules you add to
				your courses, or manually add to student's enrolment records or prior learning
				records. Each unit you deliver is only added once to the NAT00060 file, regardless
				of how many times you deliver it. </para>
			<para>When referring to units or modules, this is the data from training.gov.au that is available
				in onCourse and updated daily. When building a <link xlink:href="courses.html"
					>course</link>, these units are added to the VET tab on course creation. This
				course forms a template for adding outcomes to the student record.</para>
			<para>When a student <link xlink:href="processingEnrolments.html">enrols</link> in a
					<link xlink:href="classes.html">class</link>from the course, the units from the
				course are added as outcome records for the student enrolment. Units can be added or
				removed from a student enrolment records as needed.</para>
		
			<para>Non-accredited courses, both VET flagged and not VET flagged also add records to this file,
				using their course name and a random ISH code designator. You will also see these
				'dummy' modules added to the student enrolment record. On the VET tab of these
				courses, you can set the Reportable Hours (Nominal hours in the export) for these
				courses and a six digit Field of Education ID. If you don't set these values, the
				nominal hours will be calculated from the class delivery hours and FoEID reported as
				129999. Only some types of providers are required to report this non-accredited
				enrolment data under the AVETMISS standard. If you are not required to report this
				data, then there is no need to add Reportable Hours or Field of Education data to
				your course.</para>
		<para>As you add the units to courses, you should also add the nominal hours information to each
				unit. You only need to do this once for each unit you deliver. Many users refer to
				the <link xlink:href="https://www.education.vic.gov.au/training/providers/rto/Pages/purchasingguides.aspx">Victorian Purchasing Guides</link> for this data. </para>
		<note>
			<para>Currently training.gov.au doesn't record or publish the module details of state accredited
					courses. If you would like us to add the accredited course modules you deliver
					to onCourse, please contact us and we will import them for you at no additional
					charge. </para>
		</note>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Client (NAT00080) File </title>
			<para>Client AVETMISS files are created from onCourse contact records who have an outcome whose
				dates match the reporting period you've selected on export. Unique client
				identifiers are auto assigned and called 'Student Numbers' in onCourse. You don't
				see these in the contact detail other than in the header bar, but you can search on
				them from the contact window advanced search if you later get a validation error for
				one of your clients.</para>
			<para>Create each of your students as contacts in onCourse, ensuring you fill in their address
				details accurately, in particular the State, Suburb and Postcode which need to match
				the Australian post data set. To meet the AVETMISS export, onCourse automatically
				splits addresses into the required building name, unit name, street number and
				street name fields for export. In the user interface, the address field remains the
				same - enrolling students and administrative staff only need to enter the data in a
				single field. If the student address has a country that is not Australia, OSPC will
				be automatically exported.</para>
			<para>The data on the VET tab in the contact record also forms a large part of the data exported
				in this record, including the indigenous status identifier, language identifier,
				labour force identifier and more. It is ok to leave all or some of these fields
				blank - onCourse will automatically export the value @ for not specified. The <link
					xlink:href="usi.html">post enrolment data collection process</link> will ask the
				students these questions and ask them to supply or create their USI if they haven't
				provided it to you previously.</para>
			<para>The Unique Student Identifier (USI) is reported in the NAT00080 file for each student
				engaged in Vocational Education and Training. Students who have only attended
				non-vocational courses do not need to have a USI supplied for AVETMISS reporting. As
				of 1 January 2017, students studying AQF units will be required to have a valid USI.
				If you do not have a value in the USI field of the NAT00080 file the AVS Validation
				will generate an error.  </para>
			<para>You are required to validate each student's USI against their first name, last name and
				date of birth with the USI Registry System. If you have an onCourse support plan and
				have supplied us with your AusKey, onCourse will do this automatically for each USI
				supplied. For more information on creating and validating USIs, please refer to the
					<link xlink:href="usi.html">USI chapter.</link></para>
			<para>Students who are exempt the USI requirement will need the report the value 'INTOFF' or
				'INDIV' in the USI field to demonstrate that they are exempt and their exemption
				type. onCourse will assist you with complying with the requirements by automatically
				exporting 'INTOFF' for students with residential address in a country other than
				Australia.</para>
			<note>
			<para>Please note, RTOs must report a USI for every VET student, even if the course was delivered
					in a single day. Prior to 2018, an exemption using the USI value 'SHORT'
					applied, but this is no longer allowed. If a client doesn't supply a USI, a
					certificate can not be issued and  RTOs must advise them that their training
					will not appear on their USI transcript. The auto application of 'SHORT' has
					been removed from the AVETMISS 8 exports, but is still present in AVETMISS 7
					should you need to retrospectively export and report data from before 1/1/2018. </para></note>
			<note>
				<para>Please note, If a student has only one name, the AVETMISS 8 Standard requires that the
					single name is reported twice. e.g. "Madonna" will appear as NAT 0080 File as
					"Madonna, Madonna".  </para></note>
		</section>
	<section>
		<title>Client Postal Details (NAT00085) File</title>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Disability (NAT00090) File</title>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Prior Educational Achievement (NAT00100) File</title>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolment (NAT00120) File</title>
			<para>This is the biggest and most critical file - all the detail about what students
				have enrolled in and completed and whether or not your going to get payment for it.
				This information comes from a variety of locations in onCourse, so field by field
				we'll cover it here:</para>
			<section>
				<title>Training Organisation Delivery Location Identifier</title>
				<para>This is a numerical reference back to the site you have set up. You can cross
					reference this with the sites reported in the NAT00020 file. If your onCourse
					classes are not linked to a site, or linked to a virtual site, your default
					admin site details will be reported.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Identifier</title>
				<para>This is the onCourse student number that was automatically assigned when the
					student record was first created. This number can change over time when you
					merge students. You can cross reference the students in the NAT00080 and
					NAT00085 files. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Subject Identifier</title>
				<para>For VET courses, this is the National Code of the associated unit of
					competency. For non-VET courses this is a unique ISH reference number. You can
					see a student's unit and additional outcome data in their student record or in
					their enrolment records. This information is cross referenced with the NAT00060
					file.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Program Identifier</title>
				<para>This is the National Code of the courses related Qualification. This field is
					only populated if you marked the course as a 'is sufficient for a full
					qualification' in onCourse, unless you are exporting in QLD or NSW where it will
					always be exported if you have linked the course to a Qualification. This
					information is cross referenced with the NAT00030 file.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enrolment Activity Start Date and Enrolment Activity End Date</title>
				<para>This is set in the class you have enrolled the student in. When you set up a
					class in onCourse, create a class schedule with at least two sessions
					representing the start and end date on the timetable tab. If you need to modify
					the start or end date for an individual student, you can do it through their
					contact record or through the class window by looking on the Outcome tab and
					changing the date in the field for the student/unit combination of your choice.
					If you change the class start and end dates, it will update the outcome start
					and end dates for all students enrolled in the class, except those where you
					have already manually edited the date.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Delivery Mode Identifier</title>
				<para>Your preferred default setting can be set on the general preferences Class Defaults tab.
					This can be changed for each Class on the VET tab. You can also make changes for
					individual students on the Outcome list or through their individual enrolment.
					Because onCourse supports both AVETMISS 7 and 8, some delivery modes will be
					translated when you export to the older AVETMISS 7 standard. </para>
				<para>Classroom and online will be exported as 10, Classroom and workplace as 30,
					Online and workplace as 30, and Classroom, online &amp; workplace as 30.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Outcome Identifier - National</title>
				<para>You can set the outcome identifier (we call it status) on the Outcomes tab in
					the Class window. If you select all the records in the list and right click on
					them, you can set them all to 'Successful (20)' and then go back and change the
					others that should be other statuses (like RPL or Not Yet Competent) one by one.
					Or you can set them all one by one, whichever you prefer. You can also set the
					outcome status in the student contact record or the enrolment record.</para>
				<para>If you set an outcome an RPL, RCC or Credit Transfer status, the Delivery Mode
					Identifier will always export as 90 - NA regardless of what is set in the
					outcome value.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Scheduled Hours</title>
				<para>The scheduled hours reported are the nominal hours that you set in the unit of
					competency. If you added the nominal hours when setting up the course it will
					report here. You can override the Scheduled Hours in the individual
					outcome.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Funding Source - National</title>
				<para>You preferred default setting can be set on the general preferences Class
					Defaults tab. This can be changed for each Class on the VET tab. You can also
					change it for each outcome in the class Outcomes tab or for each student in
					their Enrolment record on the General tab. Double click the outcome to see this
					field.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Commencing Program Identifier</title>
				<para>If the student was enrolled in a class linked to a course marked as a full
					qualification, then we output the value 3 - Commencing enrolment in a
					qualification or course. If the enrolment was not linked to a course marked as a
					full qualification, then this will export as 8 - Unit of competency or module
					only enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Training Contract Identifier</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Identifier - apprenticeships</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Study Reason Identifier</title>
				<para>You can provide an answer to this question during the enrolment process, or
					after enrolment by going to the General tab on the student Enrolment. This
					question is also presented to the student in the post enrolment USI
					portal.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>VET in Schools Flag</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Specific funding identifier</title>
				<para>This field is labelled 'specific program identifier' and can be found on the
					outcome record.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Outcome Identifier - Training Organisation</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Funding Source - State Training Authority</title>
				<para>You can enter this information in the Class VET tab, the general tab in
					Enrolment or in the individual outcome record on the Class Outcomes Tab or the
					Enrolment Outcomes tab. Double click the outcome to see this field.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Tuition Fee</title>
				<para>This is the fee you charged the student at the time of enrolment, divided by
					the total nominal hours in the course, multiplied by the nominal hours of each
					unit to set a proportional student fee for each unit. To charge a fee, set a
					class fee in the Class General tab. VET courses are usually GST exempt. During
					the enrolment process, you can charge the student the full fee or give them a
					manual discount if they meet fee exemption criteria. The fee they pay here is
					what is reported. If you don't usually use onCourse for invoicing and payment
					records, create a full cash payment for each student on enrolment. Don't worry
					about the invoices that are automatically created here - they have nothing to do
					with AVETMISS.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Fee Exemption/Concession Type Identifier</title>
				<para>This is set in the student's Enrolment record on the General Tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Purchasing Contract Identifier</title>
				<para>This can be set in the class on the VET tab or in the student's enrolment
					General tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Purchasing Contract Schedule Identifier</title>
				<para>This is set in the class on the VET tab</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Hours attended</title>
				<para>This is only used when a student withdraws from a unit without completing it.
					If you need to set the hours attended you can find the field in the Outcome
					record on either the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes Tab. Double
					click the outcome to see this field.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Associated course identifier</title>
				<para>This is set in the student's Enrolment record on the General Tab.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>State Specific NAT000120 fields</title>
			<para>Some states have added extra fields to the AVETMISS standard. These are the ones
				were have added to onCourse. Please let us know if you are asked to provide
				something else that is not in the list below so we can add it to onCourse.</para>
			<section>
				<title>(NSW) Booking ID and (NSW) Course Site ID</title>
				<para>These are set in the Class window on the VET tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(NSW) Training Plan Developed</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(QLD) Full Time Learning Option </title>
				<para>In the Enrolment window on the General Tab there is a Full Time Flag
					(QLD).</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC &amp; QLD) Hours Attended</title>
				<para>This is only used when a student withdraws from a unit without completing it.
					If you need to set the hours attended you can find the field in the Outcome
					record on either the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes Tab. Double
					click the outcome to see this field called 'Reportable Hours'.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Course Commencement Date</title>
				<para>The class start date is always exported here.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Eligibility Exemption indicator</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) VET FEE-HELP (Income Contingent Loan) Indicator</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Industry code (ANZSIC)</title>
				<para>Export the ANZIC code only when VET Funding Source State data is either LSG,
					PSG or SSG</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC and QLD) Student number - VSN or LUI</title>
				<para>This is entered on the contact record AVETMISS tab in the field labelled
					Government Student Number (VIC/QLD)</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/VSN_location.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Enter a VSN or LUI in this field. Data here will only export if you
							are reporting in VIC or QLD</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Program Completed (NAT000130) File</title>
			<para>To record student completion of a qualification or skill set in onCourse, you must
				create a qualification or skill set certificate for them.</para>
			<para>onCourse will create AQF compliant certificates for your students, but for the
				purposes of lodging AVETMISS, you don't need to print or issue them. </para>
			<para>To create a Certificate record, open the certificate window and click plus. Type
				the name of the student and the code of the qualification or skill set you wish to
				issue and choose the outcomes from the student's record you wish to add to the
				certificate. Check the option 'qualification or skill set' and save the
				record.</para>
			<para>Alternatively, you can do this automatically from the class list or enrolment list
				records by highlighting the records you want to create certificates for and
				selecting the cogwheel 'create certificates' function. If the enrolment or class is
				linked to a course where 'satisfies complete qualification or skill set' is ticked,
				then a Qualification or skill set certificate will be created, otherwise it will
				default to a Statement of Attainment. Only Qualification and skill set completions
				are reported in the NAT00130 file.</para>
			<para>The 'awarded on' date determines the date of certificate issue for AVETMISS reporting
				purposes. By default, this date will be the date the certificate was created in
				onCourse. If you create certificates early in a calendar year that need to be
				reported as part of the previous calendar years completions, be sure to back date
				the 'awarded on' date to the previous year.</para>
			<para>If you are exporting a NSW DET export, and have set all the outcomes for an
				enrolment (e.g. they are no longer blank) a NAT000130 file will be automatically
				created for you, even if you have not delivered a full qualification to the student.
				This is because NSW DET uses the NAT00130 file for a different purpose than the
				national standard. </para>
			<para>If you are exporting to Victoria, the student intent to complete a certificate will be
				recorded here also. This record is created when a student is enrolled into a class
				linked to a course where 'satisfies complete qualification or skill set' is ticked.
				Until you create the Certificate record on their successful completion, the record
				will contain an 'N' for not issued.</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="rto.html">More information on creating Certificates in
					onCourse</link>
			</para>
		</section>
</section>

</chapter>
