<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
	version="5.0" xml:id="cancellingEnrolments">
	<title>Cancellations, Transfers and Refunds</title>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-single">
		<title>Cancelling a single enrolment</title>
		<para>It is important to remember that within the accrual financial system of onCourse, that
			every action has an opposite. When an enrolment is created, an invoice is generated to the
			payer. When the payer pays the invoice, a payment in record is created. If you want to cancel
			an invoice or refund a payment, you need to generate an equal and opposite record. To reverse
			an invoice, you create a credit note (a negative invoice) and to give someone back their
			money, you need to create a payment out. This section outlines the common processes involved
			in creating credit notes and refunds.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to cancel a single enrolment</title>
			<para>If you need to remove a student from a class, due to them withdrawing or failing to attend,
				you need to cancel their enrolment. If you wish to provide them with a credit note
				you can do this at the time of the enrolment cancellation. </para>
			<para>The first step is to cancel and credit the existing enrolment.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Find the enrolment in the Enrolments window</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight the enrolment by clicking on it</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the cogwheel option in the top right hand corner and choose "Cancel 1
						enrolment". This will bring up a dialog with a checkbox offering to also
						credit the enrolment fee charged. If you keep this ticked, you will create a
						create note as part of this process. If you uncheck it, you will retain all
						the student's fees as part of your business income. 99% of the time you want
						to create a credit note. If the student's enrolment is unpaid, the credit
						note will pay their unpaid invoice, rather than leaving it as an unpaid debt
						on your books.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cancellation window, choose if you want to send the student a
						credit note email. If you are have not previously agreed to transfer the
						student to another class, or provide them with a refund, selecting this
						option will let the student know how much credit they have available with
						you for future redemption.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Hit "Proceed".</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>This process will cancel the enrolment, and create a credit note in the system for the
				value of the existing enrolment. Note that the credit note will apply to the
				original payer of the invoice. This may not be the student who enrolled in the
				class, but their employer, parent or other third party. Read the text in the
				cancellation window to confirm if the student and the payer are the same or
				different people.</para>
			<para>If the invoice originally issued for this enrolment remains unpaid, the credit note created
				will create an automatic contra payment against that invoice, in effect 'cancelling'
				it from requiring payment.</para>
			<para>If the originating invoice was paid in full, the credit note can be used to contra
				pay another outstanding invoice from that debtor, if you choose. You can manually
				select this option from the invoice list window in the cog wheel options.</para>
		</example>
		<tip>
			<para>Please note that a payment back to the student will not be automatically created after
				cancelling an enrolment. That student might want use the credit to enrol into another class.
				Or you may wish to contact the student and arrange a refund. The next sections explain these
				options in detail.</para>
		</tip>
		<section>
			<title>Outcome deletion on cancellation</title>
			<para>While all enrolments in onCourse create outcomes, including those in non-VET
				programs, the outcomes that can cause concern for reporting are those associated
				with VET enrolments.</para>
		<para>During the enrolment cancellation a checkbox is ticked by default that says 'Delete outcomes
				linked to this enrolment with status "not set"'. If you have not given any outcomes
				a status yet, this will mean all the outcomes attached to the enrolment will be
				deleted. This will be desirable for most types of enrolments, where you do not want
				to report the student as having enrolled in this program at all for AVETMISS
				purposes.</para>
			<para>If the student needs to be reported as a withdrawn student for AVETMISS purposes,
				you have two options. Either set the value of the outcomes before the cancellation
				process, and they will be retained by default. Alternatively, you can untick the
				option 'Delete outcomes linked to this enrolment with status "not set"' so all
				outcomes, both set and not set, will be retained. To avoid AVETMISS errors, you will
				need to make sure that any unset outcomes that are retained are given a valid
				outcomes status, such as 60 - Withdrawn after processing the cancellation. </para>
			<para>Retained outcomes attached to cancelled enrolments are reported like all other
				outcomes. If you want to suppress them from all reporting, set the enrolment to 'Do
				not report for AVETMISS' on the enrolment general tab.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Changing a cancellation fee</title>
			
		<para>You can also elect to charge a cancellation fee (with or without tax) as per your college
				policies. The difference between the fee paid, and the cancellation fee charged will
				be available as credit to the student, or can be refunded to them. </para>
			<para>Note that if you charge GST, this amount will be added on to the value you specify e.g. in
				the screen shot below a $20 plus GST fee has been charged, totalling $22.</para>
			<para> You can select to have this administrative fee deposited into the income account of your
				choice. By default, the income account associated with the enrolment income line
				will be selected. Any GST component will be credited to the GST account.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/cancel_enrolment.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Cancelling an enrolment and charging a cancellation fee</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Cancelling an enrolment paid for by a voucher</title>
			<para>On occasion, you may have cause to cancel and enrolment that was originally paid for by an
				onCourse voucher. If this is the case, a warning will appear in the cancellation
				window to advise you that a credit note will be made for this student, just like for
				any other cancelled enrolment. There is no automatic 'crediting' of their original
				voucher.</para>
			<para>If you have a business rule that states that students who paid with vouchers can
				not access a refund, then use the credit note to purchase a new voucher for the
				student that they can again redeem.</para>
			<para>In the example below, the enrolment fee of $264 was paid for partially by a voucher ($200)
				and partially by cash ($64) - this can be found by looking at the original invoice
				for the enrolment.</para>
			<para>When the enrolment is cancelled and the credit note created, I could then purchase
				another $200 voucher for the student with the credit note, leaving them with $64 in
				general credit, that could either be used towards another enrolment or
				refunded.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/enrolment_cancellation_with_voucher.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Cancelling an enrolment that was partially paid for with a voucher</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
		<section xml:id="transferringEnrolments">
			<title>Transferring an enrolment</title>
			<para>If you are planning of transferring an enrolment, you can do this from the enrolment list
			view. This is similar to the 'cancel enrolment' process with the addition of opening
			Quick Enrol at the end of the process, pre loaded with the student, payer and course
			details, allowing you to make a speedy transfer of the student to another class. </para>
		<para>Highlight the enrolment you want to transfer, then go to the cogwheel and select the
			option 'Transfer an enrolment'. Once you have done this a sheet will appear advising you
			what is going to happen. You then have the ability to delete outcomes linked to this
			enrolment with the status "not set", this option is marked as default. You also have the
			ability to do the following things related to the invoice or invoices attached to this
			enrolment:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a credit note to reverse the enrolment fee to the payer - this is marked as
					default.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Charge the payer an administrative fee of your choice - you can also choose if it
					includes GST and what account it gets recorded against.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<para>You can only transfer one enrolment at a time.</para>
			</note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%"
						fileref="images/transferring_enrolment.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transferring an enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once you have filled out the sheet and pressed 'Proceed', a pre-populated Quick Enrol
			window will then open with the student's and payer's contact details along with the
			course from the 'transferred' enrolment. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/transfer_enrolment_QE.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transferring an enrolment in Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>IMPORTANT: Check the correct credit note is being applied to the transferred enrolment by
			clicking on the PAYMENTS heading. Any invoice with its checkbox ticked will apply to the
			current invoice. In the example below, this student has two available credit notes to
			apply to their current invoice. Also, be sure to set the payment type to Other</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/transferring_enrolment_cn.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>Applying credit notes from previous invoices in Quick Enrol</caption>
			</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-creditNote">
		<title>Creating a manual credit note</title>
		<para>On occasion, you may need to create a credit note of refund for a student without using the
			enrolment cancellation process. This may be because you wish to offer the student a
			credit to apply to further training (perhaps there was problem with the class they
			attended), because they purchased another product outside of the class enrolment, or
			because you created a credit note for the wrong amount during the enrolment
			cancellation.</para>
		<para>Before you can issue any type of refund, you must create a credit note. You can create a
			credit note manually in the invoice window. Note that this process is not necessary if
			you create a credit note during the enrolment cancellation process.</para>
		<para>The quickest way to create a credit note to fix an error is to find the original invoice,
			duplicate it and reverse it.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to reverse an invoice to create a credit note</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Reversing an invoice manually allows you to make an adjustment (partial reversal) or complete
						reversal to an invoice created in error. Begin by opening the invoice window
						and locating the invoice that is problematic.</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Single click on the invoice, and from the cogwheel select the option 'Duplicate and
						reverse invoice'. A new manual invoice/credit note window will open.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>This new credit note will contain all the same invoice lines as the
						origional invoice line, but with each line item reversed. Remove any invoice
						lines you do not want to include in this credit note.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To adjust the value of a remaining invoice line or charge the reversal to a different
						income account, double click on it. You can make changes to any of the
						fields available in the sheet. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Optionally link the reversal back to it's original course-class code to
						deduct this amount from the class income. This will also make the invoice
						show in the class budget tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click OK to save the adjustment to the invoice line, and repeat the process for each
						additional invoice line you want to reverse. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Remove the check box from the 'send email' option if you do not want a
						copy of this adjustment to be sent to the payer.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Ensure the balance of the new invoice/credit note is as you expect before
						choosing save. You can not edit the invoice/credit note after saving
						it.</para>
				</listitem>		
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reversed_invoice_for_credit.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a credit note by duplicating and reversing the values of the original invoice</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a manual credit note</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Begin by opening the Invoice window. In the top right hand corner are a
						plus and minus button. Click on the plus</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the new Invoice record window, type the name of the contact you wish to
						give the credit note/refund too. The contact needs to already exist within
						onCourse. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the invoice lines section of the window, click on the '+' button to add
						charges/credits to the record. Give your item a title, select the general
						ledger income account it will be debited from, enter the appropriate
						negative amount in the 'Price Each Ex Tax' field.  Ensure if you are
						creating a credit note that the value has a minus sign in front of
						it.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter any other relevant information and save the credit note. You will
						now see in the list view window an unbalanced invoice for a negative amount.
						This is the credit note.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Manual_credit_note.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Creating a manual credit note</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-Discounts">
		<title>Manual discounts after enrolment</title>
		<para>Sometimes students enrol in classes and pay the full fee, and after enrolment they
			realise a discount needs to be provided as the student was eligible for a reduced
			enrolment fee.</para>
		<para>In onCourse, when a discount is issued the COS account Discounts Given is credited and
			the chosen income account is debited. </para>
		<para>To create a manual discount, follow the steps above to issue a manual credit note, but
			enter an amount in the Discount Each ex tax field. This will create a credit note, but
			add the cost of the discount to the COS account, just like if it was taken during the
			enrolment.</para>
		<para>Please note that discounts processed manually will not be linked to the class and will not
			show in the class budget, unless you add the link back to the class in the invoice
			line.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-usingCredit">
		<title>Using the credited amount as credit towards another enrolment</title>
		<para>Contacts with credit will appear in the invoices window as 'unbalanced' invoices, showing
			with a negative balance. The next time the contact enrols, or pays for another student's
			enrolment, they will automatically be offered their credit to use towards their fee
			payment in the Quick Enrol process.</para>
		<para>This information will show in the bottom of the quick enrol window next to previous
			owing as a minus amount. The amount due for payment will automatically adjust. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/credit_note_qe.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A student enrolling in a class with a credit note of $132 automatically
					applied to their balance</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-paymentReversals">
		<title>Payment reversals within the payment in window</title>
		<para>If you processed a payment in record in error, i.e. recorded an EFTPOS payment that failed
			to process through your EFTPOS terminal, and want to reverse the payment to set the
			invoice back to unpaid, you can do this in the Payments In window.</para>
		<para>To reverse a payment, it first of all must be unbanked. Some payment types are set to
			bank automatically on creation. If your payment is banked, double click on the payment
			in record and removed the date banked date, then save and close the record.</para>
		<para>Your payment in is now ready to reverse via the following steps:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>In onCourse go to "Accounts" then "Payment In".</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Highlight the payment in record to be reversed.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click on the cog wheel and select "Reverse payment".</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click reverse of the new pop up window to confirm you want to the record to be
					reversed.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A new negative payment in will be created of the same payment type as your original
					payment, and both payment lines will have the status REVERSED. If the original
					payment was already marked as banked, then this reversal process will cause it
					to be unbanked.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The banking deposit window will show both halves of the reversal. You should bank them
					together so they balance each other out.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/payment_in_reverse_payment.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>View of the payments in window when trying to reverse a payment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<tip>
			<para>Only 1 payment In item can be reversed at one time and the date of reversal will
				be set as today's date</para>
		</tip>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/payment_in_reverse_payment_confirmation.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Confirmation window that pops up when trying to reverse a payment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-PaymentOut">
		<title>Refunding a student via Payment Out</title>
		<para>If you wish to give a contact back their money, you need to create a payment out
			record. You can return cash to the payer, write a cheque, or if they have paid by a
			credit card through onCourse (not via an EFTPOS terminal) you can automatically reverse
			the payment back to their card. Manual credit card reversals can also be done through an
			EFTPOS terminal, but you will need to contact the payer to get their card details first. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>If you refund a fee via an EFTPOS terminal, you will still need to record a payment out
				entry within onCourse, simply select payment type 'EFTPOS', even if the reversal was
				to a credit card. It's the method that is important to record here, not the card
				type.</para>
		</tip>
		<example>
			<title>How to refund a student via Payment Out</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In onCourse go to "Financial" then "Payment Out" </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the name of the contact who has the credit note</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> You will see the total balance of their credit notes available to be
						refunded. Some contacts may have multiple credit notes. You can refund all
						or a part of their total balance. You can not refund more than the total
						balance.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Chose the method with which you wish to refund the contact. If you choose
						credit card, any available transaction will be available from the list to
						reverse. The list of available transactions is ordered by date with the most
						recent transaction at the top of the list. As shown in the example below.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Save the payment out record. The contacts credit note balance will be
						reduced by the amount you have just refunded.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Where needed, you can adjust the 'date paid' for the payment out to a date
						other than today, if the payment out was processed in the past (e.g. EFT)
						and you are recording it in onCourse some days later.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a payment out from the credit note</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<para>Go to "Invoice" and single click on the credit note you want to apply a payment out to</para>
			</orderedlist>
			<orderedlist>
				<para>From the cogwheel choose 'apply payment out'</para>
			</orderedlist>
			<orderedlist><para>The Payment Out window will open with the contact name pre-filled</para></orderedlist>
			<orderedlist>
				<para>Continue with selecting the refund type and amount as per the process above, 'How to refund a student via Payment Out' </para>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/apply_payment_out_from_invoice.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting a credit note to process a payment out against</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/payment_out_via_credit_card.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting the credit card transaction to be refunded from the drop down
					list</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Card_declined.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The message you will see if the credit card payment out was declined</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Failed.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The message you will see if the payment out is failed</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>A few notes on onCourse credit card reversals</title>
			<para>onCourse does not store credit card numbers. What it does store is a transaction
				reference number supplied by the bank. This transaction reference number allows you
				to reverse up to the original amount paid during the transaction. This means you can
				refund the payer with complete confidence that the payment is being returned to the
				original credit card that paid for the enrolment.</para>
			<para>There are some limitations that you need to be aware of however:</para>
			<para>1. Credit card transactions are only available to reverse up to three months after
				the initial date of purchase. An attempted refund to a transaction older than this
				will fail.</para>
			<para>2. You can only refund UP TO the original amount of the transaction. You can not
				refund the student more than they paid per transaction. For example, if two $100
				enrolments we paid for in separate credit card transactions by the same contact and
				both cancelled and eligible for a refund, you would need to process two payments out
				of $100 each, once against each transaction.</para>
			<para>3. If the credit card you are attempting to refund has been cancelled by it's
				owner, or expired, the attempt to refund it will fail. You will need to contact the
				student and arrange an alternate refund method.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/accounts_paymentout.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a payment out record for a refund processed</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-cancellingAClass">
		<title>Cancelling a Class</title>
		<para> If your class is not financially viable, or needs to be cancelled for other reasons,
			onCourse has the tools to allow you to cancel the enrolments, notify the students,
			refund the students or provide them with credit notes, and use their credit to book them
			in to another, or the next available class. </para>
		<para>Before you cancel the class, you may wish to print a record of the enrolled students,
			via a report like a class roll or student contact list so you can annotate their
			preference of refund, credit note or transfer.</para>
		<para>There is an optional script you can enable to automatically notify all students enrolled in
			the class that their class is no longer running as scheduled. If this script is enabled,
			it will contact the students at the end of this process and there is no option to
			prevent the message from sending on a class by class basis. See below for more
			information regarding enabling and disabling the script.</para>
		<para>To cancel the class, select the class in the classes window and from the cogwheel option at
			the top right, select "cancel class". There are a couple choices to make in this
			window:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para>Create credit note to reverse the enrolment fee - this is always checked and cannot be
					changed. This will notify you how many credit notes will be created.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Send credit note email (ticked by default) - this sends the credit note details created
				by the first step to each payer of the enrolment, advising them of the credit they
				now have available to use towards another enrolment, or request to be
				refunded.</para></listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create credit notes to reverse invoices manually (ticked by default) - if you
					have manually created and linked additional invoices to the class, these will
					also be reversed</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/cancel_class.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Options available when cancelling a class</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once a class is cancelled it will appear in the class list view with an icon with a cross
			through it and the text greyed out, and be available in the core filter 'cancelled
			classes'. Cancelled classes that were visible on the web will have their 'enrol now'
			button changed immediately to 'cancelled', and will not allow any more enrolments either
			through the web or via Quick Enrol. </para>
		<para>It can be beneficial to leave cancelled classes displaying on the web, particularly if you
			have published the class details elsewhere in a brochure. You may also choose to
			manually unpublish the class by single clicking on it and choosing the from the cogwheel
			'Remove class from website'.</para>
		<para>A cancelled class can not be 'un-cancelled'. However, should you need to reinstate the
			class, highlight your cancelled class and from the cogwheel option choose 'Duplicate 1
			class' moving the class forward by zero days (essentially making another copy of the
			class with a new class code, but all the other details the same). This will not re-enrol
			the previously cancelled students... should you wish to do this you will need to enrol
			them again in the new class as per the usual processes.</para>
		<para>To prevent large scale errors, cancellations of classes are not available for bulk
			processing. You will need to cancel each class individually. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Scripts to automatically contact students and tutors when a class is cancelled</title>
			<para>Two scripts and sets of email templates are available by default in onCourse to contact the students enrolled and the tutors assigned to a class when it is cancelled.</para>
			<para>The 'Cancelled class notice for tutor' must be enabled to automatically contact
				tutors via the 'Tutor notice of class cancellation' email template.</para>
			<para>The 'Send class cancellation' must be enabled to automatically contact enrolled students
				via the 'Class cancellation' email template.</para>
			<para>It is important you read, and possibly customise, the text of these two sets of email
				templates before enabling the scripts as the wording must be consistent with your
				college policies regarding cancelled classes, refund options and credit
				notes.</para>
			<para>If you adjust the wording of any of the email templates, be sure to adjust the
				plain text and HTML versions in the same way.</para>
			<para>The student notification email can also be sent manually from the enrolment
				window. Highlight the enrolments you wish to send the message to and choose send
				email from template > Class cancellation from the cogwheel options.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/class_cancellation_email_template.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Default email template sent to students when their class is cancelled</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Reporting on cancelled classes</title>
			<para>Advertising classes, taking enrolments and payments and then having to cancelling the class
				due to insufficient enrolments or change or circumstance is a real cost to a
				training organisation.</para>
			<para>From a business perspective, rescheduling a class to a future date is far more advisable
				than cancelling a class, but sometimes a cancellation will still be necessary. As an
				organisation, should you wish to understand your cancellation rates and 'lost'
				potential income, a report called 'Cancelled classes count' is available from the
				class list of reports.</para>
			<para>Begin by selecting the core filter 'cancelled classes' to show only your cancelled classes
				in the list view. Then search or highlight the classes in the range you wish to
				report on. Once you have selected the classes, choose File > Print > Cancelled
				classes count, or use the share icon.</para>
			<para>This report will show you the enrolments that were in the class prior to the
				cancellation and the income that had been collected.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/cancelled_classes_report.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>An example report showing the potentially lost income and displeased students resulting from cancelled classes</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-Transfers">
		<title>Student Transfer Questions</title>
		<para>If you wish to transfer a student, first you need to cancel their existing enrolment,
			then enrol them into a new class.</para>
		<para>Student transfers need to be done one student at a time. Using the transfer wizard
			option outlined above will make this process fairly quick, ensuring the previous payer
			and class are pre-selected for you in Quick Enrol,</para>
		<section>
			<title>What if the value of the new enrolment is more expensive than the old class or
				less expensive?</title>
			<para> As onCourse tracks the amount owing for the student, no money is lost by the system by
				cancelling and refunding. If the student has been given credit from their previous
				enrolment for $100, but the class you are transferring them into costs $120 you can
				either:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Do nothing and Quick Enrol will request payment for the additional $20, which you can collect
						via all the usual payment methods available including credit card</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose to manually discount the enrolment in Quick Enrol by $20, allowing
						their credit of $100 to cover to apply leaving the account with a balance of
						$0.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>If their new enrolment is less expensive than their previous class, you can choose to keep
				their credit on file indefinitely to apply to a future enrolment, or provide them
				with a refund for the credit remaining once you have processed the new enrolment. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why can't I just edit the existing enrolment? </title>
			<para> onCourse tracks enrolments and financial data in a way which leaves a complete
				audit trail. So at any time you will be able to see all the enrolment history for
				every student, including enrolments they have withdrawn from. This is very important
				for financial auditing and system security reasons which especially when several
				staff might be making changes or looking at the history in the system. </para>
			<para>Furthermore the refund/Quick Enrol process makes the work flow clearer when the new class
				has a different cost to the old. The operator is explicitly prompted to collect an
				additional payment or retain part of the credit note. By then applying an additional
				charge or discount, general ledger adjustments are kept accurate and clear. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I fix a mistake I made where I charged the student the wrong amount or
				credited a credit note in error?</title>
			<para>Remember that the opposite of an invoice is a credit note. If the student owes you more
				than you originally charged them, create a manual invoice for the difference. If you
				charged them too much in error, create a manual credit note for the difference. If
				you want to check the balance of a student's account, go to the contact window and
				look at their finance tab. This will show all invoices, credit notes, payments in
				and payments out at the current balance of their account e.g. do they owe you money,
				do you owe them money, or is everything square? </para>
			<para>You can also use the contra pay feature to use the balance of a credit note to
				'pay off' an outstanding balance on an invoice. Select the credit note in the
				invoice window, and using the cog wheel option 'Contra Invoice..' locate the invoice
				you want to pay. This only works for credit notes/invoices for the same contact. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> How can I use one contact's credit to pay for another student's enrolment? </title>
			<para> If the contact in credit wishes to use their credit towards another person's
				enrolment, follow the steps for <uri>3rd Party Payments</uri>, ensuring that you
				select the contact in credit as the payer. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
