<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="certification">
	<title>Certification</title>
	<para>There are two types of Certification available within onCourse:</para>
	<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Vocational Education Training (VET) Certification, which creates a permanent
				record stored in the database for compliance purposes, and forms the basis of
				NAT00130 Program Completed data reported to NCVER that is used to create the
				student's official USI Transcript.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Certificates of Attendance for non accredited and professional development course
				certification. No formal register of this type of certificate creation is stored in
				onCourse, nor is their issuance reported to any formal bodies.</para>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	<para>This chapter of the user documentation covers the creation, customisation and distribution
		of both these types of certificates.</para>
	<section xml:id="rto-Certificates">
		<title>About onCourse Certificates</title>
		<para>onCourse includes the AQF recommended templates for full Qualification Certificates,
			Skill Set Statements of Attainment, Statements of Attainment and transcripts. These
			templates can be modified as needed to meet your own style guides and content
			preferences. Certificates can only be generated from units that are recorded as part of
			onCourse enrolments or Prior Learning records. If you wish to include prior learning or
			credit transfer units, you will need to add these outcomes to the student's record
			before you create the certificate.</para>
		<para>By generating the certificate record in onCourse you will have created the data
			required to meet the ASQA Standards for RTOs 2015 - Standard 3. The certificate list is
			your Certificate Register. A certificate record you create is available in the
			certificate table in onCourse for printing, AVETMISS export and re-printing. Once
			created, the certificate record can be edited and amended or even deleted prior to
			printing, but after the record is printed it becomes locked in the database to ensure an
			accurate record of your issued certificates are retained.</para>
		<para>The associate outcomes that make up the certificate also become locked in the
			database, so they can not have their outcome status changed, or be deleted after the
			certificate has been issued.</para>
		<para>Every certificate record created is issued a unique certificate number, which is
			printed on the certificate face. The same number series is used for Qualifications and
			Statements of Attainment. The records will begin at 1 and automatically increment each
			time a certificate is created.</para>
		<para>If you are required to generate and submit AVETMISS data, any certificate record you
			create that is marked as being for a full Qualification or skill set will create a
			corresponding record in the NAT00130 file. You can also go to File > Import/Export >
			Export Certificates to create a CSV file of your certificate register.</para>
		<para>There are several dates in an onCourse certificate record. They are awarded date,
			issued date, expiry date, printed on date and revoked on date. </para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Awarded:</emphasis> Awarded is the date the certificate record
			is generated in onCourse. It's an arbitrary date in that it can be edited up until the
			certificate has been printed, or a PDF generated.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Issued:</emphasis> Issued is the date the certificate is issued
			to the student. It's an arbitrary date in that it can be edited up until the certificate
			has been printed, or a PDF generated.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Expiry:</emphasis> Expiry dates are only used for timed
			certificates, like First Aid Certificates. This is the date that the certificate will
			expire.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Printed On:</emphasis> This is the date the certificate record
			was turned into a generated PDF and either distrbuted to the student digitally, or
			printed on to paper. </para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Revoked On:</emphasis> This is the date the certificate record
			was revoked by the system.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating Certificates</title>
		<para>There are three parts to the process of creating certificates in onCourse.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Creating the certificate record - this is either done automatically as part of
					a scheduled script. manually as part of a bulk process for a group of students,
					or individually</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Verifying the certificate record - before printing, check that the details are
					correct. Additional validation will also take place during the print
					process.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Printing the certificate record - this 'locks' the certificate record for
					further editing and creates a printed Certificate and Transcript based on your
					certificate report templates and background</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/certificate_window.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Certificate list view - this is the register of all certificates created,
					printed and revoked in your organisation</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Step 1 - Creating the certificate record</title>
			<section>
				<title>Automating the Certificate creation process</title>
				<para>There are two pieces of the VET certification process you can automate with
					default scripts. You can choose to enable one or both of these scripts depending
					on the business automation aspects you wish to use.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>The creation of the VET Statement of Attainment or Qualification in
							onCourse using the 'automatic creation of VET Certificates' script. This
							script looks at the units attached to the student's enrolments, and the
							Qualification properties of the course they have enrolled in. When all
							units from the enrolment have been assigned outcomes, the script creates
							either a Statement of Attainment or Qualification/Skill Set
							certification for the student in the onCourse Certificate table.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The issuing of the VET Certificate to the student via upload to the
							portal using the 'send certificate vet created notification' script.
							This script determines if the certificate is eligible to be printed
							based on the student's USI status being verified, and then prints the
							certificate, attaches it to the enrolment record, uploads it to the
							portal and sends the student an email notice where they can click and
							retrieve their certificate without a password (for 7 days) or retrieve
							by entering a password past 7 days.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enabling the automatic VET Certificate creation script</title>
				<para>Like most included scripts, the 'automatic creation of VET Certificates'
					script is disabled by default. If you wish to automate this script you will need
					to enable it in the File > Preferences> Scripts menu.</para>
				<para>The script checks at 4am every day check for outcomes which have been modified
					in the previous 24 hrs. If any outcomes attached to the enrolment are not yet
					marked, the enrolment is skipped for certificate creation. When all outcomes
					have a status, then the certificate creation process is triggered. This means if
					outcomes are marked over time, the certificate will not be created until the
					last outcome of the enrolment is marked.</para>
				<para>It is important to note here that an outcome with an indeterminate status like
					a 70 or 90 will trigger the certificate creation process. There are almost no
					cases where you should enter this value in an onCourse record - allow the
					AVETMISS export runner to set these values as needed.</para>
				<para>For students with at least one successful outcome, create the certificate
					record (Statement of Attainment or Qualification, based on the 'Satisfies
					complete qualification or skill set' flag at the course level). If the outcome
					is already joined to a certificate, this script will not create a new
					certificate containing that outcome. </para>
				<para>You can identify these auto-created certificates in onCourse as the issued on
					date will be 'not set' until they are printed.</para>
				<qandaset>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para>What will happen if a student has enrolled in full Qualification
								but only successfully completed some of their units?</para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para>If all the outcomes have been given a value, and some of the
								outcomes are unsuccessful, then the student will be issued a
								Statement of Attainment, rather than a Qualification. The successful
								units will print on the certificate face, and on the accompanying
								transcript, both the successful and unsuccessful units will be
								printed.</para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para>What happens if a student is enrolled in a class with a single
								outcome and it is marked as unsuccessful, but then they resubmit and
								assessment and the outcome becomes successful?</para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para>They will not be issued a certificate in the first instance,
								because they were unsuccessful, however when the outcome is changed
								to success, it will trigger the certificate to be created</para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para>If a student has three outcomes attached to their enrolment are
								two are marked as successful and one is not marked, will they get a
								Statement of Attainment for the two successful outcomes?</para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para>No, the automated certificate creation process won't be triggered
								until the final outcome is marked. You can choose to make them a
								Statement of Attainment for the first two units manually, and when
								the third outcome is marked, they will get a second Statement of
								Attainment containing only that unit. If you do nothing, they will
								get a single statement containing all three units when the final
								outcome status is provided.</para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para>If a Statement of Attainment is created automatically for a
								student who partially succeed in completing a qualification, but I
								don't want to issue it, what should I do?</para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para>Before the Certificate is printed, you can delete it, or if it has
								been printed, revoke it.</para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
				</qandaset>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Manually creating certificates in bulk</title>
				<para>If you wish to create certificate records for the whole class group, we
					recommend creating the certificate records from the class cog wheel option. If
					at the course level, you checked the option 'Satisfies complete qualification or
					skill set' on the VET tab, enrolled students will be automatically generated
					either the qualification or skill set certificate for which the course is for.
					If you have not selected this option, Statements of Attainment will be
					generated. This option only selects outcomes from the student's record that have
					been created due to their enrolment in this particular class.</para>
				<para>Additional validation rules apply to this creation process to ensure that only
					student's who have achieved the outcome of the course are issued with the
					correct certification. For example, where a course is marked 'Satisfies complete
					qualification or skill set' on the VET tab, and the student has one or more unit
					with a non-successful outcome, a Statement of Attainment will be generated
					instead of a Qualification or skill set certificate. Where no outcomes have been
					marked as successful, no Statement of Attainment will be created.</para>
				<para>If you wish to create a certificate based on a single, or group of student's
					enrolments, then you can do the same thing from the enrolment window, by
					highlighting an enrolment or group of enrolments and using the cog wheel
					function to create the certificate records. Like the example above, this option
					only picks up outcomes attached to the particular enrolments you have selected
					(manual outcomes can be added to enrolments prior to certificate creation if
					needed)</para>
				<section>
					<title>How to create Certificates for a class group </title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para> Open the class window and highlight the class(es) you wish to
								create certificates for. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> Select the cog wheel option 'Create certificates'. This will
								automatically create Statements of Attainment or Qualifications
								(depending what was chosen at the course level and the student's
								outcomes) and transcripts for each student enrolled in the class.
								These records are created in the certificate table.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Open the certificate window and edit any certificates that need
								changes and/or delete any certificate records that have been created
								for students who are not eligible for certification. Units can be
								added or removed from individual certificates as needed, but only
								prior to printing. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You can create the certificates, but will not be able to print
								them, until each of the outcomes are set. Ensure the outcomes have
								been set in the class outcomes window, the enrolment records or via
								the student's contact record.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>From the certificate window and print the certificates as
								needed.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>How to create Certificates from enrolment records</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Highlight one or more enrolments in the enrolment list view
								window.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Go to the cog wheel and select the option 'create certificate(s)'.
								This will automatically create Statements of Attainment or
								Qualifications (depending what was chosen at the course level and
								the student's outcomes) and transcripts for each student enrolled in
								the class. These records are created in the certificate
								table.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Follow steps 3 to 5 above</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Creating certificates manually</title>
				<para>If you have a student whom has collected units of competency across multiple
					enrolments, and you want to print a certificate showing this, you can create a
					manual certificate directly in the certificate window, selecting your choice of
					qualification reference and appropriate units from their entire transcript list.
					To create a certificate record manually:</para>
				<section>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Open the Certificate window and click on the plus sign to begin
								creating certificates. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Type the student name into the first field. This field is
								clairvoyant. They student must be in the database and the name
								entered correctly to proceed. The students suburb and date of birth
								will be displayed when their record is found. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Enter the National Code for the Qualification, Accredited Course
								or skill set you wish to use for the certificate. This is not
								limited to qualifications the student has attempted at your college,
								as many units are valid towards a number of qualifications. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>If you wish to issue a full qualification or skill set, select
								'Satisfies complete qualification or skill set'. 'Statement of
								Attainment' will be selected by default.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Select the plus sign to begin adding modules/units from the
								students record to the certificate. You can add as many as you need
								– and you must ensure that you only add units that meet the
								qualification packaging rules of the qualification or skill set you
								selected above. Modules/units selected can be added to this
								certificate only once, however they can be used again to create
								other certificates in the future. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>By default, the Awarded on date will be the date you created the
								certificate record. Edit this if needed. At this point, the Issued
								on date will be blank, and will be set based on the date you print
								the certificate. You can manually set this date now if
								needed,</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Add any public notes that you wish to display on the certificate
								face, such as information about the funded program that this
								certificate was delivered under, or the language the training was
								delivered in if not English.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>If your certificate should have an expiry (E.G. a first-aid
								certificate), you can enter the expiry date into the expiry date
								field.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>When the information is correct, select save. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Created certificates appear in the summary window. From this
								window, you can print the certificates. Select file, print and
								choose which certificates you wish to print. </para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/certificate_edit_view.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Certificate edit view in full screen mode</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Step 2 - Verifying the Certificate</title>
			<section>
				<title>Manual verification prior to printing</title>
				<para>Certificate records in onCourse can either be full Qualifications, Statements
					of Attainment working towards a Qualification, Statements of Attainment with no
					qualification reference, or a Statement of Attainment for a skill set.</para>
				<para>If you have created the certificate from the course or enrolment cogwheel
					process, onCourse will select the most appropriate certificate type based on the
					course settings and the student's outcomes. For example, if a student enrolled
					in a complete qualification has one or more outcomes not set, a Statement of
					Attainment, rather than a Qualification will be created for them. You may need
					to add the missing outcome status and then change the certificate type to
					'qualification or skill set' prior to printing.</para>
				<para>You should confirm the certificate record that was created automatically is of
					the correct type prior to printing as this can not be changed afterwards.</para>
				<para>It is worth noting, that as with the course set up process, onCourse does not
					contain any reference data to determine if a full Qualification is valid or not.
					It is up to you as the certifying RTO to ensure when you create and issue a
					certificate record you have deemed a qualification, the student has achieved
					sufficient outcomes those outcomes are attached to the certificate
					record.</para>
				<para>You can also choose to attach unsuccessful outcomes to the certificate record,
					for example, outcomes where the student has withdrawn or been deemed not yet
					competent. These outcomes will print on the accompanying transcript that is
					generated when you print a certificate, but will not print on the Statement of
					Attainment certificate face. Only successful outcomes will print on the
					certificate face. </para>
				<para>If you wish to alter the Awarded on date from the default date the record was
					created, or the Issued on date from the default date the certificate was
					printed, you should do this prior to printing. These fields can be changed after
					printing if you notice the dates are incorrect, and the certificate
					reprinted.</para>
				<para>Add any public notes that you wish to display on the certificate face, such as
					information about the funded program that this certificate was delivered under,
					or the language the training was delivered in if not English, need to be
					manually added during the pre-printing verification process. There is no
					automatic population of this data from any where in onCourse. You can add
					information to this field, and the private notes field, after printing if you
					require, and reprint the certificate.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Certificate record verification during printing</title>
				<para>When you attempt to print a certificate created in onCourse, the following
					verification checks will take place. If the certificate is not valid, you will
					not be able to print it until you have corrected the data.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can attach any outcome from a students transcript to the
							certificate record, but if you attach an outcome where the status has
							not yet been set you will not be able to print the certificate record.
							Update the outcome status in the student's record first, then attempt to
							print again.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If a certificate record contains all unsuccessful outcomes e.g. 40
							withdrawn, it can not be printed. You may choose to delete this type of
							certificate record.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>As of 1 January 2015, it is mandatory for all student's being issued a
							VET certification to have a verified USI on record. During print
							attempts, a check is conducted against the student record and the print
							process may not be allowed. If the student doesn't have a USI or doesn't
							have a verified USI, an access control option can allow you override
							this restriction and print the certificate. More information is
							available in the <link xlink:href="usi.html">USI chapter</link></para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Revoking Certificates</title>
				<para>On occasion a printed certificate will contain an error, like a misspelled
					name.</para>
				<para>After printing a certificate, if you determine the certificate was printed in
					error, you can chose to revoke the certificate using the cogwheel option. This
					maintains the certificate reference in the database, with a note as to why you
					have revoked it. </para>
				<para>A revoked certificate can not be printed, but other valid certificates can be
					reprinted at any time. The last date you printed the certificate is
					automatically recorded in the certificate record.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Step 3 - Printing Certificates</title>
			<para>To print a single certificate, go to the Certificates list view then hit the share
				button. Select the type of certificate you'd like to print and the background you'd
				like to use, then hit Print. A PDF version of the certificate will appear for you to
				print off for a student, or attach to an email to send to them.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Customising the layout of your VET Certificate template</title>
				<para>The certificate templates in onCourse contain the information about the
					certificate that is stored in the onCourse database, like the student name,
					qualification name and code and unit names and codes.</para>
				<para>Your RTO contact and registration details, logos, other required certificate
					logos and any other fixed visual elements in a printed certificate template
					should be in your background document. </para>
				<para>When you print a certificate record from onCourse, the onCourse certificate
					record information is overlaid on your background document to create a AQF
					compliant certificate. You can store multiple report background types in
					onCourse to use during printing.</para>
				<section>
					<title>Certificate Backgrounds</title>
					<para>The standard Qualification report includes a second report, the
						transcript, as the second page while a Statement of Attainment is only a
						single page report.</para>
					<para>If you already have a certificate background you have had professionally
						designed, which you order from the printers, you can choose to embed this
						background in the report. You should request a A4 PDF of your backgrounds
						from your designers first.</para>
					<para>If you do not have a professionally designed background, you can easily
						create your own using a simple word processing tool. Keep in mind the ASQA
						guidelines for issuing certificates and the appropriate use of the formal
						logos, when designing your backgrounds.</para>
					<para>You will also need a second page PDF background for the transcript
						report.</para>
					<para>If you create and upload a two page PDF, comprised of your Qualification
						background design followed by your letterhead or transcript design, for
						example, these pages will be used correctly when printing the combined
						report from onCourse. If the transcript is more than one page long, the
						second page of the template will be used for the subsequent pages
						printed.</para>
					<para>If you are printing Qualifications in bulk, onCourse will recognise when
						the student record has changed to the next student and therefore apply the
						first page of the PDF background again as this is a new Qualification. </para>
					<para>When creating a background for a Statement of Attainment report, only a
						single page background is required. On occasion, Statements of Attainment
						may contain reference to more units that can fit during printing on a single
						page. In this instance, the report will be split into multiple certificate
						pages. Each certificate number will be appended with a page number on
						printing e.g. certificate 472 may display as 472/1 and 472/2 if multiple
						pages are created.</para>
					<para>If you are manually printing a range of Statements of Attainment and
						Qualifications to the printer at a time, and you have different backgrounds
						for these reports, you need to print them in two groups - once group the
						Qualifications with their background chosen, the next group the Statement of
						Attainments with their background chosen. If you use the onCourse automated
						script to run the print and issue process, the correct background will be
						selected automatically.</para>
					<para>There is more information about how you can create and update report
						backgrounds in the <link xlink:href="reports-printing">reports
							chapter</link> of the documentation.</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Certificate signatory name and title</title>
					<para>You can update the signatory name for your Certificate reports via the
						AVETMISS tab / General Preferences settings of onCourse. Remember that this
						field will appear as one line on your Certificate report, so you would add
						the name and title of the nominated signatory name in the one line. Go to
							<guimenuitem> File - Preferences - General Preferences</guimenuitem>and
						click on the AVETMISS tab, the 'Full certificate signatory name' field you
						need to edit is under 'Optional' on this tab. Whatever content you add to
						this field, will appear automatically within your Certificate Reports,
						unless your custom report has this information hard coded into it.</para>
					<para>If you require a different layout for the signatory fields i.e. two names,
						name and title on separate lines or embedded digital signature, we recommend
						you put all this data in the background and remove the signatory details
						from the onCourse report templates.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/EditSignatoryNameViaAVETMISSTab.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Updating signatory name via General Preferences</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Changes to the report templates</title>
					<para>Within the onCourse user interface, you can make some simple
						customisations of your certificate template wording. More detailed
						customisations require you to edit the report outside of onCourse.</para>
					<para>If you wish to make other changes to the fixed wording, the font sizes or
						styles or embed any other images into the certificate templates, then you
						will need to modify the report files outside of onCourse. You can do this
						yourself or you can request a quote from ish to do this for you if you are
						on any of our support plans. There is more information about how you can
						customise reports yourself in the <link xlink:href="reports-custom.html"
							>Creating custom reports chapter</link> of the documentation.</para>
				</section>
				<section xml:id="rto-qr">
					<title>Printing Certificates with QR Codes</title>
					<para>By default, the onCourse Statement of Attainment and Qualification
						Certificate templates print with an embedded QR code and unique URL for
						online certificate validation through the onCourse Certificate Verification
						Service.</para>
					<para>This service allows employers or other RTOs to verify the issuing data
						presented to them in PDF or paper format against the RTOs records, without
						having to make personal contact with your admin staff. The end user can scan
						the QR code, or visit the www.skills.courses URL and type in the
						verification code. They will then be shown the name, qualification and/or
						units of competency that the certificate was issued for, plus the issuing
						date and issuing RTO details.</para>
					<para>This online validation service allows you to meet your RTO obligations to
						ensure your Certification process is secure and difficult reproduce in a
						forgery context, and also to make your certification documentation
						accessible to past learners.</para>
					<para>If you do not wish to print certificates with QR codes you can uncheck
						this option during the print process.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/print_with_qr_code.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Printing a certificate with the QR code option enabled</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Examples of default Certificate layouts</title>
				<section>
					<title>Standard Qualification</title>
					<para>To create a qualification for a student you need to ensure the
						following:</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>If you are creating the Certificate directly from the class or the
								enrolment, the course has to have the option 'satisfies complete
								qualification or skill set' checked and be linked to a qualification
								by it's national code to create a certificate of type 'qualification
								or skill set'.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You need to manually confirm that the qualification record you are
								creating meets the training package requirements, by adding
								sufficient and valid units of competency from the student's record
								which they have completed successfully.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>When you print a Qualification you will also print a transcript
								which shows the outcomes status of each unit you have selected.
								Unsuccessful outcomes you have added to the certificate record will
								also print on the transcript. It is your choice to add these to the
								certificate record or not, depending on your organisation's
								policies.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/CertificateQualificationPageOne.png"
								format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Standard Qualification Certificate layout without a print
								background</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/CertificateQualificationPageTwo.png"
								format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Standard Transcript layout without a print background</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Qualification for a Traineeship/Apprenticeship</title>
					<para>As per the instructions above for creating a standard Qualification, you
						can modify a qualification certificate record to show the text 'achieved
						through Australian Apprenticeship arrangements' by entering this text in the
						public (printed) notes field in the certificate record.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/qualapprentice.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>A qualification achieved via an apprenticeship arrangement</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Statement of Attainment with qualification reference</title>
					<para>To create a Statement of Attainment that references a qualification to
						need to ensure the following:</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>If you are creating the Certificate directly from the class or the
								enrolment, the course has a qualification defined, and 'satisfies
								complete qualification or skill set' is not checked you will create
								a Statement of Attainment record linked to a qualification. If you
								have not defined the reference qualification in the course, you can
								define this in the certificate record before printing.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Any unsuccessful outcome you add to the certificate record will
								not print on the certificate face, but will print on the
								accompanying transcript.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/StatementOfAttainment.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Standard Statement of Attainment layout with reference to a
								qualification</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Statement of Attainment without qualification reference</title>
					<para>If you wish to create a Statement of Attainment that doesn't include a
						reference to a qualification, you need to ensure that National Code field is
						left blank in the certificate record. Otherwise the instructions are the
						same as above.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/soanoqual.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Statement of Attainment layout without a reference to a
								qualification</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Skills Set Statement of Attainment Certificate</title>
					<para>A skill set is a relatively new concept of a fixed grouping of units of
						competency to meet an industry need, that are less units than completing a
						whole qualification. Skill sets are defined by Training Packages and
						available on training.gov.au, and their names and codes are automatically
						downloaded into onCourse, along with units of competency and qualifications.
						You could think of a skill set as a mini qualification. In onCourse, they
						are treated similarly to a qualification, as in a student has to be
						competent in all of the skill set outcomes to be issued a complete skill
						set.</para>
					<para>Like a qualification, completed skill sets are reported in the AVETMIS
						NAT00130 file. Normal Statements of Attainment are not reported.</para>
					<para>If the course has been defined as being a 'complete qualification or skill
						set', and the student has successfully completed all the units of
						competency, then onCourse will attempt to create a skill set certificate for
						the participant.</para>
					<para>If you are manually creating a skill set certificate, you need to select
						the option inside the certificate window 'qualification or skill set' rather
						than Statement of Attainment, even though a skill set is a type of
						statement.</para>
					<para>On training.gov.au, each skill set includes suggested words for the
						Statement of Attainment. If you wish to add these words to your printed
						certificate, be sure to copy and paste them into the Certificate public
						(printed) notes fields.</para>
					<para>Below is an example of a Skill Set Certificate record, and a printed copy
						of the certificate using the default onCourse template with no
						background.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/skillset_certificate_set_up.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>A Skill Set certificate record</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/reports/soaskillset.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Statement of Attainment layout for a Skill Set Certificate without
								a background</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="rto-attaching">
			<title>Certificate Distribution</title>
			<para>If you wish to distribute your VET Certificates electronically, you can either
				enable the default onCourse script to schedule this print and distribution process
				automatically, or you can manually print and distribute the PDF.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Scripted Certificate Distribution</title>
				<para>A default onCourse script called 'send certificate vet created notification'
					is available to enable so you can automate the printing, upload to the portal
					and notification to students of their VET certificate availability.</para>
				<para>By default, this script runs at 5am each day and prints all unprinted
					certificates in the database, where the student has a verified USI.</para>
				<para>Before you enable this script you need to ensure you have created and tested
					the printing of the certificate reports with the following backgrounds:</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">vet_qualification_background.pdf</emphasis> this
							background is for printing certificates of type full Qualification. It
							should be a two page background with a certificate face page, followed
							by a transcript page background</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">vet_soa_background.pdf</emphasis> this
							background is for printing certificates of type Statement of Attainment.
							It should be a two page background with a certificate face page,
							followed by a transcript page background</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">vet_skillset_background.pdf</emphasis> this
							background is for printing special Statements of Attainment that are of
							full Skill Set type. It should be a two page background with a
							certificate face page, followed by a transcript page background</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para>This script sends the email template 'certificate available' which you should
					adjust as needed before enabling the script. Keep in mind this email template is
					also used by the script to send non-VET certificates, 'send certificate created
					notification', so if you adjust it, and use both scripts, then the wording needs
					to make sense for both VET and non-VET courses. Alternatively, you could make a
					copy of this template, and use two different versions, one for each
					script.</para>
				<para>When the script runs, it will send an email, with the default template
					encouraging the student to complete the course feedback process in the
					portal.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/vet_cert_email.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Email to notify the student their certificate is available</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/portal_feedback.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>After clicking on the link in the email the student can provide
							feedback</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/vet_soa_email_sample.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Statement of Attainment PDF available in the portal for the student to
							download or print</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Manually creating and issuing PDF Certificates</title>
				<para>Once you have printed a Certificate to PDF, you can either send the PDF as an
					email attachment (outside of onCourse) or attach the Certificate PDF record to
					the student's Enrolment using the onCourse document management system so it is
					available in the student's skillsonCourse portal, and send them an email with
					the link. </para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Print the Certificate to PDF with the background of your
							choice.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/printing_a_certificate.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Printing a certificate</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Save the PDF file to a location on your computer, and give it a name
							that makes sense for later retrieval i.e. the students name and
							qualification</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/saving_a_certificate_on_your_computer.png"
									format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Saving a certificate to your computer</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Find the enrolment you want to attach the certificate in the
							enrolments list view.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/enrolment_list_view.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open the enrolment record and go to the Attachments tab.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/enrolment_edit_view_attachments_tab.png"
									format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Attaching the certificate to the enrolment record</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the '+' icon at the top right side of the window, then find
							the Certificate PDF you have just saved on your computer. More
							information about how to upload at file can be found in the <link
								xlink:href="documentManagement.html">Document Management
								chapter.</link></para>
						<note>
							<para>When uploading the Certificate you will need to set the Access
								level to 'Tutors and enrolled students' otherwise the student won't
								be able to see if in skillsonCourse</para>
						</note>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/attaching_certificate_enrolment.png"
									format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
						<para>Once the Certificate is attached to their enrolment record, the
							student will be able to see the file and download it in their
							skillsonCourse portal.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Send the student an email advising them the certificate is available
							in the portal. If you create an email template to this, you can use the
							code <code>${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(document)}</code> to send
							the student a login free link directly to retrieve their Certificate.
							After 7 days, this login free link expires, however the student can
							still click the link and login to access their Certificate again at any
							time. If you want to extend the link beyond 7 days, to say 30 days,
							format the link <code>${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(document,
								30)}</code></para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Verifying VET Certificates issued from onCourse</title>
		<para>onCourse supports your requirement to verify VET certification for Employers, other
			RTOs and interested parties with the Certificate Verification Portal. The Portal is an
			automated verification service of VET Certificates and Statements of Attainment issued
			in onCourse using the QR code printing function. See <xref linkend="rto-qr"/> for more
			information on printing your certificate with a QR code. </para>
		<para>Interested parties can confirm the certificate was issued to the student named without
			the need to contact your RTO. </para>
		<para>The Employers or RTOs have three options to access the service <orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>From a tablet or phone, scan the QR code using a QR code reader. This will
						prompt them to visit the portal. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From a computer, tablet or phone, open the PDF certificate and click on
						the QR code. This will prompt them to open the Portal. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From a computer, tablet or phone, go to the URL <link
							xlink:href="http://www.skills.courses">http://www.skills.courses</link>
						and typing in the unique certificate code</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist></para>
		<para>A verification page will be displayed with an electronic record of the units
			successfully completed, student name and date of issue. </para>
		<para>A revoked certificate or statement will state it was revoked. If the code used is
			invalid, or a false code used, it will display 'no certificate found'.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/mobile_portal_verify.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Welcome to the certificate verification portal</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/verified_soa.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A verified Statement of Attainment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/verified_cert.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>A verified Qualification Certificate</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/revoked_cert.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>A revoked certificate or statement</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/no_cert.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>No certificate or statement found</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Exporting Certificate data</title>
		<para>As an RTO, you may be required to provide reports of the certificates you have issued
			to your VET Regulator. In Western Australia, a defined format for providing this
			information existing in a format called the Client Qualifications Register (CQR). </para>
		<para>In other states and territories, there is no set defined format, outside the AVETMISS
			data reporting of the NAT00130 file.</para>
		<para>onCourse contains both a CQR layout export CSV option for use in WA and a generic
			Certificate CSV export option for use in other jurisdictions. Both of these file formats
			can be opened in Excel, Numbers or other spreadsheet or text editing tool of your choice
			to view or edit.</para>
		<para>To access these exports, first select the records in the certificate window you wish
			to export by either running an advanced search or by highlighting the records in the
			window.</para>
		<para>Then go to File > Import/Export > Export Certificates and then from the Export Format
			option in the export sheet, choose your preferred export format.</para>
		<para>When you run the export the last step is to choose the location for saving the file. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/certificate_CQR_export.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Exporting certificate registrar data in the CQR format</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Non-VET Certificates of Attendance</title>
		<para>Certificates of Attendance can be created manually and printed to paper for
			distribution, or automatically created when the class is finished and distributed via
			PDF upload to the skillsOnCourse portal, with automatic email notifications to students. </para>
		<para>By default, the automated script is disabled in new onCourse databases, but you are
			free to enable or disable this script as your require.</para>
		<section>
			<title> Manually creating Certificates of Attendance for non-VET courses </title>
			<para>Sometimes colleges run non-VET courses that are not eligible to receive official
				Qualifications or Statements of Attainment, however the students would still like to
				receive some recognition that they completed the course. In this case, you may wish
				to supply the student with a Certificate of Attendance. Please refer to the latest
				AQF Certification Guidelines regarding the issuing of non-VET certifications.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> Open the class window and select the class(es) you wish to create
						certificates for. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select the cog wheel option 'Create certificates'. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select proceed and the certificates will be created on in a PDF file to
						the location you specify. You can then print these certificates as needed.
						The whole classes certificates are created in the one PDF file. If you only
						want to print a certificate for one student, locate it in the PDF and use
						your print functions to print the specific page. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Alternatively you can print a Certificate of Attendance for a single
						student by going to the enrolment window, highlighting the student's
						enrolment and selecting File > Print > Certificate of Attendance</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> You can re-create these certificates at any time. There are no records
						created in the certificate window as they are not VET certifications.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Manually creating a Certificate of Attendance for a VET class student</title>
			<para>On occasion, a student may attend a VET course but choose not to be assessed. If
				they have met your attendance requirements, you may choose to issue them a
				Certificate of Attendance.</para>
			<para>You can do this by going to the enrolment window, highlighting the student's
				enrolment and selecting File > Print > Certificate of Attendance</para>
			<para>Please note that if you have named the course the official title of the
				Qualification or Unit of Competency (e.g. Certificate IV in Frontline Management)
				their Certificate of Attendance will include that wording.</para>
			<para>No certificate record is created in the certificate table for the printing of a
				Certificate of Attendance. This is just a printed report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/Certificate-Attendance.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Certificate of Attendance printed for a VET student who chose not to be
						assessed</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Automatically create and issue Certificates of Attendance</title>
			<para>The onCourse script "send certificate created notification" is an automated
				process that will:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Checks at 6am daily for all non-VET classes that had their last session
						the day before</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Optionally check for 80% or other minimum attendance requirement before
						creating the certificate</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Print to PDF a Certificate of Attendance using the background template
						"certificate_attendance_backgound.pdf"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Attach the PDF to the student's enrolment record and upload it to the
						skillsOnCourse portal</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Send the student and email notification with a no-login link to complete a
						short survey and download their certificate</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>Before you enable this script, there are some tasks you need to undertake to
				ensure the script and associated emails are configured to meet your
				requirements.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Decide if you want to check attendance before issuing Certificates of
					Attendance</title>
				<para>The standard script includes a commented out option to check the attendance of
					students before issuing them with a Certificate of Attendance.</para>
				<para>To enable this requirement you will need edit rights to adjust the script. We
					suggest you copy the script into an editor such as Sublime to make these
					changes, then copy your changes back into the script body when it is
					complete.</para>
				<para>There are instructions inside the script to show you how to adjust the
					requirement to 80%. For example, below is an adjusted script to only issue
					Certificates of Attendance to students who had met a 75% attendance
					requirement.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/adjust_script_attendance.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Changes made to the default script rules to check for a 75% attendance
							before issuing the certificate</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Create and test a certificate background</title>
				<para>The script calls on a PDF background in onCourse named
					'certificate_attendance_backgound.pdf' to merge with the report inside onCourse
					called 'Certificate-Attendance', called by the script through it's keycode
					""ish.oncourse.nonVetCertificate"</para>
				<para>If you have a custom Certificate of Attendance report with a different
					keycode, and/or a background report with a different name, you can change the
					references inside the script to point to different files.</para>
				<para>If you do not want to edit the script, and use the standard
					'Certificate-Attendance' report as is, you will need to make sure you have
					uploaded a background with the exact name
					'certificate_attendance_backgound.pdf'. Note that the file name is all in lower
					case and uses underscores, not hyphens, to separate each word. Create, edit and
					save the background document on your local computer, and then upload it to
					onCourse for testing.</para>
				<para>You can do this by opening the enrolment window, highlighting an enrolment and
					choosing File > Print > Certificate-Attendance. In the print dialogue background
					drop down, select Import from disk... and import your background. You will then
					see it available to select without the PDF extension on the end of the file
					name. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/print_certificate_attendance_with_background.png"
							format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Selecting and printing a Certificate of Attendance with the specified
							background for this script</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>Print and test your report layout, and if it is successful it will look
					something like this:</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/certificate_attendance_with_background.png" format="png"
						/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>A sample Certificate of Attendance printed with a custom
							background</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>If you need to adjust your background document layout after testing, return to
					the original file on your computer and make the necessary changes. Ensure the
					file is saved with the same name on your computer.</para>
				<para>Before you try testing the background in onCourse again, delete the first copy
					of the background by going to File > Preferences > Reports and click on the
					cogwheel option 'Manage print backgrounds'. Locate the background called
					'certificate_attendance_backgound', single click on it and delete it. </para>
				<para>Repeat the earlier process of printing, uploading and testing the background
					layout and alignment with the embedded report elements until you are satisfied
					with the result.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Customise your email template</title>
				<para>The onCourse email template 'certificate available' contains a time based link
					to allow the recipient to access their class via the skillsOnCourse portal,
					complete the satisfaction survey, and download their certificate as a PDF all
					without logging in.</para>
				<para>The link is valid from 7 days after the email is sent. If the user clicks on
					the link after 7 days, they will be redirected to the login screen to supply
					their name, email address and password before they can access their
					certificate.</para>
				<para>By default, the link in the email template is to
						<code>${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(enrolment)}</code>, which takes the
					student to their class page and presents them with the survey. If you do not
					wish to use this feature, you can instead replace the link in the template with
						<code>${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(certificate)}</code> to direct the
					student directly to their certificate. You will also want to adjust the wording
					of the template depending on which link you use. Be sure to make your changes to
					both the plain text and HTML versions of the email.</para>
				<para>You can test your emails by ensuring an enrolled student has your email
					address in their contact record and using the send email from template function
					in the enrolment window cogwheel.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/certificate_attendance_available_survey_HTML.png"
							format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>A sample email advising the student their certificate is available
							after completing the survey</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
