<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="classes">
	<title>Creating Classes</title>
	<section xml:id="classes-Definitions">
		<title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Course</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A course is the training product delivered by your organisation. For
						example: Computers for Beginners, Advanced Jewellery Making or MYOB for
						Professionals. A course can be given any course code to identify that course
						uniquely. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Class</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A class is the instance of a course run at a particular time and date, led
						by one or more tutors and with a group of students enrolled. Classes may
						meet for one or more sessions depending on the subject outline and
						timetable. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Timetable</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Each class has a timetable which represents each meeting between the
						students and the tutor(s). The timetable can link to rooms and sites and
						each session in the timetable has the flexibility to be allocated to a
						different tutor or a different room. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Students</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A student is a person enrolled in a class.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-workingWith">
		<title>Working with Classes</title>
		<subtitle>Navigating the list and record windows</subtitle>
		<para>All records in onCourse can be viewed in either a list view or record view. You need
			to open the list view to access individual records. </para>
		<para>To access the class records go to either the splash screen and click on
				<guibutton>Class</guibutton> or the onCourse menu <menuchoice>
				<guimenuitem>Courses</guimenuitem>
				<guisubmenu>Classes</guisubmenu>
			</menuchoice> . This will open the Class list view window. </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>The onCourse list view</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Parts of the window</emphasis> -On the right hand part of
					the window are the class records listed in a summary view. The title bar shows
					you how many records you have. The top section of the window contains the search
					function and the add and delete records button. You will also find a cog wheel
					button that allows for special functions for one or more records in the list. In
					the left hand side of the list window are quick searches to enable you to work
					with groups of data. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Record Summaries</emphasis> - The list of records in this
					window allows you to enter a record by double clicking, or select the record to
					perform special functions by single clicking. A selected record will be
					highlighted. You can select one or more records in the list by using shift-click
					to select a range, or control-click to select a group of individual records.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Columns and sorting</emphasis> - Column headings can be
					used to sort records in the list. Click on the header to sort in alphabetical
					order. Click it again to sort by reverse alphabetical order. You can also drag
					the columns around and modify their width to set your preferred layout. 9</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Quick Search</emphasis> - By typing the first few letters
					of the course name or code into the quick search field, you can reduce the list
					of records to those that match. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Advanced Search</emphasis> - Advanced search can be
					accessed by cl icking on the Magnifying glass image in the quick search field.
					This will open the query editor to allow you to choose which fields and which
					data you want to search on. You can add multiple criteria to your searches.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Saved Searches</emphasis> - After performing an advanced
					search, you can choose to save the search parameters to allow you to quickly run
					the search again. To save a search, click on the cogwheel within the query
					editor and select 'save find'. The saved search will appear in the left hand
					part of the window. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Tag Groups</emphasis> - Any tag groups you have created
					that relate to classes or their parent record, courses, like Subject, will
					appear here. By checking any of these check boxes you will see the list of
					records on the right hand side reduced to records that match that criteria. You
					can tag records in bulk by selecting a group of records on the right and right
					clicking on a tag name on the left. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Core Filters</emphasis> - Core filters reduce the list of
					records to those that match the filter criteria. By default, most onCourse
					windows open with filters applied so you are only working with your current
					records. You can switch core filters on and off by ticking the checkboxes. By
					default, each time the class window opens the core filters of <guilabel>current
						classes</guilabel> and <guilabel>future classes</guilabel> are selected. You
					can check the other core filters as needed. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<tip>
			<para>Filters and searches work together in onCourse. If you run a search and do not see
				the result you expect, this may be because a filter that is checked is preventing
				the record you are searching for from being displayed. </para>
		</tip>
		<para>You can enter a class record by double clicking on it in the window.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-specialFunctions">
		<title>Special Class Functions</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/cog.png"
					format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The cog wheel - used to perform special actions to selected classes</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>On the classes list view you will see a cog wheel icon on the right hand side of the
			window. If you highlight one or more classes in the list and then click on the cog
			wheel, a drop down menu will appear offering a range of different options. Some of these
			functions are only available through the cog wheel, while others are options that you
			can set in an individual class, but though the cog wheel can set for a group of classes. </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Send message to students from x class</emphasis> - This
					option allows you to send email and/or sms, or postal messages to students
					enrolled in the selected class or classes. You might use this option to let all
					the students enrolled in classes with a particular tutor know that their tutor
					is sick and classes this week are cancelled. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Send message to tutors from x class</emphasis> - You can
					contact the tutor from one or more classes using this options. You might use it
					to notify all tutors who are teaching this term of a staff meeting. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Duplicate x class</emphasis> - To create another
					instance of an existing class, the duplicate function will save you the effort
					of setting all the information again. Need to offer another class in a
					fortnight? Duplicate the class and move it forward by 14 days. You can also move
					a whole term of classes forward to the next term in one action. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Cancel class</emphasis> - If a class is not viable, you
					can use this cogwheel function to cancel it and create credit notes for all the
					enrolled students. Students can't enrol in cancelled classes. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">AVETMISS export</emphasis> - Exporting AVETMISS from the
					classes window allows you to export the data for one or more classes for a
					funding submission. A whole term or year's worth of data can be exported from
					the Export window. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Create certificates</emphasis> - For VET classes, this
					will create Statements of Attainment or Qualifications for all eligible
					students. For all other classes, this option will create a Certificate of
					Attendance for all enrolled students. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Generate payslips for x class</emphasis> - Use this
					option to create payslips for a selected group of classes. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Show class on website</emphasis> - You can add classes
					in bulk to your onCourse website with this option, instead of doing it one at a
					time in the individual class window. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Remove class from website</emphasis> - Use this option
					to remove classes in bulk from your onCourse website. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-recordTabs">
		<title>Class Record Tabs</title>
		<section xml:id="classes-General">
			<title>General tab</title>
			<para>This is a summary tab for the class showing information like the timetable
				summary, fee and applicable discounts, tutor summary and important notes regarding
				whether the Class running costs have been met. You can also flag a given Class as
					<guilabel>Self Paced</guilabel>, if the Class does not have a set timetable.
				This is a very important tab as it allows you to change the status of the class. You
				can select from the following options:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enrolment disabled - this means no one can enrol in the class via
						QuickEnrol or your website.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enrolment allowed - this means enrolment is allowed via QuickEnrol, but
						not online. This is the default value of a class when it is first
						created.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enrolment allowed and visible online - displays the class on the web and
						enables enrolment everywhere.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Cancelled - all enrolments have been cancelled, and no new enrolments can
						be taken for this class. This option can not be selected from within the
						class record - use the cog wheel from the class list window to cancel a
						class. Cancelled classes will still display on your website unless you
						choose to remove them using the cog wheel.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>As well as all this, the general tab has a handy summary above the status drop
				down menu: </para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Timetable Summary - including number of sessions, start and end dates (if
						applicable), Site and Room information</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Budget Summary - including Class fee which can be adjusted via the
							<guilabel>edit</guilabel> link to amend the fee amount. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Discounts fee rates applicable to this Class</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Indicative information on number of enrolments required to meet the Class
						running costs</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Tutor Summary - listing all teaching staff assigned to the Class</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Tags - any class specific tags that have been attached to this
						record</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Message alert for operator - important information you wish to share with
						your fellow onCourse users about this class e.g. 'remind enrolling students
						there is no class on the Queen's Birthday long weekend'. The copy entered
						here will appear in red text inside QuickEnrol when this class is selected
						for enrolment. This information is not published to the web.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>This overview and these calculations are designed to show you at a glance if the
				class is financially viable based on the budget expenses and current enrolment
				numbers.</para>
			<para>You can also set minimum and maximum enrolment ages for the class in this window.
				These restrictions apply only for enrolment in this particular instance of the
				class, and will prevent students without a date of birth from enrolling in this
				class, as well as preventing students who don't meet the age requirements from
				enrolling. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/class_general_tab.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of content within the Class general tab</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Self paced classes</title>
				<para>If you select <guilabel>Self Paced</guilabel> learning within the general tab,
					the tab will update to display additional fields for the operator to add the
						<guilabel>Maximum days to complete</guilabel> and the <guilabel>Expected
						study hours</guilabel> for this Class. You can also select a
						<guilabel>Virtual site</guilabel>for this Class. Please note that by
					nominating that the Class is to be self paced, the Class record will no longer
					display the Timetable tab, as this is not relevant for a Class with no set
					timetable. Any sessions you have previously created in the timetable will be
					deleted when you set a class to self paced.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/class_general_tab_self_paced_settings.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Set the maximum days to complete and expected study hours within the
							General tab of the Class record</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<note>
					<para>When setting a given Class as <guilabel>Self Paced</guilabel>, the start
						date and end date for the student outcomes are set as follows: </para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Start Date is the date the student enrols in the Class</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>End date is the start date plus the maximum days to complete that
								has been set for the Class via the General tab.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</note>
				<para>Self paced classes display online similar to a timetabled class. The words
					'self paced' appear in place of the start and end dates and instead of a fixed
					duration, show the words approximately xx hours' based on the expected study
					hours you set in the class general tab. As there is no start or end date, self
					paced classes will display online and available for enrolment until you choose
					to change their status and remove them from website display.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/self_paced_online.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>This is an example of a self paced class which has been enabled for
							online enrolment</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Tutor">
			<title>Tutor tab</title>
			<para>This tab allows you to add one or more tutors to the class. Tutors roles can be
				selected, tutors can be confirmed and tutor payrates set. You can also choose if the
				tutor is to be published as part of the class promotional material, either online or
				in a printed format. Select the "Show this tutor in class information" checkbox to
				have the tutor appear on your onCourse website linked to the class and in any
				exports or reports you run. </para>
			<para>If you show you tutors in your onCourse website, this also allows their associated
				profile picture, resume/bio and links to other classes they are teaching to be
				displayed.</para>
			<para>Tutor roles are defined in the onCourse preferences > Tutor roles. This is where
				you can name the roles specific to your organsiation and set the default pay rates
				that apply to a tutor of this role type. More information about this feature can be
				found in <xref xlink:href="#payroll"/>. You can override the payrate that applies
				for this particular instance of the class where needed, while keeping the
				relationship to the original tutor role name.</para>
			<para>Tutors can use their skillsOnCourse portal to confirm their availability to teach
				the class, or you can manually set the date they confirm in their tutor
				record.</para>
			<para>If you select the option 'Add the selected tutor to all class sessions' the tutor
				will be ticked against each session. This will create a payroll line for the tutor
				for that session. You can check and uncheck each tutor per session in the timetable
				tab.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/class_tutor_tab.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Edit view of Tutor window to allow a Tutor to be assigned and tutor role
						to be set</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Budgets">
			<title>Budget tab</title>
			<para>The budget feature is enabled with some paid onCourse support contracts. Check
				your college's support agreement to see if this feature has been enabled for your
				organisation. </para>
			<para>Class budgets allow users to add additional income, expense and wages lines to
				assist your program coordinators to determine the profitability of a class. In
				addition to the income collected from your current enrolments, you can predict the
				income and expenses you will incur for any projected number of enrolments. </para>
			<para>This function can be particularly useful for long term income planning. For
				example, if you are in a position to schedule your classes a year in advance, you
				can predict the income for each class based on the class budget. Throughout the year
				you can compare your actuals to your predicted income and see how you are tracking
				against the budget. </para>
			<para>For more information about how to create a class budget and track expenditure and
				income for classes, visit <xref xlink:href="#budgets"/></para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Timetable">
			<title>Timetable tab</title>
			<para>The timetable tab is used to create sessions for your class, from here you can set
				the following:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Site and room</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Tutor(s) assigned to deliver each session</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>First session starts - The start time and date of the first session of the
						class</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Session Duration</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Payable time - the time payable to the tutor, for example this could be
						shorter than the session duration by 30mins to account for an unpaid break,
						or longer than the session duration to account for coordination
						duties</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The session repetition schedule e.g. 10 sessions x 8 weeks</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Training plan (for courses with multiple units of competency
						attached)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Private notes (for scheduling or equipment notes)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Public notes (for session content you want to publish to students and the
						web)</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>The timetable tab let's you view the class sessions in different visual formats,
				via switching the tabs on the bottom on the page between:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Day</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Week</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>8 Weeks</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Month</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>List - offers a summary of all sessions and their attributes like start
						date and time, tutors and duration.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>In the class timetable, you can also see if any sessions or resources you have
				chosen conflict with other existing bookings. This might be other classes in the
				same room, or with the same tutor, or unavailability bookings across the whole
				college, or linked resource.</para>
			<para>If the parent course of your class is linked to multiple units of competency you
				can use the class timetable to create a training plan. By default, all outcomes will
				be set to be delivered on all sessions of the class, meaning the start and end date
				of each student outcome will default to the start and end date of the class. More
				information about creating training plans is available in <xref xlink:href="#rto"
				/></para>
			<para>Each session can also have it's own public and private notes. Public notes are
				designed for information you want to publish to students like the training content
				of each session. Private notes are for internal notes like resourcing or room
				configuration issues you want to record for the delivery of each session.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/doublebooking.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>This class shows a number of sessions with double booked resources</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-VET">
			<title>VET tab</title>
			<para>This tab relates to RTOs. AVETMISS and VET Fee Help funding source information can
				be set here for the whole class group, and modified on a student by student basis
				via their enrolment or outcome records as needed. Please note some of these fields
				are state specific. The default values of the 'Delivery mode' and 'Funding source
				national' can be set in the general preferences AVETMISS tab.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Web">
			<title>Web tab</title>
			<para>You can add class specific web information to this tab, plus class specific
				attachments that appear in the public website, in the student or tutor portals or
				are part of your private record keeping for this class.</para>
			<para> Most advertising information will come from the course record's marketing tab.
				Content added to the class web tab will appear in the class display box with the
				heading: Important information. It is recommended that you only use this field for
				limited content, like 'Funding available for existing workers' or 'This class is
				assessment only for RPL/RCC candidates"</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/website_class_description.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of content in the class Web tab displayed within the class
						summary</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Notes">
			<title>Notes tab</title>
			<para>This tab allows you to make your own internal notes regarding the class. These are
				not published to the website. </para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Enrolments">
			<title>Enrolments tab</title>
			<para>You can see a list of the students enrolled on this tab. The list view is quite
				simple, it shows you four columns:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Name</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Class</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Course name</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Status</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>Only students who currently have a status of active are enrolled in the class.
				Student's you see on this list with statuses of cancelled or credited have withdrawn
				from the class and are no longer counted in the enrolment totals.</para>
			<para>You can click on the open record icon next to the student's name to open their
				full record and confirm details of their payment status, contact details or previous
				enrolment history.</para>
			<para>Double clicking on a record in this list opens the students enrolment record for
				this class, allowing you to change details relating to the student's outcomes,
				funding or fees.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/class_enrolment_tab.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enrolment tab of Class Record including links to student records</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Attendance">
			<title>Attendance tab</title>
			<para>For each session created, and each student enrolled or tutor attached to the
				class, an attendance record will be created. Both students and tutors can be marked
				and you can add notes to the attendance record. The percentage attendance will be
				calculated. Tutor attendance is used for payroll calculations. You can mark a tutor
				or student with the following drop down options by clicking on 'mark all tutors' or
				'mark all students or by clicking the individual dates listed: </para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Attended - accompanied by a green tick</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Absent with reason - accompanied by a grey cross</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Absent without reason - accompanied by a red cross</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Partial attendance- accompanied by a clear tick</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not marked - accompanied by little icon of person</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>You can also add notes to attendance records e.g. provided medical certificate.
				You will also see a calculation of the percentage the class the student has
				attended, to monitor the student's attendance requirements.</para>
			<para>Clicking on each of the individual icons will cycle between attended (green tick);
				absent without reason (red cross); and back to the unmarked (person icon) options.
				To enter an absent with reason or partial attendance option, right click on the
				icon. A sheet will drop down allowing you to specify more information. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/markedattendance.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Students showing different attendance statuses and percentages</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="classes-Outcomes">
			<title>Outcomes tab</title>
			<para>This is a tab relevant to RTOs. The summary of the training plan created in the
				class timetable is displayed in the top half of the window.</para>
			<para>For each enrolled student, all the applicable outcomes for the class are shown
				here. For each unit of competency set in the parent course, the students enrolled
				will have an outcome record. Outcomes can be set and modified here. The list view
				contains the following columns:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Module/Course - the name or the module or unit of competency</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>National code - code of the module or unit of competency</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Name - enrolled student's name</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Status - click on this field to select and set and outcome status. By
						default, all outcomes will be set to 'not set' until a value is
						defined.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Start date - the default value in this field is inherited from the class
						training plan e.g. the first session date where this outcome is selected.
						Click in this field to override the start date for an individual
						outcome.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>End date - the default value in this field is inherited from the class
						training plan e.g. the last session date where this outcome is selected.
						Click in this field to override the end date for an individual
						outcome.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Delivery mode - the default value in this field is inherited from the
						class VET tab. Click in this field to override the value for an individual
						outcome.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>Each of these columns can be used to sort the list of data, and each record can
				also be double clicked on to see and edit more options relating to the
				outcome.</para>
			<para>You can also select a series of outcomes and right click to set the outcome status
				to 'Competency achieved/pass' in bulk.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-creatingClasses">
		<title>Creating Classes</title>
		<subtitle>Creating an instance of a course</subtitle>
		<para> It is very important that before you try to create a class you have already created a
			course.</para>
		<para>Through the classes screen you can:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para> Create classes and make them ready for enrolment </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Allocate rooms </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Assign Tutors </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Set the price of classes and applicable discounts </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Create sessions and timetables </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Keep check of enrolments </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Update budgeting information </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Enter and update your VET funding information </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Enter student outcomes and mark attendance</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Publish your classes on your website ready to take online enrolments </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>When you create a class, you bring together all the different elements of data that
			you have already entered into onCourse. Information relating to tutors, courses, sites
			and rooms etc. gets linked through the classes screen to create the event that is your
			class. </para>
		<para>For example when you assign a tutor to a class through the class screen, this
			information is also duplicated on the tutor's contact screen. So when you look at that
			tutor's screen you will see what class, which location and when the tutor is scheduled
			to teach.</para>
		<para>Once you have created a class, if you wish to offer the same program again, but
			starting on a different date, it is a simple process to duplicate the class. This allows
			all the information you have already set up to be copied into a new class, but moves the
			sessions forward to your new start date. You can also manage class duplications in bulk,
			copying all your classes from one semester to the next. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>Many colleges develop special codes to assist in identifying classes in groups
				like categories or regions to make them easier to remember and search on. A simple
				method is to number or alphabetise the classes. For example if your course is
				Dancing For Beginners and the course code is DFB, you may wish to create the class
				code for the first class of this course as “01”. This will then allow future classes
				in this same course to be listed in order ie. 01, 02, 03. When you duplicate the
				class the final number will automatically increment. </para>
		</tip>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a new class</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the class list window, click on the the <guibutton>+</guibutton>
						button in the top right hand corner of the screen. A new class screen will
						open to the general tab. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>All classes must be linked to a course you have already created. Begin
						setting up your class by typing the course name and select it from the drop
						down list. Once you have entered the course name you will see that the
						course code is automatically displayed in the 'Course code' field. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The next available class code will be automatically assigned, however you
						can change it to a code of your choice. Your class code must be unique; that
						is a code not used by any other class already created for that course.
						Please note that the class code must not have any spaces or hyphens between
						characters. The pink coloured field will change from invalid (pink) to valid
						(white) once you have entered your information correctly. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Complete any relevant fields on the General tab, such as if the class is
						self paced, has an aged based enrolment restriction or requires a message
						alert.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>By default, your class will be set to a status of 'Enrolment allowed'.
						Change it if needed to another status.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Now go to the tutor tab. This is where you can assign tutors to classes.
						Click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> sign on the right hand side of the
						screen. A drop down sheet will appear. Type the tutor's name in the tutor
						field, surname first. This is an autcomplete field so once you start typing,
						a selection of tutor's names you have previously entered will be listed.
						Select the tutor you want from the list and complete the appropriate
						information in the tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Repeat these steps to enter an additional tutor or course supervisor.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the Budget tab to set the class fee. It is important if your college
						has multiple income accounts to select the correct account for the class
						during the setup phase.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set a student fee for the class firstly, select whether or not to
						charge GST for the class or N for no GST. Make your selection then either
						enter your student fee exclusive of tax in the field 'Amount' or enter in
						the total fee including tax in the 'Amount inc tax' field. Which ever field
						you enter, the value of the other field will be automatically calculated.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Add any applicable income, expense or wage items using the + button in the
						top left hand corner of the budget tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your class will automatically have the default minimum and maximum
						enrolment numbers as per your general preferences. Update these numbers as
						applicable for this class, and enter the number of your predicted enrolment
						numbers in the 'Projected' field.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Add any class specific information that is required to the web tab or
						notes tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>For a self paced course, save and close the record. For a class with
						timetabled sessions, move on to the timetable tab and complete the steps
						from the example 'How to create sessions'.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to create sessions</title>
			<para>The following is a detailed example of how you would add sessions for a class on
				different days of the week. This example will use the scenario of a user wanting to
				add 10 sessions on consecutive Mondays and Wednesdays and a final session for
				assessment on a Saturday. </para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>On the timetable tab enter the start date and time for the first Monday
						session. In onCourse, the date and time share a field, so you need to type
						something like 22/9/2014 9am. You can also click on the calendar icon to use
						the date selector tool to find the start date of your choice. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter a duration for the session in hours and minutes e.g. 8 hrs. If the
						tutor will not be paid for the full duration for the session (e.g. an upaid
						lunch break) change the value in the payable time option. Note that changing
						this value will effect all tutors attached to this session who are paid at
						an hourly rate.</para>
					<para>Select from the tutor list any tutor(s) you wish to assign to these
						sessions.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/payable_hours.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>You can have a different value for the session duration and for
								the sessions payable hours</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose how many times this session will repeat. For this example we will
						enter 5, for the five sessions on the Monday and select the option every 1
						week.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>By clicking on the option 'week' you can change the repeat to hourly,
						daily, weekly, monthly or yearly, and make the repeat every 2 weeks or 3
						months, for example. If you choose a daily repeat you can choose to skip
						weekends. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Press the button 'create sessions'.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Now you need to do all of this again (from step 1 to 4) for the Wednesday
						sessions. Go the tab on the timetable labelled 'New' to add these new
						sessions to your existing Monday sessions. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Do it all again with a single session on the Saturday and save and close
						the record. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>If you create any sessions in error, save and close the record before you re-open
				the class record and delete or edit the sessions. You can single click on a session
				to change the date, room, duration, payable time or tutors assigned.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/timetable_sessions.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The eleven class sessions for the scenario described above.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also had either public or private notes to a session. These fields can be
				used for free notes to add training plan information, catering information or other
				resourcing requirements. </para>
			<para>To edit the training plan or session notes you need to click on each session to
				see these fields.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/private_and_public_notes.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding public and private notes to sessions</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-VETdata">
		<title>Adding RTO and VET data to class records</title>
		<para>To assist you in reporting accurate AVETMISS data, some information can be set and
			collected at the class level. You can always modify information at the individual
			student or outcome level later if needed. The information you set at the class level is
			the usual case scenario e.g. the main funding source for this particular group of
			students. </para>
		<para>The VET information can all be found on the VET Tab - most of these fields are only
			relevant to RTOs and businesses who report AVETMISS statistics as part of a government
			funding arrangement. If this doesn't apply to you, you can safely ignore these fields. </para>
		<example>
			<title>Setting the VET information for a class</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the “delivery mode” field choose the delivery mode of the selected
						class from the drop down menu. Do the same for the “funding source national”
						field. The options in the list are set by the AVETMISS standard. Note that
						this information can be updated per student once you have enrolments.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter your “funding source state” (this field is only used by some states,
						check with your reporting body for the appropriate codes for your state)
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>There are two NSW only fields here, DET booking identifier (NSW only
						field) and Course site identifier (NSW only field). If you are in NSW and
						submitting data to the Training Market, they will supply you with the data
						required for these fields for each of your contracts. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Purchasing contract identifier and Purchasing contract scheduler are
						fields is used by some states. You should check with your reporting body for
						the appropriate codes for your state and the circumstances where you are
						required to supply them. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Both your nominal hours and classroom hours will be calculated. Nominal
						hours are calculated based on the hours you set at the unit of competency
						level. Classroom hours are based on the timetabled hours for the class. The
						nominal or classroom hours multipled by the number of students enrolled is
						used to calculate your student contact hours. Where you have provided them,
						your reportable hours will default to the nominal hours, or classroom hours
						if nominal hours haven't been set up. If you wish to report different hours,
						override the data in the reportable hours field with the numbers of your
						choice.</para>
					<para>If you are reporting to Queensland or Victoria it is vital you set the
						nominal hours for each unit of competency you deliver. The nominal hours are
						used to calculate the student fee per unit by dividing the class fee by the
						total nominal hours and mulitplying it out again to each unit based on it's
						hours. If you have zero hours, you will always report $0 student fees for
						that unit. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>There are additional AVETMISS funding fields in the student enrolment
						record that you can set for each individual you report. These include Study
						reason, Fee exemption/concession type, Client identifier: Apprenticeships,
						Training contract: Apprenticeships and Full time flag (QLD only). </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-Publishing">
		<title>Publishing classes online</title>
		<para>How and where the class is visible and/or available for online enrolment depends of
			the value of the course status and class status. The rules which drive this are:</para>
		<table frame="all">
			<title>Web availability rules</title>
			<tgroup cols="6" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry><emphasis role="bold">Course Status</emphasis></entry>
						<entry><emphasis role="bold">Course URL available</emphasis></entry>
						<entry><emphasis role="bold">Class Status</emphasis></entry>
						<entry><emphasis role="bold">Class URL available</emphasis></entry>
						<entry><emphasis role="bold">Website value</emphasis></entry>
						<entry><emphasis role="bold">Example use</emphasis></entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled and visible online</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>Enrolment disabled</entry>
						<entry>No - 404 not found</entry>
						<entry>Course is included in the search results but the class is not visible
							on the website</entry>
						<entry>For courses where you want students to add themselves to wait lists
							before you choose to publish a class to enrol into.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled and visible online</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>Enrolment allowed</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>Course is included in the search results, but the class is hidden
							from the list and results views. The class page can be accessed directly
							via the class URL but there is no option to enrol. Enrolments can be
							processed via QuickEnrol only.</entry>
						<entry>Once you have closed online enrolments for the class, the URL in the
							enrolment confirmation will still return the class details.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled and visible online</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>Enrolment allowed and visible online</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>Course and class are included in the search results and online
							enrolments are available.</entry>
						<entry>Normal class product available for sale.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled and visible online</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>Cancelled</entry>
						<entry>Either - use cog wheel to remove or show on web</entry>
						<entry>Course is included in the search results. If the class is still shown
							on the web, the enrol now button will be replaced with the word
							'Cancelled'. No enrolments can be taken.</entry>
						<entry>Where classes have been published in other mediums like print, it is
							useful to keep the class on the web to prevent people from trying to
							enrol via phone when they can't find the product they want
							online.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled</entry>
						<entry>No - 404 not found</entry>
						<entry>Enrolment disabled</entry>
						<entry>No - 404 not found</entry>
						<entry>No information is available online for the course or class.</entry>
						<entry>For products you are not currently selling or seeking expressions of
							interest for.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled</entry>
						<entry>No - 404 not found</entry>
						<entry>Enrolment allowed</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>The course and class are hidden from search, but the class page can
							be accessed via the URL directly. There is no option to enrol online,
							enrolments can be processed from Quick Enrol only.</entry>
						<entry>Once you have closed online enrolments, the URL in the enrolment
							confirmation will still return the class details, even if you no longer
							display the course on the web.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled</entry>
						<entry>No - 404 not found</entry>
						<entry>Enrolment allowed and visible online</entry>
						<entry>Yes</entry>
						<entry>The course and class are hidden from search, but the class page can
							be accessed via the URL directly. Online enrolment is available.</entry>
						<entry>An option for semi-private classes - you can send the class URL
							directly to the people you want to offer enrolment to, but visitors to
							your website won't find it via browse or search.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Enabled</entry>
						<entry>No - 404 not found</entry>
						<entry>Cancelled</entry>
						<entry>Either - use cog wheel to remove or show on web</entry>
						<entry>The course and class are hidden from search, but provided the class
							has not be removed from the website the class URL will still be
							available; The enrol now button will be replaced with the word
							'cancelled' and no enrolments can be taken.</entry>
						<entry>For students who enrolled prior to the class being cancelled, the URL
							in their enrolment confirmation will still return a valid webpage,
							showing the class as cancelled.</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		<para>For both courses and classes, it is advisable to ensure all the advertising details
			are correct prior to publishing. Until this is the case, the course status should be
			'enabled' and the class status should be 'enrolment allowed'. </para>
		<para>The marketing information for most of your programs will be located in the course web
			tab. Only where there is information particular to this instance of the class would you
			need to add information to the class web tab. For example, if each instance of the class
			required students to bring different materials because they worked on new projects each
			term, would you publish this information in the class tab. </para>
		<para>Classes can be published online by selecting the option on the general tab 'enrolment
			allowed and visible online'. You can also add or remove classes to the website in bulk
			using the cogwheel function in the classes list view. </para>
		<para>Only current and future classes will show online. Classes that are not self paced, but
			have no timetable set will not be published, and classes that are complete i.e. the end
			date has passed, will be automatically removed from your onCourse website. onCourse does
			not prevent students from enrolling once the class is commenced, but commenced classes
			are clearly marked on the website. </para>
		<para>You can choose to change the class status from 'Enrolment allowed and visible online'
			back to 'Enrolment allowed' for classes which have commenced, but you no longer wish to
			allow online enrolment for,</para>
		<para>The minimum and maximum places you set in the class are also used on your onCourse
			website to show students if there are places still available. The website will not show
			students the maximum number of places, or how many students have already enrolled. This
			is what the website will display: </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para> if the class is full: it will read 'class full' </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> If the class has been cancelled it will read 'Cancelled'. If you have
					published class information in a hard copy brochure, we recommend leaving
					cancelled classes on the website so perspective students can see that the class
					they are looking for is not available. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> if there are six or more places available, it will read 'places available'
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> if there are between one and five places available, it will give a count of
					the places available, for example it may read '3 places available'. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Providing an enrolment count when their are less than five places available creates a
			sense of urgency: The student knows there are only a few places available, so they will
			hopefully be motivated to enrol as soon as possible, so they don't miss out on joining
			the class. </para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-classesWithEnrolments">
		<title>Working with classes that have enrolments</title>
		<para>After you have set up your classes and taken enrolments, there is a range of
			additional information available to you in the class record. </para>
		<para>Visit the enrolment tab to see the list of students enrolled in the class. The list
			will be automatically updated each time a new enrolment is processed in onCourse. Where
			you can see the student's names listed, you will see a small icon to the right of their
			names. When you click on this icon the selected student's contact screen will be opened
			so you can access their contact details and other history with your college. </para>
		<para>Only student's marked as Active are currently enrolled in the class and are counted
			towards the class numbers. Students marked as credited or cancelled have been removed
			from the class list, but their name still appears here for historical record keeping
			purposes. </para>
		<para>Double clicking on a student's name in the class Enrolment tab will cause a drop down
			screen to appear. This is their Enrolment record. You can also access the Enrolment
			record from the Enrolment window. This screen will open on the General tab and will show
			the student's name and their enrolment details. The top half of this screen are display
			only fields and will show information which has already been entered during the
			enrolment process. Here you will see the course-class code, the course name, the status
			of the student and the source, whether or not a discount has been applied and the price
			of the class before the discount. There is also an invoice hyperlink. Click on this and
			the invoice for the student and this class will open. This is also accessible through
			the invoice screen. </para>
		<para>Keep in mind that the invoice for a particular student may not be in the enrolled
			student's name. For example, if a company pays for a team of their staff to attend a
			class, the invoice will be to the company. </para>
		<para>The bottom half of the enrolment screen contains fields particular to RTOs who submit
			AVETMISS data. These include Study reason, Fee exemption/concession type, Client
			identifier: Apprenticeships, Training contract: Apprenticeships and Full time flag (QLD
			only). You can set this information for each student as it applies to them. </para>
		<para>In addition to the enrolment records, the class window now contains a list of outcomes
			for each student enrolled. See the RTO Guide for more information about setting and
			modifying outcomes. </para>
		<para>You can also see and mark student and tutor attendance in the class window. </para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="classes-markingAttendance">
		<title>Marking Student and Tutor attendance</title>
		<para>Attendance tracking is both useful for calculating tutor wages and also to determine
			the overall attendance percentage for a student. This is particularly relevant if you
			are required to meet CRICOS overseas student attendance requirements. </para>
		<para>For every session you create for a class, a corresponding attendance record will be
			created. Each session can be marked as Unmarked, Attended or Absent without reason by
			simply clicking on the icon for the student for the session. </para>
		<para>Alternatively, you can mark all students for a session or all sessions for a student
			by clicking on triangle next to the date or student's name and choosing one of the
			options. </para>
		<para>As you begin to mark attendance for a student, a percentage attended will be
			calculated and displayed. When attendance reaches 80% or less a yellow notice icon will
			be displayed. When attendance reaches 70% or less a red warning icon will be displayed.
			These will assist you in monitoring if students are meeting the course attendance
			requirements. </para>
		<para>You can also mark attendance as Absent with reason and Partial attendance by right
			clicking on the attendance icon. For both of these attendance types you also need to
			record a note against the student's record as to why they are absent, and for partial
			attendance you need to record the time that was attended so the percentage attendance
			calculation can be recorded. Absent with reason will still be taken into account as an
			absence for the purposes of determining percentage attendance. </para>
		<para>When you run a tutor's payslip, you will have the option to count all scheduled
			sessions towards their payment, or only those you have marked as attended or partially
			attended. </para>
	</section>
</chapter>
