<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="concessions">
	<title>Concessions and Memberships</title>
	<section>
		<title>What is a concession?</title>
		<para>A concession is a way of categorising a student into a group which may be eligible for
			a discount. Concessions may be externally defined groups, like High School Students,
			Senior's or Health Care Card Holders. You may ask these students to provide details of
			their membership to a group by providing a card number and expiry date. You may allow
			students to add these details to their record on the website during enrolment or via
			their profile. Concessions can also be internally defined groups like teaching staff,
			admin staff and VIP students. These types of concessions may not have numbers or expiry
			dates, and can not be added by students on the website, but can still be used to provide
			discounts when enrolling online.</para>
		<para>Concessions, discounts, memberships and promotional codes are a powerful part of onCourse
			marketing.  For more information on how to apply concessions or memberships to a
			discount, see <link xlink:href="#discounts">the discount chapter</link>
		</para>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>What is a membership?</title>
			<para>Memberships are products which can be purchased. Being a member may entitle a student to
			discounts, and possibly also provide that discount to their related contacts. For
			example, you may sell a membership to a company that provides a discount to all of their
			staff. Memberships are valid for a fixed period of time e.g. twelve months from
			purchase, and any discounts associated with the membership will not be available after
			expiry. Memberships may also be sold for no cost, for example for members of an external
			program, or may be sold but have no discount associated with membership, for example
			annual financial members of a community organisation who have AGM voting rights.</para>
		</section>

<section>
		<title>Creating concession types</title>
		<para>Some concession types may be available for your students to add to their own record during
			the online enrolment process, for example a Senior's Card. Other types you may want
			to restrict to only allowing the concession to be added to the student record via
			the onCourse client, for example College Staff. </para>
		<para>If you require an expiry date on the concession type, any discounts that apply to
			that concession type will not be available if the student's concession is
			expired.</para>
		<para>You may also choose to make entering a card number mandatory. Please note onCourse is not
			able to validate the authenticity of card numbers due. This is an open test field
			(string type) and will accept letters and numbers. This field is useful for ensuring
			that only card holders self identify - you can use this data to conduct random spot
			checks if required.</para>
		<para>Note that when you allow concessions to be added on the website, users must confirm
			they hold a current and valid concession. As we can not perform validation against so
			many external systems, the application for concession online is an honor system. Over
			the years, our customers have reported very low abuse of this method, as in the
			education market clients generally attend classes face to face.  Well written enrolment
			policies ensure that if a client can not present in person the concession type they have
			claimed, then they will be billed for the full course fee.</para>

		<example>
			<title>How to create a concession type</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to File -> Preferences -> Concession Types</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click the add button ( + )</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Name your concession type. This name that the students or admin staff will
						use to identify this concession type when adding it to a student record.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose if you want it to be available for self selection on the web. If
						you select this option, students can add this concession type to their
						record either during enrolment or via their student portal. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select if it the concession requires a number or an expiry date. This
						makes supplying this information mandatory to save the concession record
						against the student's file.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>Once you have created the concession type, go to <link xlink:href="#discounts">discounts</link> to define who can use it and
				how it can be used.</para>
		</example>	
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/create_concession.png"
				format="png" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Defining the parameters of a concession type for Seniors</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<section>
		<title>Adding a concession to a student record</title>
		<para>Admin staff can add a concession record to a student's record at any time, either during the
				enrolment process or by editing their contact record.</para>
			<para>To add a concession, go to the general tab of the student record. Click on the +
				above the concession panel to add the concession of your choice. The concession type
				must have already been defined as per the process described above.</para>
			<para>Depending on the settings of the concession type, the number and expiry date fields may be
				mandatory to complete. You can add multiple concessions to a student record using
				this process.</para>
			<para>If you add the concession to the student's record during the Quick Enrol process,
				any applicable discount will be applied immediately.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/concession_added.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A student with a seniors card concession added to their record</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating a membership</title>
		<para>Memberships can be created from the Resources > Memberships. A membership needs a name and
			should have a description so potential purchasers understand the benefits of the
			membership.</para>
		<para>A membership may have a fee to purchase, or could be given away for free. The
			membership will have a duration of either a set number of days from purchase, the
			beginning of the calendar or financial year or be for life.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/membershipsetup.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A membership product available for sale</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>You can choose to make the membership available for purchase online, or only via
			internal purchase,</para>
		<para>At this point, you may choose to link to existing discount policies, or you may
			prefer to define the discounts that apply to people who hold this membership type
			later.</para>
		<para>An important distinction of membership discounts is that they can also apply
			across relationships. For example, a company could purchase a membership and the
			discount policy for that membership may apply to all staff of that company who
			enrol.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/discountrelation.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A membership discount policy that applies the discount to the staff members of the membership holder</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Purchasing a membership</title>
		<para>A membership can be purchased from Quick Enrol, either in conjunction with an
			enrolment or as a standalone purchase.</para>
		<para>If the membership is purchased in conjunction with an enrolment that is eligible
			for a discount for members, then the discount will be applied at the time of
			purchase.</para>
		<para>Memberships can be purchased by either searching for a membership number or name in the
			'Enter course or item' field. Alternatively you can click on the 'Show all' button next
			to the text 'MEMBERSHIPS' on the right hand side of the Quick Enrol window; this will
			only appear once you have clicked on the 'Enter course or item' field.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/purchasingmembership.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A student purchasing a College Membership for $10.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Redeeming a membership</title>
		<para>For as long as the membership is valid, any applicable discounts will be given
			automatically when the student enrols. Discounts will no longer be given if a
			membership has expired. Current and expired memberships can be seen in the student's
			general tab of their record.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Searching for students with concessions or memberships</title>
		<para>In the contacts advanced search panel, accessed via clicking on the magnifying glass icon in
			the search window, are a range of search functions related to concessions and
			memberships.</para>
		<para>In conjunction with other search functions, such as enrolment history and demographic
			data, this information can provide opportunities for you to find and promote courses to
			particular groups of students at your college.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/contact_advanced_search.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Advanced search options for students with concessions and memberships.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
</chapter>
