<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="corporatePass">
    <title>Corporate Pass</title>
    <para>Corporate Pass is a password you can create to allow your customers to enrol online whoever they want, as many times as they want, without having to pay up front. This password can be limited to certain classes or left open to access your entire range of classes. You can create as many passwords as you like for the same customer, and for as many different customers as you chose. </para>
<section>
    <title>When to Use a Corporate Pass</title>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem><para>You may have a large customer with quite a few staff to whom you provide training. Without corporate pass your choices are to have the staff enrol online with their own credit card or some corporate card, or to process the enrolments by hand in the office in conjunction with your customer's HR department. This involves a lot of co-ordination to check each student's availability. Instead, you can now create a Corporate Pass and give the password to the customer's HR department. They then hand it out to staff, who are able to enrol in whichever classes are most suitable to their own availability. </para> </listitem>
    
        <listitem><para>Perhaps you are using onCourse to track internal training delivery in your company. You might want to assign a price to classes to help with interdepartmental cost allocation. Corporate pass gives you the ability to create a separate password for each department, allow staff to book their own training, and then perform the backend accounting you require. </para></listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>You deliver vocational training to the staff of several large mining companies. These staff need to be regularly accredited for some part of their job, but they have some flexibility to do their training around their work shifts. You can create a special landing page on your website for each of those companies, with links to the courses you deliver that are relevant to them, the password for Corporate Pass and all other relevant information. Then students are directed to that page for all their training information. </para>
    </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Students have to complete an audition or interview process to get into your programme of training. Once they are accepted, you would like them to be able to sign up to further training and tie their payments into a monthly billing process you already have in place. Just hand them a password and they can enrol 24 hours a day over the internet. </para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Controlling Usage</title>
        <para>There are several ways to prevent abuse of a corporate pass. </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each pass can be restricted to one class or a selection of classes. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Create as many passes as you want, even for the same customer. That way you can limit each pass in different ways and track its usage. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Give the pass an expiry date.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each pass has a special email address to which an invoice will be sent for each enrolment. Typically this is your customer's HR department or staff manager who will be able to monitor the emails and ensure that staff are enrolling in appropriate training. </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Setting up your Corporate Pass within onCourse</title>
        <para>This section will outline how you can set up your Corporate Pass using the onCourse Client</para>
<orderedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>To create a new Corporate Pass first click on the 'Corporate Pass' window within the
                    Marketing Tab of the onCourse Client. You can then create a new Corporate Pass
                    by clicking on the <guiicon>+</guiicon>symbol in the top right hand corner of
                    the opened window.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/CorporatePassLinkViaMarketingTab.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>The Corporate Pass window can be accessed via the Marketing Tab</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>The minimum required information to create a new Corporate Pass is a contact or Company
                    Name and a Password. Remember that the Company or Contact must already exist as
                    a record within onCourse prior to creating the Corporate Pass. </para>
    <para>You can also specify as to which email address the invoices will be sent to. An
                    expiry date can also be set for a given Corporate Pass, but this is not a
                    required field. </para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                fileref="images/CreateNewCorporatePass.png" format="png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>Corporate Pass Edit View</para>
        </caption>
    </mediaobject>
</listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>You can now define as to which Class or Classes are able to be enrolled in using this
                    Corporate Pass in the following ways:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Add all of your Classes to a Corporate Pass, this Pass will be valid for any
                            current or pending Classes.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/AddAllClassesToCorporatePass.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Add a single Class to a Corporate Pass, this Pass will only be valid for the specified Class</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/AddSingleClassToCorporatePass.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Enter Name, Course Code and Class Code</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Add all Classes for a given Course to a Corporate Pass, this pass is valid for
                            any current and future Classes of the specified Course</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/AddAllClassesForCourseToCorporatePass.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Add all Classes which have a specified subject tag. This pass will be valid for any current or future Classes which has this specific subject tag</para>
<mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
            fileref="images/AddAllClassesFromTagToCorporatePass.png" format="png"/>
    </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
    </listitem>
</orderedlist>
        <para>Once you have assigned the Corporate Pass to the specified Contact or Company and set whatever parameters in terms of which Classes can be enrolled against using the Corporate Pass, this is all that is needed to activate the Corporate Pass. 
            <tip>
            <para>If you don't specify any Classes within your Corporate Pass, this will mean that
                    the Pass can be used to enrol in any Class that is published on your website. </para>
        </tip></para>
    </section>
</chapter>
