<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="delivery">
	<title>Enrolments and Delivery</title>
    <section>
		<title>During Enrolment and Delivery</title>
		<para>Right, that's everything you need to take care of before letting students hand over their
			money to enrol in your courses. All you need to worry about from this point is what to
			do while you're delivering training, but before you hit the 'Export' button on the
			AVETMISS runner to collate all your reporting data. </para>
        <section xml:id="delivery-enrolment">
			<title>Enrolment</title>
			<para>You are required to validate each student's USI against their first name, last name and
				date of birth with the USI Registry System. If you have an onCourse support plan and
				have supplied us with your AUSKey, onCourse will do this automatically for each USI
				supplied. For more information on creating and validating USIs, please refer to the
				<link linkend="usi">USI chapter.</link>
			</para>
			<para>Students who are exempt the USI requirement will need the report the value
				'INTOFF' or 'INDIV' in the USI field to demonstrate that they are exempt and their
				exemption type. onCourse will assist you with complying with the requirements by
				automatically exporting 'INTOFF' for students with residential address in a country
				other than Australia.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Training Contract Identifier</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Identifier - Apprenticeships</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Fee Exemption/Concession Type Identifier</title>
				<para>This is set in the student's Enrolment record on the General Tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Purchasing Contract Identifier</title>
				<para>This can be set in the class on the VET tab or in the student's enrolment
					General tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>VET in Schools Flag</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Specific funding identifier</title>
				<para>This field is labelled 'specific program identifier' and can be found on the
					outcome record.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Outcome Identifier - Training Organisation</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Funding Source - State Training Authority</title>
				<para>You can enter this information in the Class VET tab, the general tab in
					Enrolment or in the individual outcome record on the Class Outcomes Tab or the
					Enrolment Outcomes tab. Double click the outcome to see this field.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Tuition Fee</title>
				<para>This is the fee you charged the student at the time of enrolment, divided by
					the total nominal hours in the course, multiplied by the nominal hours of each
					unit to set a proportional student fee for each unit. To charge a fee, set a
					class fee in the Class General tab. VET courses are usually GST exempt. During
					the enrolment process, you can charge the student the full fee or give them a
					manual discount if they meet fee exemption criteria. The fee they pay here is
					what is reported. If you don't usually use onCourse for invoicing and payment
					records, create a full cash payment for each student on enrolment. Don't worry
					about the invoices that are automatically created here - they have nothing to do
					with AVETMISS.</para>
			</section>

				<section>
					<title>(VIC) Eligibility Exemption indicator</title>
					<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
						same name.</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>(VIC) VET FEE-HELP (Income Contingent Loan) Indicator</title>
					<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
						same name.</para>
				</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC and QLD) Student number - VSN or LUI</title>
				<para>This is entered on the contact record AVETMISS tab in the field labelled
					Government Student Number (VIC/QLD)</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/VSN_location.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Enter a VSN or LUI in this field. Data here will only export if you
							are reporting in VIC or QLD</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>	
		<section xml:id="rto-attendance">
			<title>Marking attendance</title>
			<para>You must ensure that tutors are marking student attendance for every class. This can either
				be done in onCourse itself, within the attendance tab of the applicable class
				window, or more likely via the SkillsonCourse Portal. Accurately marking attendance
				means that certain fields will update automatically once a course has completed. </para>
			<para>You can learn more about marking attendance in onCourse <link linkend="classes-markingAttendance">by clicking here</link>.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Marking outcomes</title>
			<para>Tutors should always be marking student outcomes in the SkillsonCourse portal periodically
				to ensure data is as up to date as possible.</para>
			<para>You can learn more about marking outcomes in the SkillsonCourse Portal<link
					xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/web/tutors.html">by
					clicking here</link>.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Outcome Identifier - National</title>
				<para>You can set the outcome identifier (we call it status) on the Outcomes tab in
					the Class window. If you select all the records in the list and right click on
					them, you can set them all to 'Successful (20)' and then go back and change the
					others that should be other statuses (like RPL or Not Yet Competent) one by one.
					Or you can set them all one by one, whichever you prefer. You can also set the
					outcome status in the student contact record or the enrolment record.</para>
				<para>If you set an outcome an RPL, RCC or Credit Transfer status, the Delivery Mode
					Identifier will always export as 90 - NA regardless of what is set in the
					outcome value.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating certificates</title>
			<para>onCourse will create AQF compliant certificates for your students, but for the
				purposes of lodging AVETMISS, you don't need to print or issue them. Qualification and skill set completions
				are reported in the NAT00130 file for all states. If the the export flavour is for a funding type that requires it, details of anticipated qualifications e.g. NSW Smart and Skilled or Victoria's Skills First.</para>
			<para>The 'awarded on' date determines the date of certificate issue for AVETMISS
				reporting purposes. By default, this date will be the date the certificate was
				created in onCourse. If you create certificates early in a calendar year that need
				to be reported as part of the previous calendar years completions, be sure to back
				date the 'awarded on' date to the previous year.</para>
			<para>
				<link linkend="rto-Certificates">More information on creating Certificates in
					onCourse</link>
			</para>			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Cancellations</title>
			<section>				
				<title>Hours Attended</title>
				<para>If you need to set the hours attended you can find the field in the Outcome record on
					either the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes Tab. Double click the
					outcome to see this field called 'Reportable Hours'.</para></section>
		</section>
	</section>
    <section xml:id="delivery-outcomes">
		<title>Setting and modifying outcomes</title>
		<para>How to set and customise outcomes to meet your reporting needs</para>
		<para>When you set up a VET course and class and enrol students, outcomes will automatically
			be created for each of the units of competency you assigned to the course, with the
			properties start and end date, reportable hours, delivery mode and funding type you set
			in the class.</para>
		<para>There are multiple places you can access the outcomes and set them, plus modify the
			details mentioned above for individual students - in the class outcome tab, in the
			student enrolments tab, in the enrolment outcomes tab, the find related outcomes window
			and in the certificate window when you are creating a new certificate.</para>
		<section>
			<title>What are outcomes?</title>
			<para>A students outcome is the record of their engagement with a Unit of Competency or
				Module from a training package or accredited course. Outcomes are often reported to
				government through processes such as AVETMISS and must meet certain validation
				rules. Primarily, an outcome records if a student has passed or failed their course.
				The outcomes available for selection are as follows:</para>
			<simplelist>
				<member> Competency achieved/pass (20)</member>
				<member> Competency not achieved/fail (30)</member>
				<member> Withdrawn (40)</member>
				<member> Recognition of prior learning granted (51)</member>
				<member> Recognition of prior learning not granted (52)</member>
				<member> Recognition of current competency granted (53)</member>
				<member> Recognition of current competency not granted (54)</member>
				<member> Credit transfer (60)</member>
				<member> Did not start (NSW: 66, SA: @@)</member>
				<member> Continuing enrolment (70) *</member>
				<member> Non-assessed enrolment - Satisfactorily completed (81) **</member>
				<member> Non-assessed enrolment - Withdrawn or not satisfactorily completed
					(82)</member>
				<member> Result not available (90) ***</member>
			</simplelist>
			<para>Refer to the NCVER publications, VET Provider Collection Specifications and
				AVETMISS Data Element Definitions for more information regarding the definitions and
				use of these outcomes.</para>
			<para>* You do not need to set the outcome 'Continuing enrolment (70)' for any outcomes.
				During the AVETMISS export process, if the outcome end date is in the calendar year
				after the date range of the export, 70 will automatically be exported. </para>
			<para>** If you export data for non-VET outcomes, you do not need to set the outcome
				'Non-assessed enrolment - Satisfactorily completed (81)'. This will always be
				exported for unset non-VET outcomes. </para>
			<para>*** You may not need to set 'Result not available (90)'. During the export
				process, you can choose to set this outcome for all unset VET outcomes</para>
			<section>
				<title>Finding outcomes</title>
				<para>Outcome data is available in the enrolment record, the student record, the
					class record and via the 'Find related' outcomes option.</para>
				<para>From the file menu, select Activity > Outcomes to see all outcomes in the
					database. The outcomes list view allows you to search and sort on all outcomes,
					or use the core filter to view outcomes in progress, pre-commencement or
					completed.</para>
				<para>To see outcomes related to a particular record, such as an enrolment record,
					double click on the enrolment and navigate to the outcomes tab. You can do the
					same thing in a class to see all outcome records for the students enrolled in
					that class.</para>
				<para>When you look at the education tab of a student's contact record, you can see
					all their outcomes. These outcomes could have been created via enrolments in
					onCourse or through prior learning record imports.</para>
				<example>
					<title>Using find related outcomes</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Start from the classes window and locate the class, or group of
								classes you wish to find the outcomes for.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Highlight the classes, and from the 'Find related' icon in the
								list view, select 'outcomes'.</para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/classes_find_related_outcomes.png"
										format="png"/>
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>Finding the related outcomes for the highlighted
										classes</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>A new window will open showing the outcomes list. From this list
								you can run further searches or use the filters to search the
								outcome list for outcomes in progress, pre-commencement or
								completed.</para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/outcomes_list_view.png" format="png"/>
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>Looking at the outcomes list view</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>This same process can be done from the contact, student or the
								enrolments list view. Outcomes linked to prior learning records
								(which are available from the contact or student record) will not
								show any data in the course or code column, as they were not created
								via an enrolment in onCourse.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</example>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Setting individual outcomes</title>
				<para>To set the outcome, modify the start or end date, or delivery mode, simply
					click in the list view field you wish to change and enter the data. To modify
					the unit/module the outcome is linked to, to change the funding source or change
					the reportable hours, click the expansion option to open the full outcome edit
					window.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/set_outcome_status.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Setting the outcome status in the outcome edit view</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>If you wish to add additional outcomes to a students enrolment, open the
					enrolment record to the outcome tab, and click the plus sign to add an outcome.
					You may need to do this if a student completes an additional unit by RPL, or if
					the entire class complete an additional unit to what was originally planned in
					the course.</para>
				<note>
					<para>When setting a given Class as <guilabel>Self Paced</guilabel>, the start
						date and end date for the student outcomes are set as follows: </para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Start Date is the date the student enrols in the Class</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>End Date is the start date plus the maximum days to complete that
								has been set for the Class via the General tab.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</note>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Setting outcomes in bulk</title>
				<para>In the class or outcomes window, the outcome of one, some or all students can
					be selected and set as a single action.</para>
				<para>Select the outcomes you wish to set by clicking the first outcome, holding
					down shift (to select all in the range) or control / command (to select only
					those you click on). Then right click on any of the selected records and set the
					outcomes to successful. This will then set all the records to 20 in a VET class,
					or to 81 in a non-VET class.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/bulk_set_outcomes.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Setting outcomes in bulk from the outcomes list view</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>If you set an outcome to successful' in error, can always select it again
					individually and set it to a different outcome. This means you can set a whole
					class group to successful very quickly, then go back and change the outcomes for
					the 1 or 2 students who did not pass to <emphasis>30 - Competency not
						achieved/fail.</emphasis></para>
				<note>
					<para> Only the 'successful' outcome can be set in bulk </para>
				</note>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title> Exporting outcome data </title>
				<para>All RTOs are obliged to report their training activity data under the AVETMISS
					standard, as part of their registration obligations. For more information on
					Total VET Activity Reporting, please refer to the <link linkend="AVETMISS"
						>AVETMISS chapter</link> of the user handbook.</para>
				<para>There may be other occasion when you need to export your outcome data for your
					own recording keeping purposes. To that end, onCourse contains some CSV exports
					you can open in excel that are a little like more user friendly, readable
					versions of AVETMISS data.</para>
				<para>The 'Class Outcomes CSV' or 'Extended Outcomes CSV' exports in the class
					window show outcome data, funding sources, and useful information for audit
					evidence trails like the name of the tutor contact who marked the outcome via
					the portal.</para>
				<para>Another class export called 'Class Attendance CSV' exports an electronic
					record of the marked class roll, with any comments made for partial attendance
					or approved absences and the details of the tutor who marked the roll.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/extended_outcomes_csv.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>A class grouped outcomes export in excel format</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
        <section xml:id="delivery-rpl">
			<title>Importing and adding prior learning</title>
			<para>If you are migrating to onCourse from another AVETMISS compliant student
				management system, or have students who have completed training at another RTO, you
				can add prior learning data to a student's record that can be used to create
				Certificate records in onCourse and also be exported out as AVETMISS data.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Manually adding prior learning records</title>
				<para>The education tab of a student record is comprised of four sections -
					enrolments, prior learning, outcomes and certificates. In onCourse, both
					enrolments and prior learning can be vocational, and linked to one or more units
					of competency or be non-vet and linked to no formal study units.</para>
				<para>To add prior learning to a student record, click on the + option to the right
					of the prior learning panel.</para>
				<para>Prior learning must have a title - this can be descriptive of the course or
					training conducted elsewhere. Optionally, the prior learning record can be
					linked to a Qualification or Skills Set on the general tab, contain reference to
					an external system reference number e.g. the course code or enrolment code from
					the previous system and optional descriptive notes.</para>
				<para>On the second tab, outcomes, you can manually add one or more units of
					competency or accredited modules to the prior learning record. It is important
					you add start and end dates to the units of competency, and a valid outcome
					status here if you want to report them for AVETMISS or use the unit to create a
					certificate. If you are adding units completed at another RTO, you should record
					the outcome status as 'Credit Transfer'.</para>
				<para>If you scan any documents, such as a copy of their Certificate, you can add
					them to the prior learning record also. You will just need to make sure you save
					the prior learning record first, before adding documents.</para>
				<para>Once the prior learning record has been saved, the outcomes attached to the
					prior learning will appear in the outcomes section of the student's education
					record, combined with any outcomes completed by the student via enrolments into
					onCourse classes.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/manual_add_prior_learning.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The general tab of the prior learning sheet in the Education tab of a
							contact</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Importing prior learning using AVETMISS files</title>
				<para>If you are migrating to onCourse and wish to bring over your student and
					outcome data, onCourse can import standard AVETMISS files to create student
					contact records with prior learning data.</para>
				<para>There are four built in types of AVETMISS data imports, with different
					purposes depending if you are importing new data to onCourse, or updating
					existing onCourse records. If you are importing data into an active onCourse
					database, please speak with us first to confirm what import option is the best
					option to avoid creating duplicate student records.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS outcome import</emphasis> -
							This option is best for colleges starting a new onCourse database who
							want to import AVETMISS files from another system, and do not have
							student records in the onCourse database yet. You will need NAT00060,
							NAT00080, NAT00085 and NAT00120 files for this import. This import will
							create student records in onCourse, and attach prior learning records to
							those students.</para>
						<para>If you run this import twice, you will create duplicate student data.
							This import does not try and check for matches.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS student import - </emphasis>
							This is an alternative import option for colleges new to onCourse to
							import student contact data only, via the AVETMISS NAT00080 and NAT00085
							data. This will create contact records without any learning
							history.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS outcome update import
							</emphasis>- This import option is for colleges who already have student
							contact records in onCourse and wish to update those records with data
							from an external source e.g. ARMS data for AMEP students. This import
							will try to match a student to their existing onCourse record based on a
							firstName, lastName and DoB match, and will create a new student record
							if it can't find a match. Note that any student matches found will have
							their contact data overridden by the data from this import.</para>
						<para>This import also tries to match importing outcome data to data already
							recorded in onCourse, and avoid creating duplicate prior learning
							records if the record doesn't already exist. This import will add
							additional outcome data to existing prior learning records when it finds
							multiple outcomes belonging to the same qualification code.</para>
						<para>You will need NAT00060, NAT00080, NAT00085 and NAT00120 files for this
							import.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVTETMISS student update
								import</emphasis> - This import updates student contact details in
							onCourse based on NAT00080 and NAT00085 data files imported from another
							system. This import will try to match a student to their existing
							onCourse record based on a firstName, lastName and DoB match, and will
							create a new student record if it can't find a match.</para>
						<para>Note that you could potentially update onCourse student records with
							outdated data using this import option, so use with caution when
							importing data from a record set older than your onCourse
							records.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para>You will need validated NAT00060, NAT00080, NAT00085 and NAT00120 files first.
					Make sure these files have been validated in the <link
						xlink:href="https://avs.ncver.edu.au/avs/">NCVER AVS tool</link> and are
					reporting no errors before importing them into onCourse. </para>
				<para>To import these files, go to File > Import/Export > Import... and select the
					onCourse AVETMISS option required. The import process will prompt you to open
					each of the NAT files listed above from a location on your computer.</para>
				<para>Once you have selected all the required files, click on the import button on
					the bottom of the window.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/import_avetmiss_files.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Selecting AVETMISS files to import into onCourse</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="rto-Outcomes">
		<title>Understanding how outcomes are attached to enrolments</title>
		<para>When a VET course is created, qualifications, accredited courses, skillsets, modules and units of competency are set at the
			course level. More information about setting up VET courses is available in the <link linkend="courses-VET">courses chapter</link>. Classes for the course inherit the
			units set at the course level. You can see these units in the Training Plan on the
			outcomes tab of the class.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Training_plan_timetable.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting units of competency to be delivered in the first class
					session</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>When a student enrols in the class, the units of competency attached to the course
			become the outcomes attached to the student's enrolment. The start and end date of class
			become the start and end date of the outcomes, unless you choose to define different
			dates in the training plan. The settings on the class VET tab become the default
			settings for each outcome for that class, but can be changed on an outcome by outcome
			basis. Within the class level outcomes can be changed or set, but can not be deleted and
			new outcomes can not be added here. </para>
		<para>You can see the outcomes that have been assigned to each student in the class on the
			outcomes tab, in the student's record on the enrolment tab, and on the enrolment record
			on the outcomes tab.</para>
		<para>Via the student's enrolment record, outcomes added in error can be deleted from the
			enrolment record and additional outcomes can be added. Adding or deleting outcomes needs
			to be done per enrolment where training and assessment is taking place at your RTO. For
			outcomes gained in learning outside of onCourse, prior learning records can be imported,
			or manually added to the student's education tab.</para>
			<para>Once outcomes are linked to certificates, a laurel icon is displayed next to the outcome.
			Once the certificate is printed and issued, the outcomes become locked in the system and
			greyed out so they can't be edited. If the certificate is later revoked, the outcomes
			can be edited again.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Training_Plan_outcomes.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption><para>A student's education tab showing outcomes linked to certificates, via enrolments and
				prior learning.</para></caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Cancelling VET enrolments</title>
			<para>Sometimes when you cancel a VET enrolment, it is because it was created in error and you
				want to delete all the outcomes. At other times, often when the training is funded,
				you want the enrolment cancelled to make another position available in the class,
				but have the outcomes retained for reporting purposes.</para>
			<para>When you cancel an enrolment, by default the checkbox option retains any outcomes that have
				had a status set, and deletes any outcomes with a status of 'not set'.</para>
			<para>If, at this point, no outcomes have had their status set (for example, the student
				was enrolled into the wrong class) then all outcomes will be deleted. However, if
				this was a funded enrolment and you wanted to retain all the outcomes to later mark
				as 'withdrawn' then you can uncheck this option.</para>
			<para>If you are cancelling an enrolment where you have already set all the outcomes,
				e.g. all set to withdrawn already, leaving this option checked will delete
				nothing.</para>
			<para>If you have set outcomes on an enrolment record and want them deleted, and not
				retained, then you will need to either set them back to 'not set' before cancelling
				the enrolment, or you can manually delete them from the enrolment record after
				processing the cancellation.</para>
			<para>If you have created a certificate that includes outcomes from the enrolment, they will
				always be retained on the student's outcome and can not be deleted manually, even if
				the certificate has been revoked.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/cancel_enrolment.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Cancelling an enrolment and deleting all unset outcomes</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="rto-CSWECourses">
		<title>CSWE courses, classes and outcomes</title>
		<para>Making government reporting less of a hassle for student focused literacy programs</para>
		<section>
			<title>Setting up Certificate in Spoken and Written English (CSWE) courses</title>
			<para> Some colleges who deliver CSWE courses run open English language programs at different
				levels, aligned to the levels available in the CSWE program. Students enrol in
				course that is of an appropriate level and when a class group is formed, the tutor
				then assess the students and selects appropriate units from the CSWE curriculum for
				them to work towards. Some students in a class group may be working towards a single
				unit, while others may be working towards multiple units. Some students may be fee
				paying, some may be funded under various government programs. Some students may
				enrol in a class two or three times before attempting assessment against a CSWE unit
				and some students may not wish to be assessed at all. All of these circumstances
				combined can make headaches for the English classes coordinator who both wants to
				make sure the students and tutors needs are met, as well as reporting accurate
				statistics for funding purposes. Don't worry - onCourse has you covered! </para>
			<section>
				<title>Setting up the course</title>
				<para>onCourse includes all the available TGA data relating to accredited courses
					and classes. Unfortunately, TGA isn't able to provide details of accredited
					course modules, but for both the current and recently expired CSWE, we have
					built in all the modules to onCourse so you can select those you deliver.</para>
				<para>If you college chooses different modules for each class, when you create a
					CSWE course, simply add the accredited course code to the VET page but leave the
					module list empty. If you always use the same modules, you can set up your CSWE
					course like any other VET course, with accredited course detail and modules. </para>
				<para>If you do not set any modules in the course, student enrolling in CSWE linked
					classes will be given a VET-flagged but non accredited outcome, named whatever
					your course is named. You will override these outcomes later when you have the
					correct module information for each student.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enrolling students in CSWE classes.</title>
				<para>You can enrol students in CSWE classes like you would in any other program. It doesn't
					matter if you mix AMEP, BACE and fee paying students together - the outcomes you
					set later on will separate them for AVETMISS purposes.</para>
				<para>We realise many students attending CSWE classes may have enrolled in English
					classes at your college previously. Knowing the student language background,
					what classes they have attended, and what units they have completed will assist
					your tutors in selecting the best units for their current enrolment.</para>
				<para>Once your students are enrolled and classes are ready to start you can print
					the Student Details Report from the class window, which will provide the tutors
					with the information listed above.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Setting CSWE outcomes.</title>
				<para>Once your tutor has reported back to the college each of the outcomes
					attempted and/or achieved by each student in the class, you can enter the data
					into onCourse, ready for your AVETMISS exports.</para>
				<para>Go to the enrolment window and search for all the students in the class group
					you wish to work with by conducting and advanced search on the course code and
					class code.</para>
				<para>The outcome tab of each student's enrolment will show a non-VET outcome. Open
					it and change it to the first CSWE outcome you wish to record. You can also set
					the funding source information in this window. </para>
				<para>You can also add additional outcomes to the enrolment if a student has
					attempted more than one module during this class by clicking the plus
					sign.</para>
				<para>If a student chooses not to be assessed against any outcomes, you either leave them with
					the VET flagged non-accredited outcome or choose a VET outcome and set it to
						<emphasis> 30 - Competency not achieved/fail</emphasis> or if you have
					documented evidence that they have refused assessment, yet successfully attended
					the class, you can set a suitable module outcome to <emphasis> 81 - Non-assessed
						enrolment - Satisfactorily completed</emphasis>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="rto-VETDeliveryHours">
		<title>VET delivery hours</title>
		<para>How and where onCourse records and calculates student contact hours</para>
		<section>
			<title>VET data in the class window</title>
			<para>On the class window, there is a tab called VET, which contains fields that are
				useful for RTOs and relate to AVETMISS and other delivery statistics. There are also
				three AVETMISS specific fields 'Delivery mode', 'Funding source' and 'DET booking
				ID'. </para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Delivery Mode - This refers to how the class is conducted. Most programs
						are classroom based, and this is the default value. You can also change this
						at the outcome level if necessary, e.g. if one student completes the program
						by distance.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Funding Source - This refers to how the class is funded. These are set
						selection of national codes. You can also change the funding source at the
						outcome level, e.g. for AMEP funded students. For more information, visit
						the NCVER site </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>DET Booking ID - This field is specific to the NSW APL report. Visit
						Training Market NSW for more information on reporting and lodging your data
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>Information about the qualification, accredited course, skillset, modules and units of competency delivered in your
				class are set at the course level.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Nominal hours, classroom hours and Student Contact Hours</title>
				<para>The following fields in the class relate to your delivery hours and AVETMISS
					reporting. This section has been deliberately made complex to assist our clients
					who are obliged to report AVETMISS for both VET delivery and non-VET
					delivery.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Qualification Hours - These are the nominal hours set by NCVER for the
							qualification. Often, this field is left blank, which is acceptable for
							AVETMISS. You can also add the nominal hours to the qualification
							yourself in the Qualification table. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Nominal Hours - The nominal hours field in the class is the total of
							the nominal hours of the units of competency assigned to the course.
							While the nominal hours for each unit are usually set by NCVER, you can
							override them or add them where they are missing in Module/Unit of
							Competency record. You can edit these values when you attach units to
							courses by double clicking on the unit record. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Classroom Hours - The total hours you have defined as scheduled activity by setting
							sessions or by defining the minutes per sessions and number of sessions
							on the General tab. This is not reported as part of AVETMISS for real
							VET outcomes - it is for your information only. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Reportable Hours - These are the hours that will be reported against
							each enrolment in the NAT00120 file. They default to the nominal hours
							of the units attached to the course. If there are no nominal hours set
							in the unit, i.e. in a non-VET course, the nominal and reportable hours
							will default to the classroom hours. You can override the reportable
							hours field to the classroom hours or any other number that you wish to
							export in it's place for non-VET courses only. For VET courses, you can
							also override the reportable hours in each outcome, if they differ from
							the unit nominal hours. NOTE: If you have created a class which has
							units of competencies assigned and not set nominal hours for these
							units, your contact hours and reported hours for these outcomes will
							always be zero. Reportable hours based on delivery hours only populate
							non-VET outcomes.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Student Contact Hours - This totals the reportable hours in the
							outcomes attached to the class. This can also be simplified to number of
							students x total class nominal hours for most cases, but in VET classes,
							some students may have different units assigned or different reportable
							hours for their units. SCHs are often used by funding bodies to measure
							delivery. If you have not set nominal hours in the units of competency,
							your student contact hours will calculate to zero. If your classes'
							course does not have units of competency assigned to it e.g. it is a
							non-VET course, the student contact hours will by default equal the
							classroom hours x number of students, unless you override the reportable
							hours field in the class.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para>The report Class funding will provide you with summary information, per
					qualification, per funding code of how many student contact hours you have
					delivered over the classes selected for the report. This can be used to check at
					various points during the year, the number of hours you have delivered that
					compare to your funding targets. </para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="rto-coursesByCluster">
		<title>Courses by Cluster</title>
		<para>How to set up qualifications that are delivered by internal clusters where units of
			competency overlap</para>
		<para> Clusters, in this case, refers to an internal grouping of units of competency that a
			college delivers to break up a qualification into teaching-focused groups of units.
			Sometimes one unit from a qualification may be delivered across multiple clusters, and a
			student must successfully complete the assessments in each cluster to achieve competency
			in the unit. For example the Qualification Certificate IV in Training and Assessment has
			12 units in total, but the four Environment units are assessed in each cluster. The
			course is delivered in three clusters and each cluster has a fee that applies to it. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Creating the Qualification</title>
			<para>Create a new course and attach all the units that you deliver as part of the
				qualification. This is the formal enrolment where you will record the student's
				completion of outcomes once assessment has been sufficiently completed across your
				various clusters.</para>
			<para>This is the course that you will advertise on your website, so make sure you
				include the full course description and information about how you deliver the
				program.</para>
			<para>Next, create a class for this course, entering the dates, student fees and venue
				information. Details on how to create a class is available here. Web enable this
				class so students can enrol. </para>
			<para>You may choose to set up this class as an 'application fee enrolment' and advise
				the students of the full fee within this class description. Do this by setting the
				class fee as the amount you wish them to pay to apply, and ensure your information
				explains what the approval process involves. You will need to contact students who
				apply and inform them of their success or otherwise, and organise payment of the
				full course fees. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating the clusters</title>
			<para>The cluster courses that you create are for your scheduling and management
				purposes only. They will not be advertised online, as you will enrol students in
				these classes as appropriate.</para>
			<para>The clusters that you create are not VET courses - do not attach the qualification or units
				of competency to these records. You can put details of the units and content covered
				in the description if you wish.</para>
			<para>Set up each course and class with the assigned rooms, tutors and sessions</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolments and Payment</title>
			<para>As onCourse will invoice students class fees, you can allow students to make full
				payments or part payments at the time of enrolment.</para>
			<para>For example, you could set the full fee on the first class and track students as
				they make payments towards this total amount. Alternatively, you could set up
				multiple classes with fees attached, so students are only invoiced for a portion of
				the course fee each time they are enrolled in a new cluster.</para>
			<para>In the example below, the full qualification has an application fee of $100, paid
				online. Once the student's enrolment has been accepted, they are invoiced $900 for
				the first cluster, and $500 for each of the subsequent clusters, until a total of
				$2000 has been paid.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section><title>Quality Indicator Reporting</title><para>All RTOs registered with ASQA must provide an annual summary report to ASQA of their
			performance against the learner engagement and employer satisfaction quality indicators.
			You are required to send a survey to every student who undertakes VET training with your
			college (the Learner Questionnaire), and to every employer with whom you conduct
			traineeships (the Employer Questionnaire). Read more on ASQA's requirements <link xlink:href="http://www.asqa.gov.au/vet-registration/comply-with-your-obligations/quality-indicator-reporting.html">here</link> Remember that students and employers don't have to complete these
			surveys, but you do need to send them out.</para><para>You will need to collate the responses and complete ASQA's Quality Indicator annual summary
			report. The template is available <link xlink:href="http://www.asqa.gov.au/vet-registration/comply-with-your-obligations/quality-indicator-reporting.html">here.</link></para>

		<section>
			<title>Using SurveyMonkey </title>
			<para>SurveyMonkey is an online survey tool which can help you remove any paper from the
				survey process. SurveyMonkey has some pre-existing templates for the Questionnaires
				so you can get started very quickly. Set up a new account and then add them:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Log in to <link xlink:href="https://www.surveymonkey.com">SurveyMonkey</link></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>While still logged into SurveyMonkey, click on links below</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<link xlink:href="https://www.surveymonkey.net/user/create-survey?template_id=873&amp;survey_title=Learner%20Questionnaire">Learner Questionnaire template</link>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><link xlink:href="https://www.surveymonkey.net/user/create-survey?template_id=874&amp;survey_title=Employer%20Questionnaire"> Employer Questionnaire template </link></para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>There is no cost for copying these templates, and SurveyMonkey has some cheap or free
				plans, depending on your usage needs.</para>
		</section>
		<section><title>Other survey tools </title>
			<para>You might also want to look at FormStack, SurveyGizmo,
			Google Forms and wufoo forms as some other survey tools. While you might need to create
			the survey yourself, each of these tools has some interesting strengths.</para></section>
		<section>
			<title>Sending survey links</title>
			<para>There are two ways to send students a link to your survey automatically.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Integrated option</title>
				<para>In this option, onCourse sends SurveyMonkey or SurveyGizmo details of each
					student completing a VET course. The survey tool then sends out an invite to the
					student, with a link to the questionnaire.</para>
				<para>The advantage of this approach is they you can log into your survey tool to
					see a list of all the students who have not yet responded. There are features
					there which allow you to send reminders. You'll need a paid account with the
					survey tool and this option takes a bit more work to set up.</para>
				<para>Information on how to link your onCourse to your Survey Provider Account
					<link xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/externalintegrations.html#gsc.tab=0">can be found here</link>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Email link to questionnaire</title>
				<para>Alternatively you can just email the student a link to the questionnaire. This
					will work with any third party tool, but you will not easily be able to generate
					a list of students who have not completed the questionnaire. Mostly this doesn't
					matter, because you only have to invite the student to complete, not ensure they
					respond.</para>
				<para>Instructions for getting the <link xlink:href="https://help.surveymonkey.com/articles/en_US/kb/Web-Link-Collector">SurveyMonkey</link> link.</para>
				<para>Instructions for getting the <link xlink:href="https://help.surveygizmo.com/help/share-survey-via-link">SurveyGizmo </link>link.</para>
				<para>These links are then added to an email template that can be sent out to all
					completed students. The records of the emails will be stored in onCourse, while
					the Survey results will be stored on the third party tool. </para>

			</section>
		</section>
	</section>	
</chapter>
