<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="discounts">
    <title>Discounts</title>
    <para>In an ideal world you'd never have to give students a discount. They would all flock to
        your courses at full price. But discounts can form an integral part of your marketing
        strategy. Used well, they allow you to attract students who would not otherwise have
        enrolled at the full price. Used poorly, they represent income you give away to students who
        would have happily paid full price. In an ideal world, you will sell to each student at the
        maximum price they would have paid. This is called 'differential pricing' and one way to
        achieve it is through well placed discounts. It allows you to set your full price to be
        higher than you would normally, and target those individuals who would be discouraged at
        that price point with special offers.</para>
    <para>This approach has several benefits to some types of colleges: it positions you as a
        premium service, it creates an impression that you are looking after certain special
        customers and it allows you to discount more deeply for certain demographics knowing that
        higher income is coming from others. As an example of this approach look at the airline
        industry: it is very unlikely that the person sitting next to you paid the same for their
        seat as you did. And airlines economic model is a lot like education; your product is
        completely perishable. Once the flight takes off or the class starts, those empty seats can
        never be sold.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction to discounts</title>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>What is a discount? </term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A discount is an onCourse marketing tool allowing you to sell a class at a
                        reduced price. </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>How is the value of a discount calculated? </term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A discount value may be applied in dollars, percentage or a change the fee
                        to a set amount (where you specify the same fee that will apply for all
                        classes eligible). All discount values are ex GST, meaning GST (if it
                        applies) will be recalculated on the resulting class fee.</para>
                    <para>For example, if a class fee is $150 (inc GST) and you offer a $50
                        discount, the fee the student pays will not be $100.</para>
                    <para>In this instance the class fee is actually $136.36 and the GST is $13.64.
                        When the $50 discount is deducted, the class fee becomes $86.36. GST is now
                        re-calculated on the new class fee to be $8.64 and the total fee payable
                        becomes $95 (inc GST).</para>
                    <para>If the $50 discount is offered on a class where the fee is $150 (ex GST)
                        then the fee payable will be $100 (ex GST). </para>
                    <para>In both instances, your college earns $50 less income by providing the
                        discount. In the example with GST, the government also earns $5 less GST
                        income as the sale cost of your product has been reduced.</para>
                    <para>You can link classes both with and without GST to the same discount policy
                        as the calculation will be determined on each class fee individually.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>How is discount eligibility calculated? </term>
                <listitem>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Students: Discounts may be offered to anyone, students under or
                                over a certain age, students in a certain postcode, students with
                                particular memberships such as corporate members, or students with a
                                concession such as a seniors card. If a student meets the
                                requirement of the discount, it will be offered automatically on
                                enrolment. If a student is eligible for multiple discounts, the best
                                discount available will be offered.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Classes: Discounts may be offered to a course (and all it's
                                classes), a class, all current and pending classes or any
                                combination of the above. If an eligible student is enrolling in an
                                eligible class, the discount will be offered automatically.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Discount validity: The discount itself may have a valid from or
                                expiry date, or require students to enter a special promotional
                                code. Discounts are offered automatically when the student meets the
                                discount requirement and may also be offered in conjunction with
                                other discounts.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>When is a discount applied?</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Discounts always apply automatically, when the discount conditions have
                        been met. Discounts can be made available for online enrolments, or only for
                        enrolments processed through the office. There are two ways a discount will
                        apply:</para>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Discounts based on the student meeting an eligibility criteria.
                                This means you have defined some restrictions on who is able to
                                receive this discount when they enrol e.g. students with a senior's
                                card. If the student meets this criteria, or this criteria is added
                                during the enrolment process, the discount will apply.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Discounts using a promotional code. These discounts are often part
                                of a marketing campaign and are designed to be 'shared' amongst your
                                targeted clients and their friends. They do not usually have
                                additional restrictions attached - whoever can supply the
                                promotional code can access the reduced fee. The promotional code
                                has to be supplied at the time of enrolment to access the
                                discount.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Creating effective discount strategies</title>
        <para>The first consideration in creating a discount is how will you use it to help you
            bring in additional enrolments that you would have otherwise not received. </para>
        <para>Consider low income discounts. These are the discounts you think of when you imagine
            children, seniors, disability card holders or unemployed discounts - people who may have
            limited disposable income and for whom the cost of the full course is a deterrent for
            enrolling. These are discounts which can be given either as a percentage of the course
            fee, or as a fixed dollar figure. If you decide to give a percentage discount you can
            also set the minimum and maximum dollar discount which can be given. So you might to
            decide to give 10% off for seniors but cap it at $50 so that $800 course doesn't start
            to be discounted too heavily for you. Or a 2% discount which gives at least $5 off that
            $100 course so it doesn't appear too stingy.</para>
        <para>Another option is to offer early enrolment discounts, as by encouraging people to
            enrol and pay well before class start dates makes resource management easier on the
            college. You could also provide last minute style discounts, to encourage the spare
            seats to be filled or to get a not quite viable class over the line. These discounts
            could be automatically given to all enrolling students, or be restricted to students who
            can provide the matching promotional code.</para>
        <para>For these type of discounts you would set a start and end date, where other types of
            discounts continue indefinitely. onCourse gives you the choice. </para>
        <para>When considering who can access the discount, you might want to restrict it to all
            students who have enrolled in the past, are over a certain age, live in a particular
            suburb or who have certain type of concession card or membership. You aren't locking it
            to the students who currently fit the requirement: any student who later is entered into
            the system with the right age, suburb, concession or membership type will be able to
            obtain that discount. </para>
        <para>Finally, you are able to set the list of classes which may receive the discount. This
            might be every class you run, just your computer courses, or just one course you choose.
            This gives you flexibility to offer discounts where you think they will be appropriate,
            useful and affordable. You may be able to offer lower discounts to outsourced courses
            given your margins or it may not be helpful to offer seniors discounts to pre-natal
            sessions. </para>
        <para>With all this flexibility, you can offer discounts to your students in exactly the way
            you choose. For instance: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>all students under 25 receive 10% off all courses – these are often people
                    with lower disposable income and discounts are a useful way to attract them
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>all students who attended a course last term automatically get 20% off
                    selected courses this term </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>all students with a senior's card receive a $20 discount off any of the
                    daytime arts and craft classes</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Generally, concessions apply on a long term basis and are based on your college's fees
            and charges policy. Concessions are automatically applied to fees on enrolment if a
            student meets the conditions you have set. If you wish to give a special deal to a
            certain group of people for a limited time only, it is more suitable to create a
            promotion. </para>
        <para>Promotions are another type of discount with a string attached. The student must know
            a particular word or code in order to obtain the discount. You might decide to perform a
            letterbox drop in a particular area with postcard sized teasers for your new dance
            classes. They explain that the recipient can get a 15% discount by going to the web site
            and typing in 'WALTZ'. When they do this, the web site alters and shows the courses with
            fees crossed out and the discounted price alongside in red. The idea is to: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>create the feeling of an offer targeted to a particular group of people, so
                    the recipient feels special.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>track the effectiveness of your letterbox drop</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>use an expiry date to create urgency</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>micro-market: use different strategies for different demographics</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>You might distribute your promotional codes by using:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>targeted printed material</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>an email mailout to existing or potential students</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>SMS</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>an alliance with a club or user group – such as a deal with a local RSL that
                    gives their members a discount through a code in their newsletter</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Remember, the point of promotional codes is not to keep the code secret and prevent
            recipients telling their friends about it. The effectiveness of your marketing is
            greatly enhanced by potential students telling as many people as possible about this
            great deal they can get by typing in a 'secret code'. </para>
        <para>Long term, analysing the percentage take up estimations vs the actual use of the
            discount on a per class, or per enrolment period will assist you in determining if the
            strategies you are employing are effective at encouraging new or repeat enrolments.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>How to create a discount</title>
        <para>The discount window can be found on the onCourse Marketing tab, or via the courses
            menu. Opening the discount window will show a list view of all current discounts.
            Historical, or inactive discounts are suppressed by default. You can view these
            discounts by selecting 'inactive' from the core filters.</para>
        <para>Double clicking on an item in the list will open the discount edit window. You can
            create a new discount by clicking on the + in the top right hand corner of the list
            view. You can delete a discount by highlighting it and clicking on the garbage can icon.
            Discounts which have been used by students can not be deleted, but they can be made
            inactive by setting an end date in the past. This will not affect any discounts already
            processed.</para>
        <section xml:id="discounts-Value">
            <title>Defining the discount value</title>
            <para>The first tab in the discount edit view is the value tab. This is where you define
                the way the discount is calculated.</para>
            <para>The name of the discount will appear on the website, on invoices and in finance
                reports so it is important to choose a name that clearly identifies the
                discount.</para>
            <para>A discount which is available via online enrolment means students enrolling using
                your onCourse website have access to this discount. If it is un-ticked, only
                students who are enrolled via the office, in Quick Enrol have access to the
                discount. You may have chosen to stop a concession card type being added online, but
                can make the discount still available online for existing students with the
                concession type on record.</para>
            <para>A discount percent allows you to define a percentage amount that will be taken off
                the class enrolment fee. A discount dollar lets you fix a dollar amount that will be
                taken off the class enrolment fee (note, the classes attached to the discount may
                have a variety of fees, so a discount dollar will be better for some classes than
                others). Override fee lets you set a new fee for all the classes linked to the
                discount.</para>
            <para>At this point, you can also select if the discount will have any minimum or
                maximum caps or rounding applied to the nearest dollar, 50 cents or 10 cents. </para>
            <para>Setting a valid to or from date is optional. Many types of discounts don't require
                a date until you decide to retire the discount by editing it to set a date in the
                past. </para>
            <para>The default forecast take-up can be set here, or set individually in the classes
                you have linked the discount to. This is a prediction that will assist you in your
                income budgeting, based on the percentage of students you expect to utilise this
                discount for each class, and therefore the potential cost of providing this discount
                to your business.</para>
            <para>The public description field contains any additional information you wish to
                provide to potential students about who and how this discount can be accessed and is
                displayed on the website.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/discount_value.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Example value settings of a discount for seniors</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para> </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="discounts-Student">
            <title>Defining the eligible students</title>
            <para>The second tab on the discount edit window allows you to define who can access the
                discount.</para>
            <para>Some types of discount may be available to anyone, meaning any person who enrols
                will automatically have the discount applied. They may also have to supply a
                promotional code, or enrol within a fixed period of time, depending on what you set
                on the first tab.</para>
            <para>More often, discounts are restricted to people who meet certain criteria. A
                discount may require the student to meet multiple criteria. For example, in the
                Senior's Discount window below, the student needs to provide both a Senior's Card
                and a date of birth that shows they are over 60. For this to work effectively, you
                would need to ensure that the date of birth field was set to mandatory for website
                enrolments, otherwise clients just providing the details of their seniors card would
                not be sufficient to access the discount.</para>
            <para>To link concessions or memberships to the discount record, they need to already be
                set up in your onCourse records. See <link xlink:href="#concessions">the concessions
                    and memberships chapter</link> for more information about how to create a
                concession or membership.</para>
            <para>After defining the students, you can also select if you want this discount shown
                in advertising. By default, discounts will show on the website as part of the class
                advertising details. In some instances you may wish to hide the discount from
                advertising, but still allow people to access the discount online, for example, when
                providing an internal staff discount.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/discount_students.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This senior's discount has two restrictions on who can access it - people
                        over 60 years of age who also hold a seniors card.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="discounts-Classes">
            <title>Defining the eligible classes</title>
            <para>The classes tab of the discount window is where you define which classes can
                access this discount during enrolment. </para>
            <para>Using the checkbox option 'Add this discount when creating or duplicating classes'
                on the bottom of the class tab will automatically add this discount to every new
                class you create from now on. This can be useful to select for a global discount
                that applies to all your classes, like an Early Bird discount. </para>
            <para>If you choose this option, you should also select the 'All current and pending
                classes' to add the discount to the classes you have already created.</para>
            <para>Alternatively, you can select a restricted set of classes by using the add classes
                option.</para>
            <para>Click on the + symbol and then choose from the following options when defining
                which Classes are to be assigned to the discount:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>All current and pending classes</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Classes from a course</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A class</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Classes tagged with</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <tip>
                <para>Dependent on which option you select, onCourse will tell you how many Classes
                    are to be added to the discount.</para>
            </tip>
            <para>Once you have added classes, you can also use the garbage icon to delete classes
                from the list. The delete option works on one class at a time.</para>
            <para>You can assign all current and pending classes to the discount multiple times - it
                will not create duplicate records. During the class roll over process, it will also
                select the option to apply all existing discounts to the new class record by
                default.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/discount_classes.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Assigning all current and pending classes to a discount.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Accessing discounts during enrolment</title>
        <para>Depending on the discount settings, discounts can be made available to students
            enrolling through the web and office, or just for students enrolling through the
            office.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing discounts through Quick Enrol</title>
            <para>If the student and their chosen class meet the requirements of the discount, it
                will be applied by default on enrolment. If the student is eligible for multiple
                discount types, the discount that provides the lowest cost to the student will be
                applied.</para>
            <para>During the enrolment process, discounts that require a promotional code can be
                entered on the payment screen. Again, any eligible classes will have their fee
                reduced.</para>
            <para>Before saving and confirming the enrolment, you can check the discounts that have
                been applied by hovering over the notification icon next to the class fee.</para>
            <para>You can also manually adjust a discount as necessary by replacing the discount
                amount in the enrolment window.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/qediscount.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This student is eligible for a youth discount when they enrol in this
                        class</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing promotional code discounts in onCourse through Quick Enrol</title>
            <para>During the enrolment process, if a student supplies a promotional code this needs
                to be entered in the payment panel, in the field 'Enter voucher or promotion
                code...'.</para>
            <para>Any applicable classes and students in the enrolment process will have their
                enrolment fee's updated to meet the promotional code conditions.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/qe_promo.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>You can enter a promotional code in the the field 'Enter voucher or
                        promotion code...'.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Membership discounts during Quick Enrol</title>
            <para>If a student holds a valid membership, is related to a contact with a membership
                where discounts apply or purchases a membership during the enrolment process, the
                best applicable discount will automatically apply.</para>
            <para>For example, if you have created a discount policy for members and friends to
                access two different class prices - members with a 30% discount and friends of
                members with a 10% discount, members who are friends with other members will always
                be given the higher of the two discounts.</para>
            <para>Memberships can be purchased during the Quick Enrol process, with these
                memberships providing discount benefits immediately.</para>
            <para>To purchase a membership, click on the 'Enter course or item...' field in the
                Quick Enrol window and either start typing the membership code or select the option
                'MEMBERSHIPS' on the right side of the window. Look up the membership by name and
                make any changes as necessary to the membership start date, end date and cost.
                Continue with the enrolment process as usual.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/club_membership_QE.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>You can enter a promotional code in the the field 'Enter course or
                        item...'. </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>If a student already has a membership purchased, you can see the details of that
                membership in their contact record general tab. This is also the tab that loads by
                default when you add a contact to the Quick Enrol process.</para>
            <para>If your discount policy so allows, and a student is related to a contact who holds
                a membership, you will not see a membership recorded in the relation's record. You
                can see the details of their relationships, however.</para>
            <para>For example, memberships are often sold to corporate partners. In onCourse, these
                contacts are 'companies', and companies can not enrol in classes as they are not
                real people. Employees of companies can enrol, so you may like to set up the
                discount policy so the discount applies to member and their employees.</para>
            <para>If an employee of the membership enrols, and the relationship is noted in their
                contact record (you can add this during the enrolment process) the membership
                discount will automatically apply.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Manual discounts in Quick Enrol</title>
            <para>If you need to provide an 'on the fly' discount to an enrolment fee during the
                enrolment process, there is the ability to enter a manual discount in the discount
                window on the enrolment tab. This discount will be visible in the class budget,
                recorded in the class income and linked to the enrolment, so if the enrolment is
                cancelled and the payer credited, the credit will be less the amount of the discount
                provided.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/manual_discount.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A manual discount of $50 has been entered in the enrolment.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>We do not recommend using the 'Other charge' option to provide a discount. An 'other charge' is not linked to a class or enrolment and will not be automatically credited if the enrolment is cancelled and credited. The 'other charge' option is designed to add, on the fly additional line items to the invoice like a phone booking charge.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing discounts on the web</title>
            <para>If you wish, discount rates and fees can be displayed inline with the class fee on
                the website. When users hover over the discounted fee, they can see who is eligible
                to apply for it. Discounts which calculate to the same fee will be displayed once,
                with a dual label on the website. E.g. if both seniors and students are eligible for
                a 10% discount, and have separate discount policies set up, the website will show
                one fee and the hover will show both discount names. This makes the class fee
                display neater, especially for colleges who have a large variety of discount
                policies.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/discount_fee_webdisplay.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A class showing multiple discounts options available to concession card
                        holders</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>When a student is completing the enrolment process, by default they will be
                charged the full fee. If you allow the entry of the concession card details via the
                website, they can then select the option during enrolment to select a concession
                card type and enter the appropriate details you require.</para>
            <para>While concession card numbers and validity can't be checked by the website
                enrolment process, all students must confirm that their claim to access the
                concession is valid and that their details may be checked. You should ensure your
                enrolment policy and procedures includes information about how additional charges
                will be levied if students can not produce their concession card on request.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/online_enrol_concession.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>During website enrolment, students can enter concession card
                        details</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/online_enrol_discountapplied.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The appropriate fee discounts are then calculated prior to the student
                        making payment for their enrolment(s)</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Promotional codes on the web</title>
            <para>Promotional codes are applied differently on the website to discounts that relate
                to concessions. Firstly, you need to ensure that your website design includes a
                specification for the location of the 'My discounts' option. This panel allows
                students to enter a promotional code that will then be applied to all eligible
                classes across your website during their browsing of your programs.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/web_promotionalcode.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Mechanism for students to enter a known promotional code to reduce
                        eligible enrolment fees</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>Once a student has entered a valid promotional code, classes they view will show
                the full fee crossed out and the fee that applies during the promotion displayed
                instead. During enrolment, this discounted fee will be automatically applied.</para>
            <para>Promotional codes, gift certificates or voucher codes can also be added during the
                payment process. Codes added at this time will also apply the discount to any
                applicable students and classes in the enrolment selection.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Membership discounts for online enrolments</title>
            <para>If a student holds a membership which entitles them to a discount, or is related
                to a member which entitles them to a discount, this discount will be automatically
                applied during the online enrolment process.</para>
            <para>Relationships can not be added during the online enrolment process, so for the
                discount to apply, the relationship already needs to have been recorded in the
                student's onCourse record.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Financial aspects of discounts</title>
        <para>Discounts play a part in the budget of onCourse and the process of determining if a
            class will be financially viable based on the student fee's collected. As a business,
            you may also like to include predictive information about the expected take up of a
            discount. Discounts in onCourse are charged to a cost of sale account, rather than
            considered a straight reduction to income collected, as a discount is considered as a
            cost of doing business.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Discounts in the class budget</title>
            <para>When you view the general tab of a class record, you can see in the Budget
                Summary, all available class fees. These are the fees that are payable for students
                meeting any of the discount requirements.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/class_budget_summary.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This class has a full fee, plus three discount price points available</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>In each discount you create, you can define a 'Default forecast take-up'. What
                this means, is that across all the classes this discount applies to, you expect,
                say, 5% of all students to use this discount on enrolment.</para>
            <para>You can further refine this forecast on a class by class basis in the class
                budget. Double click on the discount line in the budget and setting a new forecast
                of your choice.</para>
            <para>Based on your enrolment maximum, projected and actual, all three columns will
                update, with the actual column showing you also the percentage of student's enrolled
                using the discount.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/class_discount_forecast.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Overriding the default forecast in the class</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>Using the garbage icon, you can delete discounts from classes in the budget. This
                will prevent future students from enrolling and accessing this discount. It will not
                remove the discount given to existing students. </para>
            <para>When the discount line has been deleted from the budget you will not see the total
                value of the discounts given itemised. Any budget printed report will still contain
                the detail of how many of these discounts you have given, and the class total
                incomes will still be correct.  If you add the discount back, via the discount
                classes window, the discount and value of any discounts applied will be visible
                again.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accounts and discounts</title>
            <para>In the onCourse chart of accounts, a default account called 'Discounts Given' is
                used to record all the discount costs. </para>
            <para>When a student enrols, the diagram below demonstrates how the income and discounts
                are posted against the chart of accounts, for an example $300 enrolment with a $100
                discount.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/income_discount_transactions.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Transactional entries for an enrolment with a discount.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>Item 1: When the student enrols, the income component of the enrolment fee (in
                this example $200) is posted to the liability account. It will be transferred to the
                allocated income account when the class delivery commences. See <link
                    xlink:href="#accounting">the accounting chapter</link> for more information
                about how and when income transfers occur.</para>
            <para>Item 2: Prior to the invoice being paid, the amount owing is credited to the trade
                debtor account.</para>
            <para>Item 3: The value of the discount is posted to the chosen income account directly.
                This income doesn't get posted via the liability accounts.</para>
            <para>Item 4: Discount value is charged as a Cost of Sale to the Discounts Given
                account.</para>
            <para>Item 5: When the payment for the invoice is taken (whether this is at the time of
                enrolment, or later down the track), the cheque account is credited the payment
                amount, and the amount paid debited from the Trade debtor account. There may be
                multiple payments for an invoice, for example a costly class which is paid off over
                time.</para>
            <para>Item 6: When the class commences, the rest of the class income is 'earned', and
                transferred from the liability account to the income account. Now the income account
                includes both the discount and enrolment fee components e.g. $300.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Understanding GST and rounding in discounts</title>
            <para>GST is an Australian Goods and Services Tax, currently set to a flat rate of 10%
                for all applications of the tax. GST often doesn't apply to enrolments in vocational
                classes, but does apply for enrolments in leisure classes. When GST applies to a
                class, it is important to understand that any discount applied to the class fee will
                cause the GST to be recalculated. </para>
            <para>The reason behind this is that GST must be 10% of the product cost you charge to
                the customer. If the ex GST cost of the product sold drops from $300 to $200 due to
                a discount, then the GST charged must also drop from $30 to $20.</para>
            <para>If you have discount policies that apply to groups of classes, including both GST
                inc and GST ex fees, you will notice that the resulting fee payable by the student
                is different, even if a fixed discount amount is given.</para>
            <para>To put it another way, if you have a GST free class costing $300 which has a $100
                discount, the student will be charged a straight $200. A $100 reduction in the fees
                payable by the student has been applied.</para>
            <para>However, if you have a GST inclusive class costing $300 which has a $100 discount,
                the student will end up paying a GST inclusive fee of $190. The student has been
                given an effective discount of $110, instead of $100. Why do students paying GST now
                get a 'better' discount? Beacuse they are now liable to pay less GST.</para>
            <para>In a class fee of $300 incl GST, $272.73 is the fee income. The remaining $27.27
                is not your income - it is GST you are collecting on behalf of the government and
                holding only until the time you reimburse it to them. In onCourse, GST is always
                posted to a liability account, never to your income account. onCourse budgets always
                exclude GST from any profitability calculations.</para>
            <para>As the $100 discount is actually being given on a $272.73 class fee, reducing it
                to $172.73, the GST now must be recalculated on the new fee. The GST of $17.27
                (instead of the previous GST of $27.27 on the undiscounted fee) now brings the total
                fee payable back to $190.</para>
            <para>Obviously, the different end values of the discounts are most obvious when
                comparing the same GST exclusive and GST inclusive total fees side by side. If,
                instead like in the first example, your GST inclusive class of $300 was a total cost
                of $330, while your GST free class was just $300, the $100 discount would result in
                total fees of $220 and $200 respectively. The GST paying student still pays 10% more
                for their class than the GST free student does, instead of the unexpected 5% less
                when the discounted GST inc/GST free classes have the same starting fee.  </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Example discount campaigns</title>
        <para>Some examples of possible campaigns are outlined below:</para>
        <example>
            <title>Creating a 10% discount for seniors card holders</title>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Select <guilabel>Discounts</guilabel> from the splash screen or
                            <guimenu>Courses</guimenu> menu.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Select <guibutton>+</guibutton> button from the bottom left of the
                        window</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>In the new window, enter a name for this concession e.g. Seniors Card
                        Discount</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>To set a 10% discount, select the <guilabel>Discount Percent</guilabel>
                        option and type 10 into the discount value field.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can also set a minimum and maximum amount for the concession e.g. min
                        $1 and max $10 and set the discount to round to the whole dollar, nearest
                        10c or nearest 50c. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Ensure the option 'available for online enrolment' is ticked, if you want
                        this discount to be available to Seniors enrolling online. If it is
                        unticked, the discount will only be available to Seniors enrolling via the
                        office.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Setting a valid from and valid to date is optional. If you want to make
                        the discount apply at all times, leave these fields blank. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Choose if this concession can be given with other concessions. For example
                        a student could receive this concession and a further fee discount by using
                        a special promotional code if you check this box. Most discounts can't be
                        combined. onCourse will always choose the best discount the student is
                        eligible for.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Move to the student's tab. In this example, you might select 'with the
                        following concession type(s) and add concession types you have previously
                        defined as<guilabel>Aged Pensioner concession</guilabel> or
                            <guilabel>Seniors card concession</guilabel>. You may also choose to
                        add, or use instead the parameter <guilabel>Age over 60</guilabel>. This
                        will require the student to supply a valid date of birth as well / instead
                        of a concession card to access the discount.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If you would like students to see the discounted fee that may be eligible
                        for when browsing the web, ensure you have not ticked 'Do not show
                        discounted price in advertising'. This will suppress the display of the
                        price on your onCourse website.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The last tab allows you to assign this discount to certain available
                        classes. You can add or remove classes by using the <guibutton>+</guibutton>
                        and <guibutton>Garbage can</guibutton> signs to the right, including
                        allowing this discount in all current and future classes.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </example>
        <example>
            <title>How to create a marketing campaign with a promotional code</title>
            <para>In this example we will create a last minute discount for our previously enrolled
                students.</para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Create a code for your promotion. This will be what students enter on your
                        website to access the promotional discount (or can be entered by your
                        enrolment staff with phone, mail or in person enrolments). An example code
                        might be VIPSTUDENT</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Name and describe your promotion and decide if it is to be available to
                        students enrolling online and through the office, or only to students
                        enrolling through the office.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Set the amount and valid to and from dates. In this example we have
                        limited the date to a one week range. It is usual for a promotion to run for
                        a set period of time, but you could leave these fields blank to always allow
                        this discount to apply.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>This promotion is for re-enrolling students, so we can set it to students
                        who have <guilabel>enrolled within 60 days</guilabel>.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Select your eligible classes. Generally promotions are limited to a few
                        select programs, such as those which already are over the minimum required,
                        or dance classes or those which are starting in the next two weeks.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            <para>Don't forget, promotional codes only work if you market them. You can always email
                or SMS special promotions to your students to get them out there quickly. With most
                promotions you would not want to set a qualifier, like enrolled within x days, as
                you want as many people as possible to 'use' the special code to enrol in your
                classes, and hope the students you market the promotion to assist you in your
                marketing efforts by passing the deal on to their friends. </para>
        </example>
        <example>
            <title>How to create a membership discount</title>
            <para>In this example we will create a membership students can buy to entitle them to a
                100% discount for any of our computer classes for the next six months.</para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Open the membership window and create the membership for purchase. Set a
                        cost for purchase and the duration of the membership in days.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Open the discount window and create the discount policy for computer club
                        members. The discount is for 100%. Decide if you want this discount
                        available to students who hold this membership and enrol online, or only via
                        the office.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Go to the students tab of the discount window and select the options
                        'students with' and 'with following memberships' and add the new membership
                        you just set up. In this instance we will choose to apply this discount only
                        to the student who purchased it. Leaving the option 'do not show discounted
                        price in advertising' unticked is a good choice for this discount, as seeing
                        the $0 enrolment fee online available will also encourage other students to
                        purchase this membership for the benefits it provides.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Go to the classes tab on the discount window and add all your current and
                        pending computer classes. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Save and close the record. The membership is now ready for purchase and
                        the discount policy as defined will be applied.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </example>
        <example>
            <title>How to create a private discount for your college staff</title>
            <para>In this example we will create a concession based discount for college staff,
                entitling them to 50% off all classes. The concession type 'staff' can not be self
                selected on the website</para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Create a new concession type called 'Staff' and de-select the option
                        'Allow students to self select on website'. This is because we only want
                        college staff to determine who is a staff member (and entitled to the
                        discount). This concession will not require a concession card number or
                        expiry date either.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Ensure all college staff whom you want to access this discount have
                        student/tutor records in onCourse, and have the concession type 'staff'
                        added to their record.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Create a new discount called 'College staff' and leave the option
                        'Available via online enrolment' selected. This will let staff self enrol
                        and access the discount online. Set the value to 50%, and a maximum value if
                        desired. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Apply the discount to students with the following concession types -
                        staff. Ensure the option is ticked 'Do not show discounted price in
                        advertising'. This way the general public visiting the website will not be
                        privy to the discount available to staff members.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>On the classes tab, add all the applicable classes for this
                        discount.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>When college staff enrol online, the discount will be applied
                        automatically during the checkout process. They will not see the details of
                        this 'hidden' discount until they have been matched as a staff member using
                        their first name, last name and email address on record.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </example>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Reporting on discount use</title>
        <para>The Discounts by Class report is available from the classes menu. This report shows
            you for each class selected, how many enrolments you have processed at full fee and any
            applicable discount, and the total value of any discounts applied.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/discountreport.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>An example class where some students have used a discount to reduce their
                    enrolment fees</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>As discounts are all posted to the Cost of Sale account, Discounts Given. Transaction
            reports for this account can also be printed for the date range of your choice.</para>
        <para>Transaction reports can be printed either from the transaction window or the account
            window. If you choose the account window, you can choose to print all the transactions
            for just one, a group of, or all accounts.</para>
        <para>In the example below, a date range query has been run and a Transaction Detail report
            printed for just the Discounts Given account. This report shows the movements both in
            and out of the account in the timeframe. </para>
        <para>In this account, the debits are the discounts given and the credits occur when an
            enrolment is cancelled and refunded which had had a discount. The balance of this
            account sits on the debit side of the ledger. Each detail line is linked to the invoice
            number and invoice payer which can be followed up in onCourse as needed.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/discounts_given_transaction_report.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>An example Transaction Detail report, printed for the general ledger account
                    Discounts Given</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
