<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="downloadinstall">
	<title>Downloading and installing onCourse</title>
	<para>onCourse is free to download and use and is available at <link
			xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/download"> http://www.ish.com.au/download </link> or as a cloud hosted SaaS from ish group complete with support and additional functionalty, including:
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Tutor portal</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Student portal</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>SMS messaging</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Public facing website</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Course search engine</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>USI collection tool</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Certificate verification</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>ecommerce credit card integration</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Support</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<para>Using the hosted onCourse solution also supports development of the onCourse product.</para>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-selfhosted">
		<title>Self-hosted</title>
		<para>onCourse Server can run on any platform with a JVM of version 11 or higher. This includes Windows, OSX, Linux, BSD and many more. You can run the Oracle supported JVM or one of the free open source options like Adoptium.</para>
		<para>You'll also need a database, and onCourse has been run with Derby, MS SQL, Oracle, AWS RDS and MySQL in the past. Current testing focus is against MariaDB 10.3, so that will give you best results.</para>
		<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Virtualisation">
			<title>Virtualisation</title>
			<para>onCourse is happy in a virtualised environment such as VMWare Xen, or AWS EC2. Ensure that
				you have sufficient RAM and CPU allocated. onCourse Server only writes log files to disk so memory and CPU are more important than disk performance.</para>
		</section>

		<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Installation">
			<title>Installation</title>
			<para><link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/download">Download onCourse Server</link> and unzip the package.</para>
			<para>You'll need to create a configuration file named "onCourse.yml" with the following contents:
			<programlisting language="yaml">
	http:
		port: 8080
		path: /
		ip: 10.100.0.1

	db:
		uri: jdbc:mariadb:sequential://127.0.0.1/onCourse?user=onCourse&amp;password=higr7ehfgf3FFG&amp;useLegacyDatetimeCode=false
			</programlisting></para>
			<para>The options there are self-explanatory. Port to listen on, base path of the application and IP address to listen on. Then the database connection string.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
