<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="emailTemplates">
	<title>Email Templates</title>
	<section>
		<title>It's easy to construct emails with onCourse.</title>
		<section>
			<title> Learning about email templates</title>
			<para>The best way to define a message template is that it is a predefined and preconstructed
				message that is sent out depending on what event has occured. An example would be that a
				student has just enrolled into a class on your website, after this is successful, the
				"Enrolment Confirmation" template will be sent to them, the tags &lt;student.name> in the
				template itself will look through the onCourse database and determine the details like the
				students name etc</para>
			<para>Message templates are mostly messages that students with email addresses receive after
				enrolling online or through your office. onCourse makes it easy to access and update your
				template information by keeping them in the one place. You can use the templates as they are
				or you can personalise them to your specific needs and requirements.</para>
			<para>To get to the template, in onCourse go to File > Preferences > Email templates.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<title>So how do you edit a message template?</title>
				<listitem>
					<para> In the email template list view, you will see a default list of templates, this
						includes:</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Enrolment confirmation</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Payment failed</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Payment succeeded</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>SMS Tutor reminder</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Tax invoice</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Check the default text of each template. In some instances you will want to make
						changes, in others you can leave them as is. Where onCourse draws on information from
						the data base into the message you will see a message tag in brackets &lt;like this>.
						You should not remove tags in messages unless you are sure you don't want that
						information going to the student.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Formatting and editing these templates is very easy. Simply click in the window and
						you're ready to go, deleting or adding any extra information you need. You can change
						the current layout by typing directly in the main body of text or you can use the
						onCourse tags to insert additional information from the database directly into the text.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To add additional tags, click in the body of the letter where you would like the
						extra information to be placed then go to the available tags drop down menu on the right
						of the screen. Select and click which tag you would like to use and the information is
						entered into the body of the letter. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/email_template.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Enrolment Confirmation" template window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<tip>
				<para> Please note to check the text of the templates before using them. While most of the
					text can be used as is, some letters like the enrolment confirmation template needs an
					emergency contact number inserted into the main body of text to replace the current text
					of xxxxxxxx. </para>
			</tip>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
