<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="applications">
    <title>Enrolments by Application</title>
    <section xml:id="applications-Overview">
        <title>An overview of applications and enrolments</title>
        <para>The Enrolment by Application function allows you to add an approval process between
            the student requesting a place in a class and the enrolment and payment taking place and
            to optionally provide the student with an individualised enrolment fee offer.</para>
        <para>There are many reasons a course may require applications rather than allow direct
            enrolment.</para>
        <para>A course may have certain pre-requisites that need to be assessed as being met, such
            as the student supplying evidence of completing the Certificate IV or equivalent
            workplace experience before enrolling in a Diploma course.</para>
        <para>Another course may have competitive entry requirements, such as an audition, where
            students are competing to be offered a place in a limited enrolment class.</para>
        <para>Some language programs may require the student to be assessed to determine which
            program level is the right option for their current spoken and written skills, prior to
            their enrolment.</para>
        <para>Various government funded programs, like NSW Smart and Skilled, require the student to
            meet a suite of eligibility criteria to be accepted into the program at one of the
            multiple price points available.</para>
        <para>CRICOS approved training organisations may use the application process to assess and
            offer a enrolment opportunity to an overseas student which they can then use to obtain
            the student visa they require to study in Australia.</para>
        <para>Even from a marketing perspective, enrolment by application may be used for certain
            prestige courses to indicate that entry is not available to just anyone who can pay the
            course fees.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Setting the course to Enrol by Application</title>
            <para>By default, all current and new courses in onCourse are set to 'Open Enrolment',
                in the enrolment type option located on the course general tab. When a course is
                changed to 'Enrolment by application' that will change your website to show any of
                the courses classes 'Enrol now' buttons as 'Apply now' and suppress the display of
                the class fee.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/enrolment_type.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Setting a course to 'Enrolment by application'</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>We recommend you add descriptive text to the Marketing tab's web description fee
                explaining the course fee structure for these courses. As the class won't show a fee
                during the application process, as no fee applies until enrolment, it is important
                you indicate to the student prior to their application what fee they may need to pay
                if their application is approved.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/course_fee_in_description.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Describing the fees payable on enrolment in the web description</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <section>
                <title>Implications for classes and Quick Enrol</title>
                <para>When setting the enrolment fee for a class belonging to an enrolment by
                    application course, we suggest you set the highest applicable fee. If the
                    student is eligible for a discounted fee, their individual fee, defined in the
                    application will be charged.</para>
                <para>All fee override amounts set in the application are GST exclusive. An
                    additional charge for GST will be applied on enrolment if the class fee is set
                    to have GST. </para>
                <para>Enrolments into classes marked as 'Enrolment by application' can still be
                    processed directly in Quick Enrol, without the need for an approved student
                    application. It is only the online enrolment process that requires the
                    additional step.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="enrolmentByApplication-General">
            <title>Navigating the application window</title>
            <para>An application is created in onCourse when a student applies online or a manual
                application is created though the onCourse admin interface.</para>
            <para>An application contains the student details, the course they are applying for, and
                any additional information you may wish to collect during the application process
                such as copies of certificates or portfolios.</para>
            <para>All applications have a status that indicates where in the approval process they
                are up to.</para>
            <para>Applications can be accessed in the onCourse menu Activity > Applications.</para>
            <para>By default the window will open into a standard list view showing a summary table
                of all the application records.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/application_list_view.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The application list view</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>On the left hand panel of the list view window are the application status filters.
                By default, all except expired will be ticked when you open the window. You can
                check and uncheck these as needed to change the displayed list of
                applications.</para>
            <para>In the bottom-right hand corner of the list view are the fullscreen edit, add,
                view mode, share (print) &amp; cogwheel buttons. </para>
            <para>The cogwheel option can be used to open in bulk related records to the
                applications, such as the student records or course records, or used to send
                messages to applicants. It can also be used to delete an application record.</para>
            <para>Double clicking on an application record in the list view opens the edit view. The
                application has three sections: general, notes and documents.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/application_edit_view.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Editing an application record in full screen mode</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>The general section contains fields that may be completed during the application
                or application assessment process. The notes section allows you add additional notes
                or documents to the record.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating applications</title>
            <para>To create a new application in onCourse, click on the plus button in the top right
                hand corner of the application list view window.</para>
            <para>To create a new application you need to enter the name of a student who already
                has a contact record in onCourse, and the name of a course that is set to 'Enrolment
                by application'. You can not create an application for an open enrolment
                course.</para>
            <para>You do not need to add any additional information at this point, however you can
                optionally add additional notes or attach documents on the Notes section, or assign
                a tag to the record. Once complete, save and close the record, which you will then
                see displayed in the list view.</para>
            <para>By default, all applications will be created with a 'new' status. New applications
                mean those that have been received but not yet assessed.</para>
            <para>The date of the application and the source (office or web) will be automatically
                set for all new applications. These fields can not be edited.</para>
            <para>If applications can be made online, we suggest you enable the script 'send
                application received notification' and customise the email template 'enrolment
                application received'. The script will send the template email to the student, which
                should advise them what to do next, and also an email to the default office admin
                address, so you can schedule your own internal follow up process to assess the
                application.'</para>
            <para>Once you have begun the communication with the student regarding their
                application, you should change it's status to 'in progress' to differentiate from
                applications that have been made but had no follow up yet. Changing an application
                status to 'in progress' does not trigger any scripts or email communications by
                default.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Approving and rejecting applications</title>
            <para>The outcome status indicates what stage the application is at in the approval
                process. </para>
            <para>When an application has its status changed in onCourse, this affects what actions
                are available to the student. For example, only a student with an application of
                status type 'offered' can proceed with an online enrolment in a class from the
                course.</para>
            <para>Note that an 'offered' application for a course allows the student to enrol online
                in any published class from that course. This can be a useful option for courses
                that have a day and evening class option, or for courses that have classes starting
                every month.</para>
            <para>For an approved application, you can optionally add a 'fee override' and an 'enrol
                by' date.</para>
            <para>If you don't provide a fee override, the student can enrol at any of the standard
                or eligible discount rates you have set up for the classes of that course.</para>
            <para>If you do provide a fee override, this is the only fee option available to the
                student when they enrol online, for all classes of the course. Using the fee
                override instead of the normal class discount options is most useful for government
                funded classes where a complicated metric determines the student enrolment fee on a
                student by student basis.</para>
            <para>The enrol by date can put a cap on when the student has to decide to go ahead with
                the enrolment, possibly before the next class commences, or an earlier day, so you
                can offer the position to another student. This date is not required if the approval
                to enrol can be used at any time.</para>
            <para>When you are choosing to approve to reject an application, you may wish to make
                your reason for the decision known to the student. In that case, provide some text
                in the 'Reason for decision (student visible)' field in the application.</para>
            <para>Any fields below the 'reason for decision' box that aren't a part of Notes or
                Documents are custom fields that have been added in General Preferences.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/application_rejected.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>An 'application rejected' email showing the reason for the decision from
                        the application record.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>As part of your application assessment process, you may determine that the student
                is not eligible to complete the course they applied for. For example, a student may
                have applied for a Certificate III level English course and your assessment process
                has determined they are at Certificate I level. You can choose to either reject the
                Certificate III application and create a new application for the Certificate I or
                just change the original application to the Certificate I and explain why in the
                reason field.</para>
            <para>Once the student has received their application offer, they can chose to reject
                it, which then marks the application as 'Withdrawn' in onCourse. You can also mark
                an application as withdrawn at any time if the student notifies you they don't want
                to proceed.</para>
            <para>If the student proceeds to enrolment after receiving an 'offered' application
                notice, then the application status will change to 'accepted'. You can not change
                this status once it has been set.</para>
            <para>If you set an Enrol by date in an offered application and the student fails to
                enrol by this time, the status will be automatically set to 'expired'. You can reset
                the Enrol by date to automatically set it back to 'offered'.</para>
            <section>
                <title>Sending application emails</title>
                <para>When an application is created online or via the office, a script called 'send
                    application received notification' can be enabled to send the 'Enrolment
                    application received' email.</para>
                <para>If you have enabled the standard 'send application decision' script and
                    customised your 'application accepted' and 'application rejected' templates, the
                    information will be automatically sent to the students when you change the
                    application status and save the record.</para>
                <para>If you don't want to send these emails automatically, but would still like to
                    send them out manually, you can disable the script and use the cog wheel option
                    to send the received, approved or rejected email instead.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/application_success_email.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>An example of the standard 'application accepted' template email sent
                            to a student</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="applications-Web">
        <title>Applications on the web</title>
        <para>Courses set to 'Enrolment by application' need one or more classes enabled to display
            on the web to allow students to apply.</para>
        <para>The usual 'Enrol now' button will say 'Apply now' and any information about the class
            fee will be suppressed. We suggest you add information to the course or class
            description about the fees that will be applicable if the student's application is
            successful.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/apply_now.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>A course set to 'enrolment by application' showing apply now for the classes
                    on the web</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Applying online</title>
            <para>A student can apply online for a course, or courses as well as purchasing other
                enrolments or products in the shopping cart. As per the usual checkout process, the
                contact details you have set to request on enrolment must be supplied. </para>
            <para>There is no payment required if the student is only completing an online
                application.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/online_application.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The application (with no fee charged) is clearly identified in the checkout process.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>At the end of the checkout process, the student will be sent an 'enrolment
                application received' notification, instructing them what to do next. </para>
            <para>In onCourse File > Preferences > Scripts a default script called 'send application
                received notification' is disabled by default. If you plan on using online
                applications, you need to make sure this script is enabled.</para>
            <para>The email that is sent to the student can be found in File > Preferences > Email
                templates and is called 'Enrolment application received'. You must customise this
                template by inserting a location for the next stage of the application process, or
                replace it with some text to the effect of 'We will be in contact to request
                additional documentation'.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/enrol_application_received.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The default enrolment application received email in HTML</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Enrolling after application approval</title>
            <para>Once a student's application documents have been received, you have determined the
                appropriate fee for the student and set the fee override, and changed the
                application status to success, a script called 'send application decision' (disabled
                in onCourse by default, please enable if you wish to use it) will send the email
                template 'enrolment application accepted'.</para>
            <para>Within this template, is a special URL containing a unique student id that will
                open the course page ready for the student to select their class, enrol, and pay
                their enrolment fee. If the student has been provided a special fee override, that
                is the price they will see listed for each class on the course page. Otherwise, they
                will now see the default class fee.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/application_approved_email.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The default enrolment application approved email in HTML</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>The application approval process is for a course. Once a student is approved, they
                can then enrol in any class from that course, but can only use their application
                approval to enrol in one class from the course.</para>
            <para>Alternatively, if the student returns to the public website, locates the course
                and clicks 'Apply now' after they have an approved application, they will be able to
                proceed directly to the enrolment and payment process. This only occurs if the
                student uses the same first name, last name and email address they used for their
                approved application.</para>
            <para>If during the enrolment and payment process, they wish to 'add a friend', then the
                friend will go through the application process. Only students with applications
                statuses of 'offered' can proceed to online enrolment and payment.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/application_enrolment_with_fee_override.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The approved student is charged their override fee of $88 on enrolment, rather than the standard class fee</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Application records in the portal</title>
            <para> Students can also see the history of their applications in the skillsOnCourse
                portal by going to History and selecting the tab Applications. You can send the link
                to students https://www.skillsoncourse.com.au/portal/history to take them directly
                to this page after login.</para>
            <para>The History shows all current applications where the assessment is in progress,
                offered applications, as well as any rejected or withdrawn applications.</para>
            <para>Applications with a status of offered can be rejected in the portal by the
                student, which will change their status in onCourse to 'withdrawn', or the student
                can proceed to enrol and pay for their application from within the portal. This will
                redirect them to the normal online enrolment process.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/portal_application_history.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This student has multiple applications of varying statuses recorded in their application history</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
