<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="FEEHELP">
    <title>FEE-HELP</title>
    <section>
        <title>What is VET FEE-HELP?</title>
        <para>In the onCourse context, VET FEE-HELP is a database export and reporting standard for
            students enrolled in courses for which they can apply for a government study
            loan.</para>
        <para>More information about the current reporting standard can be found on the <link xlink:href="http://heimshelp.education.gov.au">Heims Help website</link></para>
        <para>VET FEE-HELP loans are available to assist eligible students studying Diploma level
            and above VET Qualifications to pay their tuition fees. Part, or all, of an eligible
            student’s tuition fees can be deferred into VET FEE‑HELP loan. Some Government funded course fees can also be deferred under the VET FEE-HELP
            scheme.</para>
        <para>An RTO needs to be pre-approved to offer VET FEE HELP on some or all of their courses.
            If you are an approved RTO, onCourse FEE HELP functions will enable you to meet your
            reporting and record keeping obligations.</para>
        </section>
    <section>
        <title>Creating a VET FEE-HELP Class</title>
        <para>Creating the VET FEE-HELP course may involve creating a single course, for a full
            qualification, with all appropriate units of competency attached, if your course is
            delivered as a single program with one census date.</para>
        <para>Where your VET FEE-HELP course contains multiple subjects, each with one or more unit,
            and with varying census dates, you'll need to create the appropriate number of onCourse
            courses, and at least one VET FEE-HELP approved class for each course.</para>
        <para>When creating a VET FEE-HELP eligible class, you'll need to ensure the enrolment fee
            you set is the approved fee for the full course (if there is only one class) or adds up
            to the full fee if your enrolment is spread amongst multiple subjects and
            classes.</para>
        <para>The data you set in the course and the class records is combined with student and
            enrolment data to create the VET Student Enrolment (VEN), VET Enrolment Revisions (VER),
            VET Load Liability (VLL), VET Unit of Study Completions (VCU), VET Course Completions
            (VCC) and VET Commonwealth Assisted Students - HELP Due (VDU) export files.</para>
        <para>On the class VET tab, you will need to begin by checking the option 'This is a VET
            FEE-HELP eligible class'. This will show the additional class fields.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Type of attendance - select from Full time or Part Time</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Equivalent full-time student load - this must be expressed as a whole number
                    where 1 = a full time student load, 05 is 50% of a full time load and 0125 is
                    equal to 1/8th of a full time student load.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Census date - This is the last date students can withdraw before incurring the
                    course VET FEE-HELP date. This must match your pre-approved census dates for the
                    course or subject.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Reporting period - This is the year and semester period in the format YYYYp. A
                    valid entry in this field would be 20151 or 20152</para>
            </listitem>

        </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/vet_fee_help_class.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>VET FEE-HELP fields in a Class record</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
        <section>
        <title>Setting the Student's VET FEE-HELP eligibility</title>
        <para>For all students enrolled in a class where VET FEE-HELP loans are available, every
            participant must have additional data in their student VET tab record completed, even if
            they are not applying for a loan.</para>
        <para>You will need to create and record a CHESSN for each student, and complete the
            student's contact details and AVETMISS questions responses as usual.</para>
                <para>There are some additional fields in the VET tab of a contact record that need
            to be completed if the student is applying for VET FEE-HELP. You will need to mark the
            checkbox called 'VET FEE-HELP eligible' for them to appear, these are:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Citizenship status - select an option from the drop down box</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Tax file number - record the number provided by the student which they have
                    obtained from the ATO</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/vet_fee_help_contact.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>VET FEE-HELP fields in a Contact record</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Student VET FEE-HELP Loan requests</title>
        <para>Every enrolment record has a VET FEE-HELP tab that is used to record the VET FEE-HELP
            loan request, or report that the student doesn't wish to apply for a loan. </para>
        <para>The fee charged field will show the enrolment fee the student was charged. This data
            is tied to the invoices generated is not editable in their enrolment record.</para>
        <para>In the FEE HELP requested field, you can indicate that the student doesn't wish to
            apply for a loan by leaving the default value as $0.00 or enter an amount up to the full
            class fee.</para>
        <para>The loan fee will be calculated based on the value you have set in the Fee Subsidy
            drop down box. Non-state government subsidised courses will incur a 20% loan fee that
            you'll see added to the Total Loan amount. Subsidised courses incur no loan fee.</para>
        <para>Beyond this required data, you can optionally complete the fields in the section
            headed 'Credit and RPL'. Leave the fields blank that do not apply this student's
            enrolment.</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit offered value - This field contains EFTSL value of the credit/RPL
                    offered at the reporting date towards the total requirements of the course and
                    can contain values from 0001 to 9999.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit used value - This field should report the sum total value of all
                    credit/RPL used by a student toward their current course, at the reporting date.
                    The value reported in this element must be less than or equal to the value
                    reported in the 'Credit offered value' and can contain values from 0001 to
                    9999.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>RPL Indicator - select from the drop down list</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit Field of Education ID - A code that records details of the field of
                    education of the VET study for which credit/RPL was offered. Valid codes are in
                    the range 0100 - 1299​ and can be found on the <link xlink:href="http://heimshelp.education.gov.au/sites/heimshelp/resources/pages/appendices">Heims Help website</link></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit offered provider code - A code indicating the Higher Education Provider
                    where the studies for which the credit/RPL was offered were undertaken. Valid
                    codes are in the range of 1000 to 6000 and can be found on the <link xlink:href="http://heimshelp.education.gov.au/sites/heimshelp/resources/pages/appendices">Heims Help website</link> </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit type - select from the drop down list</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit provider type - select from the drop down list</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Credit level - select from the drop down list</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/vet_fee_help_enrolment.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>VET FEE-HELP tab in a Enrolment record</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
<section>
    <title>Exporting VET FEE-HELP data</title>
        <para>To perform a VET FEE HELP export open the class list window. Once you have this open,
            highlight one or more classes, click on the cogwheel and choose the option VET FEE HELP
            export.</para>
        <para>This will create a number of text files in your computer's user directory. These files
            are designed to be uploaded into HEPCAT, and are not supposed to be human readable in
            this format.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/vet_fee_help_export.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Performing a VET FEE-HELP export</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>The file names have a default structure you will need to edit prior to HEPCAT import.
            The year code after the file acronym will be the current year by default e.g.
            0000VCC2015.100001 may need to be changed to  0000VCC2014.100001 if you are reporting
            data for a previous calendar year. </para>
        <para>The final part of the name code after the full stop is the reporting period (first
            character) and submission number (numeric; 00001 to 99999). All exports will have the
            value 100001 in this part of the name, you may need to adjust before import.</para>
    <para>More information on file naming conventions is available in the <link xlink:href="http://heimshelp.education.gov.au/sites/heimshelp/resources/toolkits/pages/reporting-with-hepcat">Reporting with HEPCAT toolkit</link> </para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                fileref="images/vet_fee_help_export_files.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>Default export file names that need to be modified</para>
        </caption>
    </mediaobject>
        <para>You will need HEPCAT installed on your computer to upload the files.</para>
        <para>HEPCAT will validate the data you have exported from onCourse. You can return to
            onCourse to correct any validation errors and export the data again, or fix the errors
            directly inside the HEPCAT software.</para>
        <para>Once your data has been validated, you will be able to export it from HEPCAT to the
            Higher Education Information Management System (<link
                xlink:href="http://heimshelp.education.gov.au/sites/heimshelp/resources/glossary/pages/glossaryterm?title=Higher%20Education%20Information%20Management%20System%20%28HEIMS%29"
                >HEIMS</link>) and receive your student enrolment fee payments.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/hepcat.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where the export files get lodged and validated</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>   
    </section>
</chapter>
