<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="fundingContract">
	<title>Funding Contracts</title>
	<section xml:id="fundingContracts-whatIs">
		<title>What are Funding Contracts?</title>
		<para>Funding Contract allow you to connect additional funding to an enrolment. Whether this
			be from a state funding source or private agreement, funding contact allows you to
			create a default payer and payment that will be used to fund all or part of an
			enrolment. </para>
		<para>Funding course encompasses state funding sources link Smart and Skilled or CSO, but
			also provides for you to set up custom funding contract and link them to payers and
			enrolments. The funding contract can also be linked to the AVEMTISS Reporting type
			required for that contract. </para>
		<para>onCourse has created default template for the State based funding contract, and integrated
			them with your reporting and online enrolment process using the Data Collection
			features. On higher level subscriptions, you are able to create custom funding contacts
			for any source of funding that supports the student enrolment, such as grants,
			department co-payment or even private contracts with large organisation. </para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="DefaultFundingContracts">
		<title>Default Funding Contracts</title>
		<para>onCourse has created default template for the State based funding contract, and integrated
			them with your reporting and online enrolment process using the Data Collection
			features. All subscribers have access to the make the default funding contacts active.
			Default funding contracts are available for the major state funding sources.</para>
			<section xml:id="fundingContracts-enable">
				<title> Funding Contacts and AVETMISS exporting</title>
				<para>Many Funding Sources have their own reporting requirements, and for State
					Training Authorities, this is often a modified version of the AVEMTISS standard. </para>
				<para>AVETMISS reporting is discussed in detail in our <xref linkend="AVETMISS"/>
					chapter. </para>
				<para>State funding contracts often have their own reporting requirements. More
					detailed information on the lodgements for each default contract are outlined
					here:</para>
				<para>
					<link xlink:href="http://www.training.nsw.gov.au/smartandskilled/index.html">New
						South Wales Smart and Skilled (2015 onwards)</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link
						xlink:href="https://www.training.nsw.gov.au/training_providers/training_market/doing_business/index.html"
						>New South Wales Approved Providers List (APL) for 2014 and prior
						data</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link
						xlink:href="http://www.training.qld.gov.au/training-organisations/detconnect/index.html"
						>Queensland DETConnect</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link
						xlink:href="http://www.education.vic.gov.au/training/providers/rto/Pages/datacollection.aspx"
						>Skills Victoria</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link
						xlink:href="http://www.dtwd.wa.gov.au/dtwcorporateinfo/wavetenrolementdatastandard/Pages/default.aspx"
						>Western Australia Department of Training and Workforce Development
						(DTWD)</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link
						xlink:href="http://www.skills.sa.gov.au/for-training-providers/about-workready-contracts/contracting-under-workready"
						>South Australia Department of State Development</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link xlink:href="http://www.skills.tas.gov.au/providers/rtos">Skills
						Tasmania</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link xlink:href="http://www.det.act.gov.au/training/vet_admin">Australia
						Capital Territory AVETARS</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link xlink:href="http://www.education.nt.gov.au/rto">Northern Territory
						DET</link>
				</para>
				<para>
					<link
						xlink:href="http://www.ncver.edu.au/wps/portal/vetdataportal/ncversupport/supportsubsupport/NCVER-Standard-Support"
						>National Competency Completion Online System (CCOS)</link>
				</para>
			</section>
		<section>
			<title>Funding Contact List View</title>
			<para>To view the funding contact list view, got to the top menu
					<guimenuitem>Training</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>Funding Contact</guimenuitem>. Active Contracts are in black and
				inactive contracts are greyed out.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractListView.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Funding Contract List View</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Activating a default funding contract</title>
			<para>To activate a default funding contact, open the funding contact list view
				and then double click on the funding contact you wish to activate . Tick the
				box 'Active' to active the contact and then save. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractActive.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Default Funding Contract for STSOnline (NSW) Funding Contracts
						Smart and Skilled Funding made active</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding the default Funding Contact to a class</title>
			<para>Once a Funding Contact is active, you can add it as a default funding type to the
				class. If you add the funding contact at the class all enrolment in the class will
				have the funding contract added when they enrol. </para>
			<para>The Funding contact drop down on the class will only let you select active
				contracts. </para>
			<para>If you duplicate the class the funding contract will not be duplicated, you will
				need to update it after the new class is created.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractAddtoClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding a Funding Contract as the default on the Class VET tab</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/courses.html"
					>More instructions on how to create a course</link>
			</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/classes.html"
					>More instruction on how to create classes</link>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding or Editing the Funding Contact on an Enrolment</title>
			<para>Once a Funding Contact is active, you can add or edit it on the General Tab of the
				enrolment. </para>
			<para>The Funding contact drop down on the class will only let you select active
				contracts. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractAddtoEnrolment.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding or editing the funding Contract at the Enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				<link
					xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/processingEnrolments.html"
					>More instruction on how to enrol students</link>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Custom Funding Contracts</title>
		<para>If your subscription allows for you to make a custom funding contract, you can create them
			in the funding contact list view. </para>
		<para>You many use this feature to create different contracts for specific program types or
			funding stream in a state funding or for additional funding sources outside the normal
			state contracts, such as grants or commercial agreements.</para>
		<para>To create a new contract, <guimenuitem>Training</guimenuitem>
			<guimenuitem>Funding Contact</guimenuitem> to open the list view. Click on the "+"
			button to add a new contract. </para>
		<para>You will need to name the funding contract appropriately. It's a good idea to include
			the type or funding or source.</para>
		<para>If there is a reporting requirement you can select the AVETMISS Flavour appropriate to
			the funding time. If there is not specific flavour you should select NCVER (AVETMISS
			Standard) as the AVETMISS Flavour.</para>
		<para>You will have the option to link the funding contract to a payer. If there no payer
			you can leave this blank.</para>
		<para>Click save to complete the new contract.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/fundingContract_Custom_Contract.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Custom Funding Contract Record </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
</chapter>
