<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="generalPrefs">
	<title>General Preferences</title>
	<para>When you begin onCourse with a new database the setup process should commence with you setting your general preferences.</para>
	<tip>
		<para>You can save your changes as you work through the preferences tabs by clicking
			<guibutton>save</guibutton> This will also close the window, but you can open it again from
			File > Preferences > General </para>
	</tip>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-Terms">
		<title>General Preferences Terms and Definitions</title>
		<para> The Preferences screen is where you set up the basic administration functions of onCourse.
			Starting here provides the initial set up for onCourse. Any changes made to any
			parameters on this screen need to be saved by hitting the 'Save' button in the top right
			or the window. </para>
		<para>Click on the (?) in the window header to open the onCourse manual, or to view the
			audit trail. The audit trail allows you to view a record of  changes to records in your
			system at any one time.</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>College</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The college preferences allows you to input your organisations name, ABN and website URL.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Licences</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The licences preferences are an important part as it displays what kind of
						features your organisation have available (depending on which support plan
						you have)</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Messaging</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The messaging preferences allows you to set preferences for mail.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Class Defaults</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>These preferences allow you to set the defaults for minimum and maximum number of places,
						the delivery mode and funding source of a Class. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>LDAP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Stands for Light Directory Access Protocol and allows users to be authenticated by either
						LDAP or AD (Active Directory). If you don't know what this is, then you definitely don't
						need it.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Maintenance</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The maintenance preferences allows you to set backup preferences and change whether you
						would like automatic logout on or not. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>AVETMISS</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Stands for the Australian Vocational Education and Training Management Information
						Statistical Standard which is the national reporting standard for Australian Registered
						Training Organisations, it is essential that these fields are all filled out fully and
						correctly as it is a major part of AVETMISS reporting.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Financial</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The Financial preferences is where you set such things as what currency and local tax
						that is being used, amongst what default accounts to use.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Holidays</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>These preferences allow you to add Holidays (unavailabilities) for your whole business timetable and scheduling availability.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Payment types</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The payment types preferences allows you to define what payment methods you want to
						use.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Tax types</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The Tax types preferences allows you to define the Tax options you can use.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Concession types</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This is where you can define what concession types your students are able
						to use.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Contact relation types</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The contact relation types preferences allows you to define what relationships you want
						to be able to link contacts together with.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Custom fields</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This is where you can add any new custom fields you want to appear in contacts records,
						along with the option to add them to the online Enrolment, Waiting List and
						Mailing List questions.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-setting">
		<title>Setting your General Preferences</title>
		<para>To access the Preferences window in onCourse go to
				<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guisubmenu>Preferences</guisubmenu><guisubmenu>General...</guisubmenu>.</para>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-college">
			<title>College</title>
		<para>Once your in the Preferences window then click on the College option to see the College
				preferences.</para>
		<tip>
			<para>Entry fields coloured pink are the only places that need information entered in order to
				activate onCourse. Fields coloured white do not require any data to be entered, they are
				optional and the onCourse system will run smoothly if they are not filled in. The pink
				coloured box will change to white once you have entered your information correctly and
				pressed enter. If the box does not change to white then you will need to review your
				information and try entering again.</para>
		</tip>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>On the Services tab, Enter the <guilabel>College Name </guilabel>e.g. Rosewood College
					This is a required field and you will not be able to proceed with the set up process
					without first entering a college name.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>To the right enter the <guilabel>ABN</guilabel> e.g 18 123 456 789</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Now enter the <guilabel>College Website URL</guilabel> e.g. rosewoodcollege.com.au
				</para>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The default server timezone will be set to Sydney Australia. If you are in
						another timezone, please set it accordingly. This will effect when your
						automated scripts will run, as the cron time set for various scripts are referencing your server
						time zone.</para>
				</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
				<para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/college_tab.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The "College" preferences</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="generalPrefs-licences">
				<title>Licences</title>
				<para>The licences preferences tab shows you what features are enabled and inactive. You need to
				purchase an onCourse support contract to enable these additional features. onCourse
				is still fully functional as an enrolment system without these services. If you have
				purchased an onCourse support agreement we will enable the services for your
				plan.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/licences_tab.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "Licences" preferences</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-merchantId">
			<title>Linking your credit card merchant ID</title>
			<para>In order to use the onCourse integrated credit card gateway you need to contact ish with
				your merchant details from your bank. ish will be able to then link your account to
				onCourse and provide a quick way to take payments both in the office and your
				onCourse powered website.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Visit this page <link
								xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/oncourse/documentation/administrator-guide/internet-merchant-number-guide"
								>here</link> to learn how to request your merchant/terminal ID from
							your bank to allow internet payments and see specific banking details
							for different Australian banks.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Contact ish on 02 9550 5501 or email sales@ish.com.au if you have any further questions
							or need assistance with this process.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-messaging">
		<title>Messaging</title>
		<para>onCourse makes it easy to send emails and SMS to the students and teachers that are listed
			on your contacts list. In order to do this you first need to configure the email settings. </para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>It is important to configure an outbound mail server in order for email from onCourse to
					be delivered. This includes enrolment confirmations, invoices and other outbound
					messages. Enter the host name or IP address of the mail server in
						<guilabel>Outgoing Mail Server Address SMTP</guilabel>. Optionally you can
					add authentication settings if your mail server requires it.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the <guilabel>Email from address</guilabel> enter the address from which you want
						contacts to see that emails are sent from. i.e..
						info@rosewoodcollege.com.au</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <guilabel>System Administrator Email Address</guilabel> is the address that
					undeliverable mail and bounces will go to (if you don't use VERP). You will need a valid
					email account that will be accepted by that mail server. You should contact your mail
					administrator to verify that these details are correct. </para>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>Underneath is the <guilabel>emails queued</guilabel> notification. This field will notify
						you of how many emails are in the queue waiting to be sent. Say you are
						sending out a bulk email to prospective students to remind them of the start
						date of the new term, the number in this field will tell you how many emails
						have yet to be sent, i.e.. how many remain in the queue. Emails that are
						unable to be sent due to mail configuration errors will stay in the mail
						queue rather than be marked as failed on the sending attempt. You can not
						enter any data into this field.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<section>
			<title>Handing bounced emails (VERP)</title>
			<para>VERP - Variable Envelope Return Paths is a feature which automatically handles bounced
				emails from onCourse. When this is enabled, emails are sent out with a special From address
				that looks like "bounces+124673@rosewoodcollege.com.au". The Reply-To address is set
				normally with the standard from address you have defined in "Email from address", so a user
				can reply without any problems. The number after the plus sign is used to identify the
				Contact in onCourse to whom this email was originally sent: this is important because emails
				could be forwarded several times in remote mail systems and the bounce may not come from the
				address you expect.</para>
			<para>This "plus addressing" notation is a standard internet protocol and most mail servers
					support it. You simply define the base email account (e.g.
					"bounces@rosewoodcollege.com.au") and the mail server will ignore the part after
					the plus. </para>
			
			
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you wish to activate this function then tick the option, <guilabel>detect and process
						bounced emails</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>incoming mail server address (POP3)</guilabel> then enter the
								<guilabel>email address to where the bounced emails are
								sent</guilabel> e.g. bounces@rosewoodcollege.com.au. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>account name</guilabel> followed by the <guilabel>account
						password</guilabel>. This will be used to retrieve mail from that account by
						POP.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/messaging_tab.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Messaging" preferences</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para> The SMS box enables you to send texts. You may want to text students a reminder for the
					new term start date or for a change of venue or contact tutors about their hours
					or pay. You can send bulk texts direct from the onCourse program. What you enter
					into the <guilabel>SMS from</guilabel> field is what the receivers of your SMS
					messages will see as the sender details. Put in a mobile number for people to
					reply to or, if you do not have an inbound SMS number, you can put the name of
					your organisation. (e.g. 'Rosewood') <caution>
						<para>Only use a mobile number in this field if you have an inbound mobile
							account intended for this purpose. If you use the name of your business
							it will be clear to the receiver of your SMS who the message came from,
							but they will be unable to press 'reply' on their mobile phone to send
							you a response.</para>
					</caution></para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-classdefaults">
		<title>Class Defaults</title>	
		<para>The Class Defaults tab allows the user to set the defaults for minimum and maximum places in
			a given Class, as well as the delivery mode and funding source.</para>
		<para>Note that these defaults can be manually overridden at the individual Class level.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/class_defaults_tab.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-ldap">
		<title>LDAP </title>
		<para>LDAP - stands for Light Directory Access Protocol and allows users to be authenticated by
				either LDAP or AD (Active Directory), tying your onCourse user accounts and log ins
				to the account and logins your staff use to access other IT resources on your
				network. This is a feature that is enabled as part of a purchased onCourse support
				plan. Contact us if you need help on setting this up. <mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/LDAP_tab.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "LDAP" preferences</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject></para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-maintenance">
		<title>Maintenance</title>
		<para>The maintenance screen controls how often and where your data is backed up. This feature is
			recommended for users who are not connecting onCourse to an external server such as MySQL or
			SQL Server, as these external servers have their own daily scheduled backup routines. </para>
		<para>With the amount of information you will eventually have stored on your onCourse program,
			the backing up of this data is essential. onCourse is designed to enable you to schedule when
			and where the back ups take place. You can also set onCourse to have an automatic logout. This
			means that if onCourse is left open on the computer but no one is using it, after a specified
			amount of time it will automatically logout and save any recently entered data. </para>
		<para>Prior to setting up your backup schedule, you need to determine which folder location you
			are going to save these backup files to. It is important to ensure that you save the backups
			on a different drive to the one where you have installed your onCourse server, that way if
			your hardware / drives do fail, your backup files are safe. You also need to ensure that you
			create the folders that you have specified in the file path, otherwise the backup files that
			are created will not be able to be found. </para>
		<caution>
			<para>Running an onCourse back up to a location on your server is not the only step you need
				to take to secure your data. You should also make sure that the backup file is saved to an
				offsite location on a regular basis in case of hardware of other physical failure of your
				computer.</para>
		</caution>
		<para>An example file extension for a Mac could be as follows:</para>
		<para>/Users/Shared/</para>
		<para>[Note: the Mac file path uses the Unix system of a forward slash to separate directory and
				file components and make sure you have a forward slash at the front of the file
				path].</para>
		<para>An example file extension for Windows could be as follows:</para>
		<para>C:\onCourse\backups\</para>
		<para>[Note: the Windows backup directory uses a back slash to separate directory and file
			components. It is also recommended that you do not save your backups to your Program File
			folder within Windows as this is not designed for data files].</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<para>The process for setting up your maintenance preferences is the same for both Mac and
				Windows users, follow these instructions to set up onCourse to backup your important
				data:</para>
			<listitem>
				<para>Navigate to File > Preferences > General > Maintenance tab </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automatic Logout: This field is mandatory and allows no more than 360 minutes (6 hours).
						Place an amount of minutes e.g.; 15 to set the amount of time onCourse can
						be left idle before it shuts itself down and saves all recently made changes
						and additions.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Server backup directory: type the Windows or Mac path to the folder you wish to backup to
					as per the examples above.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Backup time: choose the time you want to run a backup. We recommend a time when the least
					amount of network traffic is occurring but with enough time to complete the backup before
					the next work day starts. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Maximum backups kept: choose how many backups you want to keep before deleting the oldest
					ones. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Next backup number: this is appended to the name of the backup file and is automatically
						incremented on each backup. For example, onCourseBackup_00001.zip </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click "Save". Note that changes to the backup schedule may not take effect until you
					restart onCourse server.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/maintenance_tab.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The "Maintenance" preferences</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-avetmiss">
		<title>AVETMISS</title>
		<para>The AVETMISS screen is where you record your organisation's details that will be used for
			all AVETMISS report lodgements. If you are not an RTO you can uncheck <guilabel>Show RTO
				related screens and menus</guilabel> to hide windows in onCourse that aren't
			relevant to your organisation. You should still enter your organisation address and
			contact details in this window, even if you aren't an RTO as onCourse uses them to
			populate data in templated email messages.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter your legal <guilabel>training organisation name</guilabel> and from the drop down
					menu <guilabel>type</guilabel>select by the type of training organisation. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the <guilabel>Identifier</guilabel> field enter your NTIS RTO id in the
					field.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter your organisations <guilabel>Address</guilabel>, <guilabel>Suburb</guilabel>,
					<guilabel>State</guilabel> and <guilabel>postcode</guilabel> in the appropriate
					fields.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Optional contact details: Here you have the option to enter a <guilabel>contact
						name</guilabel>, a <guilabel>fax</guilabel> number, <guilabel>email
							address</guilabel>, <guilabel>telephone number</guilabel>, <guilabel>Full certificate signatory name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Queensland RTO id</guilabel>.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<note><para>The Queensland RTO id is a code that all Queensland RTOs have to use when reporting their
				AVETMISS data, this is different from their training.gov RTO code.</para></note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_tab.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The "AVETMISS" preferences</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also choose to limit your staff to creating courses only from pre-approved units
				and qualifications that you mark within onCourse as 'offered'. This assists you in
				ensuring your AQTF requirements of only delivering current approved courses on your
				scope. To use this feature, first flag those you are approved to deliver in the
				qualifications and module/units table, then come back to this window and check
				<guilabel>Show only 'offered' qualifications and modules</guilabel>. We do not
				recommend checking this option as part of your initial setup as it will lock you out
				of all the embedded units. </para>
		<para>If later, after building your courses and setting the units and qualifications on your
			scope as 'offered', you choose to come back here and select this option. This means for
			future courses created, the user will only be able to select from the units you have
			already marked 'as offered' during the course building process. You will need to restart
			your onCourse server for this change to take effect.</para>
		<para>You can still make changes to any individual student's enrolment outcomes to add any
			unit from training.gov.au, even if you have this preference selected. You may need to
			access units not on your scope during a credit transfer process.</para>
		
		<para>On this tab you can also set the signatory name and post-nominals. This name will print on
			the signature line for all onCourse certificate reports. If you leave it blank, the word
			'Principal' will print.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-financial">
			<title>Financial</title>
			<para>Navigate here by clicking on 'File' -> 'Preferences' -> 'General' from the top
				menu, then click on the Financial option.</para>
			<para>Select the currency you wish to use and any local tax (e.g. GST) which may apply.</para>
			<para>Default accounts have been selected. Make any changes necessary or edit the
				accounts to add or disable options.</para>
			<para>If your college usually takes payment at the time of enrolment, then we
				suggest you leave the option 'Quick enrol payments default to $0' unchecked. If
				you usually invoice clients for payment, then select this option so you do not
				always have to override Quick Enrol.</para>
			<para>You can also set up your default for your nominated Pre Paid Fees account, as
				well as determining whether the deferred income is transferred from your Pre
				Paid Fees Liability Account to your Income Account evenly across all Sessions of
				the Class. Or alternatively you can nominate to transfer all funds across after
				the completion of the first session of the Class. Refer to the chapter on <link
					xlink:href="accounting.html">Accounting</link> for more information about
				deferred income.</para>
			<para>There is also a field at the top on the Financial preferences called 'Invoice remittance
				instructions' that allow you to define what instructions you want to provide to the
				payer on the bottom left side of a Tax Invoice report using the code
				$F{pref.college.paymentInfo}.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/FinancialPreferences.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Financial" Preferences</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-holidays">
		<title>Holidays</title>
			<para>The holidays preferences tab is where you would add information about your
				business holidays. To add a new holiday simply click on the 'Add new holiday'
				button. </para>
			<para>This feature is used to notify onCourse users when trying to schedule a class on a
				day/s that the business is closed. Below is an example of what the warning will look
				like.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/holiday_error_message.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
			<para>Every holiday has the following preferences:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Holiday Description - here is where you can name what you want the holiday is called when
						appearing in error messages.</para>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>All day - this checkbox allows you to choose whether the holiday created is an all day
						event.</para>
				</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Start - the date the holiday starts.</para>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>End - the date the holiday ends.</para>
				</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Repeat every - how often this holiday is repeated. The options you have here are: </para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>hour</para>
					</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>day</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>week</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>month</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>year</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>None</para>
						</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>End repeat - as long as you don't select 'None' in the 'Repeat every' dropdown box this
						dropdown option will appear. This option allows you to choose how many times
						the holiday is repeated before it stops. The options you have here are: </para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Never</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>After</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>On date</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>On date - this date field will only appear if you choose the option 'On date' in the 'End
						repeat' dropdown box. This option allows you to choose the date the holiday
						expires.</para>
				</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/holidays_tab.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The "Holidays" Preferences</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-paymentTypes">
			<title>Payment Types</title>
			<para>Navigate here by clicking on 'File' -> 'Preferences' -> 'General' from the top
				menu, then click on the Payment types option.</para>
			<para>You can create a new payment method by clicking on the 'Add new payment type' button at the
				bottom of the window. In this window there are several areas you have to define,
				these are:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Name - this is what you want to call the payment method</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Undeposited Funds Account - this is the account that any unbanked payments
						of this method are deposited into</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Account - you can select which bank account the funds are deposited to on
						banking. By default, all payment methods are deposited into a single bank
						account, known as the deposited funds account.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Type - There are two types which have special meaning in onCourse -
						Credit card and Cheque, because additional information is collected at
						the time of payment in additional fields. All other payment methods
						should be of type Other.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Active - this is whether you want the payment method to be active and
						used. You can mark payment types you do not accept e.g. cheque as
						inactive.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Banked Automatically - whether the money is banked into your chosen
						account automatically on receipt, such as credit cards and EFTPOS
						transactions, or needs to be manually banked as a part of a banking
						process</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Reconcilable - this is if this payment method should create records to
						reconcile</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/PaymentTypesPreferences.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Payment types" Preferences</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Some of the payment methods can't be edited and when you try and do this all the fields
				will be greyed out, as seen below when you try and edit the payment method
				'Voucher'. The reason you can't edit them is because they are internal payment
				methods with special meaning in onCourse and can't be changed. You will also see
				that if you try and edit the payment method 'Credit card' you can't change the
				'Type' because this always has to be set as "Credit card'.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/voucher_edit.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Voucher</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-taxTypes">
		<title>Tax Types</title>
		<para>Navigate here by clicking on 'File' -> 'Preferences' -> 'General' from the top menu, then
				click on the Tax types option.</para>
		<para>You can create a new Tax Types by clicking on the 'Add new tax type' button at the bottom of
				the window. In this window there are several areas you have to define, these
				are:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Tax code - this is what you see when trying to assign this tax type to a class, product,
						etc.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Rate - this is the percentage that this tax type adds.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>GST - tick this checkbox if this tax type includes GST.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Default - tick this checkbox to make this tax type the default.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Payable account - this is the account where the money gets paid to.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Receivable account - this is the account where the money gets received.</para>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Description - this describes what the tax type is.</para>
				</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/PaymentTaxPreferences.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The "Tax types" Preferences</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-concessionTypes">
			<title>Concession Types</title>
			<para>Navigate here by clicking on 'File' -> 'Preferences' -> 'General' from the top
				menu, then click on the Concession Types option.</para>
				<para>Some concession types may be available for your students to add to their own record
					during the online enrolment process, for example a Senior's Card. Other types you may
					want to restrict to only allowing the concession to be added to the student record via
					the onCourse client, for example College Staff. </para>
				<para>If you require an expiry date on the concession type, any discounts that apply to that
					concession type will not be available if the student's concession is expired.</para>
				<para>You may also choose to make entering a card number mandatory. Please note onCourse is
					not able to validate the authenticity of card numbers due. This is an open test field
					(string type) and will accept letters and numbers. This field is useful for ensuring
					that only card holders self identify - you can use this data to conduct random spot
					checks if required.</para>
				<para>Note that when you allow concessions to be added on the website, users must confirm
					they hold a current and valid concession. As we can not perform validation against so
					many external systems, the application for concession online is an honor system. Over
					the years, our customers have reported very low abuse of this method, as in the
					education market clients generally attend classes face to face. Well written enrolment
					policies ensure that if a client can not present in person the concession type they have
					claimed, then they will be billed for the full course fee.</para>
				<example>
					<title>How to create a concession type</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Go to File -> Preferences -> General -> Concession types</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Click the add button ( Add new concession type)</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Name your concession type. This name that the students or admin staff will
								use to identify this concession type when adding it to a student record.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Choose if you want it to be available for self selection on the web. If
								you select this option, students can add this concession type to their
								record either during enrolment or via their student portal. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> Select if it the concession requires a number or an expiry date. This
								makes supplying this information mandatory to save the concession record
								against the student's file.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<para>Once you have created the concession type, go to <link xlink:href="discounts.html"
						>discounts</link> to define who can use it and how it can be used.</para>
				</example>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/ConcessionTypesPreferences.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Concession types" Preferences</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-contactRelationTypes">
			<title>Contact Relation Types</title>
			<para>You can define how you relate contacts to each other via contact relation types.
				Some types are already defined by default, but you can edit or delete them as
				needed.</para>
			<para>A special, non-editable relationship for 'Parent or Guardian' and 'Child' is used
				to collect the emergency contact details for minors enrolling via the web. </para>
			<para>A relationship has two sides i.e. parent and child. Some times both sides will
				have the same name e.g. partner and partner. Relationships can be used to link
				contacts together for payment and enrolment purposes e.g. when an employer pays for
				their staff member, and also for marketing e.g. to define the HR Managers at
				companies you deliver training to, so you can promote up coming courses.</para>
			<para>For each type of relationship you define you have the option of allowing the first
				type of contact to access the training record of the secondary type of contact via
				the SkillsOnCourse portal. </para>
			<para>To add or edit relationships, go to File -> Preferences -> General -> Contact Relationship
				Types and click on the button 'Add new contact relation type'.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/ContactRelationTypesPreferences.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Contact relation types" Preferences</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-customFields">
			<title>Custom Field Types</title>
			<para>Navigate here by going to the menu File > Preferences >  General. Click on the Custom
				fields option in the left hand panel. To add a new custom field click on the 'Add
				new custom field' button.</para>
			<para>Custom fields are available for the following record types: Contact, Course, Enrolment,
				Application, Waiting List and Survey. You can rearrange how the custom fields you
				create are ordered on this page by clicking on the grouped dots icon to the left of
				a custom field, then dragging it up or down to change the order.</para>
			<para>Before you add a custom field to the database, consider how and when it will be
				used and which would be the best record type (entity) to link the custom field
				to.</para>
			<para>For example, information you would only ask the student once that will stay near to the
				same over time belongs in the contact record, like the person's Driver's Licence, or
				alternate email address. Information that is specific to a particular enrolment or
				application process belongs in those records, for example, meal selection for a
				conference or application data collected for approval for a funded program.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/CustomFieldsPreferences.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Custom fields" Preferences</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>All custom fields are searchable. This allows you to create fields for, and record
				information, that is particular to your business. Custom fields can be made
				mandatory, but that means every contact in your database needs to complete the field
				before the record can be saved. Often the better choice is to make the completion
				mandatory on the form or forms where it applies. You can add as many additional
				fields as you need to, and they will display in the records in the order they have
				been added. </para>
			<para>Each custom field has a key which is the code that is used to reference the custom field in
				exports and reports. For example, the custom field in the image below with key
				'howDidYouHearAboutUs' can be referenced as a field in email template as </para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">Thanks for letting us know that ${contact.howDidYouHearAboutUs} was how you heard about us!</programlisting>
			<para>The same custom field can easily be added to exports using it's key also:</para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">"How Did You Hear About Us?"  :  contact.howDidYouHearAboutUs?.value</programlisting>
			<para>Custom fields can be free text fields, have a list of pre-defined choices in a
				drop down list or have a single set default values. If you want to set a list of
				predefined choices, separate each item in the list with a semicolon. If you want to
				include a free choice option at the end of your list, make the final option a star
				character. e.g. Radio; TV; Internet; *</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/NewCustomField.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a new custom field </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If you include an asterisk (*) in the list as per the example above, then your users will
				also have the option to type in free text as a response by clicking on the option
				'Other', as shown below. You can also log into your onCourse CMS to make these
				custom fields, show or be a mandatory question as part of the online enrolment,
				waitlist or mailing list process.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/CFDropDownOptions.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Clicking on the custom field drop down options in the contact record</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/CustomField OtherOption.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>What happens when you select the asterisk option in a custom field drop down</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Custom fields added to contact records will appear on the bottom of the 'general' tab in
				each contacts record. Custom fields added to enrolments, applications, waiting lists
				or courses will appear on the custom field tab of that record. Custom fields added
				to surveys will appear under Student Feedback</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/waitlistCustomField.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Custom field on a wait list</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<note><para>Any custom fields created will be added to the list of questions that can be added to the
					online enrolment process, waiting list and student feedback surveys. More
					information about this can be found<link
						xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/web/configurations.html#d5e1541"
						>here.</link></para></note>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
