<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="importExport"><title>Importing and exporting</title><para>onCourse offers
		you a variety of ways to get data into and out of the system. The onCourse DSL (Domain
		Specific Language) that outlines the database objects and enumerations is available at <link
			xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/doc/latest/dsl/"/> </para>
	<para>This chapter is recommended for Intermediate to Advanced users of onCourse who have a good
		general understanding of structured data and the onCourse schema.</para>
	<section xml:id="importExport-Export">
		<title>Exporting data</title>
		<section>
			<title>onCourse Export files</title>
			<para>Go to File > Preferences > Export templates to see the list of export files available in
				your onCourse application. </para>
			<para> The list of exports available to you will include those supplied as part of the default
				onCourse application configuration and any additional custom exports you have
				created or have commissioned ish to create on your behalf.</para>
			<para>Generally, export files that end with CSV (comma separated files) are designed to be
				opened, viewed and edited in a plain text editor or spreadsheet application. These
				are flat files containing columns and rows of data. Export files that end with XML
				(eXtensible Markup Language) are designed to be imported into other software
				applications and represent a relational data structure.</para>
			<para>Each export displayed in this list has a Name, Entity, Code and Version Number. </para>
			<para>The Name is a descriptor of the export and usually includes information about the
				export format type. </para>
			<para>The Entity is the object in the database that the export is joined to, and will
				indicate which list view you will be able to find this export. </para>
			<para>The Code is a unique identifier for the export and when supplied by ish as part of the
				default onCourse application will begin with 'ish'. When the export is custom, is
				should begin with an identifying acronym for the organisation. The last part of the
				code defines the export file type, for example, CSV or XML.</para>
			<para>The Version number allows ish to automatically update the export, for example, to add
				additional fields as they are added to the database structure, when new versions of
				the onCourse application are deployed.</para>
			<para>You can double click on the export record in the list to see the structure of the
				export file, what fields are included and what formatting is applied. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/export_template_list.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>List view showing the exports available in onCourse</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Copying and pasting into a spreadsheet application</title>
			<para>In all onCourse list views, you can highlight a range of records to copy and paste
				into a spreadsheet application like Excel or Google sheets.</para>
			<para>Begin by selecting a range of records in a list view, then choose copy from the
				edit menu and paste the data into your spreadsheet application.</para>
			<para>The data you copy and then paste will come out in the same column layout and sort
				order as the window you copied it from.</para>
			<para>If you have opened a very large list of data, please note that it may take some
				time for this list to load into your onCourse client memory. This is a process that
				runs in the background of onCourse, and not something immediately visible to you as
				a user. If you try to copy and paste from a list before the load process has
				completed, the copy process will not be successful. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/export_copy_paste.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Export Icon being shown in the contacts list view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Exporting from the list view</title>
			<para>Like print reports, the list of available exports in the list view are those exports linked
				to the entity, or list view, you are viewing. In the example below the Contact
				window is open so the exports available are those linked to the Contact
				entity.</para>
			<para>Each list view in onCourse has the ability to export data in a variety of formats. You can
				either highlight the records you wish to export and choose File > Import/Export >
				Export (tablename)  or click on the Export (Share) Icon in the top right hand corner
				of the list view.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/export_icon.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Export Icon being shown in the contacts list view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>A dialog will appear giving you some choices:<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Export template:</emphasis> This list allows you to choose from
							one of the exports joined to this entity. There will usually be at least
							one CSV and one XML option to select from.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Based on:</para>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">Listed records:</emphasis> every record in the list you were
							just looking at. This is the result of whatever search you had just
							performed.</para>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">Highlighted records:</emphasis> only those records you had
							highlighted in the list. This is the quickest way to export a few
							selected records, particularly when you need to choose them by hand from
							your query results.</para>								
					</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			</para>
</section>
		<section>
			<title>Examples of default Exports and their uses</title>
			<example>
				<title>Exporting class information to create a print brochure</title>
				<para>Begin by opening the Classes window and running a query or otherwise selecting the range
					of classes you wish to export for the brochure.</para>
				<para>From the export options, select 'InDesign Brochure XML export' and save the resulting file
					to a location on your computer. This default layout includes the information
					from the course general tab 'Print brochure description' and combines it with
					the class summary information including location, cost, start date and time and
					tutor. The information is grouped by the Subject tag hierarchy.</para>
<para>The XML file is designed to be imported into a publishing product such as Adobe InDesign and
					then customised however you wish with the addition of styles and images. The XML
					tags in the onCourse export can be mapped to styles in InDesign, allowing the
					data to be imported and dropped into a brochure layout as many times as needed
					during the production cycle process. The XML file created by onCourse is not
					designed to be opened or edited in a product like Word - it is designed for
					import into a specialist layout and design software tools. If you do not have
					software that can work with these files installed on your machine, you should be
					able to email the file to your design staff for them to work with
					directly.</para>
			</example>
			<example>
				<title>Exporting from the Class - CSV data</title>
				<para>The Class list includes a number of CSV exports, some with specific purposes. The
					'CourseClass CSV export' is a generic export that includes most of the class
					fields. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/exports/class_export_options.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Available exports accessed via Class List</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Highlight the Class records you wish to export within the Class
								window.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Go to File > Import/Export > Export Classes or select the export icon in the top right
								hand corner of the list window</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You then have the following export options to select from the drop
								down menu: <itemizedlist>
									<listitem>
										<para><emphasis role="bold">CourseClass CSV
												export</emphasis> - standard export of Class
											information</para>
										<mediaobject>
											<imageobject>
												<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%"
												contentdepth="100%"
												fileref="images/exports/class_export_excel_output.png"
												format="png"/>
											</imageobject>
											<caption>
												<para>Excerpt of standard Class export viewed via
												excel</para>
											</caption>
										</mediaobject>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para><emphasis role="bold">Class Budget Summary CSV
												export</emphasis> - provides a Class per line
											summary of budgeted income and expenses against
											projected and actual costs.</para>
										<mediaobject>
											<imageobject>
												<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%"
												contentdepth="100%"
												fileref="images/exports/class_budget_summary_excel_output.png"
												format="png"/>
											</imageobject>
											<caption>
												<para>Excerpt of Class budget summary export viewed
												via excel</para>
											</caption>
										</mediaobject>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para><emphasis role="bold">Class Outcomes CSV
												export</emphasis> - Report for student outcome
											results for date range so Colleges can conduct their own
											reporting and easily identify students with outcomes
											that are not set.</para>
										<mediaobject>
											<imageobject>
												<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%"
												contentdepth="100%"
												fileref="images/exports/outcomes_export_excel_output.png"
												format="png"/>
											</imageobject>
											<caption>
												<para>Excerpt of student outcomes export viewed via
												excel </para>
											</caption>
										</mediaobject>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para><emphasis role="bold">Extended Outcomes CSV</emphasis>
											- A report to show data like the AVETMISS NAT00120, but
											in a human readable format</para>
										<mediaobject>
											<imageobject>
												<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%"
												contentdepth="100%"
												fileref="images/exports/extended_outcomes_export_csv.png"
												format="png"/>
											</imageobject>
											<caption>
												<para>Excerpt of extended outcomes export viewed via
												numbers </para>		
											</caption>
										</mediaobject>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para><emphasis role="bold">CourseClass Sessions
												CSV</emphasis> - Export for class session
											information including enrolments, room allocation, seats
											available and tutors assigned</para>
										<mediaobject>
											<imageobject>
												<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%"
												contentdepth="100%"
												fileref="images/exports/class_sessions_export_csv.png"
												format="png"/>
											</imageobject>
											<caption>
												<para>Excerpt of Class sessions export viewed via
												numbers</para>
											</caption>
										</mediaobject>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para><emphasis role="bold">Attendance
											CSV</emphasis> - Export for class session attendance showing who marked the roll (online or via the office) and when the attendance was last modified
											information </para>
										<mediaobject>
											<imageobject>
												<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%"
													contentdepth="100%"
													fileref="images/exports/attendance_export_csv.png"
													format="png"/>
											</imageobject>
											<caption>
												<para>Excerpt of Class attendance export viewed via Excel</para>
											</caption>
										</mediaobject>
									</listitem>
								</itemizedlist>
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</para>
			</example>
			<tip>
				<para>When exporting the above class exports, the resulting CSV output file will have the same
					name in all instances: it will be labelled as 'CourseClassExport.csv'. You can
					then re label these export files to whatever you need.</para>
			</tip>
			<example>
				<title>Exporting Invoice Information</title>
				<para>onCourse enables users to export not only the invoice information, with each
					invoice reflected as one line within the resulting output file, you can also
					export the invoice line detail.</para>
				<para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Highlight the invoice records you wish to export information for from within the
								Invoice window.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Go to File > Import/Export > Export Invoices/Credit notes or
								select the export icon in the top right hand corner of the list
								window</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You can then export either the invoices as a standard Invoice CSV
								(one line per invoice) or alternatively you can export the invoice
								line detail.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</para>
				<para>The following excerpts of the exported information as shown within excel,
					provides a comparison between the kind of information that each export generates
					within the resulting output file. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/invoice_export_excel_excerpt.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Excerpt of invoice export viewed via excel</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/invoice_line_export_excel_excerpt.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Excerpt of invoice line export viewed via excel</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</example>
			<tip>
				<para>When exporting the above two invoice exports, the resulting CSV output file
					will have the same name in all instances, it will be labelled as
					'InvoiceExport.csv'. You can then re label these export files to whatever you
					need.</para>
			</tip>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section><title>Customising export templates</title>
<para>There are a range of options for creating custom exports in onCourse. What you choose depends
			on your familiarity with database structures, queries and the Groovy language.</para><orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Copy an existing export to make a new export file, and then make changes to the
					copy</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create a new export from scratch</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create a standalone export that is run manually, or an export that is
					triggered by a script to pass it certain pre-defined parameters</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Engage ish or Groovy developer of your choice to create a custom export for
					your business</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist><para>onCourse exports are powered by a groovy based scripting language. These scripts run on the
			server and call the same groovy DSL that you'll find in the scripting chapter and
			available here: <link xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/doc/latest/dsl/"/>.
			You can use the full power and expression of the groovy language, and have access the
			entire onCourse schema. In short, you access the data to export from the variable
			"records" and just return from the script the formatted text to export. </para> <para>There is a built in a CSV toolkit, so exporting to CSV is the most simple export type to
			create or edit without a great deal of prior experience. By default the delimited is a
			comma, but you can define a different delimiter like a tab as per the example below: </para>
			<programlisting language="groovy"><![CDATA[
csv.delimiter = '\t'

records.each { AccountTransaction t ->
	csv << [
			"Date"          : t.transactionDate?.format("D/M/Y"),
			"Memo"          : t.transactionDescription,
			"Account Number": t.account.accountCode,
			"Debit Amount"  : t.amount.compareTo(Money.ZERO) > 1 ? t.amount.toPlainString() : Money.ZERO.toPlainString(),
			"Credit Amount" : t.amount.compareTo(Money.ZERO) > 1 ? Money.ZERO.toPlainString() : t.amount.toPlainString()
	]
}
]]></programlisting>
		<section>
			<title>Creating a new export in onCourse</title>
			<para>The simplest way to begin this process is to find an existing export from the entity to
				copy and use as the basis of your new export.</para>
			<para>For example, if I wanted a new export for Tutor data that started from the Contact entity,
				I'd choose the default 'Contact CSV export' as my starting point.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to File > Preferences > Export templates and double click on export 'Contact CSV export'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight the text in the script field and copy and paste this into a
						plain text editor like Sublime Text (In a tool like Sublime you can specify
						the text is Groovy, so it will add colour coding to assist with the editing
						process).</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/exports/export_edit_sublime.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Viewing the export text in Sublime</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The first part of the export code
						<programlisting language="groovy">records.each { Contact c ->  
csv &lt;&lt; [ </programlisting>
						means that in this file, the letter 'c' will be used as shorthand for the
						'Contact' object and the export will create a CSV file. For your export to
						work correctly, do not modify this header information.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the DSL documentation for the entity so you can see the fields, or
						instance methods names and values. For the contact entity, this information
						is available at  <link
							xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/doc/latest/dsl/ish/oncourse/server/cayenne/Contact.html"
						/></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Each row that follows defines the column name in the CSV export and where that data comes
						from in onCourse, and how it is formatted. For example:</para>
					<programlisting language="groovy">"gender"     : c.isMale ? "M" : (c.isMale == null) ? "" : "F",</programlisting>
					<para>Means create a column labelled 'gender' and from the contact record (referred to in the
						shorthand 'c') take the value from the boolean isMale. If the value = true,
						export the character 'M', if the value is null (not set) then export a blank
						space, else export "F".  </para>
					<para>In this example, the question mark character is the ternary conditional
						operator which allows for three arguments to be defined and is a shortcut
						way of writing an if...else statement in Groovy.</para>
					<para>For example, if you wanted to change these export values to Male, Female
						and Not supplied you can change this row to:</para>
					<programlisting language="groovy">"gender"     : c.isMale ? "Male" : (c.isMale == null) ? "Not supplied" : "Female",</programlisting>
					<para>If the code was just </para>
					<programlisting language="groovy">"gender"     : c.isMale,</programlisting>
					<para>Then export value would be TRUE when the contact was set to Male, FALSE when the contact
						was set as female, and blank, or null, when no value was set in
						onCourse.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can add additional rows to the export, or delete or re-order rows. Note that each row
						ends with the comma delimiter "," except the last row in the export file.
						For example, the contact export ends with the resume field value, so there
						is no comma after this row.</para>
					<programlisting language="groovy">
			"workingWithChildrenCheckDate"	: c.tutor?.wwChildrenCheckedOn?.format("yyyy-MM-dd"),
			"workingWithChildrenCheckRef"	 : c.tutor?.wwChildrenRef,
			"workingWithChildrenCheckExpiry"    : c.tutor?.wwChildrenExpiry?.format("yyyy-MM-dd"),
			"tutorResume"                    : c.tutor?.resume
		]
}
					</programlisting>
					<para>You can also see above that the export file ends with the bracket closure characters  "]"
						and "}". It is important you don't remove these.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you want to access data from other objects than the entity defined in the export, you
						need to add joins to the export and structure your query in a way that
						matches the onCourse DSL and schema. For example, in the contact CSV file,
						some of the fields are from the student or tutor object. These joins are
						represented by the full stop character. For example, the Working With
						Children Check Reference number is part of the tutor object, so the join
						from the contact to the tutor is 'c.tutor.wwChildrenRef' which means the
						same as 'contact.tutor.wwChildrenRef'.</para>
					<programlisting language="groovy">
			"workingWithChildrenCheckRef"	 : c.tutor?.wwChildrenRef,
					</programlisting>
					<para>In this example, the addition of the question mark character is a safe-navigation
						operator to avoid the export throwing a null pointer exception. Null pointer
						exceptions occur when the export can not follow the join you have defined
						because it doesn't exist (i.e. not every contact selected for export will be
						a tutor, so if there is a non-tutor contact included, adding the
						safe-navigation operator just means the export will skip past this field for
						that record.)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you have custom fields you wish to include in your export, you can use the custom
						field keycode to add these fields. You won't find these fields defined in
						the onCourse DSL documentation as they are custom to your database. For
						example, if you have a contact custom field with the keycode
						'howDidYouHearAboutUs' you could add it your export as follows:
						<programlisting language="groovy">"How Did You Hear About Us?"  :  c.howDidYouHearAboutUs?.value</programlisting></para>
					<para>Refer to the <link xlink:href="#generalPrefs-customFields">Custom Field documentation</link> for more information about creating custom fields in onCourse. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<section>
				<title>Creating and testing your export in onCourse</title>
				<para>When you are ready to test your new export in onCourse, you can create a new export and copy your export code.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Go to File > Preferences > Export Templates and click the + in the top right hand corner
							to create a new export.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Name your export. This is what appears in the drop down when you run
							the export, so make it clear.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Provide a unique keycode for your export. This should be in the format
							companyName.onCourse.exportName.exportType</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Join your export to the correct entity. The name must be spelt exactly as it appears in
							the DSL documentation with the correct capitalisation.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Copy and paste your code into the body 'script' and save your
							export.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/exports/new_export_template.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Creating a new export in onCourse</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once you have saved your export, it will now be available for you to test in the Entity you defined.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you attempt to run the report and instead of generating the expected output, it shows
							an error in the window, then you need to adjust your export code to
							resolve the error, save the changes and try again. This may be a process
							you repeat a few times if you are new to creating and editing export
							files.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>When your export runs successfully, check the output is formatted as expected, and make
							adjustments to your export as needed. Please note: When opening CSV
							files in a spreadsheet application like Excel, Excel may reformat some
							of your data based on it's own rules. For example, data it thinks are
							numbers will often be reformatted, so the leading zeros from mobile
							phones numbers may be stripped . You should run your formatting checks
							in a text editor like Sublime or Notepad.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Other export types and options</title>
		<section>
			<title>AVETMISS export</title>
			<para>To export your AVETMISS go to the file menu, select import/export and choose
				Export AVETMISS. Select the date range you wish to export and where you wish to
				export the files to, e.g. your desktop, and select proceed. The 10 txt files will
				then be created ready to be submitted to the government reporting agency of your
				choice. Easy as! </para>
			<para>For more information about how the onCourse data collection and various AVETMISS
				export options work, see the <link xlink:href="AVETMISS.html">AVETMISS
					chapter</link>. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/export_avetmiss.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="importExport_InDesign"><title>Exporting to Adobe InDesign</title><para>onCourse already comes with a template for exporting to Adobe InDesign.</para><para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open the class list view</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Use the searching feature to find the classes you want in your
							brochure. This might be one or a thousand classes.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Choose "Import/Export" from the File menu and select "Export classes". Select the
							"InDesign Brochure" output format. Export this data and save it to disk
							somewhere. It will be an XML file, ready for InDesign.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para><para>Now fire up Adobe InDesign and import this file.<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<menuchoice>
								<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
								<guimenuitem>Import XML</guimenuitem>
							</menuchoice>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Choose your XML file which you just exported from onCourse.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Ticking "Link" will keep the InDesign document linked to your source
							XML so that changes to the XML flow through</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The structure of the data will now appear in the left column. You can
							drag any element into a text box in your layout and have the text
							automatically flow through.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Use the "map tags to style..." menu item to map the tags against your
							paragraph and character style sheets. Once this is done you can save the
							mapping so that next time you create this document with fresh data all
							the styles are linked quickly and simply.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist></para><para>If you now spend a bit of time tidying up your stylesheets (both character styles and
				paragraph styles) in InDesign you can set up the whole process to be almost
				completely automated. Next time you export from onCourse, the data will flow right
				into InDesign complete with all the formatting you need. Just paginate your
				brochure, place in some pictures and you are done.</para>
			<para>If you need to customise your export further, you can do this yourself if you have the
				skills in house, or engage ish to make the changes for you.</para>
		</section>
			<section>
				<title>OLGR CSV Export</title>
				<para>onCourse has an export that allows you to export student data into OLGR for
					the state of NSW. </para>
				<para>Below are the steps you need to follow to do this:</para>
				<para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Open the 'Class' window and locate the RSA class you want to
								create the file for </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Single click on the chosen class</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Go to the cog wheel and select 'Find related &gt; enrolled
								students' </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>This will open the students from this class in a new contact
								window</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>With the contact window at the front of your onCourse view, select
								File &gt; Import/Export &gt; Export contacts</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Choose the option 'NSW OLGR CSV export' and ensure the radio
								button listed records is shown</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Click export and choose a location to save the file and give the
								file a name that makes sense to you about which class group this
								data belongs to</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Open the CSV file in excel and use your current process to upload
								the data into OLGR</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
	<section xml:id="importExport-MYOB">
		<title>Exporting to MYOB</title>
		<para> If your organisation utilizes MYOB as the key financial system, you can generate an
			export that is specifically designed for importing data directly into MYOB. There are 2
			different pathways within the onCourse Client to access and generate the financial data
			export for MYOB.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Generating a MYOB Export via the Financial Summary Extract Menu</title>
			<para>The steps involved in running this export are as follows:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to Financial > Summary Extracts and select MYOB Export</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/exports/MYOB_Export_via_Summary_Extract.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Selecting MYOB Export via Summary Extract menu</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Set the 'from' and 'to' date range for the next MYOB Export</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/exports/MYOB_Export_set_date_range.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Select date range for MYOB Export</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<note>
						<para>The benefit of utilizing the Summary Extract path when exporting
							financial data, is that onCourse enables you to set the date range for
							the data that is to be exported. As well as remembering the date up to
							when the last data export was run. </para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the <guilabel>Export</guilabel>button to run the export. Note
						that the resulting file will be generated as a text file. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/exports/MYOB_Export_data_output.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Extract of MYOB Export viewed via Microsoft Excel</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Generating a MYOB Export via the Transaction Window</title>
			<para>Unlike the approach of generating the MYOB Export via the Summary Extract menu of
				onCourse, by running the export via the Transactions window, you can define exactly
				which transactions you wish to export to the resulting text file. The steps involved
				in running this export via the Transactions window are as follows: </para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Filter and highlight the transaction records you wish to export within the Transaction
							window</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to File > Import/Export > Export Transactions to bring up the export
						dialog box</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select <guilabel>MYOB</guilabel> from the drop down list of export
						formats</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the <guilabel>Export</guilabel>button to run the export. Note
						that the resulting file will be generated as a text file. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/exports/MYOB_Export_data_output.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Extract of MYOB Export viewed via Microsoft Excel</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	</section><section xml:id="importExport-Import">
		<title>Importing</title>
		<para>Using the onCourse Groovy scripting engine, powerful import process can be created in
			onCourse for either once off events or a regular data transfer between onCourse and a
			third party software service.</para>
		<para>For once off type data imports, you may like to read our chapter on <link
				xlink:href="migrating.html">Migrating to onCourse.</link></para>
		<para>For regular data transfers, you may like to read our chapter on <link
				xlink:href="externalintegrations.html">External Integrations.</link></para>
		<para>Custom import processes and integration scripts can also be created on request. Please
			send you request to support@ish.com.au</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/exports/importafile.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Accessing the imports from the file menu</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Standard Imports available</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS outcome import</emphasis> - Using
						data from an import set of NAT00120, NAT00060, NAT00080 and NAT00085 file,
						create <emphasis>new</emphasis> students in onCourse with their existing
						AVETMISS file student number. Import their contact record into onCourse and
						update their record with their outcomes in the onCourse prior learning
						record. The prior learning records are grouped by qualification, where the
						qualification data is supplied in the NAT00120. This import is most commonly
						used during system migration to import data from another AVETMISS reporting
						tool into onCourse. Running this import on the same data set twice will
						create duplicate records for each student.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS outcome update import</emphasis> -
					Using data from an import set of NAT00120, NAT00060, NAT00080 and NAT00085
					files, <emphasis>update</emphasis> existing students in onCourse with prior
					learning data. This process does not create new contact records, only adds prior
					learning data to existing contacts.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS student import </emphasis>- Using
					a data from an import set of NAT00080 &amp; NAT000085 files, create new student
					contact records in onCourse. Running this import on the same data set twice will
					create duplicate records for each student.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse AVETMISS student update import </emphasis>-
					Using a data from an import set of NAT00080 &amp; NAT000085 files, update
					existing student contact records in onCourse. This process does not create new
					contact records, only adds prior learning data to existing contacts.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse contact CSV import</emphasis> - Import
					contact data from CSV file to create new contacts, students, tutors and/or
					companies in the database. Running this import on the same data set twice will
					create duplicate records for each student.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse paymentIn CSV import </emphasis>- Using CSV
					data, import paymentIn information in order to automatically match paymentIn
					records with invoices. </para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">onCourse Contact Update Subscriptions CSV import</emphasis>- 
				Search for contacts based on the provided email address and update their marketing permissions
				in bulk.</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="importExport-payentIn">
			<title>Payment In Import</title>
			<para>If you receive bulk payment data from an outside source, you can use the Payment
				In import process to automatically create payment ins against the appropriate
				invoices. You will just need to ensure the import file is correctly formatted and
				onCourse will do the rest for you. The import process relies on the onCourse invoice
				number being associated with the payments, and if your onCourse invoice number is
				not included in the information then the payment in import will not work.</para>
			<para>If the invoice number is included in the data, then your next step is to determine
				how you will create the import file. If your data is being sent from a supplier,
				internal department other businesses you are working with, you may be able to get
				them to format the data when they export from their system. If you are not able to
				get the export form changed, such as with internet banking, you many need download
				the data, edit it in a spreadsheet program, and save it as a CSV format. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/paymentInImportWindow.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Selecting the Payment In Import from Import/Export dialog box</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>To import the CSV, go to <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>,
					<guimenuitem>Import/Export</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Import...</guimenuitem>
				and select 'onCourse payment in csv import' as the import type.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Payment In Import file set up</title>
				<para>Please see below for the import file specification. You will need to ensure
					that each line in the CSV relates to an invoice, or the import will fail. To
					make sure this is the case, please deleted any lines in the spreadsheet that
					appear after the last invoice record.</para>
				<table frame="all">
					<title>Payment In Import file format</title>
					<tgroup cols="7" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
						<colspec colnum="1" colname="c1" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colnum="2" colname="c2" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colnum="3" colname="c3" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colnum="4" colname="c4" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colname="5" colnum="5" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colnum="6" colname="c6" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colname="7" colnum="7" colwidth="1*"/>
						<thead>
							<row>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">payment.invoice</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">payment.dateBanked </emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">payment.amount</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold"
									>paymentIn.paymentMethod.name</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">payment.chequeBank</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">payment.chequeBranch</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">payment.chequeDrawer</emphasis></entry>
							</row>
						</thead>
						<tbody>
							<row>
								<entry>the onCourse invoice numbers </entry>
								<entry>date the payment was banked here, in date format
									DD/MM/YYYY</entry>
								<entry>the payment amount as numbers. Do not use dollar symbols or
									commas </entry>
								<entry>the payment type. the name must be the same as the payment
									type in your onCourse database</entry>
								<entry>if payment was by cheque, the bank issuing the cheque</entry>
								<entry>if the payment method was by cheque, the name of the branch
									issuing the cheque</entry>
								<entry>if the payment method was by cheque, the name of the drawer
									on the cheque</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>12045</entry>
								<entry>31/10/2017</entry>
								<entry>1295.50</entry>
								<entry>other</entry>
								<entry/>
								<entry/>
								<entry/>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>12892</entry>
								<entry>30/10/2017</entry>
								<entry>1000</entry>
								<entry>Cheque</entry>
								<entry>Commonwealth Bank</entry>
								<entry>Bendigo</entry>
								<entry>A J Spencer</entry>
							</row>
						</tbody>
					</tgroup>
				</table>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="importExport-updateSubscriptions">
			<title>Contact Update Subscriptions CSV import</title>
			<para>This import will allow you to update, in bulk, the email, post and sms subscription
				preferences of a contact record, as identified by its email address. Below is an
				example of how your CSV file should be laid out. When you format your CSV, be sure
				to allow the table headers otherwise the import will fail.</para>
			
		</section>
		<table frame="all">
			<title>Contact Subscription Update CSV format</title>
			<tgroup cols="4">
				<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
				<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
				<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1*"/>
				<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1*"/>
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>email</entry>
						<entry>allowEmail</entry>
						<entry>allowPost</entry>
						<entry>allowSms</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>alice@email.com.au</entry>
						<entry>TRUE</entry>
						<entry>TRUE</entry>
						<entry>FALSE</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>bob@email.com.au</entry>
						<entry>TRUE</entry>
						<entry>FALSE</entry>
						<entry>FALSE</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>charlie@email.com.au</entry>
						<entry>FALSE</entry>
						<entry>FALSE</entry>
						<entry>FALSE</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>	
	</section>
	</chapter>
