<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="invoice">
	<title>Invoices and Payment Plans</title>
	<section xml:id="invoice-general">
		<title>Invoices</title>
		<para>Every time you create a purchase through Quick Enrol, an invoice will be automatically
			created for you. Each item purchased will create an invoice line, so multiple students
			enrolling in multiple classes each can be recorded on a single invoice. An invoice is
			assigned to a debtor, so an employer requesting two students enrolling in three classes
			each can be issued a single invoice through one Quick Enrol process. Whereas two
			individual students each enrolling and paying for their classes themselves would be
			enrolled through two Quick Enrol processes, to create two invoices - one for each
			student.</para>
		<para>During the Quick Enrol process you can see the draft details the invoice you are
			creating, and add additional information like a customer's purchase order number or add
			additional custom lines, such as a surcharge for phone bookings.</para>
		<para>Invoice lines automatically created by Quick Enrol may include purchases of
			enrolments, products, vouchers or memberships.</para>
		<para>Full or partial payment against an invoice may be taken at the time of creation
			through Quick Enrol, or at a later date. A due date for the invoice can be manually set
			in Quick Enrol.</para>
		<para>These invoices are then visible within the Invoice list view. Like all other lists you
			can sort, search, export and print from this view. </para>
		<para>The invoice list view can be opened via Financial > Invoices.</para>
		<para>The quick search option in the top left hand corner of the screen allows you to search for
			invoices by debtor last name, company name or invoice number. When you begin typing the
			text into this field, the list of invoices shown will automatically reduce to meet your
			criteria.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
					fileref="images/invoice_list_view.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Invoice list view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<para>The 'Overdue' column will show the total unpaid component of the invoice that is
				due prior to tomorrow e.g. amounts due today, and in the past, which are unpaid are
				considered overdue. This updates daily, not in real time.</para>
		</note>
		<section>
			<title>Invoice Terms</title>
			<para>By default, an invoices created by onCourse will have a due date of today i.e.
				their day of creation.</para>
			<para>If you wish to set a different default term for all your invoices, then you can
				set a 'default invoice terms (days)' in the Financial preferences, located at File >
				Preferences > General > Financial. This is a good choice for organisations who do
				not usually take payment upfront during the enrolment process.</para>
			<para>However, if most of your enrolling students require invoices with a due date of
				'today', and some corporate contacts require invoices with due date terms, you can
				also set invoice terms per contact.</para>
			<para>In the contact record, open the Financial tab and unlock the default invoice
				terms. Replace the value with the customer specific terms.</para>
			<para>All future invoices created for this customer, including invoices created for
				enrolments processed over the website using a corporatePass, will have a due date
				set according to the custom terms.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/invoiceTerms.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Invoice list view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Editing Invoices</title>
			<para>Invoices may not be deleted and all of the financial information within an invoice
				may not be edited once created - only the invoice due date and payment plan
				information can be changed. Although this may seem like an inconvenience, immutable
				invoices are extremely important to ensure a robust audit trail and to guarantee the
				integrity of the general ledger transactions.</para>
			<para>If you need to modify an invoice you should instead create a credit note. A credit
				note is an invoice where the invoice lines have negative dollar values. Remember if
				you are cancelling an enrolment or a class there are easier ways to do that from the
				class and enrolment list views.</para>
			<para>A credit note is an invoice with a negative total and is shown alongside invoices
				in the same list view. The owing amounts on an invoice and a credit note are not
				automatically zeroed against each other, however you can cancel them out by using
				the cog wheel option 'contra invoice'.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-apply-payment-in">
			<title>Applying a Payment In via Cogwheel</title>
			<para>You can apply a payment in for a specific invoice from the Invoice list view by 
				highlighting a single invoice > clicking the cogwheel > selecting 'Apply payment in'.</para>
			<para>This will open the Quick Enrol screen with the contact field pre-filled and, 
				provided the selected invoice is due on or prior to the current date, the highlighted 
				invoice will be ticked within 'Payments'. If you select an invoice that has a due date 
				beyond the current date, you will need to manually select the invoice to have the payment 
				applied to in the Quick Enrol screen. The total payment amount will be auto-calculated to 
				the balance of the selected invoice.</para>
			<para>You can apply the single payment across multiple invoices by selecting the invoices 
				you wish to have the payment applied to by selecting them in the Payments tab on the quick 
				enrol screens. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/apply_payment_in.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Applying a Payment In to a specific invoice via the cogwheel in the Invoices window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-create">
			<title>Creating a manual invoice</title>
			<para>While you will usually create an invoice through using Quick Enrol, it is
				sometimes useful to create an invoice without an associated product or enrolment.
				You can easily do that by opening the list of invoices and pressing the plus icon at
				the top right.</para>
			<para>Invoices created manually can have an invoice date in the past or the future,
				although the default setting is today. Invoices created with a date in the past will
				can be created prior to the financial period finalised date. They can only be
				created for unlocked periods. If you create a invoice in the past (or future) the
				general ledger transaction lines will be created for that date. You can not pay an
				invoice though that has a creation date in the future, as it doesn't yet exist with
				an outstanding balance. </para>
			<para>Remember to associate each invoice line with the correct income account code. Once
				you save the invoice you will not be able to change this code. </para>
			<para>Each invoice line can have a discount applied, and that discount can optionally be
				linked to a Cost of Sale (COS) account. If you do not apply the discount to a COS
				account, then the income value posted to the general ledger will be reduced by the
				value of the discount.</para>
			<para>By default, invoices are ticked to 'send email'. This sends the standard invoice
				email template to the debtor contact when you save the record.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Creating_a_new_invoice.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a new invoice</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-linking">
			<title>Link invoice lines to class budgets</title>
			<para>When creating invoice lines you may optionally link each line to a class. This
				will treat the income with the same general ledger pre-paid fees and income deferral
				plan as invoices created by enrolling in the class. This also adds the total of that
				invoice line to the class budget and can be very useful when invoicing a company for
				an entire classroom delivery without recording individual enrolments or need to
				include additional income such as funding in a classes budget. </para>
			<para>Type the course name or code, and select the class code from the drop down list to
				join a manual invoice line to a class budget.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/invoice_lines.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Linking invoice lines to a class in the Assign to Budget section</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-duplicating">
			<title>Duplicating and reversing invoices</title>
			<para>This feature is mostly used to create a credit note when you have cancelled the enrolment,
				but retained the invoice by mistake. These types of enrolments will have the status
				'cancelled' rather than 'credited'. </para>
			<para>Alternatively, you might use this option to 'fix' the fee due post enrolment, if
				the student was charged the wrong fee during the enrolment process and you don't
				want to reverse the enrolment entirely. In this case, you would create a reversed
				invoice for part of the course fee.</para>
			<para>You can also use this process to reverse a credit note that shouldn't have been created.
				The reversal of a credit note will be an invoice. </para>
				<para>If you want to create a copy of an invoice, follow the same process by remove
					the minus signs from the invoice lines.</para>
			<para>Remember, you can't edit or delete 'mistakes' in onCourse invoices, but every invoice or
				credit note can be corrected by creating an equal and opposite reversal action. This
				tool is your shortcut to fixing those sorts of mistakes.</para>
			<para>This feature can only be used on one invoice at a time.</para>
			<example>
				<title>How to manually credit an invoice</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem><para>Open the invoice list view and single click on the invoice you want to fully or partially reverse.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Click on the cogwheel and select
						the option 'Duplicate and reverse invoice'.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>A new invoice window will open. This will be a duplicate of the original invoice, in reverse.
							e.g. all the original dollar values will now have negative sign in front
							of them.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/invoice_duplicate.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Duplicating an invoice from the cogwheel</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject></listitem>
					<listitem><para>You can edit the value of every field of the new invoice/credit note,
						including changing the value the reversal is for, to make it more or less
						than the original invoice value.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Note that each invoice line from the original invoice will be reversed. You can
						delete invoice lines from this credit note you do not want to reverse e.g. if there
						were two enrolments on the original invoice and you only want to credit one.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/duplicated_and_reversed_invoice_two_lines.png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>This reversed invoice has two invoice lines. Select one and click the minus sign (delete) button to remove it from the invoice.</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject></listitem>
					<listitem><para>You can also add additional lines to the invoice, with either negative or positive values, for
							example, if you wanted to manually charge an admin fee, you can add the
							fee as an additional line with a positive amount. This will reduce the
							balance of the credit available to the student.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>If you want this new invoice/credit note to be applied to the class budget and pre-paid fee
							liability process, double click on each invoice line and manually link
							it to the course and class by code. If this invoice reversal was for an
							enrolment, you will see the course and class code you need to manually
							reverse against in the invoice line description.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem><para>By default, this new credit note won't be sent by email to the payer.
						Check the option 'send email' if you want a copy to be sent.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Save and close the new credit note/invoice once you have confirmed all
						the values are correct. You can not change any of the data after you have
						saved it as all financial records are immutable.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>If you wish to use this new credit note to contra pay and existing
						invoice with a balance outstanding, select in the invoice list, and from the
						cogwheel choose 'contra invoice'. A new window will open allowing you to
						select unpaid invoices from the same contact you can credit
						against.</para></listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="invoice-paymentPlan">
		<title>Payment plans</title>
		<para>By default invoices have a due of the day they are created. Sometimes you will want to
			allow students to pay for training over a longer period of time. Using payment plans you
			can set the amount of the up front deposit and a series of dates for payment of the
			remainder in instalments. </para>
		<section xml:id="invoice-dueDate">
			<title>Invoice due dates</title>
			<para>An existing or new invoice can be converted to a payment plan by adding payment
				due dates. This can be done by firstly either creating a new invoice as mentioned in
				the section above 'Creating a manual invoice' just stopping before you click on
				'Save', or opening an existing invoice. Then click on the '+' symbol at the top
				right side of the payment plans / payments table for as many different payment due
				dates you want to add.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/invoice_add_payment_plans.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Manually adding payment plan lines to an invoice</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once this has been done you can then start editing these payment plan lines
				starting with the dates you want the payments to be due. This is done by double
				clicking on one of the 'today' payment due date fields in the table and changing it
				to a date that you want the payment to be due by. Then do the same for the other
				payment due date fields until they are all setup correctly.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/invoice_edit_payment_due_lines.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Editing the date for each of the payment due lines</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Then lastly change the amounts that are due on each of these dates from $0 to your
				chosen amount. This is also done by double clicking on the relevant field in the
				table and editing the fee amount.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/invoice_adding_payment_plans.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Invoice with manually added payment due dates and amounts</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>It is important that the total of the payment plan amounts equals the amount owing; you
				will not be able to save the invoice unless they match. The 'Overdue' column in the
				Invoices list view will show the total unpaid component of the invoice that is due
				prior to tomorrow.</para>
			<para>You can edit the payment plan amounts and due dates at any time, for example if
				you grant the student an extension to the payment plan.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-payPlanTemplate">
			<title>Class payment plan template</title>
			<para>If you wish to offer a deferred payment scheme to all students in a particular
				class you can set up a payment plan templates from the class edit view you where you
				normally set the class fee. </para>
			<para>This can be quite useful if you an RTO who is bound by the Standards that limit
				your prepayment of fees to $1,500. For example, if you offer a 10-week course that
				costs $2000, the course costs $200 per week. Therefore, you could collect $1500 at
				the time of enrolment and the remaining $500 after week seven without needing to
				have any protection measures in place.</para>
			<para>You may also like to use payment plans as part of your online marketing strategy,
				by encouraging students to commit to enrolment early with a small refundable payment
				(say, $100), with the remainder of the fee becoming due on the class
				commencement.</para>
			<para>The payment plan template can include an amount on enrolment (deposit) and as many
				other amounts on dates relative to the start of the class. If you subsequently
				adjust the class timetable and change the class start date then the payment plan
				template will automatically be adjusted. When you duplicate classes the payment plan
				template will also be adjusted with the new timetable.</para>
			<para>To create a payment plan for a class where the fee has already been set, you may
				wish to click the lock icon next to the class fee first. This will ensure the
				payment plan adds up to the existing class fee, rather than add additional costs to
				the class fee. The 'on enrolment' fee will auto adjust to the amount
				remaining.</para>
			<para>Each payment line you add requires an offset date from the class start. This
				offset can be positive (days after) or negative (days before). The actual due dates
				for the payments for this class will be calculated and shown in the payment plan
				screen.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Class_payment_plan.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a payment plan in a class</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-QE">
			<title>Quick Enrol</title>
			<para>During enrolment info a class with a payment plan, only the deposit amount will
				normally be charged at enrolment. The payment field will auto adjust to this amount,
				but you can manually alter it to be more or less as you need.</para>
			<para>If, at the time of enrolment, the next payment dates have already passed those
				amounts will also be charged. So, let's take an example class with a $1000 deposit
				and $500 due 7 days before the start of class. A student enrolling 10 days before
				the class starts will be charged $1000 and a student enrolling 5 days before class
				starts will be charged $1500. </para>
			<para>During Quick Enrol every involvement with a different payment plan will be added
				to a separate invoice. In this way a single Quick Enrol process may generate two or
				more invoices. If several enrolments have an identical payment plan, then they will
				end up on the same invoice.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Payment_plan_invoices.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Payment plan invoices in Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Online enrolments</title>
			<para>If a payment plan applies to the class, we suggest you make some note of it in the
				class web tab, so a potential student enrolling via the web can see what amount is
				payable and when. The full class fee will still display in the class block when a
				payment plan applies.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/payment_plan_class_block.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Payment plan detail explained in the class web info</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>When the student completes the enrolment process, the 'pay now' component will be
				reduced to the deposit payable. The invoice the student receives on completion of
				the enrolment process will itemise the remaining payment components and their due
				dates.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/payment_plan_pay_now.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Pay now reduced to the applicable payment plan deposit</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="invoice-script">
			<title>Automating payment plans with scripts</title>
			<para>If you have payment plan templates to create for very many classes you may wish to
				instead use a script to automate the process. A simple script might identify all
				classes with a fee over $1500 and then limit the amount due on enrolment to $1500
				with the remainder payable over the duration of the class.</para>
			<para>More sophisticated payment plan scripts can create different plans depending on
				the duration of the class, the amount of the fee, whether the class is VET or not
				and any other criteria.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Payment plan scheduled reminders</title>
			<para>When a student is on a payment plan, you may wish to enable the default system
				script 'send payment plan reminder' so the debtor is automatically emailed a
				reminder 7 days before their payment is due a link to make the payment via the
				skillsOnCourse portal. You can enable this from the top menu by going to File →
				Preferences → Scripts, then double click on the script 'send payment plan reminder',
				click on the checkbox 'Enabled' in the top right side of the window, then
				Save.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/payment_plan_script.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>'send payment plan reminder' script</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This default reminder will also send overdue notices to any debtor who has an
				invoice (on a payment plan or otherwise) where the payment is overdue.</para>
			<para>This script will trigger the email template 'Payment reminder' which can be edited
				by going to File → Preferences → Email Templates, then double click on the email
				template 'Payment reminder'.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/payment_plan_email_template.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>'Payment reminder' email template</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
