<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="privateBookings">
	<title>Private Bookings and Custom Classes</title>
	<section>
		<title> Creating and Enrolling Students in a Custom Class </title>
		<para> The Private Booking feature can be used when you are creating a once-off custom class
			booking for an individual or group enrolment. This feature allows you to create the
			class, set the fee and take the enrolment. </para>
		<para> You might use this feature to create one-on-one booking for extra tuition, a private dancing lesson for a couple, or a custom
			corporate class booking for a small group of staff. </para>
		<para> To begin, open the quick enrol window.</para>

		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Type in a course name in the 'Enter course or item' field. This needs to be an existing
					course – even if the class content is not the same you can select one that is
					similar Salsa eg. Latin and American for a private salsa booking. If you
					regularly take private bookings you may prefer to set up a course specifically
					for that purpose. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once you have added the course you want to create a private booking for, you should see a
					button called 'Create Private Class' in the top right hand side of the window.
					Click on this button; this will open up a separate new window for you to create
					the custom class.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/create_private_class.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Where to find the 'Create Private Class' button in Quick Enrol</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Set a class code, a site and room and create a fee. Like all classes, the fee is per
					person, so if you are enrolling a couple, you can either set the fee to half the
					booking cost and charge them both, or set the fee to the full cost, and manually
					discount the second person to $0. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%" fileref="images/new_class_private_booking.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Creating a new class for a private booking</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select a tutor to deliver the class. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create one or more sessions for this class. The process is the same for creating sessions
					in other classes. If you double book a room or tutor, you will see a warning
					icon in the calendar view. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Add the contact details for the first student, and enrol them in the class, as per a
					normal enrolment. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/private_bookings.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>What you see in Quick Enrol once you have created a class and added a student for a
							private booking</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Add each of the other contacts attending this class. They will be pre-populated with an
					enrolment in this class. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter the payer and payment details and save the enrolment. </para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para> The class and enrolments will be created. The class will be set to a maximum of the number of students who enrolled. If you need
			to add an additional student to the enrolment at a later date, you can find and edit the class maximum numbers and add the additional
			student(s) as per the normal enrolment process. </para>
	</section>
</chapter>
