<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"  
	version="5.0" xml:id="processingEnrolments">
	<title>Processing Enrolments</title>
	<section>
		<title>Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Quick Enrol:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Quick enrol is a tool available to you in onCourse, it allows you to easily enrol a
						student into a class in just a few steps. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Enrolment:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>An enrolment is an instance in which a person has elected to partake in a class for
						different reasons, they will supply their details and this will be stored in the
						onCourse database. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Invoice:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>An invoice is a record/document that represents income of some sort. This can be an
						enrolment into a class or other goods and services provided. An invoice is basically a
						bill. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Payment:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A payment is an instance in which money owing has been successfully taken from one
						party and transferred to another. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Student:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A student in onCourse is a type of contact, one who is currently or has previously
						been enrolled into a class and is being taught by another person/resource. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Payer:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A payer is someone who has personally paid an invoice for an enrolment in a class.
						It is important to note that a payer does not necessarily need to be the person taking
						the class, or even an individual for that matter. They can be a relative, friend,
						manager or company. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Working with Quick Enrol</title>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>Quick enrol can be accessed through a number of methods</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>Clicking on the Quick Enrol option from the onCourse home or "splash" screen.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Selecting <emphasis role="bold">People</emphasis> from the top menu and then selecting
						<emphasis role="bold">Quick Enrol</emphasis> from the drop down menu. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> You can also bring up the Quick Enrol page if you hold down the command button on
					your keyboard and press the E button once, this is called a <emphasis role="bold">Keyboard
						Shortcut</emphasis>.Please note you can only issue this command if you are in an active
					window of onCourse, not any other program. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para> Quick Enrol is a tool in which you can enrol students into classes. Most of the fields
			have autocomplete functionality which means when you start typing, onCourse starts finding
			students that start with that name, and will display the results in a small drop down box
			under the field you are completing, for your selection. </para>
		<para>The following will identify the different elements of the Quick Enrol window, and what
			their purpose is, the left side of the windows houses the buttons to select, where the right
			side houses the fields and functions. </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>Navigating through Quick Enrol</title>
			<listitem>
				<para> The <emphasis role="bold">+ Add...</emphasis> button (left side of the window): This
					button houses several options in regards to creating an enrolment, by clicking on it, this
					button will reveal functions like: Adding an additional <emphasis role="bold">contact,
						enrolment, charge</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">membership</emphasis>, <emphasis
						role="bold">product,</emphasis><emphasis role="bold">gift certificate </emphasis>or
						<emphasis role="bold">private booking</emphasis>. Think of it as a way to add on extra
					information onto the enrolment. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> The <emphasis role="bold">Enter contact</emphasis> button (left side of the window):
					This button allows you to attach a paying person to the enrolment, they can be a student,
					a tutor or a company, remember, you don't have to be the actual student to be the payer.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> The <emphasis role="bold">Payment</emphasis> button (left side of the window): This
					button allows you to input payment type like credit card or cash and the payment amount,
					among other useful things like a customer reference number for internal use. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> The <emphasis role="bold">Enter Enrolment</emphasis> button (left side of the window):
					This button allows you to search for a course, and select a class from that
					class to enrol in, you can search with a course code or just a course name,
					these fields have auto complete functionality so this means that you don't need
					to guess the exact title of the course. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating an enrolment with Quick Enrol</title>
		<para>This section will provide you with clear and concise instructions on how to achieve certain
			things within onCourse Quick Enrol, like enrolling a student.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>A few things to consider first</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>A contact can be a student or a payer, a company can be listed as a payer but can not
					be a student. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Student names can be entered in this fashion: "Smith, John". When you type a comma, the
					auto complete looks up all students with "Smith" as a surname. As you continue
					to type letters of the first name, the list is reduced. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>You can also type student names like this: "John Smith". When you do this, the auto
					complete feature will not start showing you choices until you have typed a few
					letters of the student's surname. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>At any time you can press the up and down arrows on your keyboard to select a student,
					and press 'return' to choose the student currently selected. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If the student you are enrolling has a contact record at your college, you can select
					them from the list. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>When the student name is highlighted in the list, you will see their suburb and date
					of birth, to assist you in selecting the right record.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If the student you wish to enrol is new to your college, you can select the option
					"New…" from the list to begin creating a new student record.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once you have selected your student, you will see their information in the Quick Enrol
					window, this is the same information you see in their contact record, you can then make
					changes to any of the contact details, notes or AVETMISS information as needed. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A third party payer is a person or organisation who is not the student enrolling. This
					can include other students, friends, relatives, managers, organisations.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>When you complete the enrolment, the changes will be saved. If you cancel the
					enrolment, your changes will not be saved.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<tip>
			<para>Please note that once you open Quick Enrol, you will be defaulted to the <emphasis
					role="bold">enter enrolment</emphasis> page, you do not have to start the enrolment
				process from this page, you may start from anywhere in Quick Enrol, although it is
				recommended to start at "enter contact", as this will make things simpler.</para>
		</tip>
		<section>
			<title>How to use Quick Enrol to create an enrolment and issue an invoice</title>
			<para>When processing an enrolment via the onCourse client, it is possible to issue an invoice
				if the customer does not wish to pay the course fee at the point of enrolment. The following
				will take you through the enrolment process when an invoice is issued step by step, keeping
				it simple throughout.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open "Quick Enrol", see above for instructions.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You are defaulted to the "Enter Enrolment" page, from the left select "Enter
						contact".</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the "name" field, type in a name and click on it to select that person and
						populate the fields with their details (autofill), if the person you need is not in the
						system, you can create their profile from here, by filling out the fields and selecting
						either "Student", "Tutor" or "Company", depending on who they are (payer or student
						etc).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>After the contact is selected, click on "Enter Enrolment" from the left hand
						side.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From here input either a course code or course name, again these fields are
						autocomplete so if you were to type e.g "Comp", the rest of the word "Computer" will
						come up showing courses that contain that word in the title.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once the course is located in the system, the classes will be presented to you in
						the "Choose a class" list view, highlight the class you want, remembering that the "Show
						finished classes" checkbox can be selected to include classes that are now past their
						end date, e.g "Computers - For Beginners" is scheduled to end on 24/11/11, and the date
						is 25/11/11, selecting "Show finished classes" ensures that "Computers- For Beginners"
						is shown in the class list view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Input a discount amount and select a concession if applicable (not
						compulsory).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select a study reason (not compulsory).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Next, select "Payment" from the left hand side, you will notice there is now an
						amount next to the word "Payment" and in the "Payment amount" field.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Input a customer reference if applicable (not compulsory).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Input a promotional code if applicable (not compulsory).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select a payer from the payer field, this does not have to be the student, it can be
						any other contact in the system, including an organisation (more on that after these
						instructions).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>As the payment will not be made at the time of enrolment, enter $0 amount in the
						payment amount field, the system will then allow you to finalise the enrolment without
						selecting a payment type. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Finally, select save from the bottom of the window, a confirmation box will appear,
						form here select your methods of receiving the invoice and enrolment confirmation.
						That's it!</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/autocomplete.png"
					 />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>An example of the auto complete functionality in onCourse</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding a second or subsequent enrolment</title>
			<para>To add an additional enrolment, you must click on the "+Add..." button and select
				"Enrolment". This will create another enrolment page on the left side menu, from here, as
				per the previous instructions, you may add another class to your students enrolment. If you
				have added an additional class but changed your mind, you can just click on the "X" button
				to the right of the "Enrolment" option in the left side menu. It is grey in colour. <mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/additional_enrolment.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "add" button, selecting an additional enrolment</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding additional students</title>
			<para>To add an additional student, you must click the plus "+Add..." button in the top left
				corner and select "Contact" to add another student to Quick Enrol. You can add as many
				students as necessary, provided they are all being paid for by the same person or company.
				To change the payer at any stage, click on the "Payment" button in the left side menu and
				edit the "Payer" drop down box to switch to the other contact you want to be the payer.<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Add_contact.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "add" button, selecting an additional contact</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject> If you add extra contacts after the enrolments have been added to the first
				student, each of the contacts will be created with a copy of the first contact's enrolments.
				For example, if three friends are all enrolling in the same two dance classes, add the
				enrolments to the first person, then add your other two contacts and they will be populated
				with the same classes. If you have students enrolling together that are doing different
				classes, e.g. a husband enrolling in painting and a wife enrolling in Tai Chi, add both
				contacts first, then add the enrolments to each contact. There are small crosses on the
				right hand side of the screen that allow you to remove contacts or enrolments you don't
				need. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding additional charges</title>
			<para>Click the plus + button in the top left corner and choose Add charge to add another charge
				to your selected student. You can use this to add a charge like a phone booking fee.
				From this same button you can also add a membership or product.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding a 3rd party payer</title>
			<para>This part of the 3rd party payer topic only covers the steps to follow to add a 3rd
				party payer. For more, read on to the section "3rd Party Payments". </para>
			<para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Add the student to the enrolment as per the usual process. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Next, add the payer to the enrolment, by clicking the plus sign and add a
							contact. You do not need to enrol them in any classes, however, if they are a friend
							or family member they may be both enrolling and paying. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> You can create a relationship between contacts at this point, e.g. contact 2 is
							the employer of contact 1, or you can use existing relationships to easily find and
							add contacts via the quick enrol add contact option.</para>
						<para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/3rd_party_payer.png" />
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>The relationship option, click "select" to choose a type of relationship
										between contacts</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Set the classes for the student(s) as per the usual process.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> In the payment section, ensure you select the correct payer. The payment line
							will move to the payers record. Enter the payment details (zero payments are allowed –
							an invoice with an unpaid, partial or fully paid balance will be sent). </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Select ‘Email' and/or ‘Print enrolment confirmation and tax invoice' as
							appropriate. The invoice will only go to the payer. The enrolment confirmation will go
							to the student(s) enrolling. </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolling a student in credit or debt</title>
			<para>To enrol a student in credit or debt basically means that the student you are about to
				enrol owes your organisation money through unpaid or partially paid fees, or your
				organisation owes this student money through the student leaving a course early and thus
				being able to retrieve some funds. To achieve one of these you would need to make sure the
				following:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>The student must have been previously enrolled in a class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The student must have accrued either credit or debit depending on their actions
						during enrolment.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once trying to enrol the student, you will notice the amount either in "Previous
						Owing" or "Balance Outstanding". If the student has credit to their name, then the
						balance outstanding will be less then that of the amount the class actually
						costs.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Payment</title>
		<para>By default the first contact is nominated as the payer. If you wish to switch this to
			another contact, click on the payment button on the left and change the name of the payer with
			the field provided. This can be either by using a customer reference or just selecting the
			payer name from the payer field. As always, you can also choose the payment option from
			here.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/QE_payment_options.png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Payment options available via Quick Enrol</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If a third party, such as an employer or agency are paying the fee, add them as a contact
			to the enrolment window as per the instructions above and set them as a payer. Select your
			payment method and payment amount. If the payer has any amount outstanding, that information
			will be added to the total fee. You can choose to pay the full amount owing, zero, or a
			portion of the amount owing. </para>
		<para> If the students are using a <uri>promotional code</uri> in their enrolment, enter it in
			this window. This discount will automatically be applied to all the eligible enrolments in
			this Quick Enrol window. </para>
		<para> If you select credit card, the details will be validated as you enter the information.
			The enrolment save process will not complete until the bank validates the card number.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Recording a cash payment</title>
			<para>To record a cash payment simply select 'cash' from the payment type drop down menu, once
				you have confirmed the payment amount is correct, just click save to complete the
				enrolment.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Recording a cheque payment</title>
			<para>To record a cheque payment you will need to follow these steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>select 'cheque' from the payment type drop down menu and the window will refresh to
						update the payment type</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>enter the cheque bank, cheque branch and cheque drawer in the fields that appear.
						Note that these are required fields within Quick Enrol and you will be unable to
						complete the enrolment unless you enter the cheque details. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>once you have confirmed the payment amount matches the cheque amount, just click
						save to complete the enrolment</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/QE_cheque_payments.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Cheque payment required fields within Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Recording an EFT payment </title>
			<para>An incoming course payment may have been processed on an EFTPOS terminal external to the
				onCourse system, even though the payment has been processed, you will still need to record
				the fact that the payment has been made within onCourse. To do this you will need to follow
				these steps: </para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>select EFT from the payment type drop down menu</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>once you have confirmed the payment amount, just click save to complete the
						enrolment</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Processing a credit card payment using Quick Enrol</title>
			<para>onCourse now has a new user interface for processing credit card payments via the
				onCourse client.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/QE_credit_card_payment_window.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Secure online payment window to process credit card payments</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para> To process a credit card payment via the secure payment gateway, you need to do the
				following steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select Credit Card from the payment type drop down menu within Quick Enrol</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once you have selected that payment type, you no longer need to enter the credit
						card details into the Quick Enrol window, as a separate browser window will open to
						enable you to enter the credit card details directly into the secure payment
						gateway.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To open up this new browser window and process the transaction, click on
							<guilabel>Save</guilabel> within the Quick Enrol window</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the credit card details into the secure payment window and then click
							<guilabel>Submit</guilabel>button to process the payment</para>
					<para>Whilst the secure payment is being processed, the Quick Enrol window will remain
						open with a processing enrolment message being displayed. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The payment will be processed and if successful, the payment gateway window will
						display the message <emphasis role="bold">payment was successful</emphasis> you can then
						close the payment browser window</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The Quick Enrol window will also update to show that the transaction was successful,
						you can then click OK and then send the enrolment confirmation as per the standard
						process. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Successful_CC_Payment_Message.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Secure payment browser window updates once transaction is successful</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/QE_Successful_CC_Payment_Message.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Quick Enrol window updates once payment has been processed</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<note>
				<para>In the event that there is an outage with your internet connection whilst a credit card
					transaction is being processed, for example the separate secure payment browser
					window is unable to be opened. An error message will appear notifying you that
					the payment is unable to proceed. You will need to wait for that payment attempt
					to time out before re-attempting the process. Timing out of a failed transaction
					ordinarily takes approximately 20 minutes.</para>
			</note>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Managing cancelled and failed credit card transactions</title>
			<para>As the credit card transaction is now managed within a separate and secure browser window,
				the process by which onCourse manages cancelled and unsuccessful transactions has
				also been updated</para>
			<para>This section outlines how you manage the cancellation process and how onCourse
				reconciles those cancelled transactions</para>
			<section>
				<title>How to cancel a credit card transaction</title>
				<para>To cancel a credit card transaction that you have commenced, you need to take the
					following steps:</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>To cancel a transaction that is underway, click on the <guilabel>Cancel</guilabel>
							button within the secure payment window. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The payment window will update to show the message <emphasis role="bold">this
								payment was cancelled</emphasis>. You can then close the browser window</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>In order to ensure that the invoice is reversed in onCourse, the system will
							automatically generate a credit note </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The Quick Enrol window will display the message <emphasis role="bold">Payment is
								cancelled. A credit note has been created.</emphasis></para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<tip>
					<para>If you proceed with opening the new browser window to enter the credit card details,
						then find you need to cancel that transaction, always make sure that you click the
							<guilabel>Cancel</guilabel> button within the secure payment browser window.</para>
					<para>If you close the browser window by clicking on the close button, the QE window will
						lock and you will not be able to use QE until the transaction is timed out after 20
						minutes.</para>
				</tip>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Cancelled_CC_Payment_Message.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Secure payment browser window updates once transaction has been cancelled</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/QE_Cancelled_CC_Payment_Message.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Quick Enrol window updates to notify user of cancellation and issuing of credit
							note.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>How to manage transactions where the payment has failed</title>
				<para>The following section outlines what happens if the credit card number that has been
					entered is declined due to an invalid number, or the card has expired or insufficient
					funds are available.</para>
				<para>When a credit card payment has failed, the secure payment window will display the
					message <emphasis role="bold">This payment failed because the card was expired, invalid or
						does not have sufficient funds</emphasis> You will then be presented with three
					different options to complete the transaction. These options are clearly displayed within
					the payment window and you can hover your mouse over these options to view an explanation
					of each option, before making your selection. </para>
				<section>
					<title>Option 1: Abandon the Transaction - Keep the Invoice</title>
					<para>The payment will be marked as failed, but the invoice and enrolments kept. The
						debtor will be kept, owing you money for later payment</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/Payment_Window_Abandon_Keep_Invoice.png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Option 1: Abandon the Transaction - Keep the Invoice</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Option 2: Abandon the Transaction - Reverse the Invoice</title>
					<para>The payment enrolments will be marked as failed and a credit note created to reverse
						the invoice.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/Payment_Window_Abandon_Reverse_Invoice.png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Option 2: Abandon the Transaction - Reverse the Invoice</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Option 3: Try another card</title>
					<para>If the first card entered is declined, by clicking on <emphasis role="bold">Try
							another card</emphasis>, the payment window is refreshed and you can then enter a
						different card number to complete the transaction. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/Payment_Window_Try_Another_Card.png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Option 3: Try another card</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>What do you do if you have recorded a payment (income) without any payment actually
				being made?</title>
			<para>If for example a student has not actually given any details or handed over cash to you,
				but someone from admin has recorded this in onCourse as payed, you will need to follow these
				steps to resolve it:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a credit note for the student for the amount incorrectly recorded as paid
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a payment out for the student for the full amount, for the same method as the
						original payment in was recorded as (e.g. EFT) </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a new invoice for the student for the amount owing. Leave this invoice as
						unpaid. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>If the student has paid (by the method as originally recorded) then nothing needs to be
				done in onCourse, except to perhaps attach a private note to the invoice to state that the
				payment was recorded on the wrong date</para>
			<para> If the student has paid but now by a different method, then the steps above need to be
				followed, with the added step of creating a new "payment in" record for the correct payment
				method. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I charge a cancellation fee after I have created the credit note for the full
				amount paid? </title>
			<para>The credit note and outstanding balance on an invoice will cancel each other out. If you
				try typing the payers name into quick enrol, you should find that there will be a total
				balance of zero, also, on the printed Debtors report, there will be a balance of zero, so
				this will not affect any future enrolments you make.</para>
			<para>An alternative option to creating an 'other charge' in quick enrol, is to click on the +
				button in the top hand corner of the invoice list view to create a manual invoice (or in
				this case, a credit note), but either way this produces the same result. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I change part of an enrolment fee to a business, and part to a student? </title>
			<para>The best way to charge part of an enrolment fee to someone and another part to someone
				else would be to follow these steps, we will use an example a student who has paid half of
				an enrolment and the other half has been paid for by their job network agency:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a credit note for the student for 50% of the class fee. This will now drop
						their balance outstanding down to 50% (or $0 if they have already paid their 50%)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a manual invoice for the job network agency using the method described
						above.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Process the payment in for Job network invoice when they pay it. </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>For an invoice, you can not record some of the payment coming from a person other than
				the payer (in this case the student). In the future you will also need to do this manually,
				so two invoices are issued, each for half the value of the enrolment fee. You might do this
				by giving the student a 50% discount on enrolment (and then issuing a manual invoice to the
				job network) or by doing the method outlined above and creating the credit note for the
				student post enrolment. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Tax invoices and enrolment confirmations</title>
		<para>If the student(s) have provided email addresses, you can choose to send this information
			now. Otherwise, it can be printed at a later date. Select for each student if you would like
			this information emailed and/or mailed. </para>
		<para>The enrolment confirmation goes to each student who has enrolled in a class. The tax
			invoice only goes to the payer. For example, if two friends were attending a class together,
			paid for by one of them as a gift to the other, only the payer would receive information about
			the fees charged. The person receiving the enrolment as a gift would simply receive an
			enrolment confirmation with no information regarding the cost. </para>
		<para>Press save to process, and save the enrolment. The completed enrolment will be visible as
			‘Active' in the Enrolment window. If the save button is greyed out, it means you have not
			entered all the required information. Look for the yellow Attention signs and pink fields to
			know where the error is coming from, also you can hover over the yellow attention signs for a
			brief explanation as to what may be causing the error.</para>
		<section>
		<title>Concessions</title>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>When processing an enrolment through Quick Enrol, you can discount course fees by
				using:</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>Concession – a standard discount automatically offered to a group of people, e.g.
					seniors, on a range of courses.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Promotion – a special offer accessed through a one-time code, used as a marketing
					tool.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Manual discount or surcharge – can be used to provide bulk discounts or to pay for
					additional services, such as phone enrolment booking fee. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para> More about concessions and promotions can be found in <xref xlink:href="#discounts"
			 /></para>
		<para> If a concession type has been set, and a student meets the requirements of the
			concession, such as holding a particular type of card, living in a certain area,or being a
			certain age, and the class they are enrolling in has been set to accept that concession type
			as a discount, then the discount will automatically be applied when they enrol. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/concessions1.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Enrolment with a concession applied for one class</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Promotional codes </title>
			<para>Promotional codes can be used by students enrolling over the web and by administration
				staff through onCourse Quick Enrol. In both instances, the code word must be supplied for
				the student to gain access to the discount. </para>
			<para> When processing an enrolment, enter the code in the field Promotional code in Quick
				Enrol. This will then discount the eligible classes as appropriate. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Prom_code.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Quick Enrol promotional code field (located to the right of the screen) </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>3rd Party Payments</title>
		<para>3rd Party Payments Enrolments can be paid for by the person enrolling, by other students,
			by the student's parent or spouse, by their employer or another agency, or anyone else you can
			think of. </para>
		<para> If someone other than the student enrolling is paying for the enrolment, it is called a
			third party payment. </para>
		<para> Any person paying for an enrolment on behalf of another person need to have a contact
			record set up within your onCourse database. This is because the invoice is linked to, and
			sent to, the payer. </para>
		<para> You can set up the payer contact record prior to enrolling the student, or at the time of
			enrolment, the same way you would <uri>set up any other contact </uri>within onCourse. </para>
		<example>
			<title>How to enrol a student with a 3rd party payer</title>
			<para>In the example below, the student's employer is paying for the enrolment.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Both the student, Peter Jones, and the payer, NSW Department of Commerce are added
						to the enrolment. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Mark is enrolled in the class, MYOB (V16) Accounting Essentials.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>NSW Department of Commerce is selected as the payer.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>No payment is made at this time. An invoice will the full balance outstanding is
						emailed to NSW Department of Commerce. Peter is emailed his enrolment confirmation.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to add a company as a contact </title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to onCourse Customer Service tab > choose 'Contact' button > hit the + button in
						the top right-hand corner </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Hit the 'Company' button in the top right-hand corner > complete the contact details
						for the company that you will be invoicing > then click 'Save' </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to enrol a student and Invoice a Company for the enrolment</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to onCourse Customer Service tab > choose 'Quick Enrol' button</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the Student Name in the 'Name' field (when you hit tab, all the previously
						entered info should auto-populate) </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click 'Add' in the top left-hand corner > highlight the 'Enter Contact' field that
						appears in the left-hand frame </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Then click the 'Company' button that appears in the top right-hand corner > in the
						'Name' field type the name of the company you wish to invoice </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight the 'Enter Enrolment' option in the left-hand frame of the Quick Enrol
						process > then type the Course Name or Course Code </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight the 'Payment: None' option in the left-hand frame of the Quick Enrol
						process > then click on the drop-down menu in the 'Payer' field and select the company
						you wish to invoice </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Make the payment amount $0.00 (this will automatically generate an Invoice to the
						Payer) > then click 'Save' </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You will be prompted to Print and Email an Invoice and Enrolment Confirmation,
						choose Print for the Invoice > then choose 'Save PDF' if you want to email the Invoice
						to the company or, choose 'Print' if you want to post the invoice to the company </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to refund a company for payment marked as received, but should have been invoiced </title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to onCourse Accounts tab > choose 'Payment Out' button > hit the + button in the
						top right-hand corner </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Type the company name in the 'Payment to' field > the amount paid should be for the
						amount that was marked as received > add a Private note e.g. billing correction > then
						click 'Save' </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to manage an overpayment by a student </title>
			<para>onCourse does not allow overpayments of invoices. This is a deliberate design function
				to ensure data entry errors are not made. If a student presents a cheque made out for the
				wrong amount, so you can bank and process the cheque you can do the following:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create the enrolment as usual in Quick Enrol</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Add an 'other charge' to the enrolment, with a line item title like
						'overpayment'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Process the payment in Quick Enrol with the total balance of the cheque that has
						been presented.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Go to Invoices and create a manual credit note for the person who made an
						overpayment. This credit can then be used towards other enrolments or refunded. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Payments In</title>
		<para>Payment In, is defined as receiving money into your company, a type of income. In regards
			to onCourse, it is a tool used to take money owing from a student. Payment Out, as you may
			expect means the opposite, to give money to someone that is owed money.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Payment_In.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Creating a payment in</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Processing a Payment In</title>
			<example>
				<title>How to process a payment in</title>
				<para>Payments In can be accessed from the splash screen or from the <emphasis role="bold"
						>Financial</emphasis> menu tab the top of your screen. To process a Payment In, follow
					these steps (assuming student has debt with you):</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Go the Payment In page either through the onCourse home screen Accounts>>Payment
							In, or by selecting "Financial" from the top menu, then "Payment In"</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>From here click on the + (Add) symbol in the top right hand side of the
							window.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Type in the payer name in the "Payment from" feld, remembering the field has
							autocomplete functionality. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select payment method and make sure all other details are in order before clicking
							the "save" button.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>After you complete this a email will be sent to the payer with the payment details
							and the payer record will appear in the list view of "Payment In".</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
			<example>
				<title>Example of a Payment In</title>
				<para>A student owes $169.40. Payment of $80 is made in this payment, $89.40 still owing.
					Paying an amount outstanding through Quick Enrol. </para>
			</example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Students who already owe you money</title>
			<para>As soon as a student with a balance outstanding is selected as part of the<uri>normal
					enrolment process</uri> , the amount owing will be displayed in fee summary under
				"Previous owing" for this payer. Any new enrolments you process at the time will add to
				their total amount owing. If the student has credit with your college, their credit will be
				automatically deducted from the total owing. </para>
			<para>You can choose, when you process the enrolment, to pay the full amount owing, or just a
				portion of it. </para>
			<example>
				<title>Example of paying off a previous and current enrolment together </title>
				<para>The student enrolling in a class costing $143, owes $169.40 from a previous enrolment.
					They pay the full balance during the Quick Enrol process. </para>
			</example>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/quick_enroll.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Student enrolling who has fees outstanding</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
