<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="product">
    <title>Other products</title>
    <para>A range of products can be sold through onCourse. You have already seen how you can create
        classes and open them for enrolment at any price you set. In addition to enrolments in
        classes you can also sell:</para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Memberships</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Vouchers</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Products</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>In this chapter we'll focus on the last of these items: product sales. For more
        information on memberships, see <link xlink:href="#concessions">the concessions and
            memberships chapter</link> and for more information on vouchers, see <link
            xlink:href="#vouchers">the vouchers chapter</link>.</para>
    <para>Products in onCourse are a simple way to supply additional, defined items during an
        enrolment sale. onCourse does not manage a stock inventory or the shipping of products. It
        is expected that most products will be supplied to the student in person when they attend
        the class.</para>
    <section xml:id="products-navigatingAround">
        <title>Navigating around the Product window</title>
        <para> To open the product window you can either use the splash screen and click on the
            Voucher type option in the Marketing tab or the onCourse menu Resources →
            Products</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/products_list.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>View of the products window</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="products-Adding">
        <title>Adding a new product</title>
        <para> There are a number of fields in this tab, they are:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Name - allows you to name the product.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Code - allows you to create a code for this product.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Description - this allows you to include a description of the product in
                        rich text, useful for the online marketing of the product.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Income account - allows you to select what income account this is
                        connected to.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Status - you can choose whether this product can be either disabled;
                        purchased in the office only; or purchased in the office as well as
                        online.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist><mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/adding_a_new_product.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>View of the new product window</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject></para>
    </section>
<section xml:id="products-relatingToACourse">
        <title>Relating a product to a course</title>
        <para>Products can be related to courses, for example, if there is a textbook you suggest
            purchasing a long with enrolling in the course.</para>
        <para>After you have created the product, open the course which you with to relate it to, on
            the Marketing tab.</para>
        <para>Click on the plus button + on the panel related courses/products to add a new product
            to the list.</para>
        <para>Search for the product by it's name or SKU and save. The product will then appear on
            the web and in Quick Enrol as a suggested related purchase during enrolment in a class
            from this course.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/related_product.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Adding a product 'Cookies' as a related product to this course</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="products-Purchasing">
        <title>Purchasing a product</title>
        <para>A product can be purchased from Quick Enrol, either in conjunction with an enrolment
            or as a standalone purchase.</para>
        <para>Products can be purchased by clicking on the field Enter course or item...' then you
            can either click on the 'Show all' button next to the word PRODUCTS on the right side of
            the page and select one of the products listed. Alternatively you can start typing and
            the rest of the product record will be automatically filled. </para>
        <para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/adding_a_product_in_QE.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>View of Quick Enrol after you have clicked on the 'Enter course or
                        item...' field and selected show all next to PRODUCTS</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
        <para>Once you have found the product you want to add you can choose who you want to supply
            it to, if there is more than one contact listed. Then you can specify how many products
            want to be bought and you have the option to change the price before or after GST if
            needed.</para>
        <note>
            <para>If you change the 'Price each ex tax' field it will update the Total price to the
                correct amount, this will work in reverse also.</para>
        </note>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/Editing_a_product_added_in_QE.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>View in Quick Enrol when the product 'Chair' has been added</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
