<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="rto">
	<title>RTO Setup</title>
	<section>
		<title>Chapter Overview</title>
		<para>This chapter looks at how a RTO can prepare their courses and classes in onCourse to
			ensure they're set up properly and can correctly report their data for funding. Included
			in this chapter is what to do before taking enrolments, how to set up funding
			sources/contracts, and how to set up sites, courses and classes.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="rto-enrolments">
		<title>Before Taking Enrolments</title>
		<para>If you're required to report AVETMISS or funded training there are a few steps you'll
			need to take to ensure that reporting time goes as smoothly as possible. Do these things
			before you accept your first enrolment into any VET classes.</para>
		<section xml:id="rto-enrolments-general">
			<title>Set up General Preferences</title>
			<para>Set up your AVETMISS details within the General Preferences window. To access
				this, in the navigation menu click File > Preferences > General, then find the
				AVETMISS tab in the left-hand column on the window. 'Show RTO related screens and
				menus' should be enabled. Then fill out the rest of the page and be especially
				certain that both your Training organisation name and RTO Identifier field match the
				details recorded on training.gov.au.</para>
			<para>When you've finished, hit the 'Save' button in the top-corner of the window, then
				close it.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="rto-enrolments-competency">
			<title>Competency components</title>
			<para>onCourse imports information from training.gov.au such as Qualifications, Accredited
				Courses, Skill groups/sets, Units of Competency, and Modules. It also tracks higher
				education Courses and Units of Study. </para>
			<para>onCourse automatically imports all this data regularly. You can view Units of
				Competency or Qualifications form the nav menu by clicking Training > Units of
				Competency or Training > Qualifications. </para>
			<para>You can also create your own competencies for skills groups, modules and higher
				education which aren't imported automatically from training.gov.au. You can learn
				how to create your own Modules, Units of Competency and Qualifications in the
				paragraphs directly below.</para>
			<section xml:id="rto-createModules">
				<title>How to create your own Modules and Units of
					Competency</title>
				<para>You can add your own modules and units of competency to the onCourse system
					from within the Units of Competency window (Training > Units of Competency) by
					clicking the + button in the bottom navigation panel. It will open a new column
					in the window where you must enter a title, the national code, the field of
					education code, a credit points value and an expiry days value. You cannot save
					the record without these fields being filled. After filling these fields, the
					save icon will become enabled. Click the icon to save the record.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/new_uoc_add.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>A new unit of competency being created</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>There is an additional field for specialization, however this is not mandatory
					in order to save the record.</para>
				<para>Type is a drop-down box where you can select whether the record is for a unit
					of competency, a unit of study, a module, or other.</para>
				<para>There is a check box called 'Is Module'. If checked, then the record will be
					classed as a module for use within a qualification. If this is not checked, then
					the record is considered a unit of competency for use within non-accredited
					courses. There's also an 'Is Offered' check box that, when ticked, flags that
					UoC as being offered by your college.</para>
				<para>You can delete a custom record by highlighting it and clicking the cogwheel
					icon, then clicking delete record. You can only delete custom records.</para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="rto-createQual">
				<title>How to create your own Qualifications</title>
				<para>From within the Qualifications window (Training > Qualifications) you can
					create your own Qualifications and Skill Sets. There are four mandatory fields
					that must be filled out before the record can be created: Type, Level, Title and
					National Code.</para>
				<para>The Type field is a drop-down box that will allow you specify the type of
					record; a qualification, an accredited course, a skill set, a local skill set,
					or higher education. Level, title and national code are all free-text
					fields.</para>
				<para>Additional fields include the ANZSCO number, field of education code,
					specialization code and the number of nominal hours. There's also an 'Is
					Offered' check box that, when ticked, flags that qualification as being offered
					by your college.</para>
				<para>You can delete a custom record by highlighting it and clicking the cogwheel
					icon, then clicking Delete Record. You can only delete custom records.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/delete_custom_qual.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Deleting a custom qualification</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title xml:id="rto-enrolments-sites">Site setup</title>
			<para>Before creating courses or classes, you should ensure that all of the sites you've
				set up have the correct address, suburb, postcode and timezone set. Any sites that
				are used for VET classes will have most of these details included in reporting, so
				ensuring accuracy in this data is important.</para>
			<para>You can learn more details about <link linkend="sitesRooms">adding Sites and Rooms
					here</link>.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="rto-enrolments-courses">
			<title>Course setup</title>
			<tip>
				<para>In this section when we talk about Qualifications we really mean
					"Qualifications, Accredited Courses or Skillsets". When we say "Unit of
					Competency" we also include "Modules". Although the words are different between
					state and commonwealth accreditation regimes, the processes in onCourse are
					exactly the same.</para>
			</tip>
			<para>Before going any further, you should read the <link
					xlink:href="courses.xml#courses">Courses chapter</link> to understand the basics
				of what a course is in onCourse, and how to go about creating one.</para>
			<para>Once you have a course created, in the VET tab of the new course record you can
				select the Qualification and the Units from the built in NTIS data for your chosen
				course. If your course is VET, but not from a training package or accredited course,
				you can also flag it VET here and allocate its Field of Education ID. This is
				something you may need to do as part of your government funding requirements for non
				accredited courses.</para>
			<tip>
				<para>Do you deliver state accredited courses? You will find the course listed in
					onCourse but not the modules that make up the course. This is because they are
					not publicly available on training.gov.au. You can add your own by hitting the +
					button on either the Qualifications or Units of Competency windows.</para>
			</tip>
			<para>onCourse does not contain the qualification packaging rules, so it is up to you as
				the RTO to ensure that you are compliant with your own scope of registration and the
				requirements of the training packages you are authorised to deliver. You should
				refer to these requirements when creating your courses and only select those units
				which are allowed to contribute towards that particular qualification.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<title>There are a few different ways you can structure VET Courses within
					onCourse:</title>
				<listitem>
					<para> A full Qualification where you know all the units the students will
						complete in advance i.e. all students will complete the same core and
						elective units. Students will graduate with a complete Qualification.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A full Qualification where all students will undertake the core units, but
						may all select different elective units. Students will graduate with a
						complete Qualification.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A short course which has one or more units of competency embedded within
						it. The units may or may not all contribute to the same Qualification.
						Students will graduate with a Statement of Attainment.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A short course where you know which qualification a student will be
						working towards in advance, but the students in the class will complete a
						variable number and selection of units. Some may achieve a Statement of
						Attainment, some may be working towards a full Qualification, and some may
						simply receive a non-vet Statement of Attendance.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A course which is not linked to any national or state accredited training
						packages or accredited courses, but has a vocational learning outcome.
						Depending on your reporting requirements, these courses may also contribute
						towards your annual VET delivery.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>In onCourse, outcomes (records of undertaking and achieving a unit of competency)
				flow down from the course to the student via an enrolment in a class. If a course
				has 15 units attached to it, the students enrolled in that class will have 15
				outcomes created for them - one for each unit. You can always modify the units for
				the student in their own enrolment, for example if they change to a different
				elective. </para>
			<section>
				<title>Creating a VET Course</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Go to Courses and hit the + button to create a new course record. For
							a detailed view on how to create a new course in onCourse, <link
								xlink:href="courses.xml#courses">visit our Courses chapter</link>.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>When you're done with the initial course setup, open the
								<guibutton>VET tab</guibutton>.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Enter the <guilabel>National Code</guilabel>. The fields are
							clairvoyant, so as you type in them, onCourse will search for and list
							the qualifications in the built in training.gov.au database. Select the
							qualification by clicking on it. You can also search for qualification
							by name in <guilabel>Qualification</guilabel>. Omit the words
							Certificate in or Diploma of in your search. For example, search for the
							Certificate IV in Aged Care by typing 'Aged Care'.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> The qualification information is broken into different fields so the
							Certificate IV Training and Assessment would read <guilabel>National
								code</guilabel> - TAA40104 <guilabel>Qualification</guilabel> -
							Training and Assessment <guilabel>Level</guilabel> - Certificate IV
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can then add modules and the units by clicking the
								<guibutton>+</guibutton>icon on the right hand side of the screen.
							This will open a drop down screen.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Enter the <guilabel>National Code</guilabel> or
								<guilabel>Title</guilabel> These fields are also clairvoyant so make
							your selection and press ok. You will then be returned to the course
							screen where you will see the modules and units listed. To add more
							units simply click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton>sign and repeat the
							process. To delete any units, click the <guibutton>-</guibutton> sign.
							When you are done, click <guibutton>save</guibutton>. You can also set
							the nominal hours for the units as you attach them to the course.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/vet_course_tab.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The VET tab of the course, showing a full qualification with selected
							units</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>How to "add" a unit of competency to a course</title>
				<para>You cannot actually add a Unit of competency to a course if it already has
					enrolments (see the caution above), you can only cancel the old course and then
					create a new course with the additional unit of competency you want included.
					This is because changing the units of competency changes the very nature of the
					course, but the history of the old course and it's previous students need to be
					retained. </para>
				<para>If needed, you can also add units directly to student enrolments. This will
					not change the course units for new students enrolling, but can be used to
					correct or update the records of existing students.</para>
				<para>If the unit change is substantial, you may want to consider creating a new
					class against the new course, and transferring all the students from the class
					linked to the old course to the class linked to the new course. This will remove
					all the old units from their record (provided outcomes have not yet been set),
					and with their new enrolment, add all the new units to their record.</para>
				<caution>
					<title>Changing units in a course</title>
					<para>Once a course has a class with an enrolment in it you CAN NOT change the
						units of competency assigned to the course. This is because onCourse has
						created an immutable relationship with this data - if you changed it at the
						course level, every student ever enrolled in a class for this course would
						have their outcomes changed. </para>
					<para>However - you can always retire the old course and create a new course to
						use for future enrolment using the 'duplicate course' option in the list
						view cogwheel. The new course can have the same name but will have to have a
						different course code. You may choose to change the code of the old course
						instead, so the new course can use the existing code, which is advantageous
						for your SEO. Make sure to set the status of the old course to 'course
						disabled' and when you are ready, the status of the new course to 'enabled
						and visible online'. </para>
					<para>You may also want to duplicate one of the classes from the old course and
						assign it to the new course to use the same timetables and teaching
						schedules. </para>
				</caution>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>How to duplicate a course:</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>First go to "Course" list view and single click to select the old
							version of the course</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>From the cogwheel, select the option 'duplicate course'. This will
							make another course with the same name and all the same content, with a
							course code with a 1 on the end.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Courses can have the same name, but every course has to have a unique
							code. Because the course code is what forms your URL on the website, it
							is better for SEO purposes to change the code of the old course to
							something different before you disable it e.g. BCDCERTV could become
							oldBCDCERTV. Then you can change the code of the new version of the
							course from BCDCERTV1 back to BCDCERTV.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open the old version of the course and set the status to 'course
							disabled'.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open the new version of the course and make the required changes to
							the listed units of competency by adding or deleting from the current
							list on the VET tab. Note you will need to delete all the non-required
							units, save the record, and then reopen it to add new units.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>When you are ready to save and close the new course, set the course
							status to 'enabled and visible online' </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<orderedlist>
					<title>How to duplicate a class from an old course to a new course:</title>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open the class list view and locate a recent class from the old
							course. Following from the example before, this might be class
							oldBCDCERTV-90.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Using the class cog wheel option, duplicate this class, making any
							changes to the dates as appropriate. This new class will have the code
							oldBCDCERTV-91 and be linked to the old course.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Double click on the new class to open it. In the course code field in
							the top right hand corner, change the code from the old course to the
							new course e.g. BCDCERTV. This has now linked the class to the new
							course. Save and close.</para>
						<para>NOTE: You can only change the course a class is linked to before any
							enrolments are processed into the class. If a class has enrolments, even
							if those enrolments are cancelled, you can not change the course code it
							is linked to.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Courses which are complete qualifications or skill sets</title>
				<para>When a course has the flag 'Satisfies complete qualification or skill set'
					checked on the VET tab, this means that if the student successfully completes
					all of the attached units, they will be eligible for a Qualification or Skill
					Set Statement of Attainment. </para>
				<para>Using the automatic 'create Certificates' options from the class or enrolment
					cogwheels will look at the value of this flag and determine what type of
					certification to create.</para>
				<para>This flag, for AVETMISS purposes, also signifies the student's intent to
					complete a qualification. Outcomes linked to a class with this flag checked will
					be reported linked to the parent qualification, where courses where this isn't
					selected will be reported as module only enrolments.</para>
				<para>This value of this checkbox can be changed as needed after the course has been
					created, and even after students have enrolled.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Partial qualifications</title>
				<para>Remember that in onCourse a course is about the product you are selling to
					your students. Sometimes you may break a program of study e.g. full
					qualification into lots of short courses for students to buy, complete and over
					time, to work towards the final outcome of a qualification.</para>
				<para>In onCourse, courses don't have to be linked to a qualification or a unit of
					competency. They can just be a non-accredited course.</para>
				<para>If students are working towards a unit of competency that they will complete
					in another course, you may like to indicate this in the program description that
					you use for marketing purposes. If the student only completes this course, they
					will only be eligible for a non-accredited Certificate of Attendance, not a
					Statement of Attainment.</para>
				<para>You can set up this type of program in onCourse by attaching the Qualification
					that the student will be working towards in the VET tab of the course, but not
					adding any Units of Competency to the course. You do not have to add the
					Qualification at all - this is optional, and would not be appropriate if the
					program of study never led to any formal Qualification outcome.</para>
				<para>When students enrol in this course, they will get a dummy outcome (used for
					reporting purposes in some states) with the name of the course. You can set this
					dummy outcome to pass (81) or fail (82). Using this outcome, you will then know
					when the student enrols in the next course (where the units have been attached)
					that they have successfully completed the part one component.</para>
				<para>When you set up the second part of the course, you will add the qualification
					and the units to the VET tab, so when the student enrols they will get the
					appropriate units of competency added to their record. Then you are able to
					record their final outcome result as per the standard list of VET
					options.</para>
				<para>In the example below, a student is working towards a cluster of units from the
					Certificate I in IT. Only when they have completed the second course,
					Understanding Computer Basics, are they eligible to be assessed against the unit
					outcomes. The first course, Computing Basics, has no units attached, and the
					second course has three units attached. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/computing_basics.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>1st course: The Qualification is attached to the course, but the
							student has not completed any units of competency by completing this
							course</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/understanding_computer_basics.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>2nd course: The Qualification and Units are attached to this course.
							After completing part 1 and 2 the student can now be assessed.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/vet_student_outcomes.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The student record shows a 'dummy' outcome for the course with no
							units. They have completed it successfully. Now they can be assessed
							against the other units.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="rto-enrolments-classes">
			<title>Class setup</title>
			<para>First, you should be familiar with creating a class in onCourse. You can learn how
				to do this <link xlink:href="classes.xml#classes">in our Classes
				chapter</link>.</para>
			<para>Where a class has multiple units of competency assigned to it, you may wish to
				create a training plan to define at which points during the class delivery each unit
				begins and ends. </para>
			<para>For some government funding training, is it important in the AVETMISS reporting to
				show the sequence of the delivery of units by having varied start and end dates.
				Training plans allow you to achieve this.</para>
			<para>Training plans are linked to sessions and can be found in the class timetable. </para>
			<para>By default, all units of competency are assigned to all sessions unless you choose
				to change this in the training plan. Units can not be assigned to no sessions as
				they would then have no start or end date, creating errors in AVETMISS
				reporting.</para>
			<para>The Training Plan report allows you to provide hard copy evidence of the outcomes
				delivered in each sessions of you class and the tutors you have assigned to deliver
				them. This report may be useful to provide to government funding bodies or ASQA
				auditors, as well as being used for internal planning and resource
				management.</para>
			<example>
				<title>How to create a class training plan</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>For an existing VET class, open the class record and go to the
							Timetable tab. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select a session from the list to view the Training Plan in the left
							hand panel of the timetable. By default, all the available units will be
							ticked. You can tick all/ untick all as needed to start preparing the
							training plan for that session.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/assessment/timetable_training_plan.png"
									format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Select all outcomes for delivery during a session</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Progressing through each session, select and de-select the units in
							the left hand panel which will be delivered in that session.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Note that the first session where the unit is delivered and the last
							session where the unit is delivered will become the start and end dates
							of the outcomes. If there are sessions in between these two where the
							unit is not selected, this will have no impact on your AVETMISS
							reporting, only your internal resource management.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>For each session in the timetable, you can define one or more tutors
							and one or more units. These combine to form the training plan.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once the class record has been saved, the start and end dates now set
							for each unit are available on the class Outcomes panel, in the training
							plan section. The lower half of the window shows the outcomes assigned
							to student enrolled in this class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The start dates and end dates defined by each unit must fall within
							the sessions of the class. You can not manually set a date in a training
							plan outside the class boundaries, but you can do this on an outcome by
							outcome basis if required.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If a student's outcome has been modified manually e.g. the end date
							has been extended beyond the duration of the class, the Training Plan
							settings will not modify the manual overrides you have created. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>To print the training plan report for class, save and close the record
							and ensure the class is selected in the class list view. Select File >
							Print > Training Plan to print the report. </para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/reports/TrainingPlanPageOne.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Training Plan Report showing the unit list and their start and
									end dates</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/reports/TrainingPlanPageTwo.png" format="png"/>
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Training Plan Report showing the units scheduled for delivery
									for each session and the tutors responsible for their
									delivery</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Funding source</title>
			<para>Once you've created the class, add the correct funding contract at the Class level
				via the VET tab, and then make any required changes for individual students at the
				Enrolment level. To learn more about <link linkend="fundingContract">Funding
					Contracts, click here </link>. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
