<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="rto">
	<title>RTO Guide</title>
	<para>Documentation for features that relate to delivering Australian Vocational Education</para>
	<section>
		<title>Understanding how outcomes are attached to enrolments</title>
		<para>When a VET course is created, qualifications and units of competency are set at the course
			level. More information about setting up VET courses is available in the <link
				xlink:href="#coursesVET">courses chapter</link>. Classes for the course inherit the
			units set at the course level. You can see these units in the Training Plan on the
			outcomes tab of the class.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Training_plan_timetable.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting units of competency to be delivered in the first class session</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>When a student enrols in the class, the units of competency attached to the course become
			the outcomes attached to the student's enrolment. The start and end date of class become
			the start and end date of the outcomes, unless you choose to define different dates in
			the training plan. The settings on the class VET tab become the default settings for
			each outcome for that class, but can be changed on an outcome by outcome basis. Within
			the class level outcomes can be changed or set, but can not be deleted and new outcomes
			can not be added here. </para>
		<para>You can see the outcomes that have been assigned to each student  in the class on the
			outcomes tab, in the student's record on the enrolment tab, and on the enrolment record
			on the outcomes tab.</para>
		<para>Via the student's enrolment record, outcomes added in error can be deleted from the
			enrolment record and additional outcomes can be added. Adding or deleting outcomes needs
			to be done per enrolment. Outcomes can not be added to the class or directly to the
			student record.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Training_Plan_outcomes.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Showing the start and end dates for each unit assigned to this class on the outcomes tab</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating Class Training Plans</title>
		<para>Where a class has multiple units of competency assigned to it, you may wish to create a
			training plan to define at which points during the class delivery each unit begins and
			ends. </para>
		<para>For some government funding training, is it important in the AVETMISS reporting to
			show the sequence of the delivery of units by having varied start and end dates.
			Training plans allow you to achieve this.</para>
		<para>Training plans are linked to sessions and can be found in the class timetable. </para>
		<para>By default, all units of competency are assigned to all sessions unless you choose to
			change this in the training plan. Units can not be assigned to no sessions as they would
			then have no start or end date, creating errors in AVETMISS reporting.</para>
		<para>The Training Plan report allows you to provide hard copy evidence of the outcomes
			delivered in each sessions of you class and the tutors you have assigned to deliver
			them. This report may be useful to provide to government funding bodies or ASQA
			auditors, as well as being used for internal planning and resource management.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a class training plan</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>For an existing VET class, open the class record and go to the Timetable
						tab. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select a session from the list to view the Training Plan in the left hand
						panel of the timetable. By default, all the available units will be
						ticked.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Progressing through each session, select and de-select the units in the left hand panel
						which will be delivered in that session.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Note that the first session where the unit is delivered and the last
						session where the unit is delivered will become the start and end dates of
						the outcomes. If there are sessions in between these two where the unit is
						not selected, this will have no impact on your AVETMISS reporting, only your
						internal resource management.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>For each session in the timetable, you can define one or more tutors and
						one or more units. These combine to form the training plan.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once the class record has been saved, the start and end dates now set for
						each unit are available on the class Outcomes panel, in the training plan
						section. The lower half of the window shows the outcomes assigned to student
						enrolled in this class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The start dates and end dates defined by each unit must fall within the
						sessions of the class. You can not manually set a date in a training plan
						outside the class boundaries, but you can do this on an outcome by outcome
						basis if required.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If a student's outcome has been modified manually e.g. the end date has
						been extended beyond the duration of the class, the Training Plan settings
						will not modify the manual overrides you have created. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To print the training plan report for class, save and close the record and
						ensure the class is selected in the class list view. Select File > Print >
						Training Plan to print the report. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/TP_Report_pg1.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Training Plan Report showing the unit list and their start and end dates</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/TP_Report_pg2.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Training Plan Report showing the units scheduled for delivery for each session and the
								tutors responsible for their delivery</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Setting and modifying outcomes</title>
		<para>How to set and customise outcomes to meet your reporting needs</para>
		<para>When you set up a VET course and class and enrol students, outcomes will automatically be
			created for each of the units of competency you assigned to the course, with the properties
			start and end date, reportable hours, delivery mode and funding type you set in the
			class.</para>
		<para>There are multiple places you can access the outcomes and set them, plus modify the
			details mentioned above for individual students – in the class outcome tab, in the student
			enrolments tab, in the enrolment outcomes tab, and in the certificate window when you are
			creating a new certificate.</para>
		<section>
			<title>What are outcomes?</title>
			<para>A students outcome is the record of their engagement with a Unit of Competency or Module
				from a training package or accredited course. Outcomes are often reported to government
				through processes such as AVETMISS and must meet certain validation rules. Primarily, an
				outcome records if a student has passed or failed their course. The outcomes available for
				selection are as follows:</para>
			<simplelist>
				<member> Competency achieved/pass (20)</member>
				<member> Competency not achieved/fail (30)</member>
				<member> Withdrawn (40)</member>
				<member> Recognition of prior learning granted (51)</member>
				<member> Recognition of prior learning not granted (52)</member>
				<member> Recognition of current competency granted (53)</member>
				<member> Recognition of current competency not granted (54)</member>
				<member> Credit transfer (60)</member>
				<member> Did not start (NSW: 66, SA: @@)</member>
				<member> Continuing enrolment (70) *</member>
				<member> Non-assessed enrolment – Satisfactorily completed (81) **</member>
				<member> Non-assessed enrolment – Withdrawn or not satisfactorily completed (82)</member>
				<member> Result not available (90) ***</member>
			</simplelist>
			<para>Refer to the NCVER publications, VET Provider Collection Specifications and AVETMISS
				Data Element Definitions for more information regarding the definitions and use of these
				outcomes.</para>
			<para>* You do not need to set the outcome 'Continuing enrolment (70)' for any outcomes.
				During the AVETMISS export process, if the outcome end date is after the date range
				of the export, this outcome will automatically be exported.</para>
			<para>** If you export data for non-VET outcomes, you do not need to set the outcome
				'Non-assessed enrolment – Satisfactorily completed (81)'. This will always be
				exported for unset non-VET outcomes. </para>
			<para>*** You may not need to set 'Result not available (90)'. During the export
				process, you can choose to set this outcome for all unset VET outcomes</para>
			<section>
				<title>Setting individual outcomes</title>
				<para>To set the outcome, modify the start or end date, or delivery mode, simply click in
					the list view field you wish to change and enter the data. To modify the unit/module the
					outcome is linked to, to change the funding source or change the reportable hours, click
					the expansion option to open the full outcome edit window.</para>
				<para>If you wish to add additional outcomes to a students enrolment, open the enrolment
					record to the outcome tab, and click the plus sign to add an outcome. You may need to do
					this if a student completes an additional unit by RPL, or if the entire class complete an
					additional unit to what was originally planned in the course.</para>
				<note>
					<para>When setting a given Class as <guilabel>Self Paced</guilabel>, the start date and end date
						for the student outcomes are set as follows: </para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>Start Date is the date the student enrols in the Class</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>End Date is the start date plus the maximum days to complete that has been set for the Class
								via the General tab.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</note>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Setting outcomes in bulk</title>
				<para>In the class window, the outcome of one, some or all students can be selected and set
					as a single action.</para>
				<para>Select the outcomes you wish to set by clicking the first outcome, holding down shift
					(to select all in the range) or control / command (to select only those you click on).
					Then right click on any of the selected records and set the outcomes to successful. This
					will then set all the records to 20 in a VET class, or to 81 in a non-VET class.</para>
				<para>If you set an outcome to successful' in error, can always select it again individually
					and set it to a different outcome. This means you can set a whole class group to
					successful very quickly, then go back and change the outcomes for the 1 or 2 students who
					did not pass to <emphasis>30 – Competency not achieved/fail.</emphasis></para>
				<note>
					<para> Only the 'successful' outcome can be set in bulk </para>
				</note>
				<qandaset>
					<title>Outcomes FAQ</title>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para> Why would I want to change the start and end date of an outcome? </para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para> If a class falls over a collection period (usually a calendar year) and some
								students have been assessed and passed already, they can be reported with an end
								date in the current year. The students who have not yet been assessed, and have end
								dates in the following year will be automatically exported with outcomes of 70. You
								do not need to set the outcome to 70, then come back and change it when the results
								are received. </para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para> What is the funding source field for? </para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para> In some types of classes, overseas fee paying students may be attending, as
								well as Australian fee-paying students, and Australian government funded students.
								By setting the appropriate funding source at the outcome level, you report the
								correct student contact hours to your funding body, without having to move student
								enrolments into different class groups. If you deliver CSWE programs, where this
								often an issue, there is more information available here about how to set up your
								courses and outcomes. </para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para> I report my statistics to BACE and also need to report my non-accredited course
								outcomes. How do I do this? </para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para> ‘outcomes' are also created for general enrolments and VET flagged
								non-accredited courses. On export, they will automatically be set as type
									<emphasis>81 – Non-assessed enrolment – Satisfactorily completed</emphasis>. You
								still need to manually set the outcomes for students who do not complete or attend
								the class as <emphasis> 82 – Non-assessed enrolment – Withdrawn or not
									satisfactorily completed</emphasis>
							</para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para> What are reportable hours? </para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para> There is some disagreement between different state funding bodies on what
								number should appear in this field. Generally, it is understood to be the nominal
								hours, as defined by NCVER tables. The nominal hours set for each module will be the
								default reportable hours reported in your NAT00120 file. Non-accredited courses
								report the classroom hours in this field. If you prefer to report the classroom
								hours in this field, you can set this in the class VET tab, however you will need to
								do this BEFORE enrolling students, otherwise you will need to change the hours
								outcome by outcome. In some cases, you may need to modify the nominal hours reported
								for students being funded under particular programs, and you should do this in their
								outcome record. </para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para> A student who enrolled in one of our VET classes has completed and passed the
								assessment without attending the class. How do I report them? </para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para> You can report them as <emphasis>53 – Recognition of current competency
									granted</emphasis> and should change their outcomes delivery type to <emphasis>
									N/A(eg. RPL, credit transfer)</emphasis>
							</para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question>
							<para> A student has completed units towards the qualification they are studying at
								our college elsewhere. How do I add them to their record? </para>
						</question>
						<answer>
							<para> Find an enrolment record for the student and open the outcomes tab. Here you
								can add additional outcomes as needed. Units completed at another training
								organisation should be marked as <emphasis> 60 – Credit transfer</emphasis> and
								their nominal hours are not counted towards your colleges annual delivery. On the
								‘Notes' tab of the students record, you can also add attachments, and it would be
								appropriate to scan and attach copies of their original certification and any other
								supporting documents they have provided here, for your own records. </para>
						</answer>
					</qandaentry>
					<qandaentry>
						<question><para>A student has changed their mind about an elective choice, or wishes to do an additional unit. How do I add or change their record?</para></question>
						<answer><para>Find the enrolment record for the student and open the outcomes tab. Here you can change,
								delete or add additional outcomes as needed. To change an outcome
								from one unit to another, double click on the outcome record and
								change the module code. Modules for which you have already issued
								certificates for can not be edited and you'll see that they are
								greyed out. </para>
							<para>Using the plus or delete icon in the top right hand corner allows you to add or remove
								modules to the student's record. You can add as many units as you
								need, and delete all bar one unit from the record. All enrolments
								must be linked to at least one unit of competency.</para></answer>
					</qandaentry>
				</qandaset>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/add_unit.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Add an additional unit to the student's enrolment record by click the plus</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>CSWE courses, classes and outcomes</title>
		<para>Making government reporting less of a hassle for student focused literacy program</para>
		<section>
			<title>Setting up Certificate in Spoken and Written English (CSWE) courses</title>
			<para> Some colleges who deliver CSWE courses run open English language programs at different
				levels, aligned to the levels available in the CSWE program. Students enrol in course that
				is of an appropriate level and when a class group is formed, the tutor then assess the
				students and selects appropriate units from the CSWE curriculum for them to work towards.
				Some students in a class group may be working towards a single unit, while others may be
				working towards multiple units. Some students may be fee paying, some may be funded under
				various government programs. Some students may enrol in a class two or three times before
				attempting assessment against a CSWE unit and some students may not wish to be assessed at
				all. All of these circumstances combined can make headaches for the English classes
				coordinator who both wants to make sure the students and tutors needs are met, as well as
				reporting accurate statistics for funding purposes. Don't worry – onCourse has you covered! </para>
			<section>
				<title>Setting up the course</title>
				<para>onCourse includes all the available TGA data relating to accredited courses and
					classes. Unfortunately, TGA isn't able to provide details of accredited course modules,
					but for both the current and recently expired CSWE, we have built in all the modules to
					onCourse so you can select those you deliver.</para>
				<para>If you college chooses different modules for each class, when you create a CSWE
					course, simply add the accredited course code to the VET page but leave the module list
					empty. If you always use the same modules, you can set up your CSWE course like any other
					VET course, with accredited course detail and modules. </para>
				<para>If you do not set any modules in the course, student enrolling in CSWE linked classes
					will be given a VET-flagged but non accredited outcome, named whatever your course is
					named. You will override these outcomes later when you have the correct module information
					for each student.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enrolling students in CSWE classes.</title>
				<para>You can enrol students in CSWE classes like you would in any other program. It doesn't
					matter if you mix AMEP, BACE and fee paying students together – the outcomes you set later
					on will separate them for AVETMISS purposes.</para>
				<para>We realise many students attending CSWE classes may have enrolled in English classes
					at your college previously. Knowing the student language background, what classes they
					have attended, and what units they have completed will assist your tutors in selecting the
					best units for their current enrolment.</para>
				<para>Once your students are enrolled and classes are ready to start you can print the
					Student Details Report from the class window, which will provide the tutors with the
					information listed above.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Setting CSWE outcomes.</title>
				<para>Once your tutor has reported back to the college each of the outcomes attempted and/or
					achieved by each student in the class, you can enter the data into onCourse, ready for
					your AVETMISS exports.</para>
				<para>Go to the enrolment window and search for all the students in the class group you wish
					to work with by conducting and advanced search on the course code and class code.</para>
				<para>The outcome tab of each student's enrolment will show a non-VET outcome. Open it and
					change it to the first CSWE outcome you wish to record. You can also set the funding
					source information in this window. </para>
				<para>You can also add additional outcomes to the enrolment if a student has attempted more
					than one module during this class by clicking the plus sign.</para>
				<para>If a student chooses not to be assessed against any outcomes, you either leave them
					with the VET flagged non-accredited outcome or choose a VET outcome and set it to
						<emphasis> 30 – Competency not achieved/fail</emphasis> or if you have documented
					evidence that they have refused assessment, yet successfully attended the class, you can
					set a suitable module outcome to <emphasis> 81 – Non-assessed enrolment – Satisfactorily
						completed</emphasis>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>VET delivery hours</title>
		<para>How and where onCourse records and calculates student contact hours</para>
		<section>
			<title>VET data in the class window</title>
			<para>On the class window, there is a tab called VET, which contains fields that are useful
				for RTOs and relate to AVETMISS and other delivery statistics. There are also three AVETMISS
				specific fields ‘Delivery mode', ‘Funding source' and ‘DET booking ID'. </para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Delivery Mode - This refers to how the class is conducted. Most programs are
						classroom based, and this is the default value. You can also change this at the outcome
						level if necessary, e.g. if one student completes the program by distance.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Funding Source - This refers to how the class is funded. These are set selection of
						national codes. You can also change the funding source at the outcome level, e.g. for
						AMEP funded students. For more information, visit the NCVER site </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>DET Booking ID - This field is specific to the NSW APL report. Visit Training Market
						NSW for more information on reporting and lodging your data </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>Information about the qualification and unit/s of competency delivered in your class are
				set at the course level.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Nominal hours, classroom hours and Student Contact Hours</title>
				<para>The following fields in the class relate to your delivery hours and AVETMISS reporting.
					This section has been deliberately made complex to assist our clients who are
					obliged to report AVETMISS for both VET delivery and non-VET delivery.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Qualification Hours - These are the nominal hours set by NCVER for the
							qualification. Often, this field is left blank, which is acceptable for AVETMISS. You
							can also add the nominal hours to the qualification yourself in the Qualification
							table. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Nominal Hours - The nominal hours field in the class is the total of the nominal hours
							of the units of competency assigned to the course. While the nominal
							hours for each unit are usually set by NCVER, you can override them or
							add them where they are missing in Module/Unit of Competency record. You
							can edit these values when you attach units to courses by double
							clicking on the unit record. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Classroom Hours - The total hours you have defined as scheduled activity by setting
							sessions or by defining the minutes per sessions and number of sessions
							on the General tab. This is not reported as part of AVETMISS for real
							VET outcomes – it is for your information only. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Reportable Hours - These are the hours that will be reported against each enrolment in
							the NAT00120 file. They default to the nominal hours of the units
							attached to the course. If there are no nominal hours set in the unit,
							i.e. in a non-VET course, the nominal and reportable hours will default
							to the classroom hours. You can override the reportable hours field to
							the classroom hours or any other number that you wish to export in it's
							place for non-VET courses only. For VET courses, you can also override
							the reportable hours in each outcome, if they differ from the unit
							nominal hours. NOTE: If you have created a class which has units of
							competencies assigned and not set nominal hours for these units, your
							contact hours and reported hours for these outcomes will always be zero.
							Reportable hours based on delivery hours only populate non-VET
							outcomes.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Student Contact Hours - This totals the reportable hours in the outcomes attached to the
							class. This can also be simplified to number of students x total class
							nominal hours for most cases, but in VET classes, some students may have
							different units assigned or different reportable hours for their units.
							SCHs are often used by funding bodies to measure delivery. If you have
							not set nominal hours in the units of competency, your student contact
							hours will calculate to zero. If your classes' course does not have
							units of competency assigned to it e.g. it is a non-VET course, the
							student contact hours will by default equal the classroom hours x number
							of students, unless you override the reportable hours field in the
							class.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para>The report Class funding will provide you with summary information, per qualification,
					per funding code of how many student contact hours you have delivered over the classes
					selected for the report. This can be used to check at various points during the year, the
					number of hours you have delivered that compare to your funding targets. </para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>VET Qualifications and other Certificates</title>
		<para>onCourse includes the AQF recommended templates for full Qualification Certificates,
			Statements of Attainment and transcripts. Certificates can only be generated from units
			that are recorded as part of onCourse enrolments. If you wish to include Credit Transfer
			units, you will need to add these outcomes to the students record before you create the
			certificate.</para>
		<para>There are multiple ways to create certificates from the class, from the enrolment and
			manually in the certificate window.</para>
		<para>If you wish to create certificate records for the whole class group, we recommend
			creating the certificate records from the class cog wheel option. If at the course
			level, you checked the option 'Satisfies requirements for complete qualification' on the
			VET tab, enrolled students will be automatically generated Qualifications. If you have
			not selected this option, Statements of Attainment will be generated. This option only
			selects outcomes from the student's record that have been created due to their enrolment
			in this particular class.</para>
		<para>If you wish to create a certificate based on a single, or group of student's
			enrolments, then you can do the same thing from the enrolment window, by highlighting an
			enrolment or group of enrolments and using the cog wheel function to create the
			certificate records. Like the example above, this option only picks up outcomes attached
			to the particular enrolments you have selected (manual outcomes can be added to
			enrolments prior to certificate creation if needed)</para>
		<para>If you have a student whom has collected units of competency across multiple
			enrolments, and you want to print a certificate showing this, you can create a manual
			certificate directly in the certificate window, selecting your choice of qualification
			reference and appropriate units from their entire transcript list.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Certificate creation and validation process</title>
			<para>The process of generating a AQF Qualification or Statement of Attainment in
				onCourse starts with the certificate record creation process.</para>
			<para>By generating the certificate record, using one of the three methods described
				below, you will have created the data required to meet the AQTF 2010 Condition 6 –
				Certification &amp; issuing of Qualifications &amp; Statements of Attainment. The
				certificate record you create is available in the certificate table in onCourse.
				Once created, the certificate record can be edited and amended or even deleted prior
				to printing, but after the record is printed it becomes locked in the database to
				ensure an accurate record of your issued certificates are retained.</para>
			<para>After printing a certificate, if you determine the certificate was printed in error, you
				can chose to revoke the certificate using the cogwheel option. This maintains the
				certificate reference in the database, with a note as to why you have revoked it. A
				revoked certificate can not be printed, but other valid certificates can be
				reprinted at any time. The last date you printed the certificate is automatically
				recorded in the certificate record.</para>
			<para>Certificate records in onCourse can either be full Qualifications, Statements of
				Attainment working towards a Qualification, Statements of Attainment with no
				qualification reference, or a Statement of Attainment for a skill set.</para>
			<para>When a certificate record is created, there is a radio button option to select if the
				Certificate is a Qualification or Statement of Attainment. Based on this
				information, plus the data or lack of data in the Qualification name/national code
				fields and the Public (printed) notes field, onCourse automatically selects the
				correct layout of the certificate template to print.</para>
			<para>It is worth noting, that as with the course set up process, onCourse does not
				contain any reference data to determine if a full Qualification is valid or not. It
				is up to you as the certifying RTO to ensure when you create and issue a certificate
				record you have deemed a qualification, the student has achieved sufficient outcomes
				and attach those outcomes to the certificate record.</para>
			<para>You can attach any outcome from a students transcript to the certificate record,
				but if you attach an outcome where the status has not yet been set e.g. student has
				not been set as Competent or not yet competent, you will not be able to print the
				certificate records until you have updated the outcome status.</para>
			<para>You can also choose to attach unsuccessful outcomes to the certificate record, for
				example, outcomes where the student has withdrawn or been deemed not yet competent.
				These outcomes will print on the accompanying transcript that is generated when you
				print a certificate, but will not print on the Statement of Attainment certificate
				face. Only successful outcomes will print on the certificate face. </para>
			<para>Every certificate record created is issued a unique certificate number, which is
				printed on the certificate face. The same number series is used for Qualifications
				and Statements of Attainment. The records will begin at 1 and automatically
				increment each time a certificate is created. </para>
			<para>If you are required to generate a submit AVETMISS data, any certificate record you
				create that is marked as being for a full Qualification will create a corresponding
				record in the NAT00130 file.</para>
			<para>You can also go to File > Import/Export > Export Certificates to create a CSV file
				of your certificate register.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Examples of default Certificate layouts</title>
			<section>
				<title>Standard Qualification</title>
			<para>To create a qualification for a student you need to ensure the following:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you are creating the Certificate directly from the class or the
						enrolment, that the course has the option 'satisfies requirements for the
						complete qualification' checked to create a qualification by default. If
						this option has not been checked at the course level, you will create a
						Statement of Attainment record. You can manually change this to a
						Qualification in the certificate record before printing.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You need to manually confirm that the qualification record you are
						creating meets the training package requirements, by adding sufficient and
						valid units of competency from the student's record which they have
						completed successfully.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>When you print a Qualification you will also print a transcript which
						shows the outcomes status of each unit you have selected. Unsuccessful
						outcomes you have added to the certificate record will also print on the
						transcript. It is your choice to add these to the certificate record or not,
						depending on your organisation's policies.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/qualcert.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Standard Qualification Certificate layout</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/transcript.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Standard Transcript layout</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Qualification for a Traineeship/Apprenticeship</title>
				<para>As per the instructions above for creating a standard Qualification, you can modify a
					qualification certificate record to show the text 'achieved through Australian
					Apprenticeship arrangements' by entering this text in the public (printed) notes
					field in the certificate record.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/qualapprentice.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>A qualification achieved via an apprenticeship arrangement</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Statement of Attainment with qualification reference</title>
			<para>To create a Statement of Attainment that references a qualification to need to ensure the following:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
					<para>If you are creating the Certificate directly from the class or the
						enrolment, the course has a qualification defined, and 'satisfies
						requirements for the complete qualification' is not checked you will create
						a Statement of Attainment record. If it is checked, and you automatically
						create a Qualification for a student who is only eligible for a Statement of
						Attainment because they have not meet all the course requirements, you can
						change it from a Qualification to a Statement prior to printing. If you have
						not defined the reference qualification in the course level, you can define
						this in the certificate records before printing.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Any unsuccessful outcome you add to the certificate record will not print
						on the certificate face, but will print on the accompanying
						transcript.</para>
				</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/soawithqual.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Standard Statement of Attainment layout</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Statement of Attainment without qualification reference</title>
				<para>If you wish to create a Statement of Attainment that doesn't include a reference to a
					qualification, you need to ensure that National Code field is left blank in the
					certificate record. Otherwise the instructions are the same as above.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/soanoqual.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Statement of Attainment layout without a reference to a qualification</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Skills Set Statement of Attainment Certificate</title>
			<para>A skill set is a relatively new concept of a fixed grouping of units of competency to meet
					an industry need, that is less than completing a whole qualification.</para>
				<para>When you issue a skill set certificate, you should indicate the name of the
					skill set and the training package the units of competency are from.</para>
				<para>You can do this by adding wording like "the Assessor Skill Set. These units
					from the TAE10 Training and Education Training Package, when used with relevant
					vocational competencies, meet industry requirements for assessors." to the
					certificate record field Public (printed) notes.</para>
				<para>If you add data to the Public (printed) notes field to indicate a skill set
					you need to ensure that the qualification or national code fields for this
					certificate record are not completed.</para>
				<para>In the Statement of Attainment certificate template, where the phrase "These
					competencies form part of the" wording was printed, it will instead print
					""These competencies have been identified as meeting" followed by the text in
					your Public (printed) notes. If you have completed the qualification information
					in the certificate record, you will get the standard Statement of Attainment
					layout, instead of this Skill Set Certificate layout.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/soaskillset.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Statement of Attainment layout for a Skill Set Certificate</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Customising the layout of your VET Certificate template</title>
			<para>Within the onCourse user interface, you can make some customisations of your
				certificate templates. More detailed customisations require you to edit the report
				outside of onCourse.</para>
			<para>By default, all onCourse certificate templates will print a signature line with
				the word 'Principal' underneath. If you would like to replace the word Principal
				with the title and/or name of your certificate signatory you need to go to File >
				Preferences > General and the AVETMISS tab and change the wording in the Full
				Signatory name field at the bottom of the window. This will change the signatory for
				both Qualifications and Statements of Attainment.</para>
			<para>If you wish to make other changes to the fixed wording, the font sizes or styles or embed
				any other images into the certificate templates, then you will need to modify the
				report files outside of onCourse. You can do this yourself or you can request a
				quote from ish to do this for you if you are on any of our support plans. There is
				more information about how you can customise reports yourself in <xref
					xlink:href="#reports"/> of the documentation.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Creating Certificates for a class group </title>
			<para>This option is only recommended if most of the students have successfully completed the course, otherwise many of the certificates you create will need to be manually edited or deleted.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> Open the class window and select the class(es) you wish to create certificates for.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select the cog wheel option ‘Create certificates'. This will
						automatically create Statements of Attainment or Qualifications (depending
						what was chosen at the course level and the student's outcomes) and
						transcripts for each student enrolled in the class. These records are
						created in the certificate table.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the certificate window and edit any certificates that need changes
						and delete any certificate records that have been created for students who
						are not eligible for certification. Units can be added or removed from
						individual certificates as needed, but only prior to printing. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can create the certificates, but not print them, until each of the
						outcomes are set. Ensure the outcomes have been set in the class outcomes
						window, the enrolment records or via the student's contact record.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From the certificate window and print the certificates as needed to PDF or directly to
						the printer. Once they are printed they can no longer be modified. Printing
						to PDF is considered the same as printing to a printer, and also locks the
						record from being modified.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating Certificates from Enrolment records</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight one or more enrolments in the enrolment list view window.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the cog wheel and select the option 'create certificate(s)'. This
						will automatically create Statements of Attainment or Qualifications
						(depending what was chosen at the course level and the student's outcomes)
						and transcripts for each student enrolled in the class. These records are
						created in the certificate table.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Follow steps 3 to 5 above</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Creating manual Certificate records</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> Open the Certificate window and click on the plus sign to begin creating
						certificates. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Type the student name into the first field. This field is clairvoyant. They student
						must be in the database and the name entered correctly to proceed. The students suburb
						and date of birth will be displayed when their record is found. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Enter the National Code for the Qualification or Accredited Course you wish to use
						for the certificate. This is not limited to qualifications the student has attempted at
						your college, as many units are valid towards a number of qualifications. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> If you wish to issue a full qualification, tick the box ‘Satisfies requirement for
						complete qualification'. If you do not tick this box, you will be creating a Statement
						of Attainment. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select the plus sign to begin adding modules/units from the students record to the
						certificate. You can add as many as you need – and you must ensure that you only add
						units that meet the qualification packaging rules of the qualification you selected
						above. Modules/units selected can be added to this certificate only once, however they
						can be used again to create other certificates in the future. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> When the information is correct, select save. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Created certificates appear in the summary window. From this window, you
						can print the certificates. Select file, print and choose which certificates
						you wish to print. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Creating Certificates of Attendance for non-VET courses </title>
			<para>Sometimes colleges run non-VET courses that are not eligible to receive official
				Qualifications or Statements of Attainment, however the students would still like to
				receive some recognition that they completed the course. In this case, you may wish
				to supply the student with a Certificate of Attendance. Please refer to the latest
				AQF Certification Guidelines regarding the issuing of non-VET certifications.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> Open the class window and select the class(es) you wish to create certificates for.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select the cog wheel option ‘Create certificates'. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select proceed and the certificates will be created on in a PDF file to
						the location you specify. You can then print these certificates as needed.
						The whole classes certificates are created in the one PDF file – if you only
						want to print a certificate for one student, locate it in the PDF and use
						your print functions to print the specific page. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Alternatively you can print a Certificate of Attendance for a single
						student by going to the enrolment window, highlighting the student's
						enrolment and selecting File > Print > Certificate of Attendance</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> You can re-create these certificates at any time – there are no records created in
						the certificate window as they are not VET certifications. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating a Certificate of Attendance for a VET class student</title>
			<para>On occasion, a student may attend a VET course but choose not to be assessed. If they have
				met your attendance requirements, you may choose to issue them a Certificate of
				Attendance.</para>
			<para>You can do this by going to the enrolment window, highlighting the student's
				enrolment and selecting File > Print > Certificate of Attendance</para>
			<para>Please note that if you have named the course the official title of the
				Qualification or Unit of Competency (e.g. Certificate IV in Frontline Management)
				their Certificate of Attendance will include that wording.</para>
			<para>No certificate record is created in the certificate table for the printing of a Certificate
				of Attendance. This is just a printed report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/VETcertattend.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Certificate of Attendance printed for a VET student who chose not to be assessed</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Courses by Cluster</title>
		<para>How to set up qualifications that are delivered by internal clusters where units of
			competency overlap</para>
		<para> Clusters, in this case, refers to an internal grouping of units of competency that a
			college delivers to break up a qualification into teaching-focused groups of units. Sometimes
			one unit from a qualification may be delivered across multiple clusters, and a student must
			successfully complete the assessments in each cluster to acheive competency in the unit. For
			example the Qualification Certificate IV in Training and Assessment has 12 units in total, but
			the four Environment units are assessed in each cluster. The course is delivered in three
			clusters and each cluster has a fee that applies to it. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Creating the Qualification</title>
			<para>Create a new course and attach all the units that you deliver as part of the
				qualification. This is the formal enrolment where you will record the student's completion
				of outcomes once assessment has been sufficiently completed across your various
				clusters.</para>
			<para>This is the course that you will advertise on your website, so make sure you include the
				full course description and information about how you deliver the program.</para>
			<para>Next, create a class for this course, entering the dates, student fees and venue
				information. Details on how to create a class is available here. Web enable this class so
				students can enrol. </para>
			<para>You may choose to set up this class as an ‘application fee enrolment' and advise the
				students of the full fee within this class description. Do this by setting the class fee as
				the amount you wish them to pay to apply, and ensure your information explains what the
				approval process involves. You will need to contact students who apply and inform them of
				their success or otherwise, and organise payment of the full course fees. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating the clusters</title>
			<para>The cluster courses that you create are for your scheduling and management purposes
				only. They will not be advertised online, as you will enrol students in these classes as
				appropriate.</para>
			<para>The clusters that you create are not VET courses – do not attach the qualification or
				units of competency to these records. You can put details of the units and content covered
				in the description if you wish.</para>
			<para>Set up each course and class with the assigned rooms, tutors and sessions</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolments and Payment</title>
			<para>As onCourse will invoice students class fees, you can allow students to make full
				payments or part payments at the time of enrolment.</para>
			<para>For example, you could set the full fee on the first class and track students as they
				make payments towards this total amount. Alternatively, you could set up multiple classes
				with fees attached, so students are only invoiced for a portion of the course fee each time
				they are enrolled in a new cluster.</para>
			<para>In the example below, the full qualification has an application fee of $100, paid
				online. Once the student's enrolment has been accepted, they are invoiced $900 for the first
				cluster, and $500 for each of the subsequent clusters, until a total of $2000 has been
				paid.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Traineeships and Custom Training</title>
		<para>onCourse has the ability for courses and classes to be created under the traineeship
			model, where one student is often completing a work-based course of study, managed via their
			employer, with regular onsite visits for assessment.</para>
		<para>The custom class function available through Quick Enrol allows users to create these
			programs for students.</para>
		<para>First you need to ensure you have created a course containing the expected units of
			competency for the traineeship. See <xref xlink:href="#coursesVET" /> This could be just the
			core units, or the core units and the expected electives. The actual electives chosen by each
			trainee can either be added or changed later.</para>
		<para>Once the course has been created, you can then create a private booking in quick enrol.
			See <xref xlink:href="#privateBookings" /> You can set the assessor during this process, as
			well as schedule the first assessment/training session, or wait until later to determine this
			information.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%"
					fileref="images/creating_traineeship.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Creating a new traineeship in Quick Enrol</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>It is important that you collect the employer information for the trainee enrolled in the
			traineeship. If the employer will be paying the fee, you need to make sure this is reflected
			during the quick enrol process so the invoice is issued to the employer instead of the
			trainee. Use the contact relationship function to link the student to the employer. See <xref
				xlink:href="#contactsRelationships" />
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%"
					fileref="images/traineeship_employer_payer.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Assigning the employer as the payer of the traineeship fees</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once the student is linked to the employer, and assessor has been set from your RTO and
			you have specified the start and end dates for the traineeship, you will be able to print a
			Traineeship Training Plan. This is a useful document to provide to the trainee and their
			employer to confirm the details of the units they have chosen for their traineeship.</para>
		<para>If you have created a single trainee enrolment in the class, you can also provide the
			AVETMISS reporting for the traineeship for this single trainee as required. By using the
			AVETMISS data export by class function. See <xref xlink:href="#AVETMISSExports" />
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
