<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" version="5.0" xml:id="scripts">
	<title>onCourse scripts and custom workflow</title>
	<para>onCourse has a powerful scripting engine which can be used to implement your own specific
		workflow rules into onCourse.</para>
	<para>You can use script to send automated emails or SMS, change records inside the system,
		integrate with third party tools such as analytics or mailing lists, export data to finance
		systems or your LMS. And much much more. Scripts allow your student management system to
		become a completely customisable tool with your business workflow engine built right into
		onCourse. You can create and update onCourse records on an event, send messages to key
		contacts when a record is created or changed, or automating the publishing, exporting or
		printing of data how and when you require it. Every script has a description field to help
		explain the purpose of it.</para>
	<para>Scripting allows you to write directly to the database, calling your own program code that
		can automate almost any business practice you can imagine. Any database changes they attempt
		are subject to similar validation as data input manually.</para>
	<para>Scripts often work hand in hand with <link xlink:href="emailTemplates.html">onCourse
			templates</link>, sending automated messages to various onCourse contacts.</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
				fileref="images/send_payment_receipt_script.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Example of what a script looks like</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<section>
		<title>Navigating the Scripts view</title>
		<para>The new UI allows for Scripts to be added and/or removed, as well as customising the 
		coulumns you wish to view on the page. You can keyword search by typing your search term into 
		the Search bar, and it should return any script containing that word in the name.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="scripts-whatYouCanDo">
		<title>What can you do with scripts?</title>
		<para>Some simple ideas that could be implemented with a custom onCourse script:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Run a daily transaction export at 2am for the prior 24 hours and email it to
					your Accounts Manager</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automatically send an email to a student on their birthday containing a $10
					gift voucher</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Notify tutors their class is confirmed running when the class minimum
					enrolment number has been reached </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Notify coordinators one week before a class is due to commence if the class is
					under the minimum</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automatically notify all students on a course waiting list when you publish a
					new instance of class to the web</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Send a monthly notification to debtors or creditors of their onCourse balance
					outstanding</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Send your Enrolment Manager a daily email of students who failed to complete
					the online enrolment process so they can manually follow them up</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Send the CEO weekly summary of enrolments, income and trending programs</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Schedule a series of daily reports to print rooms labels, class rolls and sign
					in sheets every business day morning, and for all weekend classes on a Friday
					morning</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Print and send reports to site coordinators for all sessions running at their
					venue the following week</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Email students at the conclusion of their course suggesting other courses they
					might be interested in, with a time limited discount offer</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Email VET students' employers three months after the conclusion of their
					course requesting they complete the Employer Satisfaction Survey</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Integrate with an LMS such as Moodle or Canvas where you push student
					enrolments in real time as enrolments are created. You can use onCourse tags to
					control which courses are handled in this manner.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Integrate with MailChimp or other mailing list manager to synchronise mailing
					list contacts in both directions</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Verify that course administrators are writing at least 100 words of course
					description before putting the course onto your website</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Send an email to your administrator if a course administrator schedules a
					course for a public holiday</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automate integration with your accounting system</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Email students the day before their class starts</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>SMS to tutors one hour before the should be teaching</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automate compliance exports such as VET FEE HELP or AVETMISS</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Update course content on your website with data from some other source</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automate of creating Facebook or Twitter comments from "what's hot today" or
					new courses being published</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Push course enrolment events to Google analytics so that you can see office
					enrolments alongside web enrolments in your statistical reports</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="scripts-Permissions">
		<title>Script permissions</title>
		<para>All onCourse license options can choose to enable or disable scripts provided by ish. Some
			paid license plans can commission changes to existing scripts or request new custom
			scripts from ish. Customers with Enterprise level licensing can modify and add to their
			own scripts to onCourse themselves.</para>
		<para>You can enable and disabled a script by double-clicking one from the script list view, which
			you can access from the top menu File > Preferences > Scripts, and then ensuring the
			'Enabled' switch is turned on.</para>
		<para>Scripts which are enabled display the information about when they will next run in the
			list view. Disabled scripts do not show this information, and they appear greyed
			out.</para>
		<para>If you have the appropriate license for modifying scripts, you can control which users
			are able to edit them in the user Roles. We recommend you only give this permission to
			users with technical skills to properly make changes to the scripts since a bad script
			can have far ranging implications for your system.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/script_list_view.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Script list view showing enabled and disabled scripts</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="scripts-onCourseDefaultScripts">
	<title>onCourse default scripts</title>
		<para>All the default scripts come with a new installation of onCourse. They can all be found in
			our <uri xlink:href="https://github.com/ari/oncourse-scripts/tree/master/scripts">GitHub
				documentation.</uri></para>
		<note><para>IMPORTANT: Before you enable or adjust any new script, you should open the script and click
				the button in the bottom right hand corner "Update to the latest version". This will
				ensure the script is set to use the latest code version from Git Hub.</para></note>
		<section>
			<title>Auto enabled default scripts</title>
		<para>These scripts are enabled by default in all onCourse databases. Please contact us
			before you disable them as they have implications for the enrolment and sales processes:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Send enrolment</emphasis> - send the email (template - Enrolment
					Confirmation) to the enrolling student on successful creation of an enrolment,
					through the office or the website.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Send invoice</emphasis> - send the email (template - Tax Invoice) to
					the payer of the enrolment where the invoice balance is not zero.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Send payment receipt </emphasis>- send the email (template - Payment
					Receipt) to the payer when a payment in is processed outside of the enrolment
					process</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">Send voucher</emphasis> - send the email (template - Voucher Email)
					containing the voucher redemption code and details to the purchaser of a
					voucher</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Disabled default scripts</title>
		<para>These scripts have been added for all users of onCourse, but are switched off by default.
			Before enabling these scripts you should check the wording of the default email
			templates they call, and adjust them as necessary. </para>
		<para>Prior to enabling a script, you should open the script and click on the button 'update
			to latest version'. This will make sure any improvements to the original script are
			downloaded.</para>
		<para>You can enable or disable these scripts in your database at any time, and make modifications
			as desired if your licence level allows.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Student notifications</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send student class commencement notice</emphasis> - automatically
							send a reminder email (template - Student notice of class commencement) to
							active enrolled students one day before their class commences</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">send student class commencement notice 7 days</emphasis> -
							automatically send a reminder email (template - Student notice of class
							commencement) to active enrolled students seven days before their class
							commences. </para>
						<para>NOTE: Depending on your business processes, you may wish to enable only
							one of the reminder scripts (1 day before or 7 days before), or both. By
							default, these scripts use the same email template. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send class cancellation</emphasis> - Send an email
							(template - Class Cancellation) to the students who were enrolled with
							information about class cancellation options, when a class is
							cancelled</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send application received notification</emphasis> - When an
							application has been created via the web or in the office, send the student
							an email (template - Enrolment application received) to notify them, and
							send an email to the default admin email address to schedule the follow up
							process.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send application decision</emphasis> - When an application status is
							set to offered, send an email (template - Enrolment application accepted) to a
							student to notify them their application has been accepted, what their custom
							enrolment fee is and how they can enrol. When an application is set to rejected,
							send an email (template Enrolment application rejected) to the student to notify
							them.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send certificate created notification</emphasis> - Create a
							certificate of attendance for non-VET training with your custom
							certificate_attendance_backgound.pdf, upload the certificate to the portal and
							send an email (template - Certificate available) to the student containing the
							link. There are options in the script to check attendance requirements before
							creating certificates, which are commented out by default.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send class completion survey</emphasis> - The day after a class is
							completed send an email (template - Course completion survey) to all
							classes that are not tagged with "no survey" requesting students
							complete the skillsOnCourse portal survey process.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Alert student of assessment release</emphasis> -
							This script runs daily at 8am and checks if any assessments have a
							release date in the system set as today, and then sends students an
							email detailing each assessment released.</para>
					</listitem>					
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tutor notifications</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send tutor class commencement notice</emphasis> - automatically send
							a reminder email (template - Tutor notice of class commencement) to all class
							tutors two days before their class commences</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Cancelled class notice for tutor</emphasis> - automatically sends a
							cancellation email (template - Tutor notice of class cancellation) to the
							tutor/s if a class they are teaching gets cancelled</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send enrolment notice for tutors</emphasis> - For classes tagged
							with 'Notify manager', send an email (template - Enrolment notification) to the
							tutor attached with the role 'course manager' to advise them that a student has
							enrolled in the class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Notify tutor of unmarked attendance</emphasis> - This script runs
							daily and checks every session run on the previous 7 days. If any
							student attendance is unmarked, the script sends to the tutors an email
							notification (template - Tutor notice of unmarked attendance) to mark
							their class roll. One email is sent for each class with unmarked
							sessions. Tutors may receive the same email for 7 consecutive days if
							they do not follow the instructions and mark their attendance. After 7
							days from the session date, no further reminder will be sent.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Alert tutor of assessment release</emphasis> - This script
							runs daily at 8am and checks if any assessments have a release date in
							the system set as today, and then sends an email to the tutor for each
							assessment released.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>VET specific scripts</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send USI reminder</emphasis> - automatically send a reminder email
							(template - USI reminder email) to VET students every 7 days for the next month
							if they haven't supplied their USI on or shortly after enrolment</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Automatic creation of VET Certificates</emphasis> - For each
							enrolment, at 4am every day check for outcomes which have been modified in the
							previous 24 hrs. If any outcomes attached to the enrolment are not yet marked,
							skip this enrolment. For students with at least one successful outcome, create
							the certificate record (Statement of Attainment or Qualification, based on the
							isFullQual flag at the course level). If the outcome is already joined to a
							certificate, do not create a new certificate containing that outcome</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send certificate VET created notification</emphasis> - At 5am each
							day, print to PDF and upload to the portal all unprinted VET certificates, where
							the student meets the requirements for certification, including having supplied
							their USI. Send an email (template - Certificate available) to notify the
							student that their certificate is available in the portal. You must ensure you
							have created and uploaded into onCourse backgrounds named
							vet_soa_background.pdf, vet_qualification_background.pdf and
							vet_skillset_background.pdf before enabling this script.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem xml:id="scripts-VETcourseCompletion">
						<para><emphasis role="bold">VET course completion Survey</emphasis> - This script will send an
							email (template - VET course completion Survey) to each student two
							weeks after to the completion of the course. </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Financial scripts</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send refund advice</emphasis> - When a successful payment out is
							created e.g. credit card refund, send an email (template - Refund advice) to the
							payee</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send weekly finance summary report</emphasis> - Send
							the Trial Balance report for the previous 7 days each Monday morning to the
							default system administrator email address. There is an option in this
							script to change the reporting period from weekly to monthly if that is your
							reporting period preference. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send payment plan reminder</emphasis> - This script
							will send an email (template - payment reminder) to each debtor with an
							overdue invoice, or an invoice which has a payment due within the next 7
							days. Included in the email is a link where the debtor can click to make a
							credit card payment via the onCourse portal.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Membership notification renewal </emphasis>- This script will send
							an email (template - Membership Notification Renewal) to each contact with
							an active membership 7 days prior to it's expiry to remind them to purchase
							a renewal.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send account statement </emphasis>- This script will send an email
							with a PDF attachment of the printed Statement Report for each contact
							with an outstanding balance, and by default is scheduled to run on the
							first of the month. The email that is sent to the contact is plain text,
							embedded within the script. There is no separate email template to edit
							and no HTML version available. The email includes the total balance
							outstanding and a 30 day no login required link to the skillsOnCourse
							portal where the invoices can be viewed and payments made. There is no
							copy of this message stored in onCourse against the contact record. </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Marketing and sales scripts</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Synchronise availability (enrolment)</emphasis> - This script finds
							all single session classes taught by the same tutor in the same room with
							overlapping times and keeps the places available in sync. For each enrolment
							in Class A, the maximum available places in Class B is reduced by one. This
							is useful if one class is a subset of another (e.g.. a refresher First Aid
							class where students need only come to the second half of the regular First
							Aid class). If you enable this script, you'll also want to enable
							'Synchronise availability (cancellation)'</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Synchronise availability (cancellation)</emphasis> - This script
							finds all single session classes taught by the same tutor in the same room
							with overlapping times and keeps the places available in sync. For each
							enrolment in Class A, the maximum available places in Class B is reduced by
							one. This is useful if one class is a subset of another (e.g.. a refresher
							First Aid class where students need only come to the second half of the
							regular First Aid class). If you enable this script, you'll also want to
							enable 'Synchronise availability (enrolment)'</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send waiting list reminder</emphasis> - for students who have been
							added to a waiting list, send them an email (template - Waiting List
							reminder) every 7 days of the classes currently available for the
							courses they are on wait lists for. </para>
						<para>NOTE: There is also a manual email template 'Waiting list notification' that is designed
							to be sent manually when a class has limited vacancies available, to
							students on the wait list for the course.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Alert students of related class</emphasis> - DO NOT ENABLE THIS
							SCRIPT! It is designed to be manually triggered as needed on a class by
							class basis. Access the script from the class cogwheel, by single
							clicking on the class you want to promote to past students of the same
							class tutor, and choosing 'Execute script for 1 record' >  alert
							students of related class. </para>
						<para>This script finds all students who have enrolled in a class in the
							last 18 months with the tutor(s) assigned to the first class session,
							who aren't currently enrolled in this class, and sends them an email
							(template - alert students of related class) to encourage them to enrol
							in this class.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Administrative scripts</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Send product purchased email</emphasis> - Each time a product is
							purchased on the website, and email is sent to the admin email address
							to notify them of the purchase, using the same admin email as the 'From'
							address. Rather than using an email template, the email layout is a
							simple plain text email inside the script itself. To change the text,
							you need to edit the script directly. This script is disabled by
							default.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">Notification of unmarked attendance</emphasis> - This management
							script is set to run daily and check for sessions run the previous day where
							at least one of the enrolled students has an unmarked attendance record. If
							an unmarked record is found, an email is sent to the admin contact so they
							can initiate a follow up process with the tutor. Optionally, only courses
							tagged with 'checkAttendance' will be checked, so if attendance marking is
							important for some programs, like VET, you can ignore unmarked attendance
							for your leisure courses.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>

		<section>
			<title>Integration scripts</title>
			<para>A number of 3rd party integrations are included with onCourse and as standard, and each
				integration includes integration scripts to enable you to fine tune how the
				integration works. For more information about 3rd party application integrations refer to the chapter
					<link xlink:href="externalintegrations.html">external integrations</link></para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">CloudAssess course enrolment create</emphasis> Creates an enrolment in
						cloud assess where the onCourse course code and cloudAssess course code are
						the same</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Moodle enrol</emphasis> Create an enrolment in moodle where the
						course has the tag defined in the moodle integration</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Mailchimp subscribe</emphasis> Subscribe contacts to mailchimp
						mailing lists using the onCourse mailing list feature. NB The name of the
						integration must match the name of the mailing list exactly for this script
						to work. You can set up multiple integrations, one for each mailing list.
						You only need to enable this one script to run them all.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Mailchimp subscribe on enrolment</emphasis> Subscribe all enrolling
						students to a mailchimp mailing list, where the integration name is
						'Enrolment'. NB you must set up the integration before enabling this
						script.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Mailchimp unsubscribe</emphasis> Unsubscribe contacts from
						mailchimp mailing lists using the onCourse mailing list unsubscribe
						feature</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">SurveyGizmo send invite on enrolment</emphasis> Send a survey
						invite (template - survey invite) on enrolment in a course tagged with the
						tag defined in the SurveyGizmo integration</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">SurveyGizmo send invite on completion</emphasis> Send a survey
						invite (template - survey invite) on class completion in a course tagged
						with the tag defined in the SurveyGizmo integration</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">SurveyMonkey send invite on enrolment</emphasis> Send a survey
						invite (template - survey invite) on enrolment in a course tagged with the
						tag defined in the SurveyMonkey integration</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">SurveyMonkey send invite on enrolment completion</emphasis> Send a
						survey invite (template - survey invite) on class completion in a course
						tagged with the tag defined in the SurveyMonkey integration</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Xero manual journal</emphasis> Create a Xero set of journals for
						the total transactions for each account created on the previous day</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">MYOB manual journal</emphasis> Create a MYOB set of journals for
						the total transactions for each account created on the previous day</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="scripts-scriptTriggers">
		<title>Script triggers</title>
		<para>Each script is triggered by an event. An event can be time based (cron) or linked to a
			record change.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Time based events</title>
			<para>onCourse scripts can be triggered by a cron expression for firing at a repeating
				interval. cron is a Unix tool that has existed since the 1970s and is extremely
				powerful and flexible. </para>
			<para>Some pre-defined cron expressions are available to select from the drop down list
				in the script (daily, weekly or hourly), or you can create your own custom
				cron.</para>
			<para>You need only write six fields separated by spaces to describe the recurring
				timing. For example, you can specify "every Monday at 9am" or "1am on the first
				Sunday of every month".</para>
			<variablelist>
				<title>The fields are:</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Seconds</term>
					<listitem>
						<para> Allowed values: 0-59</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Minutes</term>
					<listitem>
						<para> Allowed values: 0-59</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Hours</term>
					<listitem>
						<para> Allowed values: 0-23</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Day of month</term>
					<listitem>
						<para> Allowed values: 1-31</para>
						<para> Special characters: ? L W</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Month</term>
					<listitem>
						<para> Allowed values: 1-12 or JAN-DEC</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Day of week</term>
					<listitem>
						<para> Allowed values: 1-7 or MON-SUN</para>
						<para>Special characters: ? L #</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>Every field allows the special option '*' which means all values. For example, '*'
				in the minute field means every minute. In each field you can also use ranges. For
				example '13-15' in the hour field means 1pm, 2pm and 3pm. And ',' can be used for
				multiple values such as 'mon,wed,fri' in the day of week field. You can specify a
				repeating increment in a field with a '/'. For instance "0/15" in the hour field
				means every 15 minutes starting at the hour. Or "2/3" in the day of month field
				means every three days starting on the second day of the month.</para>
			<variablelist>
				<title>Special characters</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>? ("no value")</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Because day-of-month and day-of-week overlap in meaning, one of those
							two fields should always be '?'. </para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>L ("last")</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>has different meaning in each of the two fields in which it is
							allowed. For example, the value "L" in the day-of-month field means "the
							last day of the month" - day 31 for January, day 28 for February on
							non-leap years. If used in the day-of-week field by itself, it simply
							means "7" or "SAT". But if used in the day-of-week field after another
							value, it means "the last xxx day of the month" - for example "6L" means
							"the last Friday of the month". When using the 'L' option, it is
							important not to specify lists, or ranges of values, as you'll get
							confusing results.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>W ("weekday")</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>used to specify the weekday (Monday-Friday) nearest the given day. As
							an example, if you were to specify "15W" as the value for the
							day-of-month field, the meaning is: "the nearest weekday to the 15th of
							the month". So if the 15th is a Saturday, the trigger will fire on
							Friday the 14th. If the 15th is a Sunday, the trigger will fire on
							Monday the 16th. If the 15th is a Tuesday, then it will fire on Tuesday
							the 15th. However if you specify "1W" as the value for day-of-month, and
							the 1st is a Saturday, the trigger will fire on Monday the 3rd, as it
							will not 'jump' over the boundary of a month's days. The 'W' character
							can only be specified when the day-of-month is a single day, not a range
							or list of days.</para>
						<para>The 'L' and 'W' characters can also be combined in the day-of-month
							field to yield 'LW', which translates to "last weekday of the month".
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>#</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>used to specify "the nth" XXX day of the month. For example, the value
							of "6#3" in the day-of-week field means "the third Friday of the month"
							(day 6 = Friday and "#3" = the 3rd one in the month). Other examples:
							"2#1" = the first Monday of the month and "4#5" = the fifth Wednesday of
							the month. Note that if you specify "#5" and there is not 5 of the given
							day-of-week in the month, then no firing will occur that month.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>The legal characters and the names of months and days of the week are not case
				sensitive. MON is the same as mon.</para>
			<para>
				<table frame="void">
					<caption>Examples</caption>
					<tbody>
						<tr>
							<td>0 0 12 * * ? </td>
							<td>Fire at 12pm (noon) every day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 ? * * </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am every day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 * * ? </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am every day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 * * ? * </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am every day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 * * ? 2005 </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am every day during the year 2005</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 * 14 * * ? </td>
							<td>Fire every minute starting at 2pm and ending at 2:59pm, every
								day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 0/5 14 * * ? </td>
							<td>Fire every 5 minutes starting at 2pm and ending at 2:55pm, every
								day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 0/5 14,18 * * ? </td>
							<td>Fire every 5 minutes starting at 2pm and ending at 2:55pm, AND fire
								every 5 minutes starting at 6pm and ending at 6:55pm, every day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 0-5 14 * * ? </td>
							<td>Fire every minute starting at 2pm and ending at 2:05pm, every
								day</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 10,44 14 ? 3 WED </td>
							<td>Fire at 2:10pm and at 2:44pm every Wednesday in the month of
								March.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 ? * MON-FRI </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am every Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday and
								Friday</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 15 * ? </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am on the 15th day of every month</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 L * ? </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am on the last day of every month</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 ? * 6L </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am on the last Friday of every month</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 ? * 6L </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am on the last Friday of every month</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 ? * 6L 2002-2005 </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am on every last Friday of every month during the years
								2002, 2003, 2004 and 2005</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 15 10 ? * 6#3 </td>
							<td>Fire at 10:15am on the third Friday of every month</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 0 12 1/5 * ? </td>
							<td>Fire at 12pm (noon) every 5 days every month, starting on the first
								day of the month.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td>0 11 11 11 11 ? </td>
							<td>Fire every November 11th at 11:11am.</td>
						</tr>
					</tbody>
				</table>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Entity events</title>
			<para>Rather than a specific time, the trigger for a script can instead be a record
				change, otherwise known as an entity event. You are able to specify the entity name
				and the type of change to trigger the script: create, update, create or update, or
				remove. Note that entity names are mostly the same as database table names, but
				there is a difference. Some entities don't map directly to the database.</para>
			<para>For more details of what entities are available, please consult our detailed API
				documentation.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>onCourse events</title>
			<para>There are also specific events in onCourse that can be used to trigger scripts,
				called onCourse events. These events relate entirely to cancellation and/or creation
				of enrolments as well as the publishing and/or cancelling of classes. The events
				types are specified as: enrolment successful, enrolment cancelled, class published
				and class cancelled.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>On Demand events</title>
			<para>When a script is set as On Demand it means the script can only be triggered
				manually by the user via the cogwheel menu in onCourse. The entity class defines
				from which screen in onCourse the script can be triggered, and must be defined under
				the 'Entity Event' trigger type for this to
				function.<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?></para><?oxy_custom_end?>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="scripts-Content">
		<title>Editing script content</title>
		<para>The actual script itself is written in Groovy which gives you power to implement
			almost anything. You have full access to the onCourse Server structure, code and data.
			With great power comes great responsibility, so be aware that you have the power to
			destroy data although there are layers of validation to help prevent you doing anything
			too seriously bad unless you try hard.</para>
		<para>Let's pull apart a sample script. This one sends an email when an invoice is
			created.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">def run(args) {
	def i = args.entity
			
	if (i.confirmationStatus == ConfirmationStatus.NOT_SENT) {
		def m = Email.create("Tax Invoice")
		m.bind(invoice: i)
		m.to(i.contact)
		
		m.send()
		
		i.setConfirmationStatus(ConfirmationStatus.SENT)
		args.context.commitChanges()
	}  
}</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>Every script should begin with this line:</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">def run(args) {</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>In that variable "args" you will get access to important objects to help you write
			your script. The most important two are:</para>
		<variablelist>
			<title/>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>args.entity</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This is the object which caused the script to run. It is null if this
						script was triggered by a cron event.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>args.context</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This is the Cayenne context within which the script runs. You'll use this
						to perform searches for other records or to commit changes back to the
						database.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">def i = args.entity</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>For convenience we've assigned this object to a variable with a nicer name. This just
			makes the rest of our script easier to read.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">if (i.confirmationStatus == ConfirmationStatus.NOT_SENT) {</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>So our invoice has an attribute confirmationStatus. We can find these attributes
			documented in the onCourse javadocs. In this case we just want to check to see that we
			still need to send this email. We don't want to send it if the invoice was part of a
			failed payment and reversal, or if the user already received it.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">def m = Email.create("Tax Invoice")</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>So let's make a new email and call it "m".</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">m.bind(invoice: i)</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>That email template has a property called "invoice" and we'll bind our invoice object
			to that property.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">m.to(i.contact)</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>The invoice has a property called 'contact' and we'll make sure the message will be
			sent to that person.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">m.send()</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>And we are done. This will finish all the work of creating the message.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">i.setConfirmationStatus(ConfirmationStatus.SENT)</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>We better now set the invoice to sent so that we don't send this email again. For
			example, this script might be triggered because we edit the invoice to change the due
			date. In that case, the script will be triggered.</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="groovy">args.context.commitChanges()</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>This last step is very important. All the changes we made (including the email we
			created) exist only in memory and not saved to the database until this step. Unless we
			save it, no email will go out and no other user will see our changes. When we commit,
			all the validation will run. For example, onCourse will prevent you from sending an
			email which has no 'to' contact and so the commit will fail. onCourse will also
			synchronise any objects with your onCourse website. This allows you to programmatically
			modify website content directly from these scripts.</para>
		<para>For full details of the groovy language consult the official documentation here
			http://groovy.codehaus.org/ Groovy has very nice support for iterating through
			collections (such as a big list of database objects), regular expression matching and
			much more. Plus you get to use all the Java libraries already included inside of
			onCourseServer plus the full Java JRE.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
