<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="sitesRooms">
	<title>Sites and Rooms</title>
	<section>
		<title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Sites</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Sites are the physical venues where you offer classes at places like Newtown Arts
						Club, or Parramatta High School. A site will have one or more rooms. Sites can also be
						Administration centres where you take enrolments and payments.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Rooms</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Rooms are where the classes will be held, a class may be held in one room all year,
						or may change. Rooms will have names like room 14, studio 6, the library. Rooms can have
						a seated capacity. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Timetable</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>When you create classes, you will be able to book a room. There are timetables for
						both rooms and sites. You can also make a site or room unavailable for class
						bookings.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Working with Sites and Rooms</title>
		<subtitle>Navigating the list and record windows</subtitle>
		<para>All records in onCourse can be viewed in either a list view or record view. You need to
			open the list view to access individual records.</para>
		<para>To access the site records go to either the splash screen and click on
				<guibutton>Sites</guibutton> or the onCourse menu <menuchoice>
				<guimenuitem>resources</guimenuitem>
				<guisubmenu>sites</guisubmenu>
			</menuchoice> . This will open the Sites list view window.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>The onCourse list view</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>Parts of the window - On the right hand part of the window are the site records listed
					in a summary view. The title bar shows you how many records you have. The top section of
					the window contains the search function and the add and delete records button. In the left
					hand side of the list window are quick searches to enable you to work with groups of data.
					There are default quick searches for site, but you can create your own. This part of the
					window may be collapsed if their are no related tags or saved searches.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Record summaries - The list of records in this window allows you to enter a record by
					double clicking, or select the record to perform special functions by single clicking. A
					selected record will be highlighted. You can select one or more records in the list by
					using shift-click to select a range, or control-click to select a group of individual
					records. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Columns and sorting - Column headings can be used to sort records in the list. Click
					on the header to sort in alphabetical order. Click it again to sort by reverse
					alphabetical order. You can also drag the columns around and modify their width to set
					your preferred layout.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Quick search - By typing the first few letters of the site name into the quick search
					field, you can reduce the list of records to those that match.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Advanced Search - Advanced search can be accessed by clicking on the Magnifying glass
					image in the quick search field. This will open the query editor to allow you to choose
					which fields and which data you want to search on. You can add multiple criteria to your
					searches.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Saved Searches - After performing an advanced search, you can choose to save the
					search parameters to allow you to quickly run the search again. To save a search, click on
					the cogwheel within the query editor and select 'save find'. The saved search will appear
					in the left hand part of the window.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Tag groups - Any tag groups you have created that relate to sites, like Region, will
					appear here. By checking any of these check boxes you will see the list of records on the
					right hand side reduced to records that match that criteria. You can tag records in bulk
					by selecting a group of records on the right and right clicking on a tag name on the
					left.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<tip>
			<para>Filters and searches work together in onCourse. If you run a search and do not see the
				result you expect, this may be because a filter that is checked is preventing the record you
				are searching for from being displayed.</para>
		</tip>
		<para>You can enter a site record by double clicking on it in the window.</para>
		<section xml:id="sites">
			<title>Site Record Tabs</title>
			<section xml:id="sites-General">
				<title>General</title>
				<para>Where you can set the site name and address details. You can also add the
					latitude and longitude of your site so you can use the google maps function on
					your ish website. The general tab also displays a list of the rooms at this
					site. <itemizedlist>
						<para>There are three checkboxes on this tab, they are:</para>
						<listitem>
							<para>Administration centre - allows you to set that site as the
								administration centre</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Show this site on the website - allows you to show the site, and
								anything related to it on the website</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Virtual Site - refer to related section on Virtual Sites within
								this Chapter</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				<para>The following additional features can be managed via the General tab of the
					Site record:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>By adding the street address, suburb, state and postcode, this
							information will automatically populate through to your onCourse
							website</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can set the relevant time zone for this particular Site by
							selecting the relevant option from the drop down menu on the General
							tab</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<note>
					<para>If you are running an integrated onCourse website, you will have access to
						full location searches and directions via Google maps. Just make sure that
						you set the longitude and latitude for each site. </para>
					<para>To locate the coordinates for your Site, click on the <guilabel>Find this
							location</guilabel> link within the site record. You will then be
						directed to the ish website Google maps page, where you can enter the
						address for the given site and the coordinates will be displayed for you to
						copy and paste into the Site record. </para>
				</note>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/site_record_general_tab.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>View of general tab of site record</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="sites-Directions">
				<title>Directions</title>
				<para>This tab allows you to display different types of directions for your
					students, if you input into any of the three text fields, it would be displayed
					on your website. The three types of text fields in the Directions tab
					are:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Driving directions</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Public transport directions</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Special instructions - like where the room or cafeteria is</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para>There is also an attachment window beneath, this will allow you to add
					attachments that relate to the Direction tab. To add an attachment you must
					click on the + sign on the top right hand side, to remove an attachment you will
					click on the - sign.There are three fields in the attachment window:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Name - the file name of the attachment</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Web Visible - when checked, the attachment will be visible on your
							site</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Size - the size of the attachment</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="sites-Notes">
				<title>Notes</title>
				<para>This tab is for internal notes about the site. It is not published on the
					site.</para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="sites-Timetable">
				<title>Timetable</title>
				<para>This tab shows you anything that is booked into the site through five
					views:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Day</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Week</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>8 Weeks</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Month</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>List</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<para>The list option gives you two windows, the top window "sessions" shows you all
					sessions for that site, you can click on the - sign to quickly remove a session. <mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/site_list_window1.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The "sessions" window in the timetable list view</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject> The bottom window "availabilities" will allow you to set when the
					site is not available. By clicking on the + sign, you can set when the busy
					period starts and ends as well as the option to select "all day", this is good
					for something like construction. You can also add a description for the
					unavailablility e.g; "construction on this site on 2/2/11" <mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/site_list_window2.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The "availabilities" window in the timetable list view</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Virtual Sites</title>
				<para>onCourse allows a College to flag a given Site as a <guilabel>Virtual
						Site</guilabel>. These sites can be used in either of the following
					scenarios: <itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Classes that are delivered Online </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Self paced learning where there is no set timetable</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				<para>When you create a new Site within onCourse and flag it as a <guilabel>Virtual
						Site</guilabel>, onCourse will automatically assign a <guilabel>Virtual
						Room</guilabel> to that site. The reason for this is that Class enrolments
					must be assigned to a Room, they cannot be assigned to just a Site. Whilst this
					virtual room record is hidden within the user interface, it has been created
					automatically when the Site is flagged as being a <guilabel>Virtual
						Site</guilabel>. </para>
				<para>You can also convert an existing Site to a <guilabel>Virtual Site</guilabel>
					by ticking this box within the General tab of the Site Record. Please note that
					if the existing Site which you wish to convert to a Virtual Site has more than 1
					Room allocated against it, it cannot be converted to a Virtual Site. </para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="rooms">
			<title>Room Record Tabs</title>
			<section xml:id="rooms-General">
				<title>General</title>
				<para>Here you can set the Room name, the site to which the room is related , room
					capacity, room specific directions for once the student is at the site and add
					details about the facilities available in that room. There is also an attachment
					window available for things like images (see above for more on the attachment
					window). </para>
				<note>
					<para>You will note that the Facilities and Directions fields within the Room
						record is part of the dynamic course content which is automatically
						published to your onCourse website. The <guiicon>A</guiicon> icon shown in
						the bottom right hand corner of the Facilities and Directions fields allows
						a user to view the approximate layout of the text prior to publishing the
						information on the website by hovering their mouse over this icon. </para>
				</note>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/room_record_general_tab.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>View of onCourse Room record general tab</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="rooms-Notes">
				<title>Notes</title>
				<para>This tab is for internal notes about the room. It is not published on the
					website.</para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="room-Timetable">
				<title>Timetable</title>
				<para>You can view the room timetable here, to see all sessions using this room. You
					can also set room unavailabilities (see above for more on the availabilities
					window). It is important to note that you can not add new sessions or classes
					from here - you need to do this in the class window.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating Sites and Rooms</title>
		<para>The next step in setting up your onCourse program is entering sites and rooms. You can
			give each room a name, specific directions on how to get there, and describe the facilities
			that are available. It also allows you to make it possible for students to view detailed maps
			and instructions from your website about where their class will be held, saving your staff
			time with phone calls giving directions and saving students frustration when they can't
			accurately locate the venue.</para>
		<para>Creating sites and rooms is a valuable part of your training resource management. Every
			time you book a session in a room, the timetable is updated and the room becomes scheduled.
			This means that if you try to book another session in this room at the same time, you will be
			notified that it is already booked. onCourse will not prevent you from double booking a
			room.</para>
		<para>If you have a room or site that you hire on a casual basis you can also set the
			availability for it. For example, you may hire a public hall on Wednesday evenings. When you
			set up this room, you can specify it is only available for you to book between 5pm and 9pm.
			Course coordinators scheduling classes will an error message if they try to book a class in
			this room on another night, or to start before 5pm. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>It is a good idea to enter the sites and rooms first so later when you add the courses
				you can easily assign them to a location.</para>
		</tip>
		<example>
			<title>How to set up a new site</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> From the Sites list view, click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button in the top
						right hand corner of the screen. A new site screen will open on the general tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> In the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> field enter the name of the site Waverley Campus.
						Remember the site is where the rooms are located and is not the rooms themselves, that
						comes later.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>street address</guilabel> of the site. If you report AVETMISS
						your sites must have accurate address <guilabel>suburbs</guilabel> and
							<guilabel>postcodes</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can enter the exact location of the site in the <guilabel>latitude</guilabel>
						and <guilabel>longitude</guilabel> fields. You don't need to know the latitude and
						longitude off the top of your head! By clicking the hyperlink 'Find this location' you
						are taken to the ish page www.ish.com.au/oncourse/coordinates. Type in the street
						address of the site, click view and Google Maps will find the exact location. Copy and
						paste the coordinates in to your 'new site' window. This now means the google map of
						this venue will be available to your students over the web. They can even type in their
						own address to get step by step directions to the venue.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Move to the Directions tab. If you have specific <guilabel>driving
							directions</guilabel>, <guilabel>public transport directions</guilabel> or
							<guilabel>special instructions</guilabel> like parking, you can add them here. This
						information is published to your ish website. Because these description fields are Rich
						Text enabled (the blue A indicates this) you can add hyperlinks to local bus timetables
						or other useful pages for your students, like transport infoline or your local
						equivalent.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you have any internal notes about the site, you can add them on the notes tab.
						These are not published to your ish website.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set an unavailability for the site, go to the Timetable tab and click on the
						option on the bottom of the screen <guibutton>List</guibutton>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a new availability rule by clicking the <guibutton>+</guibutton>and define
						the <guilabel>Start</guilabel> and <guilabel>End</guilabel> date and time. You can also
						select 'all day' instead of selecting a time period. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose if you wish to <guibutton>repeat</guibutton> the unavailability and the
							<guibutton>end date</guibutton> of the repeats. You also need to add a
							<guilabel>description</guilabel> of why the resource is unavailable. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click save. Once you have saved your site, you will be returned to the list
						view.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to set up a new Room</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>From the site list, double click on the site you want to add rooms to.
						Alternatively, you can open the Rooms list from the splash screen and click on the
							<guibutton>+</guibutton> button in the top right hand corner of the screen</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>name</guilabel> of the room eg. Studio 1. If your venue only has
						one room, such as a community hall, you still need to create at least one room so you
						can link a class to the room.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>seated capacity</guilabel>. This is how many people the room can
						hold. If you try to book a class into this room that has a maximum student number
						greater than the seated capacity, you will get a warning.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>On the Direction tab you can enter the <guilabel>directions</guilabel> to the room
						eg. ground floor, level 3 and the the room <guilabel>facilities</guilabel> eg. tables
						and chairs, screen projector.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you have any internal notes about the room, you can add them on the notes tab.
						These are not published to your ish website.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set an unavailability for the room, go to the Timetable tab and click on the
						option on the bottom of the screen <guibutton>List</guibutton>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a new availability rule by clicking the <guibutton>+</guibutton>and define
						the <guilabel>Start</guilabel> and <guilabel>End</guilabel> date and time. You can also
						select 'all day' instead of selecting a time period. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose if you wish to <guibutton>repeat</guibutton> the unavailability and the
							<guibutton>end date</guibutton> of the repeats. You also need to add a
							<guilabel>description</guilabel> of why the resource is unavailable. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click <guibutton>save</guibutton> to save and close the record.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> To edit any of the information you have entered simply click on the room or site
						that you wish to update. This will bring up the edit screen for that record. Make your
						changes and click <guilabel>save</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
</chapter>
