<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="tutors">
	<title>Tutors</title>
	<section xml:id="tutors-termsAndDefs">
		<title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Contact</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A person or company in onCourse is called a contact. Contact can be set as a
						Student, Tutor or Company, none of these or a combination of these.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Tutor</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A tutor is a type of contact. A tutor is anyone who teaches a class for, or on
						behalf of, your college. They may be an employee or a contractor, and could also be a
						student of your college who is enrolled in classes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Student</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A student enrols in classes. A contact or tutor who enrols in a class will
						automatically be set as a student (in addition to being a tutor).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Company</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A company contact is a business, not an individual. Companies may also be set as
						tutors, for example, you may contract to have ACME Tennis Coaching teach classes for
						your business. You can assign the company as the tutor of the class.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Relationship</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Contacts can be related to each other. For example, a company that delivers courses
						for your college, may also have individual contact records set up for their staff that
						teach or assist with the sessions. These contacts would be set as employees of the
						company. By doing this you could advertise the class as being taught by the company,
						which would be the information that displays on your ish website, while also internally
						managing the individuals that would be booked to deliver each class session.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Working with Tutors</title>
		<subtitle>Navigating the list and record windows</subtitle>
		<para>All records in onCourse can be viewed in either a list view or record view. You need to
			open the list view to access individual records.</para>
		<para>To access the tutors records go to either the splash screen and click on
				<guibutton>Tutors</guibutton> or the onCourse menu <menuchoice>
				<guimenuitem>People</guimenuitem>
				<guisubmenu>Tutors</guisubmenu>
			</menuchoice> . This will open the Tutors list view window.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>The onCourse list view</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>Parts of the window - On the right hand part of the window are the course records
					listed in a summary view. The title bar shows you how many records you have. The top
					section of the window contains the search function and the add and delete records button.
					You will also find a cog wheel button that allows for special functions for one or more
					records in the list. In the left hand side of the list window are quick searches to enable
					you to work with groups of data.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Record summaries - The list of records in this window allows you to enter a record by
					double clicking, or select the record to perform special functions by single clicking. A
					selected record will be highlighted. You can select one or more records in the list by
					using shift-click to select a range, or control-click to select a group of individual
					records. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Columns and sorting - Column headings can be used to sort records in the list. Click
					on the header to sort in alphabetical order. Click it again to sort by reverse
					alphabetical order. You can also drag the columns around and modify their width to set
					your preferred layout.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Quick search - By typing the first few letters of the Tutor's surname into the quick
					search field, you can reduce the list of records to those that match.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Advanced Search - Advanced search can be accessed by clicking on the Magnifying glass
					image in the quick search field. This will open the query editor to allow you to choose
					which fields and which data you want to search on. You can add multiple criteria to your
					searches.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Saved Searches - After performing an advanced search, you can choose to save the
					search parameters to allow you to quickly run the search again. To save a search, click on
					the cogwheel within the query editor and select 'save find'. The saved search will appear
					in the left hand part of the window.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Tag groups - Any tag groups you have created that relate to Tutors, like Subject, will
					appear here. By checking any of these check boxes you will see the list of records on the
					right hand side reduced to records that match that criteria. You can tag records in bulk
					by selecting a group of records on the right and right clicking on a tag name on the
					left.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Core filters - Core filters reduce the list of records to those that match the filter
					criteria. By default, most onCourse windows open with filters applied so you are only
					working with your current records. You can switch core filters on and off by ticking the
					checkboxes.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<tip>
			<para>Filters and searches work together in onCourse. If you run an search and do not see the
				result you expect, this may be because a filter that is checked is preventing the record you
				are searching for from being displayed.</para>
		</tip>
		<para>You can enter a tutor record by double clicking on it in the window.</para>
		<section xml:id="tutors-recordTabs">
			<title>Tutor Record Tabs</title>
			<section>
				<title>General</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/tutor_record_general_tab.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>The general tab is an important tab that holds alot of information about the tutors.
					Once in the general tab, you will be able to edit things like:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Name</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Address</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor phone and fax numbers</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor email</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Membership window - lists any memberships tutor has</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Message (alert for operator)</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Date of birth</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Gender</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Honorific</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Concessions window - This window is not applicable to a tutor as concessions are
							not needed by a tutor</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Relation Window - From this window, you can set relationships to that tutor</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/tutor_general_relation.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "relation" window in the tutor general tab</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Financial</title>
				<para>This tab is a view only screen and shows you the financial transactions your company
					has with the selected tutor. Here you will see invoices issued or received and payments
					made to the tutor listing all the relevant information and providing links these records.
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Messages</title>
				<para>This tab lists all messages sent to the tutor from onCourse via email, SMS and post
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Notes</title>
				<para>This tab keeps a list of all notes you have relating to the tutor and any web visible
					or private documents like resume, certificates and references.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Resume</title>
				<para>This is where you store the bio information about the tutor you wish to publish to
					your ish website</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tutor</title>
				<para>This tab shows a list of the classes the tutor is scheduled to teach</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Timetable</title>
				<para>This tab shows the teaching timetable for all the sessions for the tutor in a calendar
					or list layout and tutor's availability can be set here.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating Tutors</title>
		<para>You will need to keep your tutor's contact details on file and what classes and sessions
			they are scheduled to teach each term. If you are an RTO you will also need to keep copies of
			their resume and qualifications on file. onCourse allows you to do this. Each tutor has their
			own personal file in onCourse which is easy to access and update. </para>
		<para>If you have a large number of casual staff who work at a variety of different venues, it
			can be difficult to manage communication with them as you might not see them in person very
			often. Tutors listed in onCourse can be emailed or SMS'd easily and all messages sent out of
			the system are tracked in the tutors record helping you to keep all communications listed and
			organised. onCourse is designed to help you manage your staff records with ease. </para>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a new tutor</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>With either the Tutor or Contact window list view open, click on the
							<guibutton>+</guibutton> button in the top right hand corner of the screen. A new
						contact screen will open. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Set the contact as a <guibutton>Tutor</guibutton>. You will see that an additional tab
						for tutor resume is added to the record.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>First Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Last Name</guilabel> of the
						tutor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>Address</guilabel> and other contact detail for the tutor. If
						you add an <guilabel>Email</guilabel> address, your tutors can log into your ish website
						to check their class schedules and you can email them directly from onCourse. If you
						enter a <guilabel>Mobile phone</guilabel> number, you can send SMS to your tutor from
						onCourse.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>For each contact method (mail, email and SMS) you have the option to opt the contact
						out of marketing communication. The default setting is to “accept marketing material,”
						so when you click on the cog wheel above these fields, you will see this option is
						highlighted with a tick. This means that when you have marketing mail outs, this address
						will be on the mailing list. To change this setting simply click on the cog wheel and
						select the option “opt out from postal marketing material” if the person dosen't want to
						receive marketing communication from you .The other option is “undeliverable”, meaning
						that no mail is to be delivered to this address because it is incorrect, or in the case
						of an email address, has received an undeliverable response from the mail server.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The field <guilabel>message (alert for operator)</guilabel> is for any special notes
						that are important or relevant to this contact for eg. they might allow their phone
						number to be given to students.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Use the resume tab to create a publicly listed biography for the tutor. This screen shows
						that information which is displayed on your website. Be aware that this is
						an automatic function. For example, you might post a brief description for
						this particular tutor, their background and experience and how it relates to
						the courses they are teaching. As this information will be visible to
						students and general public on the website, it is recommended that you
						obtain permission from the tutor to publish this information. You can enter
						the text directly into the screen or cut and paste from another source. The
						text in the field can be formatted using Rich text. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Move to the Notes tab to add attachments or other notes to the tutor record. The
						text in the <guilabel>notes</guilabel> field is private. Attachments can be public (on
						the website) or private (only available in onCourse).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> To attach documents in the Notes tab, click on the + sign on the right hand side of
						the screen. This will open up a drop down screen “attachment (new)”. Click on
							<guibutton>import</guibutton> to open up your files. Select the file you wish to
						attach and enter You can then select the “available on web” box if you wish to publish
						the document on your website. Click <guibutton>ok</guibutton>. This will close the
						attachment screen and return you to the notes screen. Here you will see a list of the
						attached files. You can delete any files by clicking the - sign.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<note>
			<para>By creating a new tutor record and entering the email address for that tutor, the system
				will automatically create a new account for the Tutor to access the <guilabel>Skills onCourse</guilabel>
				Portal. You can then instruct your tutors to go to the <guilabel>Skills onCourse</guilabel> log in page
				and enter their first name, last name and email address and click on the <guilabel>Forgot Password</guilabel>link. They will then receive an automatically generated email with their new password. </para><para>Admin staff of the College are not able to view or update the Tutor Portal password via the
				onCourse Client, this must be done via the <guilabel>Forgot Password</guilabel>link
				on the Skills onCourse home page.</para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Contacting tutors by email or SMS</title>
		<para>You may wish to notify individual tutors if their course is running or cancelled, or
			groups of tutors with information about activities and event at the College. If you create and
			send the message from onCourse, the history of the message is stored within the tutor's record
			on the messaged tab.</para>
		<para>You must have set up an SMS and email gateway with ish to use this feature. For
			information on how to do this, read the General Preferences documentation. </para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Open the tutor window and use the 'find' to search for the tutors you want to contact
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Highlight the tutors you wish to contact in the list. To do this select the first
					contact name, hold down shift then select the last contact name and click on the cog wheel
					icon on the top right hand side of the window.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Choose “send message to xx contacts” and the email/SMS window will open.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>You will see in your list of contacts how many people can be emailed, that is have
					supplied an email address, and how many can be SMS'd having supplied a mobile phone number
					or neither of these things.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select the 'send email' and/or 'send SMS' box. If you choose to send both, you can
					also select the option under SMS 'including people who are emailed'. If people have
					supplied both mobile number and email address, it is a cheaper option (and the default
					option) to just email them, and only SMS those who don't have email. However, sometimes
					you may wish to send both, just to make sure. While most of the time it only takes a few
					seconds to deliver an SMS, it is not an instantaneous technology, even if it often seems
					this way. It can take up to 3 days for an SMS to be delivered. This has to do with the
					phone carrier, something that ish has no control over, or because the user has their phone
					switched off.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter the email subject in the <guilabel>subject</guilabel> field. This field is
					mandatory and the email cannot be sent unless you enter a subject. The same applies for
					sending SMS. You need to enter a description of the call ie. staff meeting, invoice
					reminder etc before the message can be sent. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Type your email and/or your SMS and press <guibutton>send</guibutton>.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/sending_message_to_contact.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Sending a message to a Tutor via the cogwheel function</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Payroll</title>
		<para>You will see a tag icon just above the address field. Click on this and a drop down menu
			offers you “payroll wage intervals” and “tutors.”</para>
		<para>Payroll wage intervals - put your curser here and you have the choice of weekly,
			fortnightly and monthly payment schedules. Select one. </para>
		<para>Tutors - offers you the choice of : contract tutors - those tutors who will invoice your
			business pending tutors - those tutors who are not yet working for you vet tutors - vocational
			education and training tutors</para>
		<para> Make your selection and a tag icon will appear showing the chosen tags. </para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Contacts and Attachments</title>
		<para>Attachments provide a way of adding web visible or private documents like resumes,
			certificates and references to a contact.</para>
		<section>
			<title>To add an attachment to a contact</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>open the contact you wish to add the attachment to then select the "notes"
						tab</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>select the "+" button to bring up the attachment screen</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>from the attachment screen click on the "Import" button and browse to the location
						of the file. Once you have located the file you wish to attach, select it and click
						"Open"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>the file will now appear on the attachment screen. From the attachment screen select
						"Ok" to add the attachment</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>To open or view an attachment</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>open the contact you wish to view the attachment for then select the "notes"
						tab</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>from the list of attachments double click on the attachment you wish to open. The
						attachment window will then open, from it select "Save to disk" </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>a window will open asking where to save the file. Save the file somewhere
						locally</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>you can then open the file from the location you saved it to in the previous
						step</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
