<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="usi">
    <title>Unique Student Identifier (USI)</title>
    <section>
        <title>What is the USI?</title>
        <para>Complying with the January 1 2015 USI requirements is important for our RTO customers,
            and there are a number of tools we have added to streamline this process for you. More
            information about what you need to do to be compliant is available on our forum.</para>
        <para>The new enrolment confirmation email template contains a conditional string for VET
            students that explains what a USI is and why they need to tell you theirs. This email
            directs them to a special onCourse portal page (no log in required) requesting they
            supply their USI or go through the process to create one. </para>
        <para>onCourse is now integrated with the USI Web services, so once you have received a
            student’s USI the web services verification process will run and mark the USI as either
            ‘verified’ or ‘not verified’. For students completing the self service portal, they will
            be prompted to update their name or date of birth in onCourse if this doesn’t match
            their official USI data e.g. Bob may need to update his name to Robert, as per his
            drivers license record. </para>
        <para>Every Monday morning, all recently enrolled VET students who have not supplied you
            with their USI will be sent an automatic reminder email on how to complete this process
            and why it is important they do so. There is a customisable email template and script
            that runs this process which you can edit to meet your preferred business requirements.
            A student who gives up or can not validate their USI will be flagged in onCourse for you
            to follow up. </para>
        <para>Alternatively, you may need to undertake the creation and validation process on behalf
            of the student. On the student record AVETMISS tab you will see the USI field now has an
            additional option next to it that says ‘create a USI’. Once you enter a 10 character
            USI, the verification process will run automatically in the background. If the USI
            verifies, then there is nothing more for you to do. If the verification returns an
            error, you can edit the non-matching data (first name, last name or date of birth) and
            try again. </para>
        <para>Additional validation has been added to assist your USI compliance. A student in
            onCourse who has a verified USI can’t have their first name, last name or date of birth
            changed without the USI agency having the updated change also. </para>
        <para>As you are not allowed to issue certifications to students without a USI, the onCourse
            certificate print process now includes an additional validation check. If your
            certificate record was created after 1/1/2015, it will not print unless the student has
            a verified USI in onCourse. Certificates created prior to 2015 will continue to be
            printable without a USI. Additional access control levels have been added to allow you
            to override this print control for selected users.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
