<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="usi">
    <title>Unique Student Identifier (USI)</title>
    <section>
        <title>What is the USI?</title>
        <para>On 1 January 2015 the Australian Commonwealth government introduced a Unique Student
            Identifier which will be issued to every student undertaking vocational training.
            Eventually this USI will be issued to every child starting primary school and every
            student at university. The USI is similar to existing identity systems already in place
            in Australia: medicare number, tax file number, driver's license, etc. but it is not
            printed on an identity card and it is illegal for RTOs to print them on identity cards
            or certificates.</para>
        <para>The USI can only be issued by the USI agency in response to a request from a student
            who comes with certain idenfication papers. Medicare cards, driver's licenses, birth
            certificates and passports are probably the most common forms of identification which
            can be used.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Requirements and limitations</title>
        <para>The USI legislation puts certain limitations on how the USI can be used and how it
            must be reported.<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The USI cannot be printed on certificates. None of the default
                        certificates in onCourse include the USI.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The USI must be verified by the RTO. onCourse has a special feature to
                        automate this process.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You may not issue a certificate to a student until you have their USI and
                        have verified it. onCourse will allow you to create Certificate records but
                        not print them until the USI is verified. You can override this behaviour
                        with the appropriate administrator rights, but you must then ensure you have
                        implemented another verification process in your RTO.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The USI is a new field in all AVETMISS 7 flavours.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Capturing the USI</title>
        <para>The USI need not be captured at the time of enrolment, but typically you'll want to
            have it entered and verified before the class is completed in order to not delay issuing
            of certificates.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Manual entry</title>
            <para>When you create a new student or update an existing one, you can type the USI
                directly into the field available on the "VET" tab. This can also be done directly
                within the Quick Enrol process. The USI will be checked for validity (it is the
                correct length and matches a checksum) and then verified against the USI
                agency.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/invalid_USI.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>....</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Student self-service</title>
            <para>If you don't capture the USI from the student manually, onCourse will send the
                student an email to request the details. This is done in the enrolment confirmation
                email and again every Monday at 9am until the class is complete or the USI is
                entered. You can modify these templates or alter the script which sends these weekly
                emails. Note that students are only sent this email if they are enrolled in a VET
                flagged class, to avoid bothering your students engaging in non-VET training.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/USI_email.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>An example of a confirmation email with USI information</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>Once the student gets the email requesting their USI, they will be able to click
                on a link which takes them directly to a page within the skillsOnCourse portal. They
                will not require a password and the link will be valid for 3 days from the email
                being sent. The URL is cryptographically signed so that they will not work after the
                expiry date and they will not be transferrable between students. </para>
            <para>The skillsOnCourse portal page will explain the USI to the student and give them a
                convenience link to create or recover a USI if they don't have one or have forgotten
                it. This has been optimised so that it can be used on mobile and tablet devices. The
                student will be able to enter the USI and onCourse will handle the verification
                process automatically.</para>
            <para>The student will be asked to complete three steps: first their date of birth and
                USI, then the standard AVETMISS questions which can be skipped and finally some
                additional information such as a driver's license to validate the USI. If the USI
                agency reports back that the student's name is wrong (for example, they changed
                their name after getting married) then onCourse will give them the opportunity to
                fix this.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/USI_portal_step1.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>What you see when you have entered the wrong USI in the portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Verifying the USI</title>
        <para>If you entered the USI manually, or the student entered it online, the USI will
            automatically be verified against the USI agencies system. In order for this process to
            work we will require a special authorisation key called an auskey from you and linked to
            your RTO. Please contact your onCourse account manager to assist you with this process.
            Unfortunately this system will not work for onCourse community edition users who don't
            have a support agreement with ish. In that case, you can still capture the USI within
            onCourse but you will not be able to take advantage of the online student self-service
            process or the automatic verification process.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/verification_failed.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>....</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
