<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="vouchers">
    <title>Vouchers</title>
    <para>Voucher products can be created in onCourse, and then offered for sale either via the
        College website or through the office via Quick Enrol. These vouchers can be gift
        certificates, a way to sell a bundle of enrolments as a set fee, or as a method of issuing a
        student with a credit, allowing them to apply that credit to an open or restricted range of
        courses.</para>
    <example>
        <title>Voucher Use Cases</title>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product for sale for a user specified dollar value. The redemption
                    value is the same as the purchase price and has a fixed redemption period e.g.
                    12 months. This type of voucher is typically known as a gift certificate.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product for sale for a different redemption price to the purchase
                    price. e.g. purchase price $100, redemption value $120. This type of voucher can
                    then be used as credit to purchase enrolments or other products.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product offered for sale for a fixed fee, redeemable for a single
                    enrolment in a course or set of courses.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product offered for sale for a fixed fee and fixed number of
                    enrolments from a set of one or more courses. For example 4 enrolments from one
                    course (a year's worth of enrolments in a course) or 4 enrolments in 4 courses
                    (one enrolment in each of the four courses).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A way to sell a bundle of enrolments to a company for a fixed fee, for their
                    staff to enrol in a class of their choice from a course, e.g. 10 enrolments in
                    your choice of classes for the course Computers for Beginners. This type of
                    voucher would send the invoice on redemption to the nominated company contact,
                    rather than to the student.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </example>
    <section xml:id="vouchers-Definitions">
        <title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Voucher Type</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A voucher is a product which can be sold and later redeemed for other
                        purchases or enrolments. Vouchers can be redeemed for a monetary value or
                        for a fixed number of enrolments in a set range of courses. The voucher type
                        describes how much the voucher costs to purchase, how long it is valid for
                        and what it can be redeemed for.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Voucher</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Vouchers are the list of purchased voucher type products. Vouchers can be
                        purchased and redeemed through Quick Enrol. This list shows who purchased
                        the voucher, who it is redeemable by and what the remaining value of the
                        voucher includes. Every voucher has a unique code that must be quoted for
                        redemption.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="vouchers-Creating">
        <title>Creating a voucher type</title>
        <para>For most cases when a user wants to buy a voucher, they will nominate the price they
            wish to purchase the voucher for, and that the price will also be the redemption value
            of the voucher. (Type 1) This type of voucher product will be created by default for all
            onCourse instances and be called "Gift certificate". It will only be enabled if the
            College has the right license that enables this feature. </para>
        <para>In addition, colleges can create other types of voucher products that are linked to
            enrolment permissions and these will have purchase prices fixed by the college. Some of
            these types of voucher products may also be available for sale on the website.</para>
        <para>A voucher may be sold as part of the existing QE process or it may be given away for
            free (sold with 100% discount). Either way, an email is sent to the payer with the
            details of that voucher (not the student since it may be a gift, if the student and the
            payer are different people).</para>
        <section>
            <title>Navigating around the Voucher Type window</title>
            <para>To open the voucher type window you can either use the splash screen and click on
                the Voucher type option in the Marketing tab or the onCourse menu File → Preferences
                → Voucher type. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/vouchers/voucher_list.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>View of the voucher type window</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <note>
                <para>If a voucher passes the expiry date, the status is set to 'Expired' and the
                    balance of the voucher purchase price is transferred from the Voucher Liability
                    account to the Vouchers Expired income account. Expired vouchers are greyed out
                    in the voucher list and can't be redeemed and edited. Their expiry date can not
                    be changed.</para>
            </note>
            <para>To create a new voucher type simply click on the + icon in the top right hand side
                of the window and enter the information required. </para>
            <section xml:id="voucherType-General">
                <title>Voucher general tab</title>
                <para> There are a number of fields in the general tab, they are:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>SKU - this refers to a stock-keeping unit, a unique identifier for
                                each distinct product and service that can be purchased. You can
                                create whatever product code you want for any voucher.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Name - allows you to name the voucher.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Liability Account - allows you to choose the liability account you
                                want the purchase price of the voucher to be deposited into until it
                                is redeemed or expires</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Expiry date - this allows you to create a expiry date for the
                                voucher from the date of purchase e.g. 365 days.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Options for redemption - you can select whether you want the
                                voucher to be able to be redeemed for an enrolment/s, for the
                                purchased price or for different price.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist><mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/vouchers/qual_voucher.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab in a new voucher type record</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject> If you want the voucher to be able to be redeemed for a enrolment
                    you can leave the drop down box as "enrolment in" as this is set as the default.
                    You will need to choose how many enrolments you want it to apply to in the box
                    to the right. A voucher may allow for multiple enrolments in one course, an
                    enrolment in choice of courses, or a mix of the two.</para>
                <para> From here click on the + icon to choose what course/s the voucher can be
                    redeemed against, then finally enter the voucher purchase price at the bottom
                    left hand side of the window.</para>
                <para>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/vouchers/Voucher_Type_General_Enrolment_In.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab if the option for redemption is left with
                                the default option "enrolment in"</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <para>When clicking on the + button you open up a new window that gives you
                            three options to choose what course/s the voucher can be redeemed
                            against, they are:</para>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Course - allows you to choose a specific course/s that the voucher
                                can be redeemed against.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>All courses tagged with - allows you to choose a group of courses
                                that have the same tag.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>All enabled courses - allows you to use this voucher for any
                                course available.</para>
                            <note>
                                <para>If you want to apply a voucher to more than one specific
                                    course then you can add each course one by one using the first
                                    option "Course" making sure you select OK after each course
                                    added.</para>
                            </note>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/vouchers/Voucher_Type_General_Courses.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the three options you can apply the voucher to.</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
                <para>A standard 'Gift voucher' type of voucher is redeemed for it's purchase price.
                    You can choose this option from the drop down menu. <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/vouchers/Voucher_Type_General_Purchase_Price.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab if the option "purchase price" is selected
                                from the drop down box</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
                <para>If you want it to be redeemed for a different price than the one purchased for
                    then select "value" from the drop down menu and choose the amount it will be
                    redeemed for. This would usually be more than the purchase price, not less.<mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/vouchers/Voucher_Type_General_Price.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab if the option "value" is selected from the
                                drop down box</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="voucherType-Web">
                <title>Voucher web tab</title>
                <para>This tab allows you to choose if this voucher is available to be purchased
                    online and if you wish to include any marketing copy on your website.<itemizedlist>
                        <para>There are two check boxes in this tab:</para>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Can be purchased online - when checked it allows people to buy
                                this voucher on your website. If unchecked, the voucher can only be
                                purchased via the office.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Is on sale - means the voucher is available to be purchased. If
                                you are creating a once off voucher for a corporate customer, you
                                may wish to uncheck the on sale option so it is disabled and can not
                                be purchased again through the office or website.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <para>You can also add a more in depth description that will be displayed on the
                    website (as long as both check boxes are selected) in the Web description
                    field.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/vouchers/voucher_description.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>View of the web tab in a new voucher type record</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="vouchers-Purchasing">
        <title>Purchasing a voucher</title>
        <para>Purchasing a voucher in onCourse is done through Quick Enrol window. You can search
            for a voucher by either start typing in the Vouchers name or SKU in the 'Enter course or
            item' field on the left side of the page. Alternatively you can click in the 'Enter
            course or item' field, then click on the 'Show all' button next to the word 'VOUCHERS'
            on the right side of the page. Once you have found the voucher you want click the
            'Select' button next to it.</para>
        <note>
            <para>When a voucher is purchased it always gets sent to the payer just like the invoice
                does.</para>
        </note>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/vouchers/QE_Finding_A_Voucher.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>How to find a voucher you want to purchase through Quick Enrol</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once you have found the voucher you want to add you have a few editable areas in the
            'VOUCHER PURCHASE' page<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Price each - This allows you to individually adjust the cost for this one
                        of purchase of this voucher</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Expires on - You can also adjust the expiry date for this one of purchase
                        of this voucher if it's different from the one originally setup</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>When voucher is redeemed, invoice will be sent to x - This check box
                        allows you to choose whether an invoice gets automatically sent to the payer
                        if the voucher gets redeemed.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/vouchers/QE_Selecting_A_Voucher.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Options when purchasing a voucher in Quick Enrol</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Purchasing a voucher on the web</title>
            <para>You can find a list of vouchers on your website by putting /products on the end of
                your homepages URL. A voucher is purchased the same way as if you buying a course or
                product.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/vouchers/voucher_email.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Confirmation message after purchasing a voucher online</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
        <section xml:id="vouchers-Redemption">
        <title>Redeeming a voucher</title>
        <para>A student can redeem a voucher either via an office based enrolment in Quick Enrol or
            by enrolling online themselves. They will have to supply their voucher code which can be
            found in their voucher confirmation email. A student can type in the voucher code in the
            payment window during an online enrolment or your staff can redeem the voucher for them
            during an office based enrolment.</para>
        <para>For more information on the financial transactions that occur in the general ledger
            when a voucher is bought and sold, refer to the <link xlink:href="#accounting"
                >accounting chapter.</link></para>
        <para>A voucher is a payment method against an invoice.</para>
        <para>When you are trying to redeem a voucher in Quick Enrol</para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>You have to firstly add the student/s, class/es or product/s as normal when
                    enrolling a student</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>In the bottom field on the left hand side, 'Enter voucher or promotion..',
                    enter the voucher code that the student would have received by email (as seen in
                    the screen shot below)</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                            fileref="images/vouchers/Adding_voucher_code.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Entering a voucher code during quick enrol</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Click on the '+' symbol next the field or press return on the keyboard</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>This in turn will apply amount available on the voucher as a payment towards
                    this invoice (as seen in the screen shot below)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Additional payments can be added if there is a difference between the voucher
                    balance and the invoice balance, such as a credit card payment.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                            fileref="images/vouchers/applied_voucher_code.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Redeeming a voucher on the web</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Continue the process as you normally would when enrolling someone through
                    Quick Enrol</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <note>
            <para>A voucher can online be redeemed in onCourse through the Quick Enrol window. It
                can not be used post enrolment as a payment in type.</para>
        </note>
        <section>
            <title>Redeeming a voucher on the web</title>
            <para>During the checkout stage of your website enrolment there is a field (as seen in
                the screenshot below) in the Summary section that allows you to enter a voucher
                code. This field is available again on the payment page. Enter the voucher code,
                click "Add Code' and it will redeem it against the value of the order if it is
                valid. If the code is not valid then an error message will appear.</para>
            <para>Additional payment methods will be requested during the final stages of the
                checkout process if the voucher doesn't cover the entire balance of the
                enrolment(s).</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/vouchers/Redeeming_a_voucher.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Redeeming a voucher on the web</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <note>
                <para>When someone buys a voucher through the office they need to wait up to 15
                    minutes before they can redeem it online.</para>
            </note>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="vouchers-General">
        <title>Navigating the Voucher list window </title>
        <para>This window displays the list of purchased vouchers. To open the voucher window you
            can go to either use the splash screen and click on the Voucher option in the Marketing
            tab or select from the onCourse menu Resources → Voucher. </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <para>In this window you can:</para>
            <listitem>
                <para>Check the status of a sold, redeemed or partially redeemed voucher</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Resend a voucher code by email - this can be found in the cog wheel and can be
                    done for any number of records at a time.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Cancel a voucher - this can only be done one voucher at a time. More
                    information can be found in the Cancelling a Voucher section below.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Create/purchase a voucher from the + button. This opens the Quick Enrol
                    window.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/vouchers/Vouchers_window.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>View of the voucher window</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>To open a voucher record simply double click on a record in the list, which will open
            a new window. </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <para>This window contains two main tabs, they are:</para>
            <listitem>
                <para>General - this tab allows you to choose who the invoice gets sent through to
                    if redeemed and allows to change the expiry date (prior to the voucher
                    expiring). You would usually only enter data in the 'send invoice on redemption'
                    field if you wanted the invoice to be sent to someone other than the student on
                    redemption, i.e. the employer who purchased the voucher. If you leave this field
                    blank, the invoice will go the payer of the enrolment who redeems the
                    voucher.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Redemption - this tab shows all invoices where the voucher was used as a
                    payment method during enrolment. Double clicking on an item in this list will
                    open the related invoice, where you can see the specific voucher redemption
                    information in the payment panel.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/vouchers/voucher_window_general_tab.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>View of a voucher record</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Cancelling a Voucher</title>
            <para>The cancellation process will check if any of the enrolments invoices were paid
                using a voucher. If you cancel a class and then credit all the students, regardless
                of how they paid their enrolment fee value will be created as a credit note. </para>
            <para>To cancel a voucher purchase, highlight the selected record, click on the cog
                wheel, then select "Cancel voucher". This process is similar to cancelling an
                enrolment, in that you have the option to provide a credit note during the
                cancellation process, or retain the fee paid.</para>
            <para>A cancelled voucher can not be redeemed.<itemizedlist>
                    <para>The options available are:</para>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Create credit note to reverse the voucher fee - this is checked by
                            default, however if you wish to not create a credit note then uncheck
                            this box and select Proceed. Unchecking this option retains all the fee
                            paid for the voucher for your business.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Retain administrative fee - select this box as well if you want to
                            deduct an admin fee from the credit note. From here you can then choose
                            the amount deducted, whether it includes GST and the account the
                            retained fee is attributed to.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/vouchers/Cancelling_a_voucher.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>View of the window when cancelling a voucher</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <note>
                <para>It's your responsibility to note this message during cancellation and follow
                    their own internal policies regarding voucher. You can either use the credit to
                    provide the student with a new voucher to the same or original value, or use the
                    credit note for a standard transfer or refund. For purchase price vouchers this
                    will not be a problem, only fixed price vouchers that offer greater value or
                    enrolment cluster vouchers. </para>
            </note>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
