<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="Vouchers">
    <title>Vouchers</title>
    <para>onCourse vouchers can be offered either via the College website and or issued by College
        administrative staff. These vouchers can be offered as gift certificates or as a method of
        issuing a student with a credit, allowing them to apply that credit to whichever Class they
        wish to do. </para>
<example>
    <title>Voucher Use Cases</title>

    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>A voucher product offered online for a user specified dollar value. Redemption
                    value is the same as the purchase price. This voucher can be sold many
                    times.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>A voucher product offered online for a fixed fee, redeemable for a course or set of courses </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>A voucher product offered online for a fixed fee for one enrolment from each of a set of courses to a maximum number of enrolments. For example 4 enrolments from each of 6 specified courses. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Sell 10 vouchers to a company using Quick Enrol, from a predefined list of available voucher products</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Sell a voucher linked to a particular redeeming contact through Quick Enrol. In this use case the quantity is always limited to one</para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
</example>
    <section>
<title>Issuing a Voucher</title>
        <para>For most cases when a user wants to by a voucher, they will nominate the price they wish to purchase the voucher for, and that the price will also be the redemption value of the voucher. (Type 1) This type of voucher product will be created by default for all onCourse instances and be called "Gift certificate". It will only be enabled if the College has the right license that enables this feature. </para>
  <para>In addition, colleges can create other types of voucher products that are linked to enroment permissions and these will have purchase prices fixed by the college. Some of these types of voucher products may also be available for sale on the website.</para>
        <para>A voucher may be sold as part of the existing QE process or it may be given away for free (sold with 100% discount). Either way, an email is sent to the payer with the details of that voucher (not the student since it may be a gift, if the student and the payer are different people).</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Redeeming a Voucher</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A student can click on the link in the voucher email (the URL contains the voucher code) www.collegeurl.com.au/enrol?voucher=[voucherproduct.code]</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the voucher is linked to the student, then it will be visible in their portal</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A student can type in the voucher code in the payment window (as part of the redesigned enrolment page). </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
</chapter>
