<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="webstart">
    <title>onCourse Cloud</title>
    <section xml:id="webstart-Cloud">
        <title>What is onCourse cloud?</title>
        <para>onCourse cloud is a hosted version of onCourse which ish manage and maintain on your
            behalf. It is the same software and the same user interface as the locally installed
            application.</para>
        <para>The benefits of a cloud hosted solution include:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Hosting of your onCourse server in a Tier 3 data centre
                        located in Australia.</emphasis> ish directly manages the hardware and
                    software, with the data centre providing redundant links to the internet. All
                    networking equipment is full redundant and the database clustered across primary
                    and slave machines. If your primary office loses power or internet, remote
                    access to your onCourse server is still available from other sites.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Management of your onCourse server</emphasis>. ish
                    supply and manage the physical infrastructure that hosts your server, provide
                    offsite backups and manage the upgrade process for you when new versions are
                    released. You do not need to engage your IT support company for any onCourse
                    related issues or assistance as you may with a locally managed version.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Simplified user application access.</emphasis> No
                    software to install or maintain - you launch onCourse by going to a URL created
                    just for you. The software looks and behaves the same as the locally installed
                    version; although you launch the application from inside a browser, you aren't
                    restricted to the simplified user interface of a web application. The full
                    onCourse user experience is available complete with multiple windows, printing
                    and more.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">No need to update and install new client software when
                        your server is upgraded. </emphasis>New versions of the onCourse client
                    software are applied automatically when your staff log in.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Staff access to onCourse from anywhere with internet
                        access.</emphasis> Home, remote training venues, other offices - there is no
                    need for you to set up and manage VPNs or software installation on multiple
                    machines. Access is to onCourse is secure from any venue and encrypted with SSL
                    at the same level of encryption as banking systems.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">A unique database instance for your training
                        organisation.</emphasis> Every onCourse cloud customer has their own mySQL
                    instance of the onCourse server application running. This means we can upgrade
                    your software when you are ready, and your data is not locked into our solution
                    - your database can be handed over to you for self management at any time should
                    you choose to leave the ish Cloud for a locally managed onCourse option, or if
                    you just want to get at your database. </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <section>
            <title>The onCourse Cloud Demo</title>
            <para>If you would like to trial the onCourse cloud hosted application you can find it
                at <link xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/oncourse/cloud/demo/"
                    >https://www.ish.com.au/oncourse/cloud/demo/</link></para>
            <para>This demo is designed for people who wish to explore the onCourse user interface
                and features and give onCourse a test run to see if it is the right solution for use
                in their training organisation. Existing users who want to see the difference in
                performance between their locally hosted onCourse application and a cloud hosted
                onCourse, or who wish to test out new features before their next upgrade are also
                welcome to access the demo.</para>
            <para>The demo contains sample data that is refreshed weekly, and which is shared
                between all current demo users. This demo database is not designed for users to
                enter real classes, students or enrolments. </para>
            <para>The onCourse Demo has a pre-filled user name and password. Just click 'login' to
                access it.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> Running onCourse from your browser </title>
            <para>If you are running the onCourse cloud demo, or trying to reach your training
                organisation's onCourse cloud instance, you will do this via your browser.</para>
            <example>
                <title>How to access the onCourse Cloud</title>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Open a web browser and go to the URL provided by ish. It will look
                            like
                            https://www.ish.com.au/oncourse/cloud/your_training_organisation</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                    fileref="images/URL_browser.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>This is the URL for the onCourse demo. Demo will be replaced
                                    by your training organisation name </para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Nothing will load in the browser window, but a pop up will appear
                            asking you to Open with Java Web Start (default) or Save the file.
                            Select Open with Java Web Start. You may choose to tick the 'do this
                            automatically' option to skip this step next time.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                    fileref="images/open_webstart.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>This window will open when you go to the URL</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The first time you run onCourse, or after an upgrade to the onCourse
                            server has taken place, a new window may display notifying you that the
                            application is being downloaded. This may take a few minutes.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                    fileref="images/download_webstart.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>The onCourse application is downloading for the first time. Be
                                    patient!</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Once the download is complete, or if no download is required, onCourse
                            will load to the login window. Enter your login name and password as
                            supplied by ish and select login.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                    fileref="images/demo_login_screen.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>In the onCourse demo, the login name and password is already
                                    filled in. For your own cloud hosted instance, use the login
                                    name and password provided to you from ish.</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>After you successfully login, onCourse will load to the normal splash
                            screen. Proceed to use onCourse as normal, or if this is your first time
                            in the software, explore the user and interface and press all the
                            buttons to see what they do!</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                    fileref="images/demo_splash.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>If you make it to this screen you have logged in successfully.
                                    Well done!</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Trouble Shooting Java Web Start</title>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Q: In the first window, I don't have the option available open
                    with 'Java Web Start'</emphasis></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">A:</emphasis> Your computer may not have Java installed, or
                the latest version of Java. The onCourse URL should prompt you to download the
                latest version of Java, which you can do at any time from <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.java.com/en/">http://www.java.com/en/</link></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Q: After going to the URL, my browser has given me a
                    security warning. What do I do?</emphasis></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">A: </emphasis>Seeing this window (or not) depends on the
                security settings of your browser. If you choose to 'trust' the certificate, you
                shouldn't see this warning again. If you don't 'trust' the certificate, you won't be
                able to proceed with accessing the onCourse application.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Q: Isn't Java a security risk?</emphasis></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">A: </emphasis>No. Java has been around a very long time and
                is used at large and small companies by billions of people every day. It powers more
                websites than just about any other technology. However it has been used in the past
                for things called applets in your browser and this technology has had flaws which
                allowed malicious websites to do nasty things. onCourse is different: running the
                webstart version is exactly the same as running an application on your desktop
                directly and opens no new security holes. When you see advice about turning off Java
                in your browser that is related to these applets and not to the way onCourse runs or
                any other Java applications run.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Q: When I try to log in, the window shakes and gives me an
                    Authentication Error.</emphasis></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">A:</emphasis> This means your login name or password is
                wrong. Try typing it in again and login again. If the problem persists, <link
                    xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/about/contact">contact ish</link>.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Q: When I try to log in, the window shows a message 'The
                    server could not be contacted".</emphasis></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">A: </emphasis>If it is your first time accessing onCourse,
                this may mean that your local network settings are blocking the traffic between the
                onCourse client and server. Check with your IT staff that outbound traffic over port
                6003 is enabled.</para>
            <para>For users who have logged in successfully before, but are now seeing this error,
                this may mean the hosted cloud server is down for maintenance (you will have
                received notification) or that your local internet is down. Please <link
                    xlink:href="https://www.ish.com.au/about/contact">contact ish</link>.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>