<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-2.1.2">

  <info>
    <title>Release 2.1.2</title>
    <pubdate>24 May 2011</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <section>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed all financial reports where $ displayed as ?</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new report ‘Class Information’, like enrolment confirmation but without
            student particulars</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new report ‘Sales by Course Location’, groups enrolments within data range by
            class site and shows number of enrolments and total fees paid for each class</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added discount column to ‘Class Invoice Report’</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed printing options for ‘Deposit Banking Report’ and added totals to the footer
            of the report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enabled printing of the ‘Transaction Summary and Detail Reports’ from the
            transaction window</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Suppress printing of tutor details in ‘Enrolment Confirmation Report’ when the tutor
            is not marked as being in publicity</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added the student name and invoice number to Transaction Detail report to improve
            reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Suppress display of cancelled class sessions in Room Details report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Display website label and enrolment count for Sales Report where enrolments are
            processed online</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed wrapping for long Unit of Competency names in Certificate Transcripts</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved layout of ‘class roll &emdash; contact no’ report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Suppress printing of unsuccessful units on Statement of Attainment, but ensure they
            print on student transcripts with results (for standard and customised reports)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed sorting of the ‘Budgets’ report and added a new report ‘Budget Summary’ to
            only show totals by subject tag grouping</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <section>
        <title>Important notes</title>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Searching on tags in advanced search has been removed for this release. It has a
              number of problems which are still unresolved and need extensive work. They will
              return in a future release.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Speed and responsiveness of the client and server application improved</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Exporting AVETMISS from classes now allows you to filter outcomes by date
            range</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Server startup is now much faster</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added AVETMISS field: “Still at school” to student window</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new contact fields: title and honorific (eg. “Dr” and “B.Sc”)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added ‘Do not report for AVETMISS’ field to classes to always suppress all related
            records from any type of AVETMISS export</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added choice about assigning same classes and rooms during class duplication
            process</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added additional fields to Certificate window list view and advanced search options
            to improve user interface, including full qualification identifier, certificate number,
            date created and date printed</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <section>
      <title>Important fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Certain dollar amounts for classes would not be rounded correctly, meaning they
            could be several cents away from the desired amount</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Budget tab calculations would sometimes not update onscreen in response to other
            changes even when the values in the database were correct</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Many improvements to the timetabling feature: visual display, behaviour of entry
            fields, speed improvements</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Server startup, upgrade and reference data import has been made more reliable</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Printed report templates are now properly updating when new versions of reports are
            released by ish</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sometimes reference data was not updating properly. This has been fixed.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Incorrect class venue was shown on website where class venue was different to the
            Course venue</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Minor fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>College name and administration site now always visible on the client
            dashboard</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Outcome can now be edited from student screen</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved messaging (email, sms, post) interface</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Reduced size of data file by detecting and avoiding duplicate attachment
            files</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Innodb is now the default for mysql. This only affects users creating new
            databases.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>fixed AVETIMISS export issues, mainly for QLD</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>fixed NSW DET AVETMISS export length to meet the change in standard
            requirements</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>minor adjustments to user interface layout and size</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed ability to revoke incorrectly issued VET Certificates</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Re-enabled ability to create new concession types</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Re-enabled ability to delete attachments from records</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow sales of $0 memberships</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Automatically assign the outcome of 81 to VET flagged courses during AVETMISS
            export, if not set to another value by the user</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow edit of global unavailability rules</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved implementation of access rights with timetable editor interface</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow sort by student name in enrolment window</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow creation of a private booking as the first ‘class’ for a new course</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improve private booking interface to auto select the private booking class for
            enrolment</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
