<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="theCMS_PagesMenusURLs">
	<title>onCourse CMS</title>
	<section>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>Many pages generated in your "onCourse" website will be content automatically generated
			from your Course, Classes, and Tutor descriptions. Some of the pages in your site have URLs
			like this:<simplelist>
				<member>/courses</member>
				<member>/courses/arts/photography</member>
				<member>/course/ABC</member>
				<member>/sites</member>
				<member>/tutor/123</member>
				<member>/site/234</member>
				<member>/enrol</member>
			</simplelist></para>
		<para>These are pages which are automatically handled and generated by onCourse Web. You will
			want to create a whole set of pages for your site to suit your own needs. The content
			management system (CMS) allows you to add additional content to add breadth and cohesion to
			your website. For example, you may like to add an "about us" or "contact" page; these
			additions are handled by the CMS.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Setting Up Log In Access to the CMS</title>
			<para>Before you start editing content within the CMS you need to set up a user name and password
				to log in.</para>
			<para>onCourse enables any user to also have the ability to log into and edit content within the
				CMS using the same log in credentials for the CMS that you use to access the
				onCourse Client . To do this go to File > Preferences > Users and open the relevant
				record, then tick the box to allow the user to edit the CMS. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%" fileref="images/edit_user_CMS_access.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enabling CMS Access within onCourse User Profile</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Logging in</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%" fileref="images/login.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Login to the CMS Administration</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Log into the CMS by visiting your normal live site and adding /cms/login to the end. For
				example, if your site is http://www.acme.com.au, your CMS will be accessed at
				http://www.acme.com.au/cms/login</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finding your way around</title>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
							fileref="images/findYourWay.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Finding your way around the CMS</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>Once logged in, a new toolbar will be visible on the bottom of the browser
				window. You can continue to browse through your site as normal, and when you reach a page
				you'd like to edit, the toolbar gives you the options to do so. </para>
			<para>Across the bottom of your screen you will find two grey bars. The bottom bar allows you to quickly access the primary
				areas of the CMS (each of which are explained in detail below).</para>
			<para> The upper bar concerns itself with specific information about the page you are currently browsing - for example,
				its published state and when it was last edited. </para>
			<para>Running your mouse over the page content will highlight any text panels that are
				available to edit. An "Edit Content" button will appear in the top, right hand corner of any
				editable panel... clicking this, you gain access to the text editor.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Page Options</emphasis> This panel allows you to set options
						for control and display of the current page. This includes the URL, page name and
						theme.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Current Page</emphasis> the "Current Page" item will allow you
						to quickly jump between documents at the top level of the navigation hierarchy of your
						site.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Publication status and Last Edit</emphasis> Once your page is
						published the 'publication status' will change to a red "published"; also displayed to
						the right is the last edit date.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Show Editable Areas</emphasis> at the extreme right is a slide
						that highlights all the editable areas on the page.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating a new Web page</title>
		<para>Press the <emphasis role="bold">Add new page</emphasis> button in the toolbar at the
			bottom. A page options panel slides up ready for you to enter details.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%" fileref="images/adding_new_page.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding a New Page</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>Give your new page a name and click the Save button. We now have a new page with a
			headline and a small introductory sentence already in place. Congratulations... you're on your
			way with onCourse CMS webpage creation.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Content Editing</title>
		<para>Say you have a news page on your site and you'd like to update it. Log into the CMS and
			navigate to the page you want to edit. When you roll your mouse over the text area on
			the page you'll see an <guimenuitem>edit content</guimenuitem> link which you can click on. Make sure you ensure
			that the <guibutton>Show editable area</guibutton> button is switched
				<guibutton>on</guibutton>. Once you have clicked, a dialog will appear which allows
			you to edit the content of that area directly. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/content_editing_pages.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Edit window to access and update page content</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<tip>
			<para>When navigating to a page to edit the content, it is best to search for the page via the
				search filter on the page menu or alternatively update the URL to the page you wish
				to edit. If you attempt to navigate to the page by clicking on the web pages itself,
				you may inadvertently edit the wrong page. </para>
		</tip>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Page options</title>
		<para>Every CMS page on your site has a number of page options which you can edit. You are not
			able to modify page options for core system pages generated automatically by the system (such
			as /courses).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%" fileref="images/cms_page_options.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Page options that are available for each page within the Content Management System</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Page Visibility</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>If the page is not visible it will not appear in navigation, search results or in menus.
					However if you are logged into the CMS you will be able to see and edit these
					unpublished pages.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/page_visibility.png"
							format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>To publish or remove a given page from your website, simply set the page visibility
							accordingly</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Page Links</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>All pages will always be accessible by their internal reference. That link (URL) will
					look like http://www.acme.com.au/page/123. However you will probably want to define more
					accessible URLs like /contact or /about/jobs or whatever suits your sitemap and your
					overall goals. </para>
				<para>You can add as many links as you like to each page, but you cannot remove
					the initial /page/123 style link which is used to identify the page.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/page_links.png"
							format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>You can easily set up more than 1 Page Link (URL) as well as defining the default link</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Page Themes</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>Each page has a theme which defines the look of the page and which blocks are visible on
					that page. You can drag and drop your CMS blocks into position for each theme
					that you create for your website. If you don't assign a page theme when you
					first create a new page, the default <guilabel>page</guilabel> theme will be applied.</para>
				<para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%" fileref="images/Editing_themes_within_CMS.png"
								format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Editing Themes - applying CMS blocks to a given theme</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</para>
				<tip>
					<para>The <guilabel>page</guilabel>theme is a default theme that is applied to all special pages within the CMS such as /courses or /sites. It therefore cannot be deleted within the CMS</para>
				</tip>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>
