<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="payment_options">
    <title>Payment Options</title>
    <para>onCourse makes online sales simple with a range of payment options for enrolling students.
        With a complete shopping cart students can enrol in multiple classes in a single
        transaction, enrol a friend or with your approval send the invoice to their employer.</para>
    <para>onCourse eCommerce doesn't handle only enrolments; it also includes product, memberships
        and gift voucher sales allowing you to diversify your business and the way people can buy
        and share your products.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Credit card</title>
        <para>Real-time credit card processing ensures that successful enrolments are only made when
            the money is in your account.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/payment_credit_card.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Using a credit card when paying for an enrolment</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Corporate Pass</title>
        <para>CorporatePass gives approved users the ability to invoice their employer on enrolment.
            That way you can develop a close relationship with your corporate customers, but still
            allow their staff to select training timetables to suit themselves.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/corporate_pass.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Using a CorporatePass code to complete an online enrolment without the need of
                    any payment at that time</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Vouchers and Gift Certificates</title>
        <para>Vouchers are much more than a simple gift voucher. They can be used to sell training
            in flexible groups whether it be a sampler of arts courses or OH&amp;S training for 20
            co-workers.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/add_code.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Adding a Voucher or Gift Certifcate to help pay for an online
                    enrolment/s</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Discounts and Promotional Codes</title>
        <para>A range of flexible discounting and promotional code tools allow for students to
            access your special enrolment rates right up until the point of payment.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/discounted_class.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Cost before and after discount for individual classes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>....</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/discounted_amount.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Total cost and discount for all classes you are trying to enrol in at this
                    time</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Concessions/Memberships</title>
        <para>With onCourse memberships for individuals or employers, you can offer special prices
            to your select members or create a gym membership style training programme. Memberships
            can be sold or give away, and expire whenever you choose. You can add a concession or
            membership in th summary section whilst enrolling online. A '+' symbol with text 'Add
            Concession' can be found below you name and email address.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/add_concession.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where to find the 'Add Concession' button on the Summary page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>...</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/Concessions.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Adding a Concession/Membership to an enrolment</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Credit</title>
        <para>....</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/collecting_parent_or_guardian_details_cms.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>.......</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
