<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="useful_information">
    <title>Useful Information</title>
    <section>
    <title>Timetable Information</title>
    <para>The user timetable can be viewed as either a list of sessions or as a month or calendar
        view. The timetable will display all classes on a given day, by clicking on a given day the
        session information will display at the bottom of the page, including course name, room, venue
        and tutor information. Timetables are applicable either to classes a student is enrolled in,
        or to sessions being taught by a tutor.</para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                fileref="images/Tutor Portal Timetable View.png" format="png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>skillsOnCourse timetable by month view</para>
        </caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <section>
        <title>Calendar Subscriptions</title>
        <para>Skills onCourse allows both Students and Tutors to subscribe to a Calendar for their
            Classes. To add this Calendar feed to your own Calendar, simply click on the
            <guibutton>Subscribe to Calendar</guibutton>button within the portal then add
            this to your own Calendar.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/CalendarLink.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Calendar Link</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once the subscription has been set, any amendments made to the timetable for the Classes
            you are either teaching or enrolled in will automatically flow through to your
            Calendar.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/PortalCalendarSubscription.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>URL link generated by the Portal which can be added to your own Calendar</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class information</title>
        <para>Students can access up to date class information such as the date of the next session, venue
            and room information, as well as a link through to the Class Description which outlines
            the content to be covered within the Class.</para>
        <para>Tutors are also able to access Class information, including total number of enrolments,
            venue and room information. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Details Tab.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tutors can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <tip>
            <para>Despite Tutors and Students both accessing the skills onCourse via the same log in page,
                the information displayed to these two groups is different. </para>
        </tip>
        <section>
            <title>Getting Directions to a Classroom</title>
            <para>The skills OnCourse class detail view provides a link to Google maps, providing detailed
                directions for getting to the venue. Simply click on the <guibutton>View on
                    Map</guibutton>link within the Class details view.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Location Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students can access Google Map directions via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Manage Waiting Lists and Mailing Lists</title>
            <para>A student can view what waiting lists they are on by clicking on Subsciptions -> Waiting
                List. This page with allow you to find out more information about the waiting lists
                you are subscribed to along with the option of deleting your name off that
                list.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscriptions Menu Waiting Lists.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Manage your Wait List entries</para></caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>A student can view what mailing lists they are being subscribed to by clicking on
                Subscriptions -> Mailing Lists. You have the option of choosing what method you
                would like to received the information by (E-mail, SMS, Post) and which of the
                designated mailing lists you wish to subscribe to.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscription Menu Mailing Lists.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Add or remove yourself from Mailing Lists</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>History</title>
        <para>Students can access a list of their previously enrolled classes along with their financial
            history in the History menu.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Enrolments.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of your Financial history</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of previously enrolled classes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>To find out more information about a certain transaction you can click on one of the record
            that will in turn open up payment information or a Tax invoice for the chosen payment,
            as seen below.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance Invoice.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tax invoice</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
