<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="useful_information">
    <title>Useful Information</title>
    <section>
    <title>Timetable Information</title>
    <para>The user timetable can be viewed as either a schedule list of sessions or as a month or
            monthly calendar view. The timetable will display all classes on a given day, by
            clicking on a given day the session information will display at the top of the page,
            including course name, room, venue and tutor information. Timetables are applicable
            either to classes a student is enrolled in, or to sessions being taught by a
            tutor.</para>
        <para>The timetable will open to the current date, or next scheduled session by default. You
            can navigate between months by using the calendar month tool on the left panel.</para>
        <para>By expanding a timetable session, additional options like 'view course' and for
            tutors, 'mark roll' are available.</para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                fileref="images/Tutor Portal Timetable View.png" format="png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>skillsOnCourse timetable view</para>
        </caption>
    </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Team Timetables</title>
            <para>If a portal user has permission to access the portal on behalf of other portal
                useres e.g. employers who can view their employee information, the timetable view
                will default to a team timetable view. </para>
            <para>This view shows a combined timetable view for all the linked portal users, so an
                employer can see at a glance all the sessions their staff are scheduled to attend,
                or a parent can see a combined timetable for all their children's sessions.</para>
            <para>The team view can be switched back to an individual view by using the link on the
                top of the page.</para>
        </section>
    <section>
        <title>Timetable Subscriptions</title>
        <para>Skills onCourse allows both Students and Tutors to subscribe to a timetable for their
                classes. To add this Calendar feed to your own Calendar, simply click on the
                    <guibutton>Sync to Device</guibutton>link within the portal timetable view then
                add this feed to your own Calendaring software.</para>
        <para>Once the subscription has been set, any amendments made to the timetable for the
                classes you are either teaching or enrolled in will automatically flow through to
                your Calendar. This subscription only needs to be done once, per user. Any new
                classes a user enrols in, or are scheduled to teach, will be included in this
                subscription.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/PortalCalendarSubscription.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>URL link generated by the Portal which can be added to your own Calendar</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Resources</title>
        <para>The resources tab is a quick way to navigate to any global resources that have been
            added to the portal, for example, documents like Student or Tutor handbooks, as well as
            resources for any classes currently in progress, grouped by their course name.</para>
        <para>Resources grouped by class may have been attached at either the course, class or
            student enrolment record, and may include documents such as learning and assessment
            resources, of completion Certificates.</para>
        <para>The display of resources in the portal is based on the permissions set for the
            document inside the onCourse application. Documents with the permission 'Student and
            tutor' show in the portal for both students and tutors. Documents with the permission
            'Tutor only' show only to tutors, and are a suitable permission for resources like
            assessment marking guides.</para>
        <para>The skillsOnCourse dashboard also contains links to the newest resources added to the
            portal for the student or tutor.</para>
        <para>Resources for classes which are completed can be accessed from the class record
            directly. Completed classes are listed in History tab of the portal.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                    fileref="images/portal_resources.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tutors can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Results</title>
        <para>The results tab of the portal show students the outcome results for their enrolments.
            Results may be for VET and non-VET courses.</para>
        <para>Some VET courses will show the link to the parent qualificiation, where the course has
            been created with this link in onCourse. Other VET courses, that are module only
            enrolments will list the outcomes only with no reference to a qualification.</para>
        <para>Results where no value has been set in onCourse will show as 'not marked' in the portal.</para>
        <para>Results where the outcome was successful will show in green font 'Pass' with the
            AVETMISS value set in onCourse displayed below.</para>
        <para>Results where the outcome was not successful will show in red font 'Not yet competent'
            and the AVETMISS value set in onCourse.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/portal_results_tab.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List of all class results on the results tab</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
            <para>A student can also view their results for an individual class by clicking on the
                'Results' tab on the class detail view.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Result Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students results within a single class record</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class information</title>
        <para>Classes can be accessed from the link within the timetable, through the sidebar
            classes menu or via the History tab.</para>
        <para>Students can access up to date class information such as the date of the next session,
            venue and room information, as well as a link through to the class description which
            outlines the content to be covered within the class.</para>
        <para>The class tab also contains links to the class resources, such as learning and
            assessment materials, which have been uploaded to skillsOnCourse and any outcome
            results. Students can see their overall attendance calculation for the class, and the
            attendance value set for each class session.</para>
        <para>Tutors are also able to access class information,  which includes information about
            the students enrolled, total number of enrolments, and can mark the class rolls.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Details Tab.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tutors can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <tip>
            <para>Despite Tutors and Students both accessing the skills onCourse via the same log in page,
                the information displayed to these two groups is different. </para>
        </tip>
        <section>
            <title>Class feedback</title>
            <para>Students have the ability to rate classes they enrolled in and provide feedback
                comments. They can provide a Net Promoter Score response out of 10 (How likely are
                you to recommend us to a friend) and rate out of 5 stars how they found the Venue,
                Course and Tutor with a notes field below for them to add comments. The tutors that
                are teaching these class will then be able to see their overall class rating in
                their portal, without any information identifying the student/s who provided the
                rating. More information about the Feedback function is available in <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/feedback.html"
                    >the onCourse user manual Feedback Chapter</link></para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/class_rating_student.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students have the ability to rate classes they enrolled in</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Getting Directions to a Classroom</title>
            <para>The skillsOnCourse class detail view provides a link to Google maps, providing
                detailed directions for getting to the venue. Simply click on the <guibutton>View on
                    Map</guibutton>link within the Class details view.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Location Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students can access Google Map directions via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Subscriptions</title>
        <para>A student can view what waiting lists they are on by clicking on Subsciptions and then
            clicking Waiting List. This page with allow you to find out more information about the
            waiting lists you are subscribed to along with the option of deleting your name off that
            list.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscriptions Menu Waiting Lists.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Manage your Wait List entries</para></caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>A student can view what mailing lists they are subscribed to by clicking on
            Subscriptions and then clicking Mailing Lists. You have the option of choosing what
            method you would like to received the information by (E-mail, SMS, Post) and which of
            the designated mailing lists you wish to subscribe to.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscription Menu Mailing Lists.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Add or remove yourself from Mailing Lists</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <note><para>Students have the ability to manage their unsubscriptions without a login by adding the follow
                syntax ${contact.getPortalLink("subscriptions")} in email templates. We recommend
                you include this link in email templates sent from wait lists.</para></note>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>History</title>
        <para>Students can access a list of their previously enrolled classes, their financial
            history and any applications they have submitted in the History menu.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Applications</title>
        <para>If a student has submitted a applications that has been approved, they will have the
            option to enrol in the class or reject the offer.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Applications.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of applications submitted by the student</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
            <para>If you want to withdraw the application simply click on the 'Reject' option. You
                will then be taken to the page as shown below, confirming the application has been
                withdrawn. If you want to enrol in the class you have applied for, simply click on
                the 'Enrol now' option which will take the student to that course page on your
                website.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Application withdrawn.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Application has been withdrawn</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
            <section>
                <title>Classes</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Enrolments.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of previously enrolled classes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
            </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Finance</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of your Financial history</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>To find out more information about a certain transaction you can click on one of the record
            that will in turn open up payment information or a Tax invoice for the chosen payment,
            as seen below.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance Invoice.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tax invoice</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
                    <section><title>Making a credit card payment in the portal</title>
                        <para>A student has the ability to make credit card payments in the
                    skillsOnCourse portal, so debtors are allowed to make payments against their
                    outstanding invoices or payment plans. This can be found in the Finance tab of
                    the History menu. The payment option UI will only appear if the student has an
                    overdue payment, if not, then this tab will just show a list of their finanical
                    history. A student has an option to reduce the amount they want to pay if they
                    can't afford to pay the full amount at the present time, with a minimum limit of
                    $20 unless the total overdue amount is less than this. Once the user has defined
                    the amount they want to pay the student just needs to enter the credit card
                    details of person making the payment. The user will then get a message notifing
                    them if the payment was successful or if it failed. If the payment fails, then a
                    few seconds after getting a notification of this they will get directed back to
                    the payment page allowing them to try again.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                            fileref="images/Tutor Portal Making a payment.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Making a $550 overdue payment in the skillsOnCourse portal</caption>
                </mediaobject>
                        <para>If a payment is due there will be a block on the dashboard notifying
                    the student of this, as seen below. If they click on the 'PAY ONLINE NOW' button
                    in the block it will take them to where they can make the payment, as shown
                    above.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                    fileref="images/portal_payment_due_dashboard.png" format="png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>Payment Due dashboard block</caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                        <note><para>If a student has mulitple invoices that are overdue the amount shown that needs to be paid
                        will be the combined overdue total. If they don't want to pay the full
                        amount yet, then the payment will be taken off the oldest invoice first,
                        even if they are on a payment plan.</para></note>
                        <para>There is also a script called 'send payment plan reminder' that automatically sends a message
                    7 days before the payment due date, on the day the payment is due and every 7
                    days after that.</para><mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                            fileref="images/send payment plan reminder.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>send payment plan reminder script</caption>
                </mediaobject>
                <para>Below is an example of the email that gets sent to a student who is overdue.
                    There is also a link in the email that allows them to go straight to the portal,
                    without having to log in, and pay the overdue balance.</para><mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                            fileref="images/Payment Reminder Script.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Payment reminder email</caption>
                </mediaobject>
                    </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Certificates in skillsonCourse</title>
        <para>Once you have attached the students Certificate to their enrolment record you will
            want to be able to direct the student to where they can find it in their skillsonCourse
            portal. More information about attaching Certificates to student records can be found <link xlink:href="rto.html#rto-attaching"
                >here.</link></para>
        <para>They can find this by: </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>clicking on 'History' tab in the top menu, then on 'Classes' to see the full
                    list of past classes. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Under this section the student will see a list of past classes and to find the
                    certificate for class 'Certificate III in Children's Services (CHC2-4)' they
                    would need to click on this class in the list. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Finally click on the 'Resources' option; this option will only appear if they
                    have something attached to their enrolment record. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>When they have done this the student will be able to download and print their
                    Cerificate themselves.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/finding_certificate_portal.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where a student can find their Certificate in skillonCourse</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
