<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="general">
    <title>General</title>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>skillsOnCourse is a web site for tutors and students which allows them to interact with your
        college and with each other. Every student and tutor is automatically given a login when
        their record is created in onCourse or when they enrol online. </para>
    <para>skillsOnCourse gives tutors the information they need without having to contact you
        regularly. "Is my class full?", "Will my class go ahead?", "Can I get a class roll".
        These are all things that your teaching staff will ask you every day; now you have a 24
        hour assistance to help tutors get the answers they need.</para>
    <para>Students will also enjoy the skillsOnCourse portal. They can quickly and easily get the
        information they need about their classes and timetable.</para>
        </section>
         <section>
        <title>Creating accounts and logging in</title>
        <para>All students when they are created in onCourse, will automatically have a skillsOnCourse
            account set up for them. The first time a student enrols in your college, they will be sent an
            email which allows them to log into skillsOnCourse and set their password. Tutors are also
            given an account when their record is created in onCourse.</para>
        <para>The skillsOnCourse login screen will prompt the student or tutor to enter their details.
            Like the onCourse enrolment process, a student is identified by name and email address
            to avoid forcing students and tutors to remember another user id.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Log In Screen.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>skillsOnCourse web login page </para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>It is also possible to log into skills onCourse as a Company rather than an individual. To
            do so simply tick the <guilabel>As company</guilabel>box, then enter the email address
            and password for your Company.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Log In Screen Company.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Recovering and Resetting Passwords</title>
            <para>The main login screen for the skillsOnCourse portal includes a 'forgot password' link. The
                user will need to provide a name and valid email address in order to initiate the process.
                If the student or tutor does not have an email address in onCourse then they must contact
                the college so that you can manually update their record. It is important that you implement
                an appropriate set of policies around how to authenticate users over the phone when they
                request that their email address be changed or added, since that email address will give
                them access to the full profile and history of the user. </para>
            <para>If the user clicks on the forgot password link and enters the other details, an email will
                be sent to them with a link to enable them create a new password. This link will be valid
                for 24 hours only, after that time the link within the email will not work. Once the student
                has reset their password, they can continue using skillsOnCourse.</para>
            <para><programlisting>Dear {name},

To reset your SkillsOnCourse password, simply click the link below. That will take you to a web page
where you can create a new password. Please note that the link will expire 24 hours after
this email was sent.
				
  {recoveryLink}

If you weren't trying to reset your password, don't worry - your account is still secure and no
one has been given access to it. Most likely, someone just mistyped their email address
while trying to reset their own password.</programlisting></para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Updating Your Details</title>
            <para>Once logged in, users are able to update their contact details via the <guimenu>My
                Profile</guimenu> menu. This screen also enables them to update their password
                and their responses to the RTO AVETMISS, USI and VET FEE Help student questions,
                under the various tabs available in their profile.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile View.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>My profile page of skillsOnCourse</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile Update Password.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Reset your skillsonCourse Password</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Updating AVETMISS Details</title>
            <para>If a student is undertaking an RTO Course, they can provide / update the required
                AVETMISS information via the profile page.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile Census Info.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Student AVETMISS Information</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Navigating skillsOnCourse</title>
        <para>Students and Tutors are able to navigate their way around skillsOnCourse via the top of page
            menu options. By clicking on the 'skillsOnCourse' logo in the top left hand corner of
            the page, they can return to the home page of the site. Because the site is built using
            modern html techniques, the user can safely use the back button on their browser or
            bookmark any page they like. When they return to a bookmarked page they will be asked to
            log in and will then be redirected to the page they bookmarked.</para>
        <para>If a student or tutor is updating their profile, they must save their changes before
            navigating away from that page. If they leave the page without saving the changes, those
            changes are lost.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>

