<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="tutor">
    <title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
    <section>
        <title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
        <para>Some features are only visible to tutors, including real time marking of the
            attendance roll for their classes.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing and Marking a Class Roll</title>
            <para>Tutors can access the attendance roll for the class they are teaching, updating
                the attendance records in real time. Only class rolls for sessions in the past, or
                in progress, can be marked.</para>
            <para>If you have uploaded student profile images in onCourse, their image will appear
                along side their name assisting the tutors in verifying their identify. onCourse is
                also integrated with Gravatar, so if students have a loaded a profile image against
                a Gravatar profile using the same email address as they use in onCourse, this image
                will be used.</para>
            <para>Students can be marked as attended, partially attended, absent or absent with
                reason. For both partially attended and absent with a reason a note can be recorded
                against the attendance record to provide more information.</para>
            <para>Marked attendance data is then used to calculate the student's attendance
                percentage. This percentage may be important for reasons like CRICOS student visa
                compliance, or the college's own minimum attendance requirements in order to be
                eligible for a certificate of attendance.</para>
            <para>The attendance roll can also list contact details such as mobile and email
                addresses for students, allowing the tutor to easily contact students as
                needed.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Marking Roll.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Live attendance tracking via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/marked_roll_mobile_portal.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Marking the class roll on a mobile device</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <tip>
                <para>A College can set whether or they wish the Tutor to see the contact details of
                    the students via the Website CMS under the <guimenu>Site Settings</guimenu>
                    menu. Whether this information is displayed is dependent upon the individual
                    policies of Colleges and the management of student records. </para>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Approving Class Information</title>
            <para>Tutors can confirm their availability for a given Class using the Portal. To
                access any Classes that a Tutor has not yet confirmed their availability for, simply
                click on the <guimenu>To Confirm</guimenu> menu within the Portal. There is also a
                dialog box available to the tutor so they can send in comments and or suggested
                amendments to the course copy. College staff then approve and update the changes via
                the onCourse Client. Tutors cannot edit the course schedule or description
                themselves, since it needs to be properly approved by College staff.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Tutor_Class_Approval.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Tutors can confirm availability for a given Class via the Portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing Student Results</title>
            <para>Tutors have the ability to view a list of results for each unit of competency for
                their students. They will be marked either 'Pass', 'Not Yet Competent' or 'No
                Result'. The AVETMISS specific value of the outcome is displayed below this summary
                label</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Results Tab.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Student Assessment Sorted by Unit of Competency</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Marking Students in the Tutor Portal</title>
            <section>
                <title>Enabling Marking via the Tutor Portal</title>
                <para>You can give your tutors access to mark the class outcomes via the Tutor
                    Portal. This is an extremely effective time saving measure, as the results will
                    be updated directly to your onCourse database. The outcomes are then available
                    for viewing and scripting.  </para>
                <para>Combined with the Marking the Class Roll, Tutor marking allows for a full
                    integration for the most common information tutors need to supply to your
                    college. </para>
                <para>You can enable tutor marking in the portal in the CMS settings. </para>
            <para><orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Login to the CMS</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Go to 'Site Settings'</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Tick the check box 'enable outcome marking in tutor portal'</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Click Save</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                            fileref="images/tutor_marking_CMS_setup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>CMS Site Settings to enable tutors marking in the portal</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Marking via the Tutor Portal</title>
            <para>If you have enabled outcomes marking in the tutor portal, Tutors will be able to
                    mark the students competent, not yet competent, no result and withdrawn in the
                    'outcomes' section in the class. Tutors will be able to mark VET and Non VET
                    Courses. </para>
                <para> </para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para> Log in to the Tutor Portal</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>It will open at the Dashboard. You will see a widget 'Mark Outcomes'  with
                        the most recent class.</para><mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                                    fileref="images/tutor_marking_Dashboard.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>Class Page VET Class Mark by Outcomes</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Click on the 'Mark Outcomes' widget</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                        <para>This will open the Class page to the 'outcomes' section. If you are
                            already on the class you can select 'Outcomes' from the top of the Class
                            page. </para>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                                fileref="images/tutor_marking_nonVET_class.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                                <para>Outcomes Page in a non-VET Class</para>
                            </caption>
                    </mediaobject></listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>To mark the student's outcome, click on their name. If you are on a
                            mobile device with a touch screen you can tap the touchpad. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>For VET Courses, you will be given the option to mark by module or by
                            student. For non-VET training all marking will be against the
                            student.</para>
                    </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
                <example>
                    <title>Marking a VET Outcome via the Tutor Portal</title>
                    <para>Jane Citizen is a tutor for Cert III Aged Care. Jane's student has
                        completed all her assessments at the end of the course and made competent on
                        the same day. Jane logs into the Tutor Portal, goes to the student's class,
                        selects 'Mark by Student', selects the student from the list. Under the
                        student Jane selects 'Mark All', Competent, and ticks 'Show Today's date'.
                        The office staff will be able to see the competency in onCourse within 15
                        minutes. </para>
                </example>                
        </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class Resources and Files</title>
        <para>Tutor also have access to a list of resources and files for each individual class they
            teach. These resources could be teacher training and assessment resources, marking
            guides or additional course materials. These documents are uploaded via the class or
            course in the onCourse database with a 'Tutors only' permission. </para>
        <para>Tutors can also see documents uploaded with 'Tutors and enrolled students' permission,
            that may include documents like learning guides for students.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Resources Tab.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Available teaching resources and documents for a Class</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
