<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="user_switching">
    <title>User Switching</title>
    <para>This feature allows you to set up different relationships between e.g. An employer and
        their staff members and allow them to have access to their skillsonCourse portal
        login.</para>
      <section>
        <title>onCourse Settings</title>
        <para>To enable this feature between certain relationship you need to tick the checkbox in
            the Contact Realtion Type edit view window. You can find this by going File ->
            Preferences -> Contact relation types, then either double click on am exsting
            relationship or click on the '+' Symbol at the top right side on the window to create a
            new relationship.</para>
          <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                  <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                      fileref="images/contact_relationship_list.png" format="png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>
                  <para>Contact Relation Type list view</para>
              </caption>
          </mediaobject>
          <para>Once you have the marked the checkbox, as shown below, the employer will be able to access their
              staffs skillsonCourse portal.</para>
          <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                  <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                      fileref="images/contact_relationship_edit.png" format="png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>
                  <para>Contact Relation Type edit view</para>
              </caption>
          </mediaobject>
          <para>After a relationship has been created and marked as giving access to information
            with the skillsonCourse portal then you can start creating relationships between
            contacts. To do this you have to open up the contact you want to create relationship to,
            then in the General tab at the bottom right side of the window click the '+' button next
            to the table called 'Relation'. From here a sheet will appear that will allow you to
            choose who you want to create a relationship to along with what type of relationship. In
            the example below I am trying to make 'Natalie Morton' the employer of 'James Matthew'. </para>
          <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                  <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                      fileref="images/adding_a_relationship_to_contacts_record.png" format="png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>
                  <para>Adding a relationship to a contacts record</para>
              </caption>
          </mediaobject>
          <para>Once you have added the relationship you will see the name of who you have added in
            the Relation table at the bottom right side of the window.</para>
          <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                  <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                      fileref="images/relationship_added_to_contacts_record.png" format="png" />
              </imageobject>
              <caption>
                  <para>Relationship added to a contacts record</para>
              </caption>
          </mediaobject>
       </section>
    <section>
       <title>What will you see in skillsonCourse</title>
        <para>Once you have marked the checkbox in the Contact Relation Type edit view window there
            should now be an option to switch users within skillsonCourse. This can be found at the
            top right hand side of the window. In the example below you can see user Natalie Morton
            has access to James Matthews skillsonCourse details. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/skillsonCourse_user_switching.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where to switch users within skillsonCourse</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para/>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/skillsonCourse_user_switching2.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>View of what you will see in the top right side of the window when Natalie has
                    switched to James'  skillsonCourse login</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>