<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="tutor">
    <title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
    <section>
        <title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
        <para>Some features are only visible to tutors, including real time marking of the
            attendance roll for their classes.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing and Marking a Class Roll</title>
            <para>Tutors can access the attendance roll for the class they are teaching and mark the
                attendance records in real time, back to your onCourse database. Only class rolls
                for sessions in progress, or in the past, can be marked. Attendance can not be
                marked before the session has commenced.</para>
            <para>If you have uploaded student profile images in onCourse, their image will appear
                along side their name assisting the tutors in verifying their identify. onCourse is
                also integrated with Gravatar, so if students have a loaded a profile image against
                a Gravatar profile using the same email address as they use in onCourse, this image
                will be used.</para>
            <para>Students can be marked as attended, partially attended, absent or absent with
                reason. For both partially attended and absent with a reason a note can be recorded
                against the attendance record to provide more information.</para>
            <para>Marked attendance data is then used to calculate the student's attendance
                percentage. This percentage may be important for reasons like CRICOS student visa
                compliance, or the college's own minimum attendance requirements in order to be
                eligible for a certificate of attendance.</para>
            <para>The attendance roll can also list contact details such as mobile and email
                addresses for students, allowing the tutor to easily contact students as
                needed.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Marking Roll.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Live attendance tracking via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="25%" contentdepth="25%"
                        fileref="images/marked_roll_mobile_portal.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Marking the class roll on a mobile device</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <tip>
                <para>A College can set whether or they wish the Tutor to see the contact details of
                    the students via the Website CMS under the <guimenu>Site Settings</guimenu>
                    menu. Whether you want this information displayed is dependent upon the policies
                    of your business and the management of student records. This setting is for all
                    tutors of the college.</para>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Approving Class Information</title>
            <para>Tutors can confirm their availability for a given Class using the Portal. To
                access any classes that a Tutor has not yet confirmed their availability for, simply
                click on the <guimenu>To Confirm</guimenu> menu within the Portal. There is also a
                dialog box available to the tutor so they can send in comments and or suggested
                amendments to the course copy. College staff then approve and update the changes via
                the onCourse Client. Tutors cannot edit the course schedule or description
                themselves, since it needs to be properly approved by College administrative
                staff.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Tutor_Class_Approval.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Tutors can confirm availability for a given Class via the Portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing Student Results</title>
            <para>Tutors have the ability to view a list of results for each unit of competency for
                their students. They will be marked either 'Pass', 'Not Yet Competent' or 'No
                Result'. The AVETMISS specific value of the outcome is displayed below this summary
                label</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Results Tab.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Student Assessment Sorted by Unit of Competency</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Marking in the tutor portal</title>
            <para>You can give your tutors access to mark their student's outcomes in the tutor
                portal. This will save time for the tutor and the college, and will give you
                fast, accurate results in your onCourse database. The system is simple and easy
                to use for tutors, and has the advantage of updating the onCourse database
                automatically, so no further staff time is needed to have up to date results for
                AVETMISS reporting or certificate issuing purposes. </para>
            <para>If your existing assessment strategy is for tutors to determine competency and
                notify the college, this system will be easy for you to enable, as it simply
                moves the notification to an online, integrated platform. </para>
            <para>Tutors will be able to mark the students competent, not yet competent, no
                result and withdrawn in the portal. onCourse will automatically assign the
                correct reporting codes based on the student's enrolment. The tutor is also be
                able select the date the outcome is marked as the end date of the outcome. This
                will override the existing outcome end date (or planned outcome end date) in the
                database.</para>
            <para>All other VET Outcomes, such as 51- Recognition of Prior Learning (RPL) and
                60- Credit transfer (CT) are only available to college staff. This is to ensure
                the internal processes are meet before they are entered into your database. </para>
            <para>We recommend you have a policy for the tutors that outlines what settings you
                expect tutors to use. Please feel free to send the <link
                    xlink:href="tutors.html#tutor_outcome_marking">tutor instructions</link> or edit them to include
                your own process with the specific steps and setting for your college.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="all">
                    <title>Outcome Values in the portal and their values in onCourse</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.73*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="2.35*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Portal</entry>
                                <entry>VET outcomes</entry>
                                <entry>non-VET outcomes</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Competent</entry>
                                <entry>20 - Competent</entry>
                                <entry>81 -Non-assessed enrolment - Satisfactorily
                                    completed</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Not Yet Competent</entry>
                                <entry>30 - Competency not yet achieved / failed (NYC)</entry>
                                <entry>82 - Non-assessed enrolment - Withdrawn or not
                                    satisfactorily completed</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Withdrawn</entry>
                                <entry>40 - Withdrawn</entry>
                                <entry>82 - Non-assessed enrolment - Withdrawn or not
                                    satisfactorily completed</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>No Result</entry>
                                <entry>Not set</entry>
                                <entry>Not Set</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
            <para>This feature is best for colleges that have a periodic, sample based
                assessment validation and moderation processes. If your college does ongoing
                moderation and validation on each assessment, it may be worthwhile considering a
                shift to a periodic system. Ongoing moderation and validation is a time
                intensive process that limits access to solutions that improve your overall
                efficiency and effectiveness.</para>
            <para>Attendance and outcome marking in the portal enables your college to collect
                the most update to date and accurate training information from your tutors, and
                allows for you to access further benefits when combined with default scripts. </para>
            
            <section>
                <title>Enabling outcome marking via the tutor portal</title>
                <para>You can enable marking in your CMS Site settings. Note that this is a single
                    setting for the whole business. If this feature is enabled all tutors will have
                    access to outcome marking. This setting is disabled by default.</para>
                <para>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Login to the CMS</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Go to 'Site Settings'</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click on 'skillsOnCourse'</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Tick the check box 'Enable outcome marking in tutor portal'</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click Save at the bottom of the screen</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                                fileref="images/tutor_marking_CMS_setup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>CMS Site Settings to enable tutors marking in the portal</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class Resources and Files</title>
        <para>Tutor also have access to a list of resources and files for each individual class they
            teach. These resources could be teacher training and assessment resources, marking
            guides or additional course materials. These documents are uploaded via the class or
            course in the onCourse database with a 'Tutors only' permission. </para>
        <para>Tutors can also see documents uploaded with 'Tutors and enrolled students' permission,
            that may include documents like learning guides for students.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Resources Tab.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Available teaching resources and documents for a Class</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
