<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="tutors">
    <title>Information for Tutors</title>
    <section>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <para>The <link xlink:href="https://www.skillsoncourse.com.au/portal/login">skillsOnCourse
                portal</link> is a web site that gives you the information you need about your
            classes and students without having to contact the college regularly. "What am I
            scheduled to teach?", "How many students are enrolled in my class?", "What resources
            should I use to teach the class?". These are all things that the portal can help
            answer.</para>
        <para>You can access your skills onCourse portal on your desktop computer, tablet, or mobile
            phone. The screenviews may alter from those shown in this document based on the screen
            size of your device, but all the functionality is the same.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Log In Screen.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>skillsOnCourse web login page </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
    </section>
                    <section>
                <title>Creating, Recovering and Resetting Passwords</title>
        <para>The first time you visit skillsOnCourse, you will not have a password to login. If the
            college has your name and email address details recorded in their onCourse database, a
            password link can be automatically sent to you. If you are not sure what details they
            have on record, please contact the college so that they can check or update your record
            with your preferred name and email address.</para>
        <para>The main login screen for the skillsOnCourse portal includes a 'forgot password'
            option. Enter your first name, last name and email address and then click on the 'forgot
            password' link.</para>
                <para>When you click on 'forgot password', an email will be sent to you with a link
            to allow you to create a new password. This link will be valid for 24 hours only, after
            that time the link will not work. Once you have reset your password, you will be logged
            in and can continue using skillsOnCourse.</para>
        <para>The next time you visit skillsOnCourse, you can use this new password to login
            directly.</para>
                <para><programlisting>Dear {name},

To reset your SkillsOnCourse password, simply click the link below. That will take you to a web page
where you can create a new password. Please note that the link will expire 24 hours after
this email was sent.
				
  {recoveryLink}

If you weren't trying to reset your password, don't worry - your account is still secure and no
one has been given access to it. Most likely, someone just mistyped their email address
while trying to reset their own password.</programlisting></para>
            </section>
    <section>
        <title>Your timetable</title>
        <para>The first page you see when you arrive in skillsOnCourse is your personalised
            timetable. This shows you the sessions you are scheduled to teach in a month by month
            format. The timetable summary of sessions on the top of page shows your upcoming
            sessions.</para>
        <para>Clicking on a session will expand the session view to show any session notes, and also
            provide you with a quick link through to mark the class roll for that session.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Timetable View.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>skillsOnCourse timetable view, showing the first session expanded</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Using the 'Sync to Device' link in the top of the timetable, you can subscribe to your
            timetable so the sessions show in another electronic calendar, such as your phone. You
            only need to do this once - if the college adds new classes for you to deliver, or if
            the details of one of your class sessions changes i.e. a room change, then your
            subscribed calender updates also.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class information</title>
        <para>As a tutor, the primary function of skillsOnCourse is to show your class information,
            including total number of enrolments, venue and room information. You can navigate to
            classes through the timetable page or from the history page.</para>
        <para>Alternatively you can click on the class name under the 'Classes' column on the right
            side of the window. The classes column is available in every page of the portal except
            the timetable view.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Details Tab.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>You can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing and Marking a Class Roll</title>
            <para>You can access the class roll by clicking on the name of the class, and locating
            the session you wish to mark. The attendance records are then sent to the college in
            real time. Each session of your class has it's own attendance record, and you can scroll
            through each session. By default, the next session (based on the current date) will show
            first.</para>
        <para>If your college collects student identification photos as part of their enrolment
            process, you will also see those images in the class roll.</para>
        <para>To mark a class roll, you can select the simple options of tick for attended, or cross
            for absent. If a student arrived late, left early or was absent from the whole session
            for a valid reason, you can click on the icon next to the roll marking option to add a
            note and record the student's arrival and departure times.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Marking Roll.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Live attendance tracking via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/partial_attendance.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Marking partial attendance for a student</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Confirming your classes</title>
        <para>When you are offered a class teaching opportunity, the college requires you to confirm
            that you are available to deliver the content as described and according to the schedule
            of delivery dates.</para>
            <para>To access any classes that you have not yet confirmed your availability for,
            simply click on the <guimenu>APPROVALS</guimenu> button at the top right hand side of
            the Portal. If you are not available, or can not otherwise agree to teach the class as
            described there is a message box to email the college your feedback.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Tutor_Class_Approval.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>You can confirm availability for a given Class via the Portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Class Resources and Files</title>
            <para>You have access to a list of resources and files for each individual class you
            teach. These can be found by clicking on the 'Resources' option in the top menu. Some of
            the resources listed will also be available to your students in their portal, while
            other resources are only available to tutors of the class.</para>
        <para>Tutor resources that are generic to the college, rather than specifically related to
            one of your classes will appear at the top of the list.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Resources Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Available teaching resources and documents for a Class</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class survey results</title>
        <para>Students attending your class may be asked to complete a survey rating their
            experience at the conclusion of their training. You will be able to see a summary of
            their feedback in the class window.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/survery_rating.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Feedback from a student about a class you taught</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Updating Your Details</title>
        <para>Once logged in, you are able to update your contact details via the <guimenu>My
            Profile</guimenu> menu.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile View.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>My profile page of skillsOnCourse</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>This screen also enables you to change your password at any time.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile Update Password.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Reset your skillsonCourse Password</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
