<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="online_enrolments">
	<title>Online Enrolments</title>
	<para>onCourse has a password free purchasing process meaning that students don't have to remember
		obscure student identification details from their last enrolment, like a student number or a
		password they may have created some time ago. onCourse does everything possible to move the
		student quickly and simply through the enrolment process to secure their payment and
		commitment to the enrolment. Forcing a student to remember a old password will result in
		some loss of enrolments as students give up in frustration.</para>
	<para>Where a student has enrolled previously they are identified by their contact details and can move immediately to the payment
		process. No information they have previously provided is exposed during this process.</para>
	<section>
		<title>Student Details</title>
		<para>After a student has selected which class/es they want to enrol in and clicked on the button 'PROCEED TO CHECKOUT' they will see
			the page below. All the student needs to enter here is their first name, last name and email address. Based on an exact match of these
			three fields, this determines if they are a new student or a returning student.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/your_details_page.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Student details landing page</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Previously Enrolled Students</title>
			<para>If the student enrolling in the class/es has already enrolled in a previous class, been added to a waitlist or had some other
				interaction with you (therefore their details are already stored in your database), then onCourse will be able to immediately
				identify that student and skip any further questions.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/your_details_page_with_info.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enrolling a previously enrolled student</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If, since their last contact with your you have made some additional fields mandatory for online enrolment, and they didn't
				previously supply this data, a page will be shown requesting these additional details be provided. </para>
			<para>At no time are previously supplied details shown to the student.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/returning_student_additional_info.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>What the student will see if additional details need to be obtained since the their last enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>New Students</title>
			<para>If this is the first time the contact is interacting with your college, after they have entered their first name, last name and
				email address it will take them to the next details page where more information can be added. All the fields on this page can be
				shown or hidden, or made mandatory or optional within the CMS settings. As you can see below the only question that is mandatory is
				their postcode which is marked with a '*' symbol.</para>
			<para>If you have set a minimum age for enrolment in the CMS, the date of birth will be mandatory. If you have classes that have an
				age range requirement set, you should also choose to make the Date of Birth mandatory during online enrolment to enforce these
				rules.</para>
			<para>In the onCourse CMS, you can choose to show or hide the AVETMISS questions. These questions can not be made mandatory as they
				are required to be optional responses for students undertaking vocational training.</para>
			<para>If in onCourse, you allow concession details to be added online, there will also be a dropdown for the student to select from
				the list whether they have any concessions you accept, and if you require concession card details or an expiry date, these fields
				will also be required.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%" fileref="images/new_student.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>New student questions page</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also include custom fields you've added to onCourse contact records into the online enrolment process. By default these
				will be hidden, but in the CMS you can choose to expose them. The 'Special needs' field is also available to show or hide, allowing
				you to collect additional text about the any dietary or medical considerations that make impact on training.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/custom_field_questions.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Custom field and Special needs questions</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>De-duplicating students</title>
			<para>When a student changes their name or email address it is possible they will create
				duplicate records in your system. This is easily handled with the de duplication
				functionality inside onCourse, allowing you to merge those students into one.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolling an additional student</title>
			<para>Once a student has entered all their details they will be directed to a summary page. In this page they have the option of
				adding another contact/student to this order. The button can be found below the class/es that are being enrolled in and above the
				field where they can add a promotional code.</para>
			<para>If they click on it then it will take them back to the 'YOUR DETAILS' page allowing them to enter the additional students'
				details.</para>
			<para>To add another person, they need to know their first name, last name and email address, plus complete the responses for any
				fields you have deemed mandatory.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/adding_another_student.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add another student button</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>By default, second and subsequent students added to the online enrolment process will also have the enrolment option selected
				for the same class(es) as the first student. These can be unchecked where required.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/multiple_students_enrolling.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Multiple student enrolling in multiple classes</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Summary</title>
		<para>Once a student has entered all their details they will be directed to a summary page. </para>
		<para>This page includes the following information:</para>
		<para>* Full name and Email Address of the student/s enrolling or paying</para>
		<para>* Classes they are enrolling in and products they are purchasing</para>
		<para>* Price before and after discount of each class along with a total at the bottom right of the page</para>
		<para>* A option to add another student (please see the section above called 'Enrolling an additional student' for more
			information)</para>
		<para>* A field to enter promotional codes, gift certificates or vouchers (more information on this can be found in <link
				xlink:href="#paymentoptions">payment options chapter</link>)</para>
		<para>The student can adjust the details and then proceed to the payment page by clicking on the 'Proceed to Payment' button at the
			bottom of the page.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/summary_page.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Summary page</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Adding a Parent or Guardian</title>
		<para>Within the CMS settings you can specify an age under which all enrolments will require parent or guardian contact details e.g. for
			students under 18. In the example below, student Alicia Badgery, is trying to enrol in 'Course 22435' however since she is under 18
			years of age the following message appears at the bottom of the page 'We require the details of a parent of guardian for billing and
			emergency contact'. We recommend that you also make the date of birth field mandatory for your system.</para>
		<para>If the student has enrolled before, and already has a parent/guardian contact related to them in onCourse, then this information
			will not be requested and they can proceed to payment.</para>
		<para>Until these details are supplied, there is no option to proceed to the payment screen. Instead the button changes to say 'Add
			parent or guardian' and there is a new step at the top of the page called 'PARENT'. Clicking the button directs to the same initial
			'YOUR DETAILS' page where the parent or guardian contact details can be supplied. As per adding all other contacts, if their details
			are already in onCourse, then only a first name, last name and email address are needed to identify them.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/needing_to_add_a_parent.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>What happens when a student is below a certain age and needs to add their parent or guardian details</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once the guardian or parents details have been captured the 'PARENT' step will be removed from the top of the page. There will
			also be a message informing the student that since they are below 18 the parent or guardian that has been entered has been set as the
			payer. They can now proceed to payment page as normal.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/parent_has_been_added.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Summary page after the student has added their parent or guardians details</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Payment</title>
		<para>At the point of payment, the payer (person who will receive the invoice) can be selected. In the example of an enrolment with
			multiple students, the first contact added will be set as the payer by default. In the drop down list, you can select another
			payer.</para>
		<para>If the student is under 18, their parent/guardian will be set as the payer by default. This can be changed back to the student if
			required.</para>
		<para>For an enrolment to be successful, the payment section must be successfully completed. Credit card details are validated in real
			time and if the student abandons the transaction because they can not supply these details, you will see their enrolment in onCourse
			as 'failed', which you may choose to follow up. </para>
		<para>Once the student is on the 'PAYMENT' page there are two main ways to pay for their classes, these are:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Pay using a credit or debit card (default)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click on the 'CorporatePass' option. They can enter their CorporatePass code in the field to complete the transaction without
					the need for a payment at this time. This process works via pre-approval and it can't just be chosen by any visitor to the website
					(more information on this can be found in the <link xlink:href="#paymentoptions">payment options chapter</link>). </para>
				<para> </para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>If the payer is listed below then all they have to do is make the radio button next to their
			name is marked before filling in their credit/debit card details. If the payer is not
			already listed then they can click on the 'Choose a different payer' button, select
			whether the payer is a person or business and then add them as a contact. If the payer
			is a business when trying to add them as a contact instead of the 'Your details' page
			asking for the first and last name of the contact, it will instead ask for the business
			name.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/payment_credit_card.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Payment page</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Confirmation</title>
		<para>After the student has clicked on the 'Confirm purchase' button at the bottom of the PAYMENT
			page, then they will be directed to a confirmation page with a message informing them
			that their online enrolment was either successful or rejected.</para>
		<para>If the student is paying by credit card, this is the point where their card details are verified with the bank as being correct
			and having sufficient funds available.</para>
		<para>At this point, onCourse also verifies there is still a place available in the class. If
			between the student commencing and completing the online enrolment process, the last
			place has been booked by another student, the enrolment process will fail at this point.
			Their credit card will not be billed. You will see the enrolment attempt and failure in
			onCourse, so you can follow them up if they don't successfully complete the
			enrolment.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/class_full_during_online_enrolment.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>What the student will see if the class has suddenly becoming full while enrolling</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If the enrolment and payment were successful, at the bottom of the page there will be a continue button. If you've created a post
			enrolment page within the CMS, they will be redirected there, if not they will be re-directed to the courses list page.</para>
		<para>If the students enrolment goes through successfully and their credit card is accepted they will see a page similar to the screen
			shot shown below.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/credit_card_successful.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>What the student sees if their credit card has been accepted</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If the credit card is not accepted the student will see a page similar to the screen shot shown below explaining what they may
			need to check or correct. At this point the student can try again or abandon their enrolment.</para>
		<para>Abandoned enrolments are shown as 'failed' enrolments in onCourse.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/credit_card_failed.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>What the student sees if their credit card has been rejected</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>After a successful online enrolment process, the payer of the invoice will be emailed a tax invoice, and each of the successfully
			enrolled students will be emailed an enrolment confirmation. If the student is enrolling and paying for themselves, then they will
			receive both emails.</para>
		<para>These automatic emails are sent based on your customisable invoice and enrolment confirmation email templates in onCourse.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
