<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-8.21">

  <info>
    <title>Release 8.21</title>
    <pubdate>18 July 2016</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Two new AVETMISS imports were added to onCourse, allowing users to import data from external
          systems 'AVETMISS student update import' and 'AVETMISS outcome update import' which either
          create new, or update existing student records with the same First Name, Last Name and
          Date of Birth. <systemitem>#26792</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Fix to the 'Enrolment notification' email to tutors to display the price the student paid
          inclusive of any discounts. Change the line <code>Fee Paid:
            ${enrolment.invoiceLine.priceEachExTax.add(enrolment.invoiceLine.taxEach)} GST
            ${enrolment.invoiceLine.taxEach.isZero() ? 'free' : 'inc'} </code></para>
    <para>to</para>
    <para><code>Fee Paid: ${enrolment.invoiceLine.discountedPriceTotalIncTax} GST ${enrolment.invoiceLine.taxEach.isZero() ? 'free' : 'inc'} </code></para>
    <para>in both the plain and HTML copy of the template, or update the whole template with the latest version from the <link xlink:href="https://github.com/ari/oncourse-scripts"
      >Github repository</link><systemitem> #29002</systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>The Tag edit view has been redesigned for a clearer and more concise user experience, including a new field to add a custom URL to your tags <systemitem>#27055</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>When duplicating courses, related courses and products and attachments are copied to the new
          course <systemitem>#29136</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Show a red arrow in the preferences window if an aspect of the settings have a validation
          error and are preventing the window from saving <systemitem>#26613</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>The invoice remittance field height in the financial preferences has been increased to display
          multiple lines of text <systemitem>#27796</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Report retained outcomes from cancelled enrolments in AVETMISS. By default, only outcomes given a status prior to cancelation are retained <systemitem>#28141</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Remember last used directory when selecting files for import<systemitem>#26650</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Reinstate the Trial balance and MYOB export options option from the Financial - Summary
          Extracts menu so historical reports can be reprinted/re-exported
            <systemitem>#29213</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Update the list of required import files when switching between import types<systemitem>
            #27351</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to the AVETMISS import to always select English for any English equivalent
          language type such as 'American' <systemitem>#28239</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Reinstate admin permision to edit historical note records
          <systemitem>#29284</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to invoice date time to avoid date display changes across timezones
            <systemitem>#28861</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix to credit card banking settlement date, to be reported date from the gateway rather than the onCourse banked on date <systemitem>#29335</systemitem></para></listitem>
    
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
