<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-1.7.13">

  <info>
    <title>Release 1.7.13</title>
    <pubdate>17 Sep 2009</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed a problem with downloading AVETMISS related modules, and qualifications where
          the records downloaded would reach a certain number and refuse to download more.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed a number of server shutdown issues </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>for Windows: the window would go away but it required opening up Task Manager to
              actually quit the onCourseServer.exe process</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>for Mac OS X: the server window would not go away and requires a Force Quit in
              order to quit onCourseServer</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed a rare bug in QE where setting the discount value manually in the class
          selection pane equal to the total value of enrolments would credit the payer 10% of the
          total when the enrolment was saved.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed a problem when trying to import XML import files.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed not being able to share saved finds.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enrolment confirmations now correctly display all lines in the address block, instead
          of just the first line.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section>
      <title>Known Issues</title>
      <section>
        <title>Problem saving a session</title>
        <para>If you: </para>
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>add a new tutor to an existing class which already has sessions,</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>tick the “Add the selected new tutor to class sessions” check box</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>without saving the class, edit an existing session and tick the tutor you added in
              step 1</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>then, you will not be able to save the class.</para>
        <para>The workaround is to save the class after step 2.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Saved find</title>
        <para>Deleting a saved find does not refresh until a new list window is opened. </para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
