<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<chapter xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink' version='5.0' xml:id='release-9.7'>
  <info>
    <title>Release 9.7</title>
    <pubdate>17 Oct 2018</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role='important'>
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para/>
  </section>
  <section role='major'>
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>New login and security screens</title>
      <para>The entire login process (<systemitem>OD-11935</systemitem>) and the security
        preferences (<systemitem>OD-11936</systemitem>) have been rebuilt using our new user
        interface. Users might notice several things:</para>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para>the new design</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>a reminder to set two factor authentication</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>a prompt to change their password if it's considered of low quality</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <para>Although we've had two factor one-time-passwords (OTP) for about five years, few people
        have used it. Yes, it's slightly less convenient, but it does improve security by a huge
        amount, so onCourse will start nagging you to turn it on at every launch. You can still
        ignore these requests, but the administrator can enforce an OTP policy in the new security
        settings. The administrator can also increase the threshold of what we consider a rubbish
        password, forcing users to change to a better one.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Special interests in data collection</title>
          <para>With mailing lists being removed from onCourse (everyone is using more specialised
        advanced tools like Mailchimp), we've repurposed the old functionality into 'special
        interests' <systemitem>OD-11833</systemitem>. This means that you can now add Contact tags
        into data collection rules and make them part of the questions you ask during enrolment,
        applications or waiting lists.</para>
          <para>For example, you might like a set of checkboxes whenever someone adds themselves to a waiting list</para>
          <para><programlisting>
Other than this course, what other areas of training are you interested in:
[ ] leisure courses
[ ] languages
[ ] computer courses
            </programlisting></para>
          <para>Or, ask specific questions about experience, work history or profession as part of the enrolments process. Any set of Contact tags in onCourse can now be entered by students directly if you choose to make them part of a Data Collection rule.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role='scripts'>
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Smart &amp; Skilled reporting 85 - Not Yet Started and TNC for Did Not Start outcome
          results. This has been in place since version 9.6 <systemitem>OD-11982</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Update contact CSV export to include the standard working with children check fields
            <systemitem>OD-11793</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section role='minor'>
      <title>Minor features</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added script to send birthday gift email <systemitem>OD-11746</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added link to manual to question mark help icon within preferences
              <systemitem>OD-11917</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New generic import to change subscription to marketing materials permissions, per
            user <systemitem>OD-11962</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Deprecate id methods in the DSL. You should rarely be using the record ids directly
            in an onCourse script and we've now removed them from the documentation. They will still
            work for now. <systemitem>OD-12018</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Certificate expiry. You can now add an expiry date to a certificate record. Although VET certificates don't expire according to the standard, there are many cases where other bodies require regular recertification such as First Aid.
            <systemitem>OD-12031</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add to class duplication: optionally skip copying of class tags and class notes
            <systemitem>OD-7475</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Link a manual invoice to an enrolment
            <systemitem>OD-8284</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section role='fixes'>
      <title>Fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed small error that caused Special Smart &amp; Skilled and SkillsTAS NAT00130
            rules to no longer apply <systemitem>OD-11753</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed where no 'from' email address was defined in default script 'send product
            purchased email' <systemitem>OD-11928</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed handling of single name students in AVETMISS 8 NAT00080 files
              <systemitem>OD-11950</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed issue where users couldn't add VET modules to course on OS X webstart with
            Java 10 <systemitem>OD-11997</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed the scrolling bug in Class Attendance tab <systemitem>OD-12004</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an issue where the COS account wasn't appearing in Invoice Detail as expected
              <systemitem>OD-12005</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an issue where sessions information for class records were being saved before
            sessions were added <systemitem>OD-12014</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an issue where the Attendance screen didn't line up
              <systemitem>OD-12042</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an issue where users could no longer mark Attendance by the column
              <systemitem>OD-12043</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section role='web'>
      <title>Web features</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The Google Maps implementation has been reworked to load less often, reducing
            traffic and cost to the google map servers.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
