<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<chapter xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink' version='5.0' xml:id='release-9.7'>
  <info>
    <title>Release 9.7</title>
    <pubdate>17 Oct 2018</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role='important'>
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para/>
  </section>
  <section role='major'>
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>New login and security screens</title>
      <para>The entire login process (<systemitem>OD-11935</systemitem>) and the security
        preferences (<systemitem>OD-11936</systemitem>) have been rebuilt using our new user
        interface. Users might notice several things:</para>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>the new design</listitem>
          <listitem>a reminder to set two factor authentication</listitem>
          <listitem>a prompt to change their password if it low quality</listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <para>Although we've had two factor one-time-passwords (OTP) for about five years, few people have used
        it. Yes, its slightly less convenient, but it does improve security by a huge amount, so
        onCourse will start nagging you to turn it on at every launch. You can still ignore these
        requests, but the administrator can enforce a OTP policy in the new security settings. The
        administrator can also increase the threshold of what we consider a rubbish password,
        forcing users to change to a better one.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Special interests in data collection</title>
          <para>With mailing lists being removed from onCourse (everyone is using more specialised advanced tools like Mailchimp), we've repurposed the old functionality into 'special interests' <systemitem>OD-11833</systemitem>. This means that you can now add Contact tags into data collection rules and make them part of the questions you ask during enrolment, applications or waiting list.</para>
          <para>For example, you might like a set of checkboxes whenever someone adds themselves to a waiting list</para>
          <para><programlisting>
Other than this course, what other areas of training are you interested in:
[ ] leisure courses
[ ] languages
[ ] computer courses
            </programlisting></para>
          <para>Or, ask specific questions about experience, work history or profession as part of the enrolments process. Any set of Contact tags in onCourse can now be entered by students directly if you choose to make them part of a Data Collection rule.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role='scripts'>
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Accurate Program identifier reporting
          <systemitem>OD-11340</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Smart &amp; Skilled reporting 85 - Not Yet Stared and TNC for Did Not Start outcome results
          <systemitem>OD-11982</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Update contact CSV export to include the standard WWCC fields
          <systemitem>OD-11793</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section role='minor'>
      <title>Minor features</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Possible incorrect setting VCU File outcomes statuses
            <systemitem>OD-11620</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Script to send birthday email
            <systemitem>OD-11746</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Question mark help icon for preferences <systemitem>OD-11917</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New generic import to unsub contacts from marketing materials
            <systemitem>OD-11962</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Deprecate id methods in the dsl. You should rarely be using the record ids directly in an onCourse script and we've now removed them from the documentation. They will still work for now.
            <systemitem>OD-12018</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Certificate expiry. You can now add an expiry date to a certificate record. Although VET certificates don't expire according to the standard, there are many cases where other bodies require regular recertification such as First Aid.
            <systemitem>OD-12031</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add to class duplication: optionally skip copying of class tags and class notes
            <systemitem>OD-7475</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Link a manual invoice to an enrolment
            <systemitem>OD-8284</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section role='fixes'>
      <title>Fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Special Smart &amp; Skilled and SkillsTAS NAT00130 rules no longer apply
            <systemitem>OD-11753</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>onCourse login doesn't show 2FA token field
            <systemitem>OD-11878</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>No from email address defined in default script 'send product purchased email'
            <systemitem>OD-11928</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>AVETMISS 8 defect: NAT00080 - Client Name for Encryption: single name students
            <systemitem>OD-11950</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Can't add VET modules to course on OS X webstart with Java 10
            <systemitem>OD-11997</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Scrolling bug in Class Attendance tab
            <systemitem>OD-12004</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Invoices - COS account not appearing in Invoice Detail as expected
            <systemitem>OD-12005</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Scripts are sending emails twice
            <systemitem>OD-12012</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Don't save Sessions information for Class record until sessions are added
            <systemitem>OD-12014</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Authorisation for preferences
            <systemitem>OD-12024</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Attendance screen doesn't line up
            <systemitem>OD-12042</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Attendance screen mark whole column
            <systemitem>OD-12043</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section role='web'>
      <title>Web features</title>
      <itemizedlist />
    </section>
    <section role='web-fixes'>
      <title>Web fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist />
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
