<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-8.23">

  <info>
    <title>Release 8.23</title>
    <pubdate>22 August 2016</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
<section>
  <title>Default invoice terms per contact</title>
  <para>A new field has been added to the general preferences to allow for a default due date for
        all invoices to be set. Previously, the default due date was always the day of creation. In
        addition, each contact in onCourse can have their own default due date that overrides the
        default, so you can offer a range of relative terms like 7 days, 14 days, 31 days to auto
        calculate an invoice due date for your corporate clients. This features ties in with the new
        invoice payment due reminder script and portal payment gateway also included in this
        release.</para>
</section>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>A new script has been added to onCourse called 'notification of unmarked attendance'. When
          enabled, this script sends a daily notification to advise an admin user of any sessions
          run the previous day where attendance was all or partially unmarked. If you have scripts
          enabled that rely on tutors electronically marking the roll, we suggest you enable this
          monitoring script also. <systemitem>#26608</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>A new script has been added to onCourse called 'send payment plan reminder'. When enabled,
          this script sends a reminder to the invoice payer if they have a payment due within the
          next 7 days or if they have a payment overdue. The email template link includes a password
          free one time login to the portal payment gateway to make the payment via credit card
            <systemitem>#28806</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Fix to Payment In an Payment Out reports to render company names correctly <systemitem>#28802</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>All list view prefetches have been reviewed and updated, to ensure all onCourse windows are
          opening in the fastest possible time. Windows with noticeable delays, like Applications
          and Payment In load significantly faster <systemitem>#29058</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Allow the change of settlement date for deposited banking records <systemitem>#28972</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Fix to wait list link in course record to open filtered list view of waiting list entries for that course only <systemitem>#27584</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to editing of attendance records to ensure if cancel is chosen, instead of save,
          no changes to the attendance records are saved <systemitem>#28793</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvements to the WA RAPT report have been implemented to export the start and end date of
          self paced outcomes which have been overridden, calculate the course fee based on the
          enrolment fee divided by the units of competency, and export the USI data
            <systemitem>#28933</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fis to the deposit bank 'dank banked' field to allow the date to be typed into the field rather than just chosen from the calendar tool <systemitem>#29164</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>The onCourse credit card payment gateway has been added to the skillsOnCourse portal, to allow debtors to make payments against their outstanding invoices or payment plans <systemitem>#19455</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>A design refresh of the portal timetable has been implemented to show sessions in a continal scrolling schedule. Each session can be clicked on to expand and show additional notes and links <systemitem>#28496</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>A neew team timetable view has been implemented for users with group permissions for other users in the portal. In this view you will see the attendees scheduled for each session <systemitem>#28496</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>An all new and improved design for tutors marking attendance via the portal now includes the CRICOS marking options for partial attendance and absent with reason <systemitem>#27482</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>A feature for marking the class roll has been added to show the attendance percentage of each student <systemitem>#27482</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Students (and their approved portal contacts) can see information about the student's attendance for each class, showing the marked roll results for each session as well as an overall attendance calculation <systemitem>#28804</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>A new feature has been added to the skillsOnCourse login screen to auto detect first time
          visitors to the site, when following a login link from onCourse. They system will auto
          populate their name and email address and prompt them to set up a password on their first
            visit <systemitem>#28881</systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Improved display of invoices in the portal to better match onCourse email templates and print reports <systemitem>#28286</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Hide payments in the portal of $0, including internal system payments and failed payment attempts <systemitem>#29162</systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
