<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-8.23">
  <info>
    <title>Release 8.23</title>
    <pubdate>22 August 2016</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>A new script has been added to onCourse called 'notification of unmarked attendance'. When
          enabled, this script sends a daily notification to advise an admin user of any sessions
          run the previous day where attendance was all or partially unmarked. If you have scripts
          enabled that rely on tutors electronically marking the roll, we suggest you enable this
          monitoring script also. <systemitem>#26608</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem>Fix to Payment In an Payment Out reports to render company names correctly<para><systemitem>#28802</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>All list view prefetches have been reviewed and updated, to ensure all onCourse windows are
          opening in the fastest possible time. Windows with noticeable delays, like Applications
          and Payment In load significantly faster <systemitem>#29058</systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Fix to wait list link in course record to open filtered list view of waiting list entries for that course only <systemitem>#27584</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to editing of attendance records to ensure if cancel is chosen, instead of save,
          no changes to the attendance records are saved <systemitem>#28793</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvements to the WA RAPT report have been implemented to export the start and end date of
          self paced outcomes which have been overridden, calculate the course fee based on the
          enrolment fee divided by the units of competency, and export the USI data
            <systemitem>#28933</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fis to the deposit bank 'dank banked' field to allow the date to be typed into the field rather than just chosen from the calendar tool <systemitem>#29164</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para><systemitem></systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
<itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>A new feature has been added to the skillsOnCourse login screen to auto detect first time
          visitors to the site, when following a login link from onCourse. They system will auto
          populate their name and email address and prompt them to set up a password on their first
            visit.<systemitem>#28881</systemitem></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
