<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         version="5.0" xml:id="release-2.1.10">

  <info>
    <title>Release 2.1.10</title>
    <pubdate>05 Jan 2012</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <para>This release has a relatively minor set of bug fixes, mainly focussed on VET and AVETMISS
      reporting. We strongly recommend this upgrade to any RTO since the issues here are quite
      important. For other users, it is a low priority upgrade.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Since onCourse 2.1.0 the Qualification selected in Course could change to a different
          qualification. In reality, this did not happen often which is why it hasn’t been seen
          until now. The only real impact is typically related to AVETMISS exports.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Allowed creating Courses with Unit of Competency but no Qualification</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Invoices created in Quick Enrol should be linked to the Account derived from Class.
          Fixed problem where this Account could change to the default account defined in
          preferences.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Added field ‘Country’ in the Site user interface</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>In NAT0020 export default country is Australia</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>‘Credit note’ heading appeared in overpaid Invoice, when printed. ‘Invoice’ heading
          appeared on overpaid Credit Note, when printed.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tutors were missing when upgrading onCourse. This only affects customers upgrading
          from 1.7 to 2.x who are using an MS-SQL database</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Reduced onCourse memory footprint during upgrade process from 1.7</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
