<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-7.2">

  <info>
    <title>Release 7.2</title>
    <pubdate>22 May 2015</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>Payment plans</title>
      <para>A new concept for enrolment fee payments has been developed to allow for online
        enrolments by paying a deposit, and regular payments thereafter.</para>
      <para>Payment plans consist of scripts which can be applied to classes en masse, and plans in
        individual classes with payment dates and amounts which can be modified as required.</para>
      <para>The student fee window in the class has changed to allow for more options in creating
        and setting a class fee with a deposit and then additional amounts payable in relation to
        the class start date. </para>
      <para>During enrolment, the default option of payment of a payment plan class is for the
        deposit component only, but additional amounts up to the full class fee can be taken at this
        time.</para>
      <para>Any discount that applies to an enrolment will be deducted from the final payment
        amount.</para>
      <para>The invoice window layout has also had significant change to clean up the view and
        accommodate the payment plan schedule. Within the payment plan invoice, payable amounts and
        due dates can be adjusted, added or removed, for the individual student. Any invoice can be
        manually turned into a payment plan invoice if the balance was not paid in full on
        enrolment.</para>
      <para>The printed invoice template has also been updated to include the payment plan schedule
        of dates and amounts payable, as have the email templates.</para>
      <para>When a student has an invoice with payment plan amounts due in the future, and they
        enrol in another course, the future payable components will not be added to their amount
        payable in Quick Enrol. Only overdue payment amounts will be automatically added.</para>
      <para>A new access right has been created for payment plans. Ensure you update your access
        roles to allow the appropriate permissions for your staff to create and edit payment plans
        within both classes and invoices.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <para>When a change has been made to a script or template, onCourse will not automatically
      overwrite your files as you may have added your own customisations. You can choose to update
      your templates and scripts manually by accessing the latest versions on GitHub.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Wording in the default Voucher purchase plain text and HTML template was made
          consistent, with the word ‘quick’ removed from the HTML voucher template.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Labels for tax amounts updated in the plain text Tax Invoice. Total is now shown
          inclusive of tax, and tax is itemized separately.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Payment plan payment dates and amounts payable have also been added to the Tax Invoice
          plain text and HTML templates. The link for the item above is directly to the plain text
          template which includes these changes. </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>An optional clause can be added to the student and tutor reminder scripts to only send
          to classes that have met their minimum enrolment requirements – if (
          courseClass.successAndQueuedEnrolments.size() >= courseClass.minimumPlaces ) {.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add find related invoices from products window cog wheel <systemitem>#24215</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add find related payslips from classes window cog wheel <systemitem>#24508</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add ‘last login’ date to users list view, to assist with finding users who no longer
            log in to onCourse regularly <systemitem>#24475</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Change the discount default option to ‘classes tagged with’ to avoid users
            accidentally selecting all classes <systemitem>#24319</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improve voucher redemption process in Quick Enrol to show the voucher redemption
            balance available and to edit the value being redeemed as part of this purchase <systemitem>#24130</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>For find related ‘contacts purchased’ from product find contacts with successful
            purchases, and exclude contacts with failed purchase attempts <systemitem>#24211</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>For the advanced search option in contacts ‘number of enrolments’ only count active
            enrolments, and exclude failed, cancelled or credited enrolments <systemitem>#24504</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Quick Enrol window layout was adjusted so relationships window was better accessible
            as it was sometimes drawn off screen <systemitem>#22983</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure outcomes tab correctly updates UOC when the course code is changed to another
            course after class creation. The course code can not be changed for a class once the
            class has enrolments <systemitem>#23570</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Display payment out amounts in banking with a negative symbol in front of the the
            amount <systemitem>#24015</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to the certification creation logic from the class cog wheel. In
            summary: When a course is ‘sufficient for qualification’ a qualification is created for
            student where all outcomes have been successfully achieved, a Statement of Attainment
            when some of outcomes are successful and some unsuccessful, and no certificate is
            created when all outcomes are unsuccessful. When a course is NOT ‘sufficient for
            qualification’, a Statement of Attainment is created when at least one outcome was
            successful, and no certificate is created when all outcomes are unsuccessful. <systemitem>#24223</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to the labeling and identification of failed payment attempts on the
            invoice payment summary <systemitem>#24781</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
