<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<chapter xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook ../../../src/docbook.xsd' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink' version='5.0' xml:id='release-9.4'>
  <info>
    <title>Release 9.4</title>
    <pubdate>14 Dec 2017</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role='major'>
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <para>onCourse now has a new dashboard which you can access from the File > Preferences > New
        Dashboard. It is still in beta testing so we would appreciate your feedback to let us know
        how it works for you. It includes some new features:</para>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Smart search across many entities in one go e.g. searching 'cook' will give you
              results of courses and class containing the name cook, and contacts whose name
              contains cook.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Ability to personally customise your list of frequently used elements of onCourse
              using the favourites function</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>An easier way to find the functions of onCourse you need to use via search e.g.
              type discount in the search bar in press enter on your keyboard to open the discount
              window </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Website eCommerce engine</title>
      <para>Significant updates to the online sales process have taken place in the last release, to
        allow you to implement your data collection rules (released in 9.3) into the checkout
        process, including the addition of enrolment, application and waiting list custom
        fields.</para>
      <para>This means you can now ask additional per enrolment / per application specific questions
        of each student, replacing processes that may have been asked post enrolment or via
        surveys.</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
      <para>Add custom enrolment fields to the checkout <systemitem>OD-11002</systemitem>
          </para> </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display custom application fields in checkout <systemitem>OD-11182</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Implement Waiting list form for checkout app <systemitem>OD-11188</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Checkout: CorporatePass preference only enabled when active corporate passes exist
            <systemitem>OD-11148</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>AVETMISS improvements with funding contracts</title>
      <para>The AVETMISS export runner window has undergone some significant updates to make it
        simpler to use and to provide you with more options when exporting your data to various
        reporting agencies.</para>
      <para>Most significantly, the export runner will pre-count the outcomes that will be exported,
        advise you of any that need a final outcome status because their end date is in the past,
        and allow you to set an override end date option for export to push their end date into the
        future.</para>
      <para>The new funding contact option will allow you to set classes and enrolments belonging to
        specific state funding programs, which is a list you can extend with as many program types
        as you wish.</para>
      <para>A history of each export you run is stored in onCourse as a funding upload, allowing you
        to track when you last reported and set if the funding export from onCourse was accepted by
        the funding agency. </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role='scripts'>
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Script: Send statement report to contact with outstanding balances
          <systemitem>OD-10416</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Script: notify the trainer when a session has not been marked
          <systemitem>OD-10048</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Marketing Script: Related class taught by the same tutor
            <systemitem>OD-10701</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Marketing Email Template: Related class taught by the same tutor
            <systemitem>OD-10702</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Email Template - class schedule changes <systemitem>OD-10978</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Report: Contract Demographic data <systemitem>OD-10734</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Report - Assessment Outcomes - per Student' <systemitem>OD-11054</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New Export: Debtor Payment summary report
          <systemitem>OD-11133</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Script update: Send monthly finance summary script was reporting incorrect date. If
          you use this script, please go to File > Preferences > Scripts, locate the script, open it
          and select 'update script', save and close. <systemitem>OD-10911</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve validation in contact CSV import script to work correctly
          <systemitem>OD-11057</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add message created by key to avoid message sending duplication when messages are sent
          by scripts <systemitem>OD-10520</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add new onCourse script trigger option - 'Class published'
            <systemitem>OD-10776</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Class Invoice Report - Incorrect outstanding total balance removed
            <systemitem>OD-11151</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Invoice Print Report - was printing on two pages when only one printable page exists
          <systemitem>OD-11134</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem><para>Certificate of Attendance print report - printing without expected page breaks between
          certificate records <systemitem>OD-11053</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Hide {block} syntax in portal content <systemitem>OD-10319</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Portal: sort related contacts by name in drop down list
            <systemitem>OD-10419</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve portal user switching list to support more than 30 users
            <systemitem>OD-10879</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve portal Class Roll: partially attended duration
            <systemitem>OD-1949</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Robots.txt to include pointer to sitemap <systemitem>OD-10434</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fix portal render queue error on tutor class page <systemitem>OD-10264</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display RTO name instead of college name in Portal certificate validation tool
            <systemitem>OD-10609</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Update Tutor portal widget data in real time <systemitem>OD-10625</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fix class rating feature where is was not working on iPhone
            <systemitem>OD-10922</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Portal: class page should not display web description images and blocks
            <systemitem>OD-11085</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Portal: allow removal Waiting List when there's a custom field attached
            <systemitem>OD-11171</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Portal: Mark roll doesn't scroll down to list of contacts
            <systemitem>OD-11174</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fix Language setting error in AVETMISS when students enrol online
            <systemitem>OD-9958</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Available places wording incorrect on website - should read 'There are x places
          available' <systemitem>OD-11213</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <section> 
      <title>Financial and payroll features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>New feature: Process payment out from credit note by selecting cogwheel option
            <systemitem>OD-10032</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New feature: Add cogwheel option to invoice - create payment in
            <systemitem>OD-10033</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Improve relation between Tutor Attendance status and Payable time
              field<systemitem>OD-10120</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tutor payable time sheet UI improvement <systemitem>OD-10494</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Attendance UI Scrolling improvements <systemitem>OD-10132</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve Attendance tab loading speed and performance <systemitem>OD-10220</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Make payroll confirmation editable in attendance confirmation sheet
          <systemitem>OD-10497</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve validation for $0 tutor wage so it can not be copied when duplicating a class
              <systemitem>OD-10305</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>$0 wages should not try to generate payroll records <systemitem>OD-10459</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Exclude from unprocessed payroll counter - non-timetable related wages where class hasn't started yet
          <systemitem>OD-10876</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Exclude from unprocessed payroll counter - tutor pay requiring confirmation that has
            already been confirmed <systemitem>OD-11219</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New field on contact finance tab: override class GST settings on purchase
            <systemitem>OD-10466</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use Contact GST override in invoice and finance <systemitem>OD-10467</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use Contact GST override in web enrol (invoice and finance)
              <systemitem>OD-10468</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Other features</title>
      <itemizedlist>

      
            <listitem>
        <para>Move contact record custom fields to their own tab <systemitem>OD-10744</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Remove the ability to set a default value for Custom Fields in preferences (a
          requirement for Data Collection) <systemitem>OD-10798</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Implement USI soap service new version <systemitem>OD-10880</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improve UI display for USI verification <systemitem>OD-10285</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve arrived / departed time fields behaviour when setting partial attendance on
            onCourse <systemitem>OD-10949</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add to class duplication: optionally skip copying of class tags and class notes
            <systemitem>OD-7475</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Improve the design of the Student fee sheet <systemitem>OD-9287</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Auto select appropriate student/payer when using pre-populated QE from Enrolment
            transfer function of enrolment window cogwheel <systemitem>OD-9346</systemitem>
          </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>New access control - view private documents <systemitem>OD-9631</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>New access control - mailing list create permission <systemitem>OD-10590</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enrolling existing students from inside contact record doesn't load contact into QE as expected <systemitem>OD-10306</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Prevent General Preferences screen loading blank if data connection lost
          <systemitem>OD-10328</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Catch exception cancelling an enrolment joined to a certificate
            <systemitem>OD-10344</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Show error message in QE when promo code fails to apply as expected during office
          enrolment due to corporatePass join <systemitem>OD-10558</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Tag set bound to Tutors does not accept mandatory option even though all tutors are
          tagged <systemitem>OD-10787</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Quick Enrol: adding payment plan class before contact keeps duplicating records on
          Payments view <systemitem>OD-10886</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Emails cannot send to contacts with comma in their name
          <systemitem>OD-10986</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Automatic logout stopped working <systemitem>OD-11065</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Outcome delivery mode was not getting value from value set in the
            class<systemitem>OD-11078</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Java 9 support <systemitem>OD-11115</systemitem>
          <systemitem>OD-11116</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Adjust USI service to return plain string response instead of complex SoapFault
          <systemitem>OD-11117</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use contra instead of zero payment type for credit payment transfer process
          <systemitem>OD-11124</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Tutor and Student attendance marking freezes the window
          <systemitem>OD-11143</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Angel Client: http://www.ish.com.au/blog/rss.xml is not available
          <systemitem>OD-11206</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix display of documents list view to load records as expected
            <systemitem>OD-10921</systemitem></para></listitem>


    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
