<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-9.2">

  <info>
    <title>Release 9.2</title>
    <pubdate>16 Jan 2016</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
<section>
  <title>Assessment tasks and Training Plans</title>
  <para>A new feature for onCourse has been added to allow you to create assessment tasks.
        Assessment tasks have a name, description, due date, release date and attached documents.
        This is the beginning of a series of development work scheduled for assessment tasks.</para>
      <para>The Attendance tab layout has been updated to show more information, including the
        training plan information mapping the units of competency to the scheduled sessions,
        assessment and their due dates.</para>
      <para>For more information about the new features and changes to this tab, refer to the
        Assessment tasks chapter of the user documentation.</para>
</section>
    <section>
      <title>Time and Attendance (payroll) updates</title>
      <para>A number of visual changes have been made to the attendance marking tab, including the
        marking of tutor attendance for payroll purposes.</para>
      <para>New tutor attendance/payroll status for scheduled sessions are Confirmed' (green),
        'Rejected' (red), 'Not confirmed' (grey). Tutor payable time for each session can be
        modified as needed to be either more than or less than the scheduled payable time from the
        class timetable.</para>
      <para>For more information about the new features and changes to this tab, refer to the
        Payroll chapter of the user documentation.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>The AVETMISS data checking export 'Extended outcomes CSV' has been added to the enrolment window, and includes the additional field 'Do no report for AVETMISS' 
        <systemitem>OD-9894</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>A new email template has been added to the waiting list cogwheel option to allow you to manually notify students when a last minute place becomes available in a class
        <systemitem>OD-9895</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem>A new script and email template set have been added for 'Send VET course completion
        survey' 14 days after completion of training <systemitem>OD-10041 and
        OD-10042</systemitem></listitem>
      <listitem>Payslip Report updated to sort printed results by tutor last name, sort pay lines
        per tutor by date, and include a report total sum
        <systemitem>OD-10077</systemitem></listitem>
      <listitem>Student detail report updated to show time stamp and user for each note record printed in the report
        <systemitem>OD-10045</systemitem></listitem>
      <listitem>Invoice reports (both print and email templates) now sort invoiceLines in alphabetical order
        <systemitem>OD-9935</systemitem></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Addition of a new Outcomes list view, available from the find related option in
          contacts, classes and enrolments <systemitem>OD-9474</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Site columns added to class list view, to allow by simple sorting by class location
          <systemitem>OD-9891</systemitem></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Check all units/ uncheck all units option added to session training plan view
        <systemitem>OD-9890</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>A new status of 'in progress' has been added to applications, to differentiate between new and
        un-actioned items, and those that have been followed up
        <systemitem>OD-9892</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>A new core filter has been added to the course window to, by default, hide disabled courses from the list view when it opens
        <systemitem>OD-10031</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Invoice window quick search now allows for search on invoice number or debtor name 
        <systemitem>OD-9841</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Update to merge student default message to include the student number of the record that was merged
        <systemitem>OD-9844</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Using the AVETMISS reporting code '66 - Did not start' will export two blank spaces for NSW Smart and Skilled enrolments. This is of particular use for Training Not Complete (TNC) student records.
        <systemitem>OD-9864</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem>Add the following automatic data export rules to AVETMISS to assist with managing
        CSO enrolments: When 'Funding source – state training authority' state begins with CS or TSS
        then Fee exemption/concession type identifier = Y, Funding source – national = 11, When
        'Funding source – state training authority' is equal to CSO, then export CSD
          <systemitem>OD-9945</systemitem></listitem>
      <listitem><para>VET Fee Help Provider code added to the AVETMISS general preferences tab, to export this code during the VFH export file process 
        <systemitem>OD-9584</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Vouchers with a dollar value for redemption can now be used as payment method after the enrolment has been processed in Payment In / Quick Enrol
        <systemitem>OD-9877</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvements to tutor records with 'date finished' in their record, to show their record in a
          greyed out font in the tutor list view and stop them from being looked up by the
          clairvoyance when adding tutors to classes <systemitem>OD-8336</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Addition of 'active' flag to tutor roles, to allow old roles to be disabled and not available to select in the drop down list when adding a tutor to a class
        <systemitem>OD-9941</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Allow tutor payable time to be edited for all attendance time, so payable time can be
          increased or decreased per tutor per session <systemitem>OD-9944</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Document all the preference keys <systemitem>OD-10014</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Scrolling added to Quick Enrol related contact record list
        <systemitem>OD-9847</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Outcomes not editable in the contact edit view
        <systemitem>OD-9983</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Delivery mode would show "not set" when in fact they were inherited from the class. This was a cosmetic bug only.
        <systemitem>OD-9984</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Financial record sorting in the contact financial tab adjusted to allow for modified invoice dates, to ensure running totals by date remain accurate
        <systemitem>OD-9789</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improved AVETMISS calculation of  '3 - New Enrolment' or '4 - Continuing enrolment' to take into consideration students enrolling in pathway programs that require the completion of multiple short courses
        <systemitem>OD-9903</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix typo in payment in process <systemitem>OD-9990</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix to the validation process for the contact state field data to allow up to 20 characters to handle overseas customer data <systemitem>OD-10058</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix to the invoice creation process where in some instances the student name was missing from the invoiceLine detail <systemitem>OD-10043</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to the layout of the duplicate class sheet. 'Remove class notes' is now ticked by default <systemitem>OD-10028</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>LDAP SSL setting incorrect changes Bind user DN <systemitem>OD-9880</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Hide the 'USI required' portal dashboard widget for students who have not enrolled in a
          vocational courses <systemitem>OD-1993</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improve the layout of the portal dashboard resources display <systemitem>OD-1987</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improve the layout of the portal dashboard next class block display <systemitem>OD-1988 and OD-1989</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Auto complete Country of Birth country name in the portal and USI portal process
            <systemitem>OD-9959</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improvement to the layout of portal related contacts UI to allow better scrolling and navigation <systemitem>OD-9988 and OD-1961</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix to delete the class web tab copy from the class web block when it is deleted from the onCourse class record <systemitem>OD-10013</systemitem></para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Fix to display discounts correctly on the web for search result classes <systemitem>OD-10061</systemitem></para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
