<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<chapter xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook'
         xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd' version='5.0'
         xml:id='release-18'>
  <info>
    <title>Release 18</title>
    <pubdate>7 Apr. 2020</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role='important'>
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para>
      When viewing an outcome in detail view, you'll now see a list of any
      associated AVETMISS uploads the outcome is attached to. You'll see the date the export was
      run, who it was run by and the status of the outcome.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can now log in with your email address. The old username also works, but email address is preferred and is
      what people expect from applications these days.
      Check that your email address is properly configured in security settings.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role='major'>
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para>The following windows have been migrated to the new user interface:</para>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Documents</listitem>
        <listitem>Assessments</listitem>
        <listitem>Change password</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>For users of onCourse in a web browser, we've improved the way the back and forward buttons on
      work without losing any search or filtering information. This also means you've be
      able to save windows as bookmarks in your browser and to share those links with colleagues.
      When creating support tickets with ish, please send us the URL of the window you are looking at.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role='scripts'>
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed an error where demographic report ignores selection of records
          <systemitem>OD-14144</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role='minor'>
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add documents search on dashboard
          <systemitem>OD-12684</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Removed unneeded scroll bar in Share on Mac OS
          <systemitem>OD-13562</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Animated dragging columns
          <systemitem>OD-13934</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Added left sidebar navigation to additional pages like Automation
          <systemitem>OD-14018</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Email marketing in new contact now set as accepted by default
          <systemitem>OD-14125</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Tutors list view: non-active tutors now appear greyed out
          <systemitem>OD-14134</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role='fixes'>
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Security settings: "Require 2fa every ... hours" now works in browser instead of asking every time.
          <systemitem>OD-14000</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Added error messaging around outcome deletion when attached to successful AVETMISS export
          <systemitem>OD-14014</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Can now search for @ in email
          <systemitem>OD-14136</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Find Related from Invoices to Classes now works
          <systemitem>OD-14138</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Gmail now renders new lines in custom messages
          <systemitem>OD-14139</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Notes were not duplicating to new classes
          <systemitem>OD-14140</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>New notes now add at the top
        <systemitem>OD-14142</systemitem>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Can now remove site from session
          <systemitem>OD-14159</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed course page not rendering data in new UI
          <systemitem>OD-14165</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed enrolment status appeared differently between old and new UI
          <systemitem>OD-14166</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed certificate couldn't print using outcome from prior learning
          <systemitem>OD-14179</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
