<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         version="5.0" xml:id="release-8.4">
    <info>
        <title>Release 8.4</title>
        <pubdate>17 Nov 2015</pubdate>
    </info>
    <section role="major">
        <title>Major features</title>
        <section>
            <title>New types of discounts</title>
            <para> Two new bulk purchase discount types were added to onCourse. One option allows
                you to define discounts based on the number of enrolments in the transaction e.g.
                enrol 2 people and each get 5% off, or buy one get one free. </para>
            <para>The second option allows you to define a discount based on the total value of the
                invoice, e.g. a 10% discount applies when the total invoice value is over
                $1000.</para>
            <para>Corporate passes can now also be linked directly to discounts, so employers or
                agents enrolling students can have access to a special price.</para>
            <para>Discounts can now also be for a negative amount i.e. the discount raises the class
                fee instead of lowering it. If an enrolment is eligible for multiple types of
                discounts, and one of these discounts raises the class fee, that discount will be
                selected by default.</para>
            <para> In the case where an enrolment is eligible for multiple types of discounts that
                reduce the class fee, as always, the best price for the enrolling student will be
                selected by default.</para>
            <para>With the new addition of these more complicated types of discounts, the option to
                'combine discounts' has now been removed from onCourse.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Rewrite of the import feature</title>
            <para>onCourse imports have been re-written in a groovy syntax, making them easier for
                users to edit and extend. The most commonly used import, the AVETMISS 80 &amp; 85
                allows you to customise the student contact data import using AVETMISS files
                generated by another student management system.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>onCourse font change</title>
            <para>The onCourse system font has been changed to SourceSansPro to allow for clearer
                display on Retina and other high resolution screens.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Prior Learning data</title>
            <para> To extend upon the exisiting AVETMISS data import option in onCourse that was
                used to create student records, the NAT0060 and NAT00120 files can also be imported
                to creating prior learning records in onCourse. This allows for simple migration
                from another AVETMISS compliant student management systems. The prior learning table
                can also be used to add enrolment and outcome data to exisiting students inside
                onCourse, where learning has taken place externally to the onCourse system.</para>
            <para>These records are visible in the contact enrolment tab 'outcomes' list, like other
                outcomes the student obtains via onCourse enrolments.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Payroll Improvements</title>
            <para> Tutors can now be attached to classes with multiple roles and payrates, allowing
                you to assign the same contact, for example, as both a tutor with an hourly payrate
                and an assessor with a per enrolment pay rate. Per session pay rates now display the
                correct pay value in the class budget, depending on the number of sessions the tutor
                is assigned to, rather than multiplying the rate by the total number of sessions in
                the class. </para>
            <para>The payslip edit view layout has been rebuilt to better group and display line
                items and make the editing processes, where class defaults are overridden, clearer
                by displaying variations with red text. A cogwheel option has been added next to
                each pay line item, replacing the cross/delete icon, allowing you to 'defer to next
                pay run' to improve the clarity of what this function does. </para>
            <para>When you choose to defer a pay line, it will be removed from the pay slip total
                for the current period, but when the payroll is generated for the following pay
                period, it will appear again on that payslip. This will continue until the pay line
                is processed via a pay slip.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Payment In &amp; Quick Enrol redesign for payment processing</title>
            <para>Creating a payment separately from an enrolment process used to open a 'payment
                in' window. The window that opens now is Quick Enrol. Validation has been removed
                from inside Quick Enrol requiring the transaction to contain at least one purchase. </para>
            <para>Now, you can use Quick Enrol to process payments against invoices with outstanding
                balances. You can do this via the normal Quick Enrol window, or when clicking on the
                plus option inside the payment in list view. This change in user interface also
                introduces the opportunity for vouchers to be used as payment method after the
                enrolment process.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Preference user interface updates</title>
            <para>The preference settings for payment types, custom fields, contact relations and
                concession types have been moved from being their own menu item and windows, to
                being added to the list of preference options in the File > Preferences > General
                list view.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>AVETMISS improvements</title>
            <para> A new 'suppress for AVETMISS' field has been added to the enrolment record. This
                will let users met the NSW Smart &amp; Skilled reporting requirements of reporting
                and retaining records of a deferred or discontinued student once, and then suppress
                the data from reporting in subsequent monthly reports without needing to cancel the
                enrolment in onCourse.</para>
            <para>The AVETMISS export runner default has also been changed to automatically tick and
                select the option 'Export 90 for VET outcomes which are not set'. This can still be
                changed to export another value, and won't affect the rules that govern the export
                of two blank spaces for NSW Smart &amp; Skilled or 70 for outcomes completing in the
                following calendar year.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section role="scripts">
        <title>Reports and scripts</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Improvement to date references used within the Tax Invoice email
                        templates. We recommend you update the date fields in your template as per
                        the latest version on Git Hub. <systemitem>#25971</systemitem>
                    </para>
                    <para>If you would prefer not to overwrite the full invoice template and remove
                        other modifications you have made, please replace in the plain text version
                        of the template</para>
                    <programlisting>Invoice created on: ${invoice.createdOn.format("d/M/yy")}</programlisting>
                    <para>with</para>
                    <programlisting>Invoice created on: ${invoice.invoiceDate.format("d/M/yy")}</programlisting>
                    <para>and in the HTML version replace</para>
                    <programlisting>${invoice.createdOn.format("EEEEE d MMMMM yyyy")}
            </programlisting>
                    <para>with</para>
                    <programlisting>${invoice.invoiceDate.format("EEEEE d MMMMM yyyy")}
            </programlisting>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A new export called 'Extended outcome CSV export' was added to the class
                        window. It creates an excel file that looks similar to an AVETMISS NAT00120
                        file, but includes additional data referencing the student name and onCourse
                        course and class names and codes. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Grouping and display of costs and budget items improved in the 'Budget
                        summary by class' report <systemitem>#25391</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Improvement to the contact CSV export layout to include all available
                        onCourse fields <systemitem>#25900</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A new trigger type was created that can be used to execute scripts: class
                        cancelled <systemitem>#26272</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Improvement to the Outcome Assessment Report to sort by student last name
                            <systemitem>#26404</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section role="minor">
        <title>Minor features</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>All discounts are now allowed to be negative (i.e. a surcharge) in both
                        discount schemes and manual discounts. This means the increased fee is part
                        of the enrolment invoice line, so the full fee charged will be reversed
                        should the enrolment be cancelled <systemitem>#25447</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Allow purchased memberships and products to be cancelled and an optional
                        credit note provided on cancellation <systemitem>#25807</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Payslips are now taggable <systemitem>#25815</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Added validation message if a tutor added to a class has an end date in
                        the past <systemitem>#17775</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>New fields for recording Working with Children Check (WWCC) number, expiry
                        date, status and check date to the tutor tab of a tutor record
                            <systemitem>#26006</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Moved the creation of email messages to the onCourse server. This has
                        greatly improved the speed of sending large numbers of emails
                            <systemitem>#20489</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>AusPost suburb and postcode datafile added to onCourse, to improve
                        accuracy of address data entry <systemitem>#22533</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Show a message in the payment window when the payment attempt fails and
                        the window stays open to allow for another attempt or manual refund
                            <systemitem>#25367</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Validation added to ensure an outcome end date set manually can not be
                        before the outcome start date <systemitem>#25521</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Added date and time of document creation to the documents window.
                        Documents are shown sorted in chronological order by default, with the
                        newest documents at the top of the list <systemitem>#25621</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Added contact middle name to the AVETMISS data export files
                            <systemitem>#25783</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Descriptions and other rich text content can now be added to the root tag
                        e.g. subjects so that tag content will display for the URL
                        www.mycollege.name/courses <systemitem>#23330</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Allow the purchase of pre-defined products when using a corporatePass
                            <systemitem>#19808</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The VET Fee-Help 'Type of attendance' field has been added to the
                        enrolment record. This allows you to set a 'Type of attendance' i.e. full
                        time at the class level, but change it to part time for some students
                        enrolled in the class <systemitem>#25034</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Remember and return by default to the last browsed location when uploading
                        a new document to onCourse <systemitem>#25465</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section role="fixes">
        <title>Fixes</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Fix to the class duplication process which could sometimes fail when tutor
                        attendance was marked but not approved <systemitem>#26023</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Validation message added when adding contact headshot to ensure the
                        contact record has been saved to the database first
                            <systemitem>#25972</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Automatically tick the 'VET' flag of a course when a unit of competency is
                        added to the VET tab <systemitem>#25973</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Fix to classes that were duplicated over a daylight savings change period
                        to show the correct time for each session <systemitem>#26157</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Label in Quick Enrol 'concession type' changed to 'Discount type' to
                        improve clarity of meaning <systemitem>#26183</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A technical fix was implemented to prevent a race condition in the
                        replication process which could leave some enrolments in an 'in transaction'
                        state where there were multiple users attempting to process an enrolment
                        into the last place in a class <systemitem>#25706</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A maximum width for tags names was introduced to visually truncate long
                        tag names attached to records and allow the tags to wrap correctly in the
                        window <systemitem>#26226</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Fix to the label in the class fee sheet to switch between "Total class fee
                        (inc GST)" and "Total class fee (no GST)" depending on the GST option
                        selected <systemitem>#24264</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Improvement to window view copy and paste to excel functions to ensure
                        date formats appear the same way in the pasted data as they did the onCourse
                        window <systemitem>#25918</systemitem>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>
