<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-8.14">

  <info>
    <title>Release 8.14</title>
    <pubdate>30 March 2016</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para> A new script has been created called 'Send weekly finance summary report' to email
            the Trial Balance for the previous 7 days to the system admin email address every Monday
            morning. You may like to alter the email address in the script, so this report sends to
            to your finance managers email address. This script is disabled by default
              <systemitem>#27107</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> Added new ReportSpec API functions to allow reports to be printed and emailed via scripts
            <systemitem>#27405</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> Added new DocumentSpec API functions to allow documents to be created and uploaded into the skillsOnCourse portal via scripts
            <systemitem>#27696</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para> Two new reconcilliation reports have been added to the Banking Deposits window
            called 'Reconcilliation Summary' and 'Reconcilliation Detail' that group and total
            payments by type, better assisting bank account reconcillation for daily Credit Card and
            AMEX transactions <systemitem>#27696</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <para><itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para> Improved prefetches for creating large message batches, to ensure server is not overloaded
          <systemitem>#27748</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para> Removed lock/unlock icons from outcomes obtained via prior learning, as there are no class dates to inherit this data from
          <systemitem>#27241</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para> AVETMISS improvements for non-VET Prior Learning, to export a default FOE ID of 1299999 where no value is provided
          <systemitem>#27241</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="web">
    <title>Web features</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section role="web-fixes">
    <title>Web fixes</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
