<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<chapter xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
         xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd'
         version='5.0' xml:id='release-16'>
  <info>
    <title>Release 16</title>
    <pubdate>17 Feb. 2020</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes and updates</title>
    <section>
      <title>AVETMISS data no longer inherits</title>

      <para>Class, Enrolment and Outcome AVETMISS fields no longer inherit values. For example,
        'funding source state' could be entered in the Class and if you didn't override that field
        in the Enrolment or in the Outcome, the Class value would be used. The value would display
        with a padlock to show the value that was used came from the Class.
      </para>
      <para>Now in release 16, this doesn't happen. Instead, when you create an Enrolment or an
        Outcome, the value is copied from the Class, rather than inherited. This happens once so
        that if you then change the value in the Class, the Enrolments and Outcomes that already
        exist are not updated, but new enrolments and outcomes will reflect the change. We made this change since
        it causes less confusion for new users.
      </para>
      <para>It is important to note that this change means that changes to the class timetable after enrolments are
        created will not automatically update the start and end dates for outcomes.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Old AVETMISS export gone</title>

      <para>The old AVETMISS export window had a number of bugs and has now been completely removed.
        There is nothing you could do in the old window that you cannot do in the new.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Dashboard search</title>
      <para>The search panel on the dashboard has been moved to the left and is now collapsible.
        Given that we're moving to a browser-based application later in 2020, we needed to re-think
        our approach to navigation as it won't be possible to use the standard navigation menus like
        we do in the current java version of onCourse. This small but noticeable addition is the
        first step towards introducing this change.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Missing features</title>
      <para>In version 16 there are some features missing from the new Class user interface. They will be
        returned in version 17. In the meantime you can hold SHIFT while opening the window to
        access the old UI. These features are:
      </para>
      <para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>clash detection on timetable</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>bulk updating classes to publish them online</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>bulk updating timetables</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>bulk updating outcome statuses</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role='major'>
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para>The following windows have been migrated to the new user interface:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Courses</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Classes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Contacts</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enrolments</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Outcomes</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      There are significant changes particularly in the class edit view including a
      new places available projection graph and a new timetable editor.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role='scripts'>
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Outcomes which have been reported are now locked
          <systemitem>OD-12759</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Class UI: Reportable hours field now populates with data from Course by default
          <systemitem>OD-13659</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>'Default reportable hours' label in Classes is now simply called 'Reportable Hours'
          <systemitem>OD-13668</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Added Historic projected pre-paid fee export
          <systemitem>OD-13511</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section role='minor'>
      <title>Minor features</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new Class duplicate UI
            <systemitem>OD-12994</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Removed inheritance functionality from some fields
            <systemitem>OD-13042</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Contact Merge: Added a merge success pop-up.
            <systemitem>OD-13289</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new UI for class cancellation.
            <systemitem>OD-13423</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new UI to generate tutor pay for class
            <systemitem>OD-13427</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Contacts: added find related items to new UI
            <systemitem>OD-13457</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added merge contacts to new UI
            <systemitem>OD-13466</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Contacts: Added generate tutor pay for tutor
            <systemitem>OD-13467</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added Traineeship Courses to Courses list
            <systemitem>OD-13517</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added new USI integration
            <systemitem>OD-13533</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Removed list view counts to improve performance
            <systemitem>OD-13538</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Animation on attendance scrolling
            <systemitem>OD-13613</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Contacts: Can now select Gender > Other
            <systemitem>OD-13616</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tutor Pay generation from cogwheel generates for all classes when non are selected
            <systemitem>OD-13619</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added help icon for prior learning
            <systemitem>OD-13637</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added vetPurchasingContractScheduleID field to Outcome edit UI
            <systemitem>OD-13640</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Dashboard: Added keyboard control for search results
            <systemitem>OD-13658</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added custom field keys to search query autocomplete
            <systemitem>OD-13680</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Courses: Add sorting by code for modules at searching
            <systemitem>OD-13681</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added Contact image editable indicator
            <systemitem>OD-13706</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section role='fixes'>
      <title>Fixes</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed a pagination issue when list updated between pages
            <systemitem>OD-13086</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Removed extra scroll bar that appears on OSX
            <systemitem>OD-13562</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved audit table query performance
            <systemitem>OD-13545</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Made easier to edit label, help text of custom fields within Data Collection Form
            <systemitem>OD-13530</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Security: Set Account permission to View if role has Invoice and Payment permissions
            <systemitem>OD-13377</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Find Anything results - windows should include search term when opened
            <systemitem>OD-13439</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved performance when opening Scripts in Automation section
            <systemitem>OD-13498</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where vouchers were created with expiry type NULL
            <systemitem>OD-13502</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where wrong 'Due Date' was displayed for invoices with payment plan
            <systemitem>OD-13516</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed instances of old UI windows opening when using Find Related instead of new
            ones
            <systemitem>OD-13519</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where users could not reconcile banking deposits manually
            <systemitem>OD-13522</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where Waiting Lists window went white when creating new record</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error that could occur when re-ordering multiple tags
            <systemitem>OD-13528</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where 'Course' drop-down shows all courses instead of checked as
            'Allows Waiting lists' in Waiting Lists
            <systemitem>OD-13542</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where root tag without child is displayed in edit view
            <systemitem>OD-13543</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed the 'Unauthorised' error that occasionally appears before login
            <systemitem>OD-13546</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Timetable: fixed an error that occurred if start date time and end date time were
            different years
            <systemitem>OD-13549</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where Custom Field would let you save in incorrect circumstance
            <systemitem>OD-13556</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added a warning message on edit view about mandatory tags
            <systemitem>OD-13557</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where font weights didn't display in Firefox
            <systemitem>OD-13560</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where courses list was not updated after duplication
            <systemitem>OD-13578</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed a Sales search query not working
            <systemitem>OD-13596</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed incorrect validation when changing Payment Out banked date
            <systemitem>OD-13600</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Preferences &gt; Tutor Pay Rates. Fixed an endless spinner after updating record
            <systemitem>OD-13601</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed an error where some dashboard latest activity records contained invalid urls
            <systemitem>OD-13635</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>AVETMISS Export - Fixed rare error where NT was not exporting with correct state
            identifier in NAT00080 and NAT00085
            <systemitem>OD-13677</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Invoice line: fixed an error where course related link is always disabled
            <systemitem>OD-13691</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Enrolments: Full time flag (QLD). Fixed an error where unable to set 'No' or 'Not
            set' values
            <systemitem>OD-13723</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>2-column view: Fixed an error where list could break when there were few records
            <systemitem>OD-13736</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Certificate - Find Related - fixed an error where enrolments showed incorrect
            results
            <systemitem>OD-13762</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Don't show '0 enrolments already have certificates'
            <systemitem>OD-13763</systemitem>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
