<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<chapter xmlns='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
         xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd'
         xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink' version='5.0' xml:id='release-20'>
  <info>
    <title>Release 20</title>
    <pubdate>8 May 2020</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role='important'>
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para>With this release we strongly recommend you run onCourse from Firefox or Chrome using the new pure web
      interface. Use the URL https://***.cloud.oncourse.cc and replace *** with the name of your college. We're very
      proud of our work up to this point, and would like to thank those of you who helped shape this new
      onCourse UI with your excellent feedback. We've incorporated almost all of your suggestions along the way, and
      onCourse is the better for it.
    </para>
    <para>From this point on, we'll be rolling out changes more often, but they will be much less dramatic. Mostly
      you'd not even notice the changes other than things working faster or more intuitively. So we'll not be emailing
      you notifications before each release, unless there is something important to tell you. Instead, you'll notice an
      enhanced news panel within the dashboard. There you will see webinars, new changes and other useful information.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role='major'>
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para>Checkout has now been added to onCourse, replacing the old Quick Enrol with something that
      is faster, better and easier to use. We've covered the four main steps of the Checkout process
      <link xlink:href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLMUUqiowAJZeO70mfaEIz6xiA3x2n8uFC">in a set of videos.</link>
    </para>
    <para>There are a couple of things still missing from checkout which you'll need to hold Shift and use the old
      window for. We are working hard to bring those to you as soon as possible.
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Traineeships</listitem>
      <listitem>Voucher redemption</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role='minor'>
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Show detailed error message from USI agency if there's a setup error
          <systemitem>OD-14443</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role='fixes'>
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed an error where Print Certificate without USI permissions checkboxes in User
          Roles didn't function
          <systemitem>OD-13593</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>Added UI warning if user tries to unlink tutor from session where payline already exists
        <para>
          <systemitem>OD-14157</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Recovering a deleted document
          <systemitem>OD-14352</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed an error in Contacts - VET &gt; Achieved In Year validation
          <systemitem>OD-14354</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed flickering scroll bar problem
          <systemitem>OD-14366</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed an error where Contact relations appeared broken
          <systemitem>OD-14420</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed an error that occurred when email template had no html or plain body
          <systemitem>OD-14421</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed issue around adding payment plan to class with already defined enrolment fee
          <systemitem>OD-14423</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed and issue where Module Name and Code weren't updating when scrolling in 3 column
          view
          <systemitem>OD-14424</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed error where users couldn't save Query script block
          <systemitem>OD-14431</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixed an error where outcome list fails to open class outcomes
          <systemitem>OD-14444</systemitem>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
