<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         version="5.0" xml:id="release-5.0">

  <info>
    <title>Release 5.0</title>
    <pubdate>16 Apr 2014</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>Quick Enrol user interface</title>
      <para>Months in the making, a sophisticated new design for Quick Enrol has been built so your
        staff can process enrolments, sell products, create invoices and record payments at
        lightning speed.</para>
      <para>Some of the improvements include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved contact look-up selection: See a full list of possible contact matches,
            with more data shown</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Simpler class and product selection: search, show all, or choose for the quick list
            of recently sold items</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sell products and vouchers: Two new types of products, which can be bought along
            with the existing enrolment and memberships</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>More flexible invoicing: easily add custom invoice lines on the fly, and set the
            invoice due date into the future</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Your choice of payment delegation: Manually select which historical invoices you
            wish the payment to apply to, or use our auto-calculate feature to disperse the value of
            this payment against the invoices outstanding</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Redeem vouchers for payment: a new feature for this release, allowing vouchers to be
            redeemed during Quick Enrol</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Choice of confirmation method: after enrolment, send emails, print confirmations or
            both</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="images/select_invoice_partial_pay.png"
              depth="306" width="480"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Vouchers</title>
      <para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="images/voucher_list.png"
              depth="106" width="480"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </para>
      <para>Vouchers are a new way to sell training to your customers. Vouchers can be used in the
        traditional sense of a gift voucher, where the price of purchase is the dollar value
        available for redemption, for example, a voucher bought for $120 can be redeemed for $120
        worth of training or product. In addition, a voucher can be sold for a different value to
        it’s redemption value, for example, you can sell for $90 a voucher with can be redeemed for
        $100, or give away free $20 gift vouchers as part of a promotion you are running.</para>
      <para>But more exciting than traditional style gift vouchers is the new concept of vouchers as
        a way to bundle together the purchase of a group of enrolments at a special price. For
        example, if you want to sell a qualification as both a series of short courses and a full
        qualification, you can bundle together the short courses and sell the qualification as a
        voucher. The voucher will entitle the student to an enrolment in each of the short
        courses.</para>
      <para>Another way to use a voucher could be to sell one to a company for 20 enrolments in a
        particular course, as they know they have 20 staff they wish to send along over the course
        of the year. As the staff enrol, they redeem an enrolment from the voucher one by one,
        giving them the freedom of selecting an advertised class from your schedule that fits around
        their commitments (but not the freedom to use the voucher to enrol in any other type of
        course). Or perhaps they all enrol in a custom class you have created just for them, but are
        responsible for completing the online enrolment process and filling out their contact
        details and AVETMISS responses, so you don’t need to do the data entry from paper
        forms.</para>
      <para>Each voucher has a unique identifying code and an expiry period (set by you) and can be
        used in multiple transactions until it’s total value has been redeemed or it has expired.
        Vouchers can also been locked to send the redemption invoice to a nominated individual and
        can be edited to change the ‘invoice to’ and expiry date after sale.</para>
      <para>A new chapter in the user handbook is available.</para>
      <para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="images/qual_voucher.png"
              depth="420" width="480"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Products</title>
      <para>Products, like textbooks, mugs, Certificate re-prints, and other fixed charge items can
        now be created in onCourse and sold during the enrolment process in the office or
        online.</para>
      <para>See the user handbook for more information.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Selling memberships</title>
      <para>Memberships can now be sold during the online enrolment process, along with products and
        vouchers.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <section>
      <title>Western Australia specific reporting</title>
      <para>The West Australian RAPT and CQR exports are now implemented.</para>
      <para>Additional WA only options have been added to the class delivery mode options, enrolment
        concession options and outcome status options to meet this requirement.</para>
      <para>The RAPT export format is available in the list of AVETMISS 7 options in the File >
        Import/Export window, class cogwheel or enrolment cogwheel.</para>
      <para>The CQR export format is available from the Certificate list cogwheel.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>VET FEE HELP</title>
      <para>The first round of User Interface features for VET FEE HELP functionality has been added
        to onCourse. In the student AVETMISS record, class VET tab, and enrolment FEE-HELP tab
        additional fields have be added to record information that relates to VET FEE HELP
        reporting.</para>
      <para>In following versions of onCourse, HEPCAT and CHESSN integration will be added.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Performance</title>
      <para>In this release we continue our work on improving performance over slow networks. A high
        speed NBN may now never happen, so every bit helps. In particular we compress network
        streams to get a 30% reduction (roughly) in bandwidth needed. There is a new option in
        onCourse.cfg to tweak the compression setting.</para>
      <para>We have also moved the AVETMISS reporting system onto the server, so performance of this
        export will be dramatically improved (in some cases by a factor of 10).</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <section>
      <title>Quick Enrol</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to contact name clairvoyant look up to improve search behaviour on
            company names</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow new concessions to be added to existing contacts in Quick Enrol</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Messaging</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to the send message window, to allow contacts to be manually added to or
            deleted from the send list</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Contacts</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>New attachment types: tutors only, and tutors and enrolled students for attachments
            available via the onCourse portals</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to ensure attachments linked to contacts can be opened and viewed from within
            the contact window</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Discounts</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvements to the membership discount relationship window to allow relationships
            to be edited and viewed</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Allow classes to be added and deleted to the discount classes tab in a single action
            (previously, a record save was required between add and delete actions)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Course and class records</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Increased the field length for the course code from 10 to 32 characters. The course
            code creates the default URL for a course e.g. www.sttrinians.com.au/course/BCFS. With
            up to 32 characters now available you can create more SEO relevant URLs e.g.
            www.sttrinians.com.au/course/computerclassseniors</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the display of the class attendance tab, where the final student’s sessions
            sometimes couldn’t be edited as they were hidden under the scroll bar</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the timetable repeating session function so repeating every 2 or 3 days each
            week, skipping weekends, recreates the first session on the same day of the week as the
            original session</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to class timetable sessions to allow session times of less than 15
            minutes</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Corrected an error in the onCourse calendar tool that in a mySQL database sometimes
            incorrectly rounded the session time to a few minutes past the selected time</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure self-paced cancelled classes are included in the cancelled classes
            filter</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>AVETMISS</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to AVETMISS to better comply with the new or continuing enrolment
            specifications in the NAT000120. When the course is marked as a full qualification, and
            the enrolment commenced before the ‘outcomes after’ date specified when running the
            AVETMISS export, then the value ’4 – continuing enrolment in the qualification or course
            from a previous year’ is exported. When the course is marked as a full qualification and
            the enrolment commenced after the ‘outcomes after’ date then the value ’3 – commencing
            enrolment in the qualification or course’ is exported. For all other enrolments, where
            the course is not marked as a full qualification, the value ’8 – units of competency or
            module only enrolment’ is exported. This fix is for both AVETMISS 6.1 &amp; 7.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the NSW DET version of the AVETMISS 7 export to change the fill character for
            the Booking ID and Course Site ID are zeros instead of spaces.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Change to the AVETMISS 7 export to export all non-VET courses with an ISH123 or
            similar code, to prevent code duplication errors now onCourse allows 32 characters in
            this field, and AVETMISS allows only 12.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Update to the NSW DET Export to meet the March 2014 ePayments Data Extract File
            Technical Specifications. Changes include always including a qualification reference in
            the NAT00120 record, even for a short course and recalculating the NAT00130 export to
            export “Y” to indicate that training in the full qualification was completed
            successfully but “N” to indicate that the training was successfully completed in a
            partial qualification, or unsuccessfully completed for a full or partial qualification;
            or not completed in all UoCs enrolled.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Finance</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to the payslips ‘add custom line’ process to allow a description</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Added payroll reference number to the payslip list view and made the contact name
            column in the payslip window sortable</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Credit notes which automatically contra pay invoices, contra the originating invoice
            in the first instance, an improvement from defaulting to the oldest unpaid
            invoice</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure automatically reversed web payments for failed enrolment attempts reverse the
            originating income account, instead of the default income account</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add ‘reverse payment’ cog wheel feature to the payment in window</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Email templates</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>‘Invoice due date’ and ‘Customer reference number’ now an available field to insert
            into the email template for the Tax Invoice</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A new XML email template has been added to send the voucher code and redemption
            information on purchase</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Change record sorting for Class Contact List to be alphabetical</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Sort order for invoice lines now grouped by class code</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Invoice report now grouped into taxable items i.e. enrolment and product purchases
            and non-taxable items i.e. gift vouchers and enrolment vouchers</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Bank process Banking report only shows cash and cheque payment type items</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the Class Sign report to print the first session site and room information,
            rather than the default class site and room info</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix for Statements of Attainment reports to ensure long unit of competency names on
            the certificate face wrap instead of truncate</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure rich text such as {blocks} and {image} textile in the course marketing copy
            is not printed in the Enrolment Confirmation report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the exception that could occur when printing the Trial Balance report, where
            onCourse gave an error ‘could not materialise value for key
            ‘accountOpeningCredit’</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to a range of printed Budget reports to ensure wage expense lines are itemized
            and included in totals</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to the Payslip export to include the fields for the Course-Class code
            and the tutors payroll number</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the Class Hours report to ensure the Student Contact Hours are correctly
            calculating</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure the Transaction Summary and Detail reports print the selected date range used
            to run the report, on the report</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
