<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="seo">
    <title>SEO and analysis</title>
    <section>
        <title>Overview</title>
        <para>onCourse is pre-configured with a whole range of SEO features to make your life easier
            and get good search ranking with minimal effort. Although we take care of many of the
            technical details, there is absolutely no substitute for writing good copy. That is, if
            you don't spend the time to write words which will get you ranking, then you are doomed
            from the outset. But if you write course descriptions and tag descriptions which are
            both engaging to potential students and use the correct search terms that people will
            search for, you are well on your way to a successful website.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Tag Manager</title>
        <para>Every site we build is created with Google Tag Manager integrated. This service drives
            the injection of javascript and tracking pixels or html into your site in really neat
            ways. In particular it allows:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Adding livechat systems to your site</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Facebook, Google and other tracking code</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A/B testing (show some elements to some people and not others)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Different content for different country regions</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Inject advertising panels</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Javascript is asynchronously loaded (so it doesn't slow the page
                        draw)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Versioned changes (so you can roll back easily)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Event tracking (such as add to shopping basket)</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>When we build your site, we'll give you access to Google Tag Manager, set up some
            initial Analytics tags for you, and get you started. You can then build more tracking or
            hand over access to your SEO consultants.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Google analytics</title>
        <para>Although the Google Analytics javascript is driven from Tag Manager, onCourse also
            injects some additional data into your analytics.<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Transactional sales dollars. Every sale through the website puts the
                        dollar value into your Analytics. So not only can you see how many page
                        views you got from that ad campaign, you can see the dollar value of the
                        sales that generated. You'll discover that the two aren't always
                        correlated.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Course and products. Drill down in your data to see where sales are coming
                        from. Getting lots of language course sales from an ad you placed on a
                        friendly site? Great, now you know what works and where to focus your time
                        and money.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Events. Because we log "add to shopping basket" and other events, you'll
                        be able to see who is engaging with your site but not following through to
                        the end.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Checkout steps. Coming very soon you'll be able to see each step in the
                        checkout process through a Google Analytics acquisition funnel. See where
                        and why people are dropping off.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Sitemap</title>
        <para>We generate a /sitemap.xml file automatically which you can add to Google's webmaster
            tools. This allows Google to quickly find all the pages on your site without crawling
            through them one at a time, and it also gives Google hints about when those pages are
            updates so that they are crawled more quickly.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>HTML markup</title>
        <para>The html markup of your site is customisable throughout, but by default you get some
            robust templates that Google will love.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Semantic HTML</title>
            <para>By building the html of your onCourse site with a clear structure and meaning,
                search engines such as Google are able to make sense of the structure and meaning.
                onCourse comes with good html that gives you a good starting point. For example,
                each page should only have a single h1 element, sections, footer and other modern
                html elements.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accessibility</title>
            <para>Although this is not strictly an SEO benefit, adhering to <link
                    xlink:href="https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/">accessibility standards</link> means
                that students with disabilities such as poor sight will be able to access your
                website more easily. This goes hand in hand with good semantic HTML and also means
                that Google and other search engines will properly index your site and understand
                the content structure rather than just index a mass of words.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Schema.org</title>
            <para>Schema.org is a set of markup rules endorsed by Google and other search engines.
                It specifies ways to annotate the html to give it specific meaning allowing Google
                to create rich search results. For example, we can markup data so that Google can
                provide navigation structure, course dates, prices and other information right in
                their search results.<inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/schema-results.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Navigation</title>
        <para>The navigation and structure of the site's page are important to good search
            results.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Canonical links</title>
            <para>Some pages in your onCourse site don't last very long. In particular, the class
                pages with a URL like <code>/class/ABC-123</code> will be irrelevant as soon as that
                class is finished. You don't want to accumulate page rank on these pages, only for
                that to evaporate. onCourse automatically adds a canonical link to the correct
                course page, transferring any page rank and inbound links to somewhere it will do
                good.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>URLs</title>
            <para>onCourse has clean URLs which are easy for users and contribute to your SEO. All
                course detail and list pages contain the word "course" and you are free to create
                long course codes which contain useful SEO keywords. And your tag structure can be
                structured however you want.. For example, a URL like
                "/courses/business/communication" picks up several important keywords.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Redirects</title>
            <para>If you ever change URLs it is vital that you don't lose page rank on those old
                pages. While you don't need to worry about classes, tags and course pages can
                accumulate valuable scores and you should implement redirects to the closest new
                page.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Meta headers</title>
        <para>onCourse does not implement meta-keyword headers since it is well documented that no
            search engines use them for indexing. However we do implement:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>og:image</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>og:type</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>og:description (meta-description)</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>These tags are useful for both Facebook, Bing and Google, helping you display better
            search results from data discovered by each of their crawl engines.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>SSL/TLS encryption</title>
        <para>Google has indicated that sites with end-to-end encryption will get higher search
            rankings since they are more likely to be ligitimate sites which care about the privacy
            of their users. All onCourse sites redirect immediately to HTTPS for even the
            non-payment gateway parts of the site.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Page speed</title>
        <para>A lot of effort goes into making onCourse really fast, even when displaying faceted
            search results from thousands of courses. We use separate SSL/TLS load balancers to
            remove encryption load from the application servers, we cache database requests and page
            rendering, and use Apache Solr as a high speed search cache. We also offload large image
            serving to a third party AWS S3 storage, again increasing the speed with which your site
            displays.</para>
        <para>The end result of all this is that search engines give your site bonus points for
            being fast. Which is good.</para>
    </section>

</chapter>