<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="static">
	<title>Static files</title>
	<section xml:id="css">
		<title>Stylesheets</title>
		<para>One of the first ways you'll want to modify the look of your site is by changing css stylesheets. onCourse stylesheets are a little
			different from what you might be used to, so you will want to read this before diving straight in. Inside the '<emphasis role="bold"
				>/s/stylesheets</emphasis>' folder on the ftp server are two further folders: 'css' and 'src'. It is important that you do not edit
			the files in 'css' directly, but instead edit the files in src:</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting>/s/stylesheets/src/</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>You will see that the file site.scss contains the following by default:<programlisting>@import "base";</programlisting></para>
		<para>Add any stylesheet modifications you want to below this line, but don't remove the import of the base stylesheets. That import
			brings in the basic stylesheet definitions which are required for your onCourse site: shortlists, course and class listings, enrolment
			templates and much more.</para>
		<section xml:id="scss">
			<title>SCSS</title>
			<para>onCourse uses a variation of CSS called SCSS. This extends the basic stylesheet concepts and adds some very useful abilities:<simplelist>
					<member>
						<link xlink:href="http://sass-lang.com/#nesting">nested rules</link></member>
					<member>
						<link xlink:href="http://sass-lang.com/#variables">variables</link></member>
					<member>
						<link xlink:href="http://sass-lang.com/#mixins">mixins</link></member>
					<member>
						<link xlink:href="http://sass-lang.com/#extend">selector inheritance</link></member>
				</simplelist></para>
			<para>Every time you edit any file in /s/stylesheets/src/, the destination /s/stylesheets/css/site.css is automatically regenerated. This
				usually takes only a couple of seconds, so you can see the results almost immediately. This is why you should not edit the site.css
				file directly, as any changes you make will be overwritten.</para>
			<para>If you don't want to bother with learning SCSS that's fine. Just write ordinary CSS in the site.scss file. As your stylesheets
				become more complex, you will find that SCSS gives you valuable shortcuts to achieving what you want.</para>
			<para>If you would like to break up your stylesheets into more manageable pieces, add another import statement under the 'base' import
				like this:<programlisting>@import "base";
@import "colours";</programlisting></para>
			<para>Then create a file /s/stylesheets/src/_colours.scss (with the underscore). When you make changes to that file, onCourse will
				automatically merge any content from _colours.scss into the main css for your site. Comments will be stripped out, so don't hesitate
				to put lots of useful notes in your scss files. The output will be merged and compressed (minified) before serving out as part of
				the page load. This process can make a big improvement to page load speeds.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Compass</title>
			<para>By default your stylesheets include Compass. This css library gives you lots of free functionality that you'd otherwise have to
				write by hand. <link xlink:href="http://compass-style.org/reference/compass/">Read up on this library</link> and get instant rounded
				corners across all browsers, typography features, reset, and much much more. As just one simple example
				<programlisting>ul.pretty   +pretty-bullets("my-icon.png")</programlisting></para>
			<para>will give you a fancy bulleted list with icons of your choosing. Or <programlisting>@include border-radius( 25px );</programlisting></para>
			<para>gives you rounded corners in all browsers without having to remember to put Opera, webkit, Mozilla and html5 elements into your
				css.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Compression</title>
			<para>No matter how many separate files you break up your stylestyles into, or how many comments you insert to document your work, the
				output will be compressed into one file and minified. This means whitespace is stripped and the file is pretty hard to read. However
				browsers will be able to parse it just fine.</para>
			<para>Finally we compress the file with gzip to serve it across the internet as fast as possible.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Responsive design</title>
			<para>It is extremely important in a modern world filled with tablets and smart phones that your
				site is built to make life easy for those users. onCourse sites already are prepared
				with responsive designs at four sizes. That means that as the browser window gets
				smaller with different sized devices, the design itself alters to work better at
				that size. It is still up to you as a designer to properly take advantage of this
				responsive design, but the groundwork is already there for you in onCourse and the
				enrolment pages as well as skillsOnCourse are optimised already.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section xml:id="js">
		<title>Javascript</title>
		<para>Upload your javascript files into <programlisting>/s/js/</programlisting></para>
		<para>Just like with css, javascript is merged and (optionally) minified to accelerate page loading. Start with site.js and notice these
			lines at the top</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting>//= minify off
//= require base.js
//= require extra.js</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>This is telling you that minification is disabled and that the javascript files base.js and extra.js are automatically merged into
			the output. This isn't quite the same as scss. The output file is called all.js and the files which are merged don't need to start
			with an underscore.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Minification</title>
			<para>Unlike CSS, the javascript is not automatically minified. This is because sometimes javascript minification can actually break
				your javascript (particularly if it contains errors). Browsers will often manage to figure out your broken javascript, but once
				minified errors really cause problems.</para>
			<para>You can enable minification by changing the "off" to "on" and saving the file. Wait about 30 seconds (it takes a while to run
				the code) and then review your site in staging before pushing it to live.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Base</title>
			<para>Base.js is included from a hidden place you cannot see. It pulls in some javascript essential for the functioning of onCourse,
				shopping cart, enrolments, searching and much more. It also pulls in some libraries you probably know of:</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery-ui</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.cookie</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.nyroModal</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.tooltip</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.cycle</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.utils</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.validate</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>jquery.juitter</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Video</title>
		<para>Although it is possible to load video files directly into the static folder, the onCourse servers are not optimised for serving
			video. You will get much better results by hosting your video at a site such as YouTube or Vimeo and linking to them from within your
			pages. Not only do they have servers placed in data centres around the world, but also the allow streaming of video. That is, the
			video can start playing even before all of the file has downloaded.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
