<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="advanced">
	<title>onCourse CMS - Advanced</title>
	<section>
		<title>Advanced techniques with onCourse</title>
		<para>Other than directly editing the content of pages within your site, there are a number of
			other parts of your site you might like to edit. These things can be accessed from the
			toolbar: Site Settings, Blocks, Pages, Menus and Themes.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="siteSettings">
			<title>Site settings</title>
			<section>
				<title>Introduction</title>
				<para>The onCourse website CMS allows users to manage a number of different aspects of how their website and portal displays information. </para>
				<para>This includes determining which fields are display within online forms, what
					information can be viewed through the Skills onCourse portal and it allows the addition
					of social media links. These options can be accessed by clicking on the Site Settings
					tab within the CMS. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/cms_settings_home_page.png" width="80%" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>CMS Site Settings menu options and link to onCourse CMS User Handbook</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Contact entry</title>
				<para>This page enables users to determine whether fields within the Enrolment and Mailing list online forms are shown or hidden, as well as the ability to set a given field as mandatory. You can also set whether or not the AVETMISS questions should display at the bottom of
					the Enrolment Form. </para>
				<para>Please note that the fields for First Name, Last Name and Email address are the
					minimum required fields that can be displayed and therefore these fields cannot be
					edited. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/enrolment_questions_cms.png" width="70%" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Manage the display of fields within the enrolment and mailing list forms</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<section>
					<title>Setting Enrolment Minimum Age</title>
					<para>If a particular Class has a minimum age requirement, you can now set this via the Site
					Settings / Contact Entry view of the CMS. Simply add the minimum age as a year
					to the CMS field, as well as setting the Date of Birth field as 'required'. The
					enrolling student will then need to supply a valid date of birth and if that
					date is less than the minimum enrolment age, the system will display a
					validation error message to the student within the online form. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/minimum_age_validation.png" width="60%"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Validation message if student is younger than minimum age</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Gathering Missing Contact Details for Existing Students</title>
					<para>You could have a scenario whereby you have an existing student who enrols in a given
					Class via the website, but you do not have a mobile telephone number for them
					recorded within onCourse database. </para>
					<para>By setting the mobile phone field to a status of 'Required' within the Contact Entry view
					of your CMS Site Settings, this will then allow you to gather this information
					from the existing student within the online enrolment process. This works on the
					basis that if the field is set to required, and the existing contact does not
					have any information against the field, then the student is asked to supply a
					mobile phone number as part of their online enrolment process. </para>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Skills onCourse</title>
				<para>The CMS settings page allows Colleges to manage the amount of information that is able to be viewed by Tutors on the Skills onCourse portal. It is also possible to specify as to which email address tutor feedback is sent to within the College.  </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/cms_skillsonCourse_setting_page.png" width="100%" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Manage the information  that tutors can access via the tutor portal</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>When viewing the class roll via the Skills onCourse, Colleges can determine whether
					they want their tutors to be able to view the email address, phone numbers of each
					student on the class roll. Please note that it is not possible to not display the
					contact details for one class, but display it for another, as this setting is
					universally applied. </para>
				<para>See the following screen from the Skills onCourse portal which shows where the student contact details display within the class roll. By specifying that you do not want the contact details to be displayed, this class list would simply show as a list of student names. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/cms_set_portal_info_display.png" width="60%" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Manage the display of student email and telephone contacts within the class roll on Skills onCourse</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Website</title>
				<para>The onCourse CMS now gives you access to a powerful social media linking tool called
					'Add This'. This free application will enable a college to insert social media links
					into courses and web pages, as well as giving you access to analytical tools to gain
					insight into your audience. </para>
				<para>In order to add these social media links, you need to set up a free account with 'Add
					This',  including specifying which social media links you wish to display on your
					website, the size and format of those links, as well as the free analytics tools that
					are part of your account set up. </para>
				<para>Once you have set up the 'Add This' account by following the link within the CMS, all
					you need to do to insert the id into the field provided and then specify as to whether
					you wish these links to appear on your course description and or web page. </para>
				<para>Once you set up your AddThis account you will be given a snippet of html to
					put into your site. It might look something like this:</para>
				<para><programlisting language="html">&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
&lt;div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style ">
&lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_1">&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_2">&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_3">&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_4">&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="addthis_button_compact">&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="addthis_counter addthis_bubble_style">&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#pubid=ra-4f0fc25723d304e0">&lt;/script>
&lt;!-- AddThis Button END--></programlisting></para>
				<para>Take the code following "pubid" in the last line and insert it into the field within the CMS site settings page. In this case enter "ra-4f0fc25723d304e0"</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/cms_website_settings_page.png" width="100%" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Set up and manage the addition of social media links to your website</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>If you insert the social media links to your course information, it displays as
					follows. The list of available links does include the ability to email a friend. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/adding_social_media_links.png" width="80%" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Example of how you can add social media links to any courses on your website</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Payment Options</title>
				<para>There are two payment options available via this menu in your CMS site settings:</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you want to redirect your clients to a specific web page once the online enrolment
						process has been completed. You can do this simply by entering the URL you
						wish to redirect your students to. Please note that this URL is universally
						applied for all online enrolments. </para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/cms_payment_settings_page.png" width="80%" />
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Specify page that students will be directed to after completing online enrolment</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
<listitem>
	<para>Within the online enrolment and payment confirmation pages of your website, you can link to a
						specified page which outlines the Terms and Conditions of Enrolment. Note
						that this link opens in a new tab on your web browser so the client is able
						to safely navigate back to the payment page to confirm their purchase. </para>
<mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
		<imagedata fileref="images/terms_and_conditions_link.png" width="70%" />
	</imageobject>
	<caption>
		<para>Link through to college terms and conditions of enrolment</para>
	</caption>
</mediaobject>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
				<tip>
					<para>When entering the URL for the post enrolment redirect and or the terms and conditions
					within your CMS payment settings, you do not need to add a '/' symbol to the URL
					that is entered. For example if the full URL is
					http://www.yourcollege.edu.au/terms, you would simply enter 'terms' into the
					relevant field of the CMS. </para>
				</tip>
				
				
				
			</section>
		
	</section>
	<section xml:id="blocks">
		<title>Blocks</title>
		<para>Blocks are the cornerstone to your website's variety and page dynamics. For example if you
			wanted an element (a banner for example) on every page of your web site, then blocks are your
			answer. If you wanted an area on several different pages dedicated to a contact form, blocks
			are ideal. Blocks are re-usable snippets of text, pictures, rich text markup, javascript,
			etc.</para>
		<para>The block listing page allows you to easily add and edit blocks. Give them a name which
			means something to you as users of the website will never see the name. However just creating
			a block will not achieve anything of itself. You need to place that block onto your site in
			one of two ways:<simplelist>
				<member>within a <emphasis role="bold">Theme</emphasis>. See <xref xlink:href="#themes"
					 /></member>
				<member>using <emphasis role="bold">rich text markup</emphasis>. See <xref
						xlink:href="#richText" /></member>
			</simplelist></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/blocks.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Adding a Block through the Theme Editor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="pages">
		<title>Pages</title>
		<para>This list of all the pages in your site gives you quick access to find the page you need,
			then edit or delete that page. The search box to the top right gives you quick access to find
			pages by name.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="menus">
		<title>Menus</title>
		<para><mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" align="right" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/dragDrop_menu.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Drag and Drop Menu hierarchy </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>Most websites will have a primary navigation menu which users will use to find
			their way around. In this place you can add new menu items, and link them to particular pages
			or external URLs. The user interface here is very simple: click on the menu name to edit it.
			The name is visible to users of your website. Drag the menu items into a different order or
			nest them within other menu items. And click to edit the URL (that is, the page to which the
			menu links).</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="themes">
		<title>Themes</title>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/themeEditor2.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Themes - adding variety</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>Themes are a way to describe a page structure made up by a number of blocks and
			by a design layout created for you by your designer. There will always be a layout called
			"default" available and many sites will need no more than just that one layout. If you want
			different parts of your site to have very different looks, ask your designer to create
			alternative layouts for you to use.</para>
		<para>Each theme can have a number of blocks arranged in any way you choose. There are five
			regions available:<simplelist>
				<member>header</member>
				<member>left</member>
				<member>content</member>
				<member>right</member>
				<member>footer</member>
			</simplelist></para>
		<para>Each region can contain one or more blocks which you drag from the right area. To remove a
			block just drag it back into the list of unused blocks on the right. You can order the blocks
			on the page by dragging them into the position of your choice. Remember, that when the page is
			shown the content area will also contain any content for the page itself. The blocks are shown
			above the page content, although your web designer can change that if they choose.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
