<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="configurations">
    <title>Configurations</title>
    <para>There are several areas that you can edit to change how the enrolment process works. </para>
    <section>
        <title>Mandatory/Optional</title>
        <para>You have the ability to choose whether an enrolment question is made mandatory,
            optional or hidden within the CMS by going Site Setting -> Contact Entry. The first
            three questions 'First name', 'Last name' and 'Email' are set to Required as default and
            can't be changed. The other questions will have a drop down next to them so you can
            choose whether that question is made mandatory, optional or hiddens for the enrolment
            process, waiting list and mailing list. The three options in the drop down list are
            'Show', 'Hide' and 'Required'.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/enrolment_questions_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Choosing whether you want a question to be mandatory, optional or hidden
                    during the online enrolment process</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Custom Fields</title>
        <para>Any custom fields created within the contact record of onCourse will be added to the
            list of questions that can be added to the online enrolment process, waiting list and
            mailing list. You will also be able to choose whether these questions are made
            mandatory, optional or hidden. They are set to 'Hide' as default.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/custom_fields_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where the Custom fields created in onCourse will appear within the CMS</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Minimum Age</title>
        <para>There is an option to also only allow online enrolments above a certain age. It's set
            to 0 as default and can be changed at the bottom of the Contact Entry page within the
            CMS.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/minimum_age_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>The field where you can choose if there is a minimum age to enrol
                    online</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>.......</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/collecting_parent_or_guardian_details_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>The field that allows you to choose whether a student requires to provide a
                    parent or guardians contact details if they below a certain age</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Post Enrolment Questions</title>
        <para>....</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/post_enrolment_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where you can choose what page you want a student to be directed to at the end
                    of the online enrolment process</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
