<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="configurations">
    <title>CMS Site Settings &amp; Configurations</title>
    <para>There are several areas that you can edit to change how the enrolment process works. </para>
    <section>
        <title>Contact Entry - Mandatory/Optional fields</title>
        <para>You have the ability to choose whether an enrolment question is made mandatory,
            optional or hidden within the CMS by going to Site Setting -> Contact Entry. The first
            three questions 'First name', 'Last name' and 'Email' are set to Required as default and
            can't be changed. </para>
        <para>The other questions will have a drop down next to them so you can choose whether that
            question is made mandatory, optional or hidden for the enrolment process, waiting list
            and mailing list. The three options in the drop down list are 'Show', 'Hide' and
            'Required'.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                    fileref="images/enrolment_questions_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Choosing whether you want a question to be mandatory, optional or hidden
                    during the online enrolment process</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    <section>
        <title>Custom Fields</title>
        <para>Any custom fields created within the contact record of onCourse will be added to the
            list of questions that can be added to the online enrolment process, waiting list and
            mailing list. You will also be able to choose whether these questions are made
            mandatory, optional or hidden. They are set to 'Hide' as default.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/custom_fields_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where the custom fields created in onCourse will appear within the CMS</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Minimum Age</title>
        <para>There is also an option to only allow students enrolling online to be above a certain
            age. The age is set to 0 as default and can be changed at the bottom of the Contact
            Entry page within the CMS. Any age set in this field will only apply to classes where
            you have not specified a maximum or minimum age. For example, your global (CMS)
            preference may be 18, however you may also have some children's classes where you have
            set an age range of 5 to 12 years..</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/minimum_age_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>The field where you can choose if there is a minimum age to enrol
                    online</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>You also have an option to choose whether the student needs to provide additional
            details of their parent or guardian if they are below a certain age. The check box
            determines if the feature to be used at all, and the age field to specify when this
            feature will be activated.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/collecting_parent_or_guardian_details_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>This feature allows you to choose whether a student requires them to provide a
                    parent or guardians contact details if they below a certain age</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    </section>
        <section>
    <title>
        skillsOnCourse Settings
    </title>
    <para> On this tab you can select some configuration settings for your skillsOnCourse student,
            tutor and company portals. This allows colleges to manage the amount of information that
            is able to be viewed by Tutors on the skillsOnCourse portal. It is also possible to
            specify as to which email address tutor feedback is sent to within the College. </para>
            <para>When viewing the class roll via the skillsOnCourse, Colleges can determine whether
            they want their tutors to be able to view the email address, phone numbers of each
            student on the class roll. Please note that it is not possible to not display the
            contact details for one class, but display it for another, as this setting is
            universally applied. </para>
            <para>See the following screen from the skillsOnCourse portal which shows where the
            student contact details display within the class roll. By specifying that you do not
            want the contact details to be displayed, this class list would simply show as a list of
            student names. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/cms_set_portal_info_display.png" width="50%" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Manage the display of student email and telephone contacts within the
                    class roll on skillsOnCourse</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </section>
    <section>
        <title>
            Website Settings
        </title>
        <para>The onCourse CMS now gives you access to a powerful social media linking tool called
            'Add This'. This free application will enable a college to insert social media links
            into courses and web pages, as well as giving you access to analytical tools to gain
            insight into your audience. </para>
        <para>In order to add these social media links, you need to set up a free account with 'Add
            This',  including specifying which social media links you wish to display on your
            website, the size and format of those links, as well as the free analytics tools that
            are part of your account set up. </para>
        <para>Once you have set up the 'Add This' account by following the link within the CMS, all
            you need to do to insert the id into the field provided and then specify as to whether
            you wish these links to appear on your course description and or web page. </para>
        <para>This is also the area where you will find the 'Publish' button to publish changed you
            made to your live website.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/cms_website_settings_page.png" width="80%" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Set up and manage the addition of social media links to your website</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
        <section>
        <title>Payment &amp; Post Enrolment Questions</title>
        <para>In the website tab, you have the option of setting up a page where the student gets
            re-directed to after they have finished with the online enrolment process.</para>
        <para>Some users choose to create a page with additional form questions at this point,
            others may redirect to another internal page showing some marketing copy for deals to
            share with friends and colleagues.</para>
        <para>To set which page you want them to be directed to, within the CMS, click on Site
            Settings -> Payment and make sure the checkbox is selected and the URL is entered in the
            field next to the text 'After payment successful redirect user to URL'</para>
        <para>You also need to specify the page in the CMS which contains your enrolment/refund
            policy. This is the page students must click to agree they accept your conditions during
            the online enrolment process.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/post_enrolment_cms.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where you can choose what page you want a student to be directed to at the end
                    of the online enrolment process</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
