<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="editor">
    <title>onCourse CMS - Editor </title>
    
    <section xml:id="editorIntroduction"><title>Introduction</title>
            <para>The onCourse Editor is your platform to create, manage and distribute information
            to your website. Editor is a Content Management System (CMS) that provides simple but
            powerful tools to manage the structure and content of your website in a collaborative
            environment. </para>
        
        <section xml:id="editorAccess"> <title> Access to the Editor </title>
            <para>Before you start editing content within the Editor you need to set up a user name
                and password to log in. </para>
            <para>onCourse enables any user to also have the ability to log into and edit content
                within the Editor using the same log in credentials that you use to access onCourse
                . To do this go to File > Preferences > Security and open the relevant user record,
                then tick the box 'Can access #editor'.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorCanEditOC.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Enabling Editor Access within onCourse User Profile</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorLoggingIn"><title>Logging In</title>
            <para>Access the editor by visiting your website and adding <code>#editor</code>
                at the end of the url. For example, if your website url is
                <code>http://www.acme.com.au</code> the editor can be accessed at
                <code>http://www.acme.com.au#editor</code>. </para>
            <para>Log in using your email address.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_login.png" format="png"/>        
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorView"><title>The Editor View</title>
            <para>Once logged in, a toolbar is visible to the left hand side of the window. You can
                continue to browse through your site as normal while logged into the Editor. </para>
            <para>On the toolbar, you can see icons that allows you to quickly access the primary
                areas of the Editor. At the bottom of the toolbar, there is an option to publish any
                changes you've made. This will push all your changes to the production servers so
                they are visible to everyone.</para>
            <para>While you are logged into the editor you are looking at a draft version of the
                site which cannot be seen by anyone not also logged into the editor. Changes you
                make with webDAV (static files, images, javascript, css, etc) are also only visible
                while logged in to the editor, until you publish the site.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_SideBar.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Finding your way around the Editor view</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            
            <para>Navigate through the Editor by using the icons on the toolbar. These icons allows
                you to access different areas of the Editor quickly. </para>
            <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Site </term>
                    <listitem>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorIconSite.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                        <para>Returns you to viewing your website. All changes made in the Editor
                            (and not published) will be visible until you log out.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Content </term>
                    <listitem>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorIconContent.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                        <para>Allows you to edit the Blocks, Pages and Menus that appear on your site</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Settings </term>
                    <listitem>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorIconSettings.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                        <para>Allows you to manage how your website and portal display information. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Design </term>
                    <listitem>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorIconDesign.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                        <para>Allows for the themes of the website to be edited</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorContent"><title>Editing Content</title>
    
    <para>Click the Content icon to see the editor for Blocks, Pages and Themes. These three
            components make up the structure of the website. </para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_content.png"/>
        </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    
        
        <section xml:id="editorBlocks">
            <title> Blocks </title>
            <para>Blocks are re-usable snippets of text, pictures, rich text markup, etc. If you
                wanted to add a banner on every page of your web site or an area on several
                different pages dedicated to a contact form, blocks are ideal. Even if you only use
                them once, they are a convenient way to break apart complicated pages into easy to
                edit pieces.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_blocks.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para> The Blocks page allows you to easily add, search and edit blocks. </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <section>
                <title>Editing a block</title>
                <para>Selecting a block takes you to the Editor page for that specific block. Here,
                    you can change the name of the block and edit the contents. On the right hand
                    side of the screen you see a preview of what the block will look like on your
                    website.</para>
                <para>Click on the block contents to open the block in a text editor view. Enter
                    your rich text or html to be added to the block and click save. This closes the
                    text editor and renders your changes for you to review. </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_BlocksHTML.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
                <para> You can navigate back to the Blocks page by clicking the title of the block
                    in the top right hand corner.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorBlocksBack.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Creating a new block</title>
                <para>You can create a new Block from the Block view by clicking on 'ADD NEW'. You
                    will have to give your new block a name in the 'Title' field, as well as some
                    rich text or HTML in the content field do the right. Remember that renaming a
                    block might break places you have embedded that block using rich text.</para>
                <para>Once you are happy with your new block, save it by hitting the blue 'SAVE'
                    button. If you wish to discard the your new block, hit the red 'REMOVE'
                    button.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editorNewBlock.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
                
            </section>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorPages">
            <title>Pages </title>
            <para>Many pages on your website are automatically generated from onCourse. These pages include:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/courses</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/courses/arts/photography</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/course/ABC</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/sites</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/tutor/123</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/site/234</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/checkout</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Pages not automatically generated from onCourse can be created in the Editor. The
                Pages view shows a list of all the static pages in your website and gives you quick
                access to search for, edit and delete pages. Similar to the Block view, clicking on
                a Page will open text editor.</para>
            <section>
                <title>Editing existing pages</title>
                <para> From the Content menu, select Pages to get a list of all static pages on your site. </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_pages.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
                
                <para>When a specific page is selected, the editor allows you to change the theme
                    that is applied to this page, the page name, as well as editing the content. You
                    can also select whether any given page is 'visible'. The page title will be
                    visible in the window title of the user's browser. Every page will be given an
                    automatic URL like /page/5 however you may wish to give it an easier to use URLs
                    like /terms or /about/contact-us. You can even give a page multiple URLs which
                    will all work to display the same page to the user. Only one of the pages will
                    be 'canonical' and the others will redirect to it.</para>
                    <para> You can also select to have a page omittied from the site map. Hiding a page from the sitemap will make it
                    invisible to web crawlers and search engines.                    
                    </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_pagesEdit.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Create new pages</title>
                <para>Click the 'ADD NEW' button to create a new blank page. Here you can edit the
                    pages Title, the pages URL as well as the theme that is applied to this page.
                    You can also toggle if the new page is visible. Clicking the 'Sample content'
                    will open the page in the text editor to be edited.</para>
                <para>Once you have finished creating your new page, you will have to save it by
                    hitting the blue 'SAVE' button or discard your changes by the red 'REMOVE'
                    button.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_newPage.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorMenus">
            <title> Menus </title>
            <para>From the Content view, the primary header navigation can be edited from
                'Menus'.</para>
            <para>Most websites have a primary navigation menu which users will use to find their
                way around. In Menu's you can add new menu items, and link them to particular pages
                or external URLs.</para>
            <section><title>Edit an existing menu item</title><para>Click on a menu name to edit it.
                    The menu name is as shown on your website. </para><para>Click, hold and drag the
                    menu items into a different order or nest them within other menu
                    items.</para><para>Click to edit the URL, that is, the page to which the menu
                    links. Ensure this matches the page name exactly. If it doens't, it won't work
                    as you expect. </para><para>Menus exist in a heirarchy. Clicking, holding and
                    drag a menu item to reorder the menu. Clicking and dragging a menu item on top
                    of, and to the right of another will nest the menu item and make it a submenu
                    item. </para>

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_menus.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject></section>
            <section>
                <title>Add a new menu item</title>
                <para>Clicking 'ADD NEW ITEM' will create a new menu item with no URL. 
                    This menu item will appear as the top menu level and will not link to any page.</para>
                <para>A menu item can be deleted by clicking the red 'REMOVE' button to the right of each menu item.</para>
                <para>Once you are happy with your changes, you can save them by clicking the blue 'SAVE' button.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorSettings"><title>Settings</title>
        <para>The editor allows you to manage a number of different aspects of how the website and
            portal display information. This includes determining  what information can be viewed
            through the SkillsonCourse portal, general website settings, any checkout settings or
            preferences and the site's 301 redirects. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settings.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
             
        <section xml:id="editorSkillsOnCourse">
            <title>SkillsOnCourse</title>
            <para>The SkillsonCourse Settings page allows you to manage the amount of information
                that is able to Tutors in the SkillsonCourse portal. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsSkillsOnCourse.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Hide student contact details from tutor</emphasis>: When a
                tutor is viewing the class roll via the SkillsonCourse, you can determine whether
                you want them to be able to view the email address, phone numbers of each student
                listed on the class roll. Please note that it is not possible to not display the
                contact details for one class, but display it for another, as this setting is
                universally applied. </para>
            <para>The below SkillsonCourse portal view shows the student contact details displayed
                within the class roll. By specifying that you do not want the contact details to be
                displayed, this class list would simply show as a list of student names. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/cms_set_portal_info_display.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorWebsite"><title>Website Settings</title>
            <para>The website settings page gives a few different options on how things are
                displayed on the website. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsWebsite.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Add This</emphasis> is a powerful social media linking tool
                that enables you to insert social media links into your web pages, as well as giving
                you access to analytical tools to gain insight into your audience. </para>
            <para>Add This accounts are free and the first step is to create a new account. Do this
                by clicking the 'Click here' link. Set up your account including specifying which
                social media links you wish to display on your website, the size and format of those
                links, as well as the free analytics tools that are part of your account set up. </para>
            <para>Once complete, insert the Add This id into the field provided. You can choose what
                pages the Add This! buttons appear on by ticking the 'Course' or 'Web Page' boxes
                below the Add This! field.</para>
            <para>Add This also gives you a snippet of HTML to put into your site. You can put this
                HTML snippet into a page or block manually.</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting language="html">&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
&lt;div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style ">
    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_1">&lt;/a>
    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_2">&lt;/a>
    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_3">&lt;/a>
    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_4">&lt;/a>
    &lt;a class="addthis_button_compact">&lt;/a>
    &lt;a class="addthis_counter addthis_bubble_style">&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#pubid=ra-4f0fc25723d304e0">&lt;/script>&lt;
!-- AddThis Button END-->
                </programlisting> 
            </para>
            <para>
                   If you insert the social media links to your course information, it displays as
                follows. 
            </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/adding_social_media_links.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Example of how you can add social media links to any courses on your
                        website</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Hide Classes on Website/Stop web enrolments</emphasis> Here you can set classes to hide or 
                stop taking enrolments automatically after some threshold is passed. For examples, after a class starts, before a class starts
            after a class ends or beforea class ends.</para>
            
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Show Suburbs from</emphasis> The 'Show suburbs from' dropdown
                allows you to filter out suburbs being returned in the  site search. For example,
                when entering the search query 'Newtown', with 'Show suburbs from' set to 'All
                states' the advanced search will return classes from: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>NEWTOWN, 2042</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>NEWTOWN, 3220</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>NEWTOWN, 3351</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>NEWTOWN, 4305</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>NEWTOWN, 4350</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist> Setting 'Show suburbs from' to NSW will just return: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>NEWTOWN, 2042</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>            
            
            <para> Once you have finished changing your website settings, hit 'SAVE' to apply them. </para>
            
        </section>
        <!--
        <section xml:id="editorCheckOut"><title>Checkout</title>
            <para>The checkout settings allow you to customise the checkout process.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">After payment successful redirect user to URL</emphasis>
                allows you to set where a student is directed after the enrolment process. Maybe you
                want to take them to the homepage or the enrolment terms and conditions - you can
                set this here.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Refund policy page</emphasis> allows you to set a custom
                page to outline any policies, procedures or terms and conditions a student must
                agree to. They will have to tick a checkbox stating that they agree on the final
                checkout page.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsCheckout.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        -->        
        
        <section xml:id="editorRedirect"><title>Redirects</title>
            <para>The redirect settings allow you to create 301 redirects to your website by
                entering the path in the field on the left (starting with '/') and the destination
                in the field on the right (either starting with '/' for another local page or
                starting with http/https for redirecting to another website)  </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsRedirect.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para/>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Editing an existing redirect</title>
            <para>You can edit an existing redirect by changing the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >From</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">To</emphasis> parameters. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a new redirect</title>
            <para>Clicking 'ADD NEW' creates a new redirect at the bottom of the redirects, with
                blank <emphasis role="bold">From</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">To</emphasis>
                parameters. </para>
        </section>
        <para>Once you have finished editing the list of redirects, click 'SAVE' to add the
            redirects to your site.</para>
   
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorDesign"><title>Design</title>
        <para>The Design menu lets you edit the Themes applied to your onCourse website. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_design.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <section xml:id="Theme"><title>Themes</title>
            <para>Themes are a way to describe a page structure made up by a number of blocks and is
                a design layout created for you by your designer. There will always be a layout
                called "default". If you want different parts of your site to have very different
                looks, ask your designer to create alternative layouts for you to use. </para>
            <para> Each theme can have a number of blocks arranged in any way you choose. There are
                five regions available: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>header</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>left</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>content</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>right</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>footer</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>Each region can contain one or more blocks which you click and drag
                from the right hand side 'Blocks' area. To remove a block, click and drag it
                back into the list of unused blocks on the right. Order the blocks on the page by
                clicking and dragging them into position.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_designEditThemes.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>  
    
    
    <section xml:id="editorHistory"><title>History</title>
        <para>The History menu displays the most recent reversions of your site, the date this reversion of the site was publish and who
            published each reversion.</para>
        
        <para> You can also see the current version of your site and have the option to publish recent changes from this page. </para>
        
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_History.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        
        <section xml:id="editorRevertingChanges"><title>Reverting Changes</title>
            <para>
                For each published revision of the site, there is an option to revert to that version. 
                Click 'Revert' to roll your site back to how it was on the given date.
                <emphasis role="bold">Note that this cannot be undone.</emphasis>
            </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_revertHistory.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    
    <section xml:id="editorPublish">
        <title>Publishing your changes</title>
        <para>Any changes you've made are only visible when logged into the Editor. Your site must
            be published before any changes appear on the live site. </para>
        <para>To publish your changes to your live site, click 'Publish' from the bottom of the
            toolbar. This prompts you to confirm that you want the changes published. Click
            'Confirm' to commit any changes you have made and make these changes visible on the live
            site.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_publish.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>    
