<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="editor">
    <title>onCourse CMS - Editor </title>
    
    <section xml:id="editorIntroduction"><title>Introduction</title>
            <para>The onCourse Editor is your platform to create, manage and distribute information
            to your website. Editor is a Content Managment System (CMS) that provides simple but
            powerful tools to manage the struture and content of your website in a collaborative
            environment. </para>
        
        <section xml:id="editorAccess"> <title> Setting up Access to the Editor </title>
            <para>Before you start editing content within the Editor you need to set up a user name
                and password to log in. </para>
            <para>onCourse enables any user to also have the ability to log into and edit content
                within the Editor using the same log in credentials that you use to access onCourse
                . To do this go to File > Preferences > Users and open the relevant record, then
                tick the box 'Can edit CMS'. ***is this screenshot correct? I feel like 'Reset
                password' now reads 'reset authentication'</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/edit_user_CMS_access.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Enabling Editor Access within onCourse User Profile</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorLoggingIn"><title>Logging In</title>
            <para>Access the editor by visiting your website and adding
                    <emphasis>'#editor'</emphasis> at the end of the url. For example, if your
                website url is <emphasis>'http://www.acme.com.au'</emphasis> the editor can be
                accessed at <emphasis>'xml http://www.acme.com.au#editor'</emphasis>. </para>
            <para>Log in using the same credentials that you use to access onCourse.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_login.png" format="png"></imagedata>        
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorView"><title>The Editor View</title>
            <para>Once logged in, a toolbar is visible to the left hand side of the window. You can
                continue to browse through your site as normal while logged into the Editor. </para>
            <para>On the toolbar, you can see icons that allows you to quickly access the primary
                areas of the Editor. At the bottom of the toolbar, there is an option to publish any
                changes you've made to the live site,and a log of all recent changes. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_SideBar.png"></imagedata>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Finding your way around the Editor view</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            
            <para>Navigate through the Edutor by using the icons on the toolbar. These icons allows
                you to access different ares of the Editor quickly. //TODO ***add icon</para>
            <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Site ***add icon</term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Returns you to viewing your website. All changes made in the Editor will be visible.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Content ***add icon</term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Allows you to edit the Blocks, Pages and Menus that appear on your site</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Settings ***add icon</term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Allows you to manage a number of different aspects of how your website and portal display information. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                
                <varlistentry>
                    <term>Design ***add icon</term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Allows for the themes of the website to be edited</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorContent"><title>Editing Content</title>

    <para>Click the Content icon ***add icon to see the editor for Blocks, Pages and Themes. These
            three components make up the strucutre of the website. </para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_content.png"></imagedata>
        </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    
        
        <section xml:id="editorBlocks">
            <title> Blocks </title>
            <para>Blocks are the cornerstone to your website's variety and page dynamics. Blocks are
                re-usable snippets of text, pictures, rich text markup, javascript, etc. If you
                wanted to add a banner on every page of your web siteor an area on several different
                pages dedicated to a contact form, blocks are ideal.  </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/editor_blocks.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para> The Blocks page allows you to easily add, search and edit blocks. </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <section>
                <title>Editing a block</title>
                <para>Selecting a block takes you to the Editor page for that specific block. Here,
                    you can change the name of the block and edit the contents. On the right hand
                    side of the screen you see a preview of what the block will look like on your
                    website ***can this screenshot include some content? </para>
                <para>Click on the block contents to open the block in a text editor view. Enter
                    your markup text or html to be added to the block and click save. This closes
                    the text editor and renders your changes for you to review. </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/editor_blocksEditHtml.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
                <para> ***How do I navigate back to the main view?</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Creating a new block</title>
                <para>***How do I create a new block? </para>
                <para>However just creating a block will not achieve anything of itself. You need to
                    place that block onto your site in one of two ways: //TODO </para>
            </section>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorPages">
            <title>Pages </title>
            <para>Many pages on your website are automatically generated from onCourse. These pages include:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/courses</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/courses/arts/photography</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/course/ABC</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/sites</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/tutor/123</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/site/234</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>/checkout</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Pages not automatically generated from onCourse are known as static pages. The
                Pages view shows a list of all the static pages in your website and gives you quick
                access to search for, edit and delete pages. Similar to the Block view, clicking on
                a Page will open that Page in a text editor view. ***please add a screenshot</para>
            <section>
                <title>Editing existing pages</title>
                <para>**How do I get here? </para>
                <para>When a specific page is selected, the editor allows you to chage the theme
                    that is applied to this page, the page name, as well as editing the content. You
                    can also elect whether any given page is 'avaiable' ***UI says 'visible' - also
                    add that checking and unchecking the box allows visibility or not. Pages that
                    are not marked as available (***visible?) can only be accessed with their direct
                    url link. Keep pages that you don't want users stumbling across, or that may be
                    under contruction, as 'invisible'. (***unchecked?)</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/editor_pagesEdit.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Create new pages</title>
                <para>You can also create 'static' pages. These allows you to add additional content
                    to add breadth and cohesion to your website. For example, you may like to add an
                    "about us" or "contact" page. </para>
                <para>***How do I get to this view? There is no details on what to do next? Do I
                    click "add new'? If so, what happens then? How do I save my changes? How do I
                    then make it live? </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/editor_pages.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
                <para>***How do I get back to the main view? </para>
            </section>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorMenus">
            <title> Menus </title>
            <para>***How do I get here? </para>
            <para>Most websites have a primary navigation menu which users will use to find their
                way around (***do any of our sites not have this?). In Menu's you can add new menu
                items, and link them to particular pages or external URL's.</para>
            <section>
                <title>Edit an existing menu item</title>
                <para>Click on a menu name to edit it. The menu name is as shown on your website. </para>
                <para>Drag the menu items into a different order or nest them within other menu
                    items ***Do I click, hold and drag? </para>
                <para>Click to edit the URL, that is, the page to which the menu links. Ensure this
                    matches the page name EXACTLY. If it doens't, it won't work as you expect. </para>
                <para>Menus exist in a heirarchy. Dropping a menu item onto another will make it
                    part of a submenu. ***How do I drop it?</para>
                <para>***How do I delete a menu item?</para>
                <para>*** Do I need to save my changes? How do I make them live?</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/editor_menus.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Add a new menu item</title>
                <para>***How do I add a new menu item?</para>
                <para>***How do I get back to the main page?</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorSettings"><title>Settings</title>
        <para>The editor allows you to manage a number of different aspects of how the website and
            portal display information. This includes determining the site redirects, what
            information can be viewed through the SkillsonCourse portal and any checkout settings.
            ***checkout except data collection? This list should also be arranged in the same order
            as the list appears in the UI</para>
        <para>***Update screenshot for skillsoncourse wording</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settings.png"></imagedata>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
             
        <section xml:id="editorSkillsOnCourse">
            <title>SkillsOnCourse</title>
            <para>The SkillsonCourse Settings page allows you to manage the amount of information
                that is able to Tutors in the SkillsonCourse portal. </para>
            <para>***Update screenshot for skillsoncourse wording</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/editor_settingsSkillsOnCourse.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Hide student contact details from tutor</emphasis>: When a
                tutor is viewing the class roll via the SkillsonCourse, you can determine whether
                you want them to be able to view the email address, phone numbers of each student
                listed on the class roll. ***Do I check or uncheck the checkbox to allow them to
                see/ not see? Please note that it is not possible to not display the contact details
                for one class, but display it for another, as this setting is universally applied. </para>
            <para>The below SkillsonCourse portal view shows the student contact details displayed
                within the class roll. By specifying that you do not want the contact details to be
                displayed, this class list would simply show as a list of student names. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/cms_set_portal_info_display.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Enable outcome marking in tutor portal </emphasis> ***what
                does this mean?</para>
            <para>***What do I do after this? Save? How do I get back to the main page?</para>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorWebsite"><title>Website Settings</title>
            <para>The website settings page gives a few different options on how things are
                displayed on the website. </para>
            <para>***Update screenshot for skillsoncourse wording - also why is there a checkbox for
                'Hide student contact details from tutor' here?</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsWebsite.png"></imagedata>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Add This</emphasis> is a powerful social media linking tool
                that enables you to insert social media links into course and web pages ***define
                course and web page, as well as giving you access to analytical tools to gain
                insight into your audience. </para>
            <para>Add This accounts are free and the first step is to create a new account. Do this
                by clicking the 'Click here' link. Set up your account including specifying which
                social media links you wish to display on your website, the size and format of those
                links, as well as the free analytics tools that are part of your account set up. </para>
            <para>Once complete, insert the Add This id into the field provided and then specify if
                you want these links to appear on your course description and or web page. ***I'm
                not sure what this means? What happens on each when I do this?</para>
            <para>Add This also gives you a snippet of html to put into your site ***where do I put
                this?. It might look something like this:</para>
            <para>
                <programlisting language="html">&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
                    &lt;div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style ">
                    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_1">&lt;/a>
                    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_2">&lt;/a>
                    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_3">&lt;/a>
                    &lt;a class="addthis_button_preferred_4">&lt;/a>
                    &lt;a class="addthis_button_compact">&lt;/a>
                    &lt;a class="addthis_counter addthis_bubble_style">&lt;/a>
                    &lt;/div>
                    &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#pubid=ra-4f0fc25723d304e0">&lt;/script>
                    &lt;!-- AddThis Button END-->
                </programlisting> 
            </para>
            <para>
                   If you insert the social media links to your course information, it displays as
                follows. 
            </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/adding_social_media_links.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Example of how you can add social media links to any courses on your
                        website</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>***<emphasis role="bold">Hide Classes on Website</emphasis> what does this
                do?</para>
            <para>***<emphasis role="bold">Stop Web enrolments</emphasis> what does this do?</para>
            <para>***Do I need to save these changes? How do I publish to make them live?</para>
            
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorCheckOut"><title>Checkout</title>
            <para>The checkout settings allow you to customise the checkout process. ***excluding
                data collection?</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">After payment successful redirect user to URL</emphasis>
                allows you to set where a student is directed after the enrolment process. Maybe you
                want to take them to the homepage or the emrolment terms and conditions - you can
                set this here.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Refund policy page</emphasis> allows you to set a custom
                page to outline any policies, procedures or terms and conditions a student must
                adhere to on enrolmnet.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsCheckout.png"></imagedata>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>***Do I need to save these? How do I get back to the main page?</para>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="editorRedirect"><title>Redirects</title>
            <para>The redirect settings allow you to create 301 redirects to your website by
                entering the path in the field on the left (starting with '/') and the destination
                in the field on the right (either starting with '/' for another local page or
                starting with http/https for redirecting to another website)  </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_settingsRedirect.png"></imagedata>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
            <para/>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Editing an existing redirect</title>
            <para>***How do I edit an existing one? </para>
            <para>Once you have done this click save. This adds to the list of redirects below
                ***below where?</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a new redirect</title>
            <para>***How do I add a new one? Whats the saving process?</para>
            <para>***How do I get back to the main page?</para>
        </section>
   
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorDesign"><title>Design</title>
        <para>The Design menu lets you edit the Themes applied to your onCourse website. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_design.png"></imagedata>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <section xml:id="Theme"><title>Themes</title>
            <para>Themes are a way to describe a page structure made up by a number of blocks and is
                a design layout created for you by your designer. There will always be a layout
                called "default". If you want different parts of your site to have very different
                looks, ask your designer to create alternative layouts for you to use. </para>
            <para> Each theme can have a number of blocks arranged in any way you choose. There are
                five regions available: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>header</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>left</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>content</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>right</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>footer</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>Each region can contain one or more blocks which you click and drag
                from the right area ***the right hand side?. To remove a block, click and drag it
                back into the list of unused blocks on the right. Order the blocks on the page by
                clicking and dragging them into position. Remember, when the page is shown the
                content area will also contain any content for the page itself ***What?. The blocks
                are shown above the page content, although your web designer can change that if they
                choose. </para>
            <para>***can you add a screenshot for the default theme showing the regaions and
                blocks?</para>
        </section>
    </section>  

    <section xml:id="editorChangeLogs"><title>Change Log</title>
        <para>View the change log by clicking 'Edits' from the toolbar. The change log displays the
            most recent versions of the site, the date this version of the site was publish and who
            published each version of the site. You can also see the current version of the site and
            have the option to publish your changes from this page. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_changeLog.png"></imagedata>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <section xml:id="editorRevertingChanges"><title>Reverting Changes</title>
            <para>For each published revision of the site, there is an option to revert to that
                version. Click 'Revert' to revert the site to how it was on the given date.
                    <emphasis role="bold">Note that this cannot be undone.</emphasis></para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/editor_revertChanges.png"></imagedata>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="editorPublish">
        <title>Publishing your changes</title>
        <para>Any changes you've made are only visbile when logged into the Editor. Your site must
            be publshed before any changes appear on the live site. </para>
        <para>To publish your changes to your live site, click 'Publish'  from the bottom of the
            toolbar. This prompts you to confirm that you want the changes published. Click
            'Confirm' to commit any changes you have made and make these changes visible on the live
            site. ***can you review this screenshot please? The first green box hasn't rendered
            properly and looks a bit odd. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/editor_publish.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>    
