<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="adding_content">
	<title>Creating an onCourse website</title>
	<section>
		<title>Your college online</title>
		<para>One of the key features of onCourse is the integrated website. This allows you to promote your courses on your website and provide
			seamless online enrolments, waiting lists, mailing lists, discounts, credit card payments, student and tutor portals and much
			more.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Updating your site</title>
		<para>Because ish onCourse has been written as one comprehensive system, updating your web site is completely painless. Every time you
			make a change to any relevant information those changes are automatically uploaded to your web site in the background. So, as courses
			are filled, the web site shows prospective students that places are limited.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/updating1.jpg"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para> Connectivity between your website and the onCourse client software</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>onCourse makes the uploading and downloading of information (the replication) foolproof so that you don't have to worry about it.
			Replication was designed by ish to work perfectly even after your internet connection has been offline for a while (say, because your
			ISP had an outage). It was designed to not require high performance internet links, so you can use very low cost ADSL. Because you
			aren't hosting the web site in your office, you don't need to invest in expensive, high performance, high reliability internet
			connections (such as SHDSL which are typically $400 / month and up). You don't need servers which provide 24×7 web access for
			students. You don't need backup power and generators to assure high reliability web site service. You don't need a 24 hour climate
			controlled server room in a secure facility which complies with the Mastercard/Visa PCI security regulations. ish already does all
			that for you.</para>
		<para>All you need are the computers you own today and a simple server (possibly shared on your existing server) to run ish onCourse.
			And a plain, simple low-cost internet link. We provide the rest.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>Key features</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>automatic uploads to web site every time you make a change</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>resilient to outages in your internet connection</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>does not require a high speed connection</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>automatic download of new enrolments and students from web site</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>since you aren't serving the web site from your office, you don't need to supply, support or service data-centre quality links
					and equipment</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>our data centre is constantly monitored and supported by experienced Unix system administrators. It has 24 hour airlock
					security, temperature control, diesel power backup, halon gas fire control and its own electricity sub-station.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>separate monitoring systems at ish check the availability of every web site every 15 minutes. Any outage is notified to our
					support staff by SMS.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Enabling courses for online display</title>
		<para>Courses need to be checkmarked “Enabled and visible online” in the General tab of each course, to display on your site. To get
			here in the onCourse client follow these steps:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Go to "Course"</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Double click on a class record</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the general tab, make sure the "Enabled and visible online" option is on under "status"</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Press save</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/visibleOnline.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting this option will display the course online</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>You must also tag your courses with Subject tags for them to display on your web site. You may choose to allow subject tags to be
			set more than once, or limit to one. If a course is tagged with more than one subject, it will appear in the menu for each tag you
			have assigned. Check the onCourse manual for more on tagging.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/WelcomePageSubjectTag.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para> Example of a welcome page and Subject tags at the bottom</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Course description</title>
			<para>The field ‘web description' is where you should enter all the information about the course description, what people should
				bring, pre-requisites, outcomes and anything else you can think of. As this is the course, this information needs to pertain to all
				the classes of this course. If you have class specific information you should put this in the class web description.</para>
			<para>The description fields are rich text fields, so you can use bullets, headings and numbered lists. See <xref xlink:href="#richText"/> for more on this. You can also include images and attachments in your pages.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Displaying Classes</title>
			<para>Once a course has been tagged and enabled for the web, classes in that course will be displayed if they have the “Enrolment
				allowed and visible online” option selected in their “General” tab. The classes themselves do not need to be tagged with anything
				from the Subjects tag group in order to appear on the website. You can also select a series of classes in the list view and select
				the cog wheel option "Show class on website" to web enable classes in bulk.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Class descriptions</title>
			<para>The information that you put in this field should be specific for just this instance of the class. Keep your general course
				information in the course itself.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Summary</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Here are some handy tips to help ensure that courses/classes appear on the main page of the website.</title>
				<listitem>
					<para>Courses have “Enabled and visible online” selected on the General tab</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Courses are tagged with at least one tag under Subjects in the tag group (if it has multiple tags, this course will appear
						under each tag)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Ensure "Enrolment allowed and visible online” is selected on the "General" tab of every class you want to appear on your
						website.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Other information</title>
		<para>Other information which makes its way automatically to your website includes tutors, rooms and sites. In particular, be sure to
			fill out the latitude and longitude of the sites since this will automatically give the website the ability to show a Google Maps
			driven location finder for students trying to find the venue.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Special Pages</title>
		<para>Some URLs in your site are reserved for special pages. These pages are delivered by the onCourse software itself. To customise
			them, consult the templates chapter for details of how these pages are created. These pages include:<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/courses</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A list of all courses which are marked as web visible.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/courses/arts</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A list of all courses tagged with the tag "arts" from the "subject" tag group.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/course/ABC</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The detail of the course with code ABC.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/class/ABC-123</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The detail of the class with code ABC-123</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/sites</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A list of all sites marked as web visible.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/site/12</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The detail of site with internal id 12.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/tutor/23</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The detail of the tutor with internal id 23.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/enrol</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>All pages under this path are reserved for the enrolment processing pages.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>/cms</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>All pages under this path are reserved for the cms.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist></para>
	</section>
	<section>
			<title>Advanced Search options</title>
		<para>onCourse includes a Solr search engine indexed to your website. This allows users to use the
			built in simple or advanced search tools on your webpages to find the courses they are
			looking for, or for you to craft URLs which include certain search results.</para>
		<para>You can also choose to include only courses tagged with a set tag group in your search
			engine index, which is commonly done when a college has multiple websites for different
			training departments. i.e. the workplace learning site only ever searches on and shows
			results tagged with professional development, while the community site indexes all
			courses.</para>
		<para>The usual sort order for course results in a list view page prioritises courses with classes
			starting next. When a search parameter is added into a page, the sort order is shifted
			to bring results with a greater relevancy to the top of the page, and then to sort by
			classes starting next. </para>
		<para>When adding a 'near=' search, it will automatically hide results outside of 100km radius the
			search suburbs' GPO. This can be useful if you deliver in a variety of physically
			seperated locations. For example, a website visitor who searches for courses in Sydney
			is unlikely to be interested in results in Melbourne, but may be interested in results
			in Chatswood. In this case the Melbourne class results would be suppressed from the list
			but shown to the user if they click the button 'Show other classes'</para>
		<para>Classes that are full or classes that are cancelled are suppressed from results list
			pages in the same way.</para>
		<para>Searches created by website users are always run against all your courses e.g.
			www.myurl.com/courses?s=whatever</para>
		<para>If you want to craft some specific searches to put behind image banners, promotional
			ads or other links, you can build your search within a tag group URL to make the results
			more specific. For example, if you want a promo for day time cooking classes your search
			might be www.myurl.com/courses/cooking?time=day which will find all the courses tagged
			with the subject tag group named cooking that have classes running during the day
			time.</para>
		<para>The onCourse search options available are:</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?s=cook</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This is standard keyword search, which includes stemming so the term cook will find cook,
						cooks, cooking, cookery ect. The search results prioritise courses where the
						search term appears in the course name, over courses where it appears in the
						course description.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?near=Chatswood+2057</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Search on both the Suburb+postcode. While the search may work without the postcode,
						adding the postcode is essential to determine location if the suburb exists
						in multiple states.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?price=200</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This searches for classes with an enrolment fee less than the specified dollar
						value.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?time=day</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Searching for a day class means the first session commences before 5pm.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?time=evening</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Searching evening means the session starts after 5pm</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?day=weekday</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A weekday course means the first session is held Monday to Friday.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?day=weekend</term>
				<listitem><para>A weekend search means the class starts on a Saturday or Sunday.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?after=20141201</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This will show class that start after the date 1/12/2014. The date in the search is in format yyyymmdd.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses?before=20150101</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This will show classes that start before 1/1/2015. The date in the search is in format
						yyyymmdd. This can be used in combination with the after search option to
						create a date range. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>/courses/cooking?tag=delivery/School+holidays</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This search allows you search for courses that are tagged with multiple tags. You must
						use the full secondary tag path. This means the course is tagged with both
						the landing page tag (usually the tag group from within the subjects tag)
						and the search term tag.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<para>Multiple search teams can be concatenated to created complex search strings such as
			www.myurl.com/courses/cooking?s=thai&amp;near=Chatswood+2057&amp;price=500&amp;time=day&amp;tag=level/beginner
			which is searching inside the subject tag group cooking for courses also tagged with the
			level tag group beginner that contain the keyword Thai, held near Chatswood NSW in the
			day time and costing under $500.</para>
		<note>
			<para>A note on the space character inside a URL: If you have a tag name that contains a
				space, and you are manually crafting a URL that includes that tag, you need to replace
				the space character with "+" e.g. tag name "cooking for kids" in a URL becomes
				"cooking+for+kids". This is done automatically for pages generated by onCourse, it is
				only in hand crafted URLs you need to remember to add the space delimiter. Old school
				style space character replacement with "%20" works also, but makes the URL harder for a
				human to read.</para>
		</note>

	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Search Engine Optimisation</title>
		<para>There are a number of tools available to you to help maximise the search engine optimisation for your onCourse website. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Google tools</title>
			<para>Google offer a range of really useful free tools to help drive search results to your site and analyse who is visiting your
				site, why they are visiting your site and how much they are spending. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Analytics</title>
			<para>ish will automatically sign you up to this service when we set up your account. onCourse has special hooks into Google Analytics
				to pass through spending details of people who visit your site, so not only can you see who is coming to your site and from where,
				but you can see which sources of traffic result in actual money being spent. It is all very well to get thousands of page views from
				Facebook, but unless that traffic is generating enrolments you aren't getting the results you really need.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Tag Manager</title>
			<para>Google Tag Manager is a powerful tool which allows you to inject javascript, images or other content into your web pages. Every
				onCourse site automatically comes with a tag manager account for your use.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Webmaster Tools</title>
			<para>This free tool is something you can set up yourself. Just go to <link xlink:href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools">www.google.com/webmasters/tools</link> and click "add a site". You'll be given several choices for how to verify your site;
				choose "HTML file upload" option. Take the file and upload it to your onCourse site in the top of the /s folder. Don't forget to
				then publish your site changes into production. </para>
			<para>You may decide to engage the services of an SEO company, and they may want to add your site to their own Webmaster tools. There
				is no problem with uploading several different Google html verification files to your site. </para>
			<para>Once you have performed the verification, a huge number of options are available to you. Most importantly you'll want to review
				your organic search results, look at who is linking to you, make sure Google knows which country you are in. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Site Map</title>
			<para>onCourse automatically generates a sitemap for all your content, so you don't need to maintain this by hand. This ensures that
				Google is able to locate every page in your site and index it. Whether you get page hits from Google search will of course depend on
				what you have on that page and how popular it is, but at least you know that Google will find every single page of your site.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
