<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="payment_options">
	<title>Payment Options</title>
	<para>onCourse allows for a range of payment options for enrolling students. Students can pay for multiple classes and multiple students
		in a single transaction and choose to send the invoice to their employer.</para>
	<para>onCourse eCommerce doesn't handle only enrolments in classes; it also includes product, memberships and gift voucher sales allowing
		you to diversify your business and the way people can buy and share your products.</para>
	<section>
		<title>Credit card</title>
		<para>Real-time credit card processing ensures that successful enrolments are only made when the money is in your account. Once the
			student has entered their credit card details they will need to select the checkbox at the bottom of the page that says 'I understand
			the enrolment and refund policy', then click on the 'Confirm purchase' button to complete the order.</para>
		<para>The credit card is captured by onCourse over an SSL encrypted connection. The full card number and CVV are never stored in the
			database, only passed directly to the banking system, so in the unlikely event of a security breach there are no stored card details
			for anyone to steal. The user should expect a response in about 5-10 seconds, and during this time the enrolment is put on hold,
			preventing someone else taking the last place available in a class.</para>
		<para>Should the payment fail due to insufficient funds or some other problem, onCourse will retain the transaction history as an
			invoice, a failed payment, and a credit note reversing out the invoice. We encourage you to regularly review failed payments in your
			system and follow up with the user to offer them alternative payment means.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/payment_credit_card.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Using a credit card when paying for an online enrolment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Corporate Pass</title>
		<para>CorporatePass gives approved users the ability to invoice their employer on enrolment. That way you can develop a close
			relationship with your corporate customers, but still allow their staff to select training timetables to suit themselves. </para>
		<para>You can view, edit, create or disable a Corporate Pass within onCourse by clicking on the CorporatePass button that can be found
			in the marketing tab. Once you have clicked on the CorporatePass button a window will pop up with a list of current and expired (if
			you check the filter in the left column) Corporate Passes created. You can view an existing corportate pass by double clicking on a
			record, or alternatively create one by click on the '+' symbol in the top right hand of the window. More information on Corporate
			Passes can be found in the <link xlink:href="#corporatePass">CorporatePass chapter</link> of the handbook. To pay using a CorporatePass during the online enrolment process the
			student has to simply click on the CorporatePass tab on the left side of the 'PAYMENT' page. The student has to then enter the
			CorporatePass code that would have been supplied by their employer (this code can also be found in onCourse).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/corporate_pass.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Using a CorporatePass code to complete an online enrolment without the need of a payment at that time</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once the student has submitted a valid CorporatePass code they will see a message confirming that the code they have used has been
			accepted. They will also be given an option to add a references for this transaction that will be sent to their employer.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/corporatepass_validation.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>CorporatePass reference</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once the student has choosen or not to enter a reference; marked the 'Conditions' checked; and clicked on the button 'Confirm
			enrolment' they will be directed to a page informing them the CorporatePass was successful as shown below.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/corporatepass_confirmation.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>CorporatePass confirmation page</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Vouchers and Gift Certificates</title>
		<para>Vouchers are much more than a simple gift voucher. They can be used to sell training in flexible groups whether it be a sampler of
			arts courses or OH&amp;S training for 20 co-workers. More information on Vouchers of Gift Certificates can be found in the <link xlink:href="#vouchers">vouchers chapter</link> of the handbook.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/add_code.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Adding a Voucher or Gift Certifcate to help pay for an online enrolment/s</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Discounts and Promotional Codes</title>
		<para>A range of flexible discounting and promotional code tools allow for students to access your special enrolment rates right up
			until the point of payment. More information on discounts and promotional codes can be found in the <link xlink:href="#discounts">discounts chapter</link> of the handbook.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/discounted_class.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Cost before and after discount for individual classes</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The total cost breakdown will include how much the class/es have been discounted by. In the case below the class has been
			discounted by $51.01.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/discounted_amount.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Total cost and discount for all classes you are trying to enrol in at this time</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Concessions/Memberships</title>
		<para>With onCourse memberships for individuals or employers, you can offer special prices to your select members or create a gym
			membership style training programme. Memberships can be sold or given away, and will expire whenever you choose. You can add a
			concession or membership in the summary section whilst enrolling online. A '+' symbol with text 'Add Concession' can be found below
			the students name and email address.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/add_concession.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Where to find the 'Add Concession' button on the Summary page</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once you have clicked on the 'Add Concession' button you will be directed to the following page, as shown below. More information
			on how to add Concessions/Memberships within onCourse can be found in the <link xlink:href="#concessions">concessions chapter</link> of the handbook.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Concessions.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Adding a Concession/Membership to an enrolment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Credit</title>
		<para>If a student has credit when enrolling they will have an option to use it on the 'PAYMENT' page during the online enrolment
			process. There will be text saying 'Credit available' above the payment summary. To use their credit they have to click on the text
			'Access'.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/credit_available.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>What the student you will see if they have credit</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once they have clicked on the text 'Access' a box will appear for them to enter their password (this will be the same password
			they use to log into skillsonCourse). If they can't remember it then they can click the 'Forgot password' link that will take them to
			their skillsonCourse log in page where inturn they can recover their password.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/credit_available_password.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>How to use your credit</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>After they have summited their password a new line of text will appear where the text 'Credit available' was. As in the case below
			the student had $200 of credit and the cost of the class was only $175, so they have nothing to pay today along with an additonal $25
			of credit left over.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/credit_being_used.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Total cost with the credit being applied</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
</chapter>
