<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="useful_information">
    <title>Useful Information</title>
    <section>
    <title>Timetable Information</title>
    <para>The user timetable can be viewed as either a list of sessions or as a month or calendar
        view. The timetable will display all classes on a given day, by clicking on a given day the
        session information will display at the bottom of the page, including course name, room, venue
        and tutor information. Timetables are applicable either to classes a student is enrolled in,
        or to sessions being taught by a tutor.</para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                fileref="images/Tutor Portal Timetable View.png" format="png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>skillsOnCourse timetable by month view</para>
        </caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <section>
        <title>Calendar Subscriptions</title>
        <para>Skills onCourse allows both Students and Tutors to subscribe to a Calendar for their
            Classes. To add this Calendar feed to your own Calendar, simply click on the
            <guibutton>Subscribe to Calendar</guibutton>button within the portal then add
            this to your own Calendar.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/CalendarLink.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Calendar Link</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once the subscription has been set, any amendments made to the timetable for the Classes
            you are either teaching or enrolled in will automatically flow through to your
            Calendar.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/PortalCalendarSubscription.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>URL link generated by the Portal which can be added to your own Calendar</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Class information</title>
        <para>Students can access up to date class information such as the date of the next session, venue
            and room information, as well as a link through to the Class Description which outlines
            the content to be covered within the Class.</para>
        <para>Tutors are also able to access Class information, including total number of enrolments,
            venue and room information. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Details Tab.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tutors can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <tip>
            <para>Despite Tutors and Students both accessing the skills onCourse via the same log in page,
                the information displayed to these two groups is different. </para>
        </tip>
        <section>
            <title>Class rating</title>
            <para>Students have the ability to rate classes they enrolled in. They can rate out of 5 stars how 
                they found the Venue, Course and Tutor with a notes field below for them to add comments. 
                The tutors that are teaching these class will then be able to see this information in their portal.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/class_rating_student.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students have the ability to rate classes they enrolled in</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Getting Directions to a Classroom</title>
            <para>The skills OnCourse class detail view provides a link to Google maps, providing detailed
                directions for getting to the venue. Simply click on the <guibutton>View on
                    Map</guibutton>link within the Class details view.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Location Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students can access Google Map directions via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Class Results</title>
            <para>A student can also view their results for an individual class by clicking on the
                'Results' tab on the class detail view. Each unit will either say PASS, NOT YET
                COMPETENT or NO RESULT.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Result Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Students results</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>A student can also view a list of all their class results by clicking on the 'Results' tab in the top menu.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/portal_results_tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>List of all class results</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>If a VET course is not linked to a qualification, then the only thing that will
                appear below each class is the unit/list of units.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/VET course is not linked to a qualification.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A VET course that is not linked to a qualification</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Manage Waiting Lists and Mailing Lists</title>
            <para>A student can view what waiting lists they are on by clicking on Subsciptions -> Waiting
                List. This page with allow you to find out more information about the waiting lists
                you are subscribed to along with the option of deleting your name off that
                list.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscriptions Menu Waiting Lists.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Manage your Wait List entries</para></caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>A student can view what mailing lists they are being subscribed to by clicking on
                Subscriptions -> Mailing Lists. You have the option of choosing what method you
                would like to received the information by (E-mail, SMS, Post) and which of the
                designated mailing lists you wish to subscribe to.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscription Menu Mailing Lists.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Add or remove yourself from Mailing Lists</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <note><para>Students have the ability to
                manage their unsubscriptions without a login by adding the follow syntax
                ${contact.getPortalLink("subscriptions")} in email templates.</para></note>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>History</title>
        <para>Students can access a list of their previously enrolled classes, their financial
            history and any applications they have submitted in the History menu.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Applications</title>
        <para>If a student has submitted a applications that has been approved, they will have the
            option to enrol in the class or reject the offer.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Applications.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of applications submitted by the student</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
            <para>If you want to withdraw the application simply click on the 'Reject' option. You
                will then be taken to the page as shown below, confirming the application has been
                withdrawn. If you want to enrol in the class you have applied for, simply click on
                the 'Enrol now' option which will take the student to that course page on your
                website.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Application withdrawn.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Application has been withdrawn</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
            <section>
                <title>Classes</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Enrolments.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of previously enrolled classes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
            </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Finance</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List view of your Financial history</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>To find out more information about a certain transaction you can click on one of the record
            that will in turn open up payment information or a Tax invoice for the chosen payment,
            as seen below.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance Invoice.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Tax invoice</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
                    <section><title>Making a credit card payment in the portal</title>
                        <para>A student has the ability to make credit card payments in the
                    skillsOnCourse portal, so debtors are allowed to make payments against their
                    outstanding invoices or payment plans. This can be found in the Finance tab of
                    the History menu. The payment option UI will only appear if the student has an
                    overdue payment, if not, then this tab will just show a list of their finanical
                    history. A student has an option to reduce the amount they want to pay if they
                    can't afford to pay the full amount at the present time, with a minimum limit of
                    $20 unless the total overdue amount is less than this. Once the user has defined
                    the amount they want to pay the student just needs to enter the credit card
                    details of person making the payment. The user will then get a message notifing
                    them if the payment was successful or if it failed. If the payment fails, then a
                    few seconds after getting a notification of this they will get directed back to
                    the payment page allowing them to try again.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                            fileref="images/Tutor Portal Making a payment.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Making a $550 overdue payment in the skillsOnCourse portal</caption>
                </mediaobject>
                        <note><para>If a student has mulitple invoices that are overdue the amount shown that needs to be paid
                        will be the combined overdue total. If they don't want to pay the full
                        amount yet, then the payment will be taken off the oldest invoice first,
                        even if they are on a payment plan.</para></note>
                        <para>There is also a script called 'send payment plan reminder' that automatically sends a message
                    7 days before the payment due date, on the day the payment is due and every 7
                    days after that.</para><mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                            fileref="images/send payment plan reminder.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>send payment plan reminder script</caption>
                </mediaobject>
                <para>Below is an example of the email that gets sent to a student who is overdue.
                    There is also a link in the email that allows them to go straight to the portal,
                    without having to log in, and pay the overdue balance.</para><mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                            fileref="images/Payment Reminder Script.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Payment reminder email</caption>
                </mediaobject>
                    </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Where a student can find their Certificate in skillsonCourse</title>
        <para>Once you have attached the students Certificate to their enrolment record you will
            want to be able to direct the student to where they can find it in their skillsonCourse
            portal. More information about attaching Certificates to student records can be found <link xlink:href="rto.html#rto-attaching"
                >here.</link></para>
        <para>They can find this by: </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>clicking on 'History' tab in the top menu, then on 'Classes' to see the full
                    list of past classes. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Under this section the student will see a list of past classes and to find the
                    certificate for class 'Certificate III in Children's Services (CHC2-4)' they
                    would need to click on this class in the list. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Finally click on the 'Resources' option; this option will only appear if they
                    have something attached to their enrolment record. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>When they have done this the student will be able to download and print their
                    Cerificate themselves.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
                    fileref="images/finding_certificate_portal.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Where a student can find their Certificate in skillonCourse</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
