<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="tara_overview">
	<title>skillsOnCourse</title>
	<section>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>skillsOnCourse is a web site for tutors and students which allows them to interact with your
			college and with each other. Every student and tutor is automatically given a login when
			their record is created in onCourse or when they enrol online. </para>
		<para>skillsOnCourse gives tutors the information they need without having to contact you
			regularly. "Is my class full?", "Will my class go ahead?", "Can I get a class roll".
			These are all things that your teaching staff will ask you every day; now you have a 24
			hour assistant to help tutors get the answers they need.</para>
		<para>Students will also enjoy the skillsOnCourse portal. They can quickly and easily get the
			information they need about their classes and timetable.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating accounts and logging in</title>
		<para>All students when they are created in onCourse, will automatically have a skillsOnCourse
			account set up for them. The first time a student enrols in your college, they will be sent an
			email which allows them to log into skillsOnCourse and set their password. Tutors are also
			given an account when their record is created in onCourse.</para>
		<para>The skillsOnCourse login screen will prompt the student or tutor to enter their details.
			Like the onCourse enrolment process, a student is identified by name and email address
			to avoid forcing students and tutors to remember another user id.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal Log In Screen.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>skillsOnCourse web login page </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>It is also possible to log into skills onCourse as a Company rather than an individual. To
			do so simply tick the <guilabel>As company</guilabel>box, then enter the email address
			and password for your Company.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal Log In Screen Company.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Recovering and Resetting Passwords</title>
			<para>The main login screen for the skillsOnCourse portal includes a 'forgot password' link. The
				user will need to provide a name and valid email address in order to initiate the process.
				If the student or tutor does not have an email address in onCourse then they must contact
				the college so that you can manually update their record. It is important that you implement
				an appropriate set of policies around how to authenticate users over the phone when they
				request that their email address be changed or added, since that email address will give
				them access to the full profile and history of the user. </para>
			<para>If the user clicks on the forgot password link and enters the other details, an email will
				be sent to them with a link to enable them create a new password. This link will be valid
				for 24 hours only, after that time the link within the email will not work. Once the student
				has reset their password, they can continue using skillsOnCourse.</para>
			<para><programlisting>Dear {name},

To reset your SkillsOnCourse password, simply click the link below. That will take you to a web page
where you can create a new password. Please note that the link will expire 24 hours after
this email was sent.
				
  {recoveryLink}

If you weren't trying to reset your password, don't worry - your account is still secure and no
one has been given access to it. Most likely, someone just mistyped their email address
while trying to reset their own password.</programlisting></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Updating Your Details</title>
			<para>Once logged in, users are able to update their contact details via the <guimenu>My Profile</guimenu> menu.
				This screen also enables them to update their password and subscribe to receive
				marketing material via email SMS or post, as well as signing up to receive a regular
				newsletter via the <guimenu>Mailing List</guimenu> menu. Students can also manage their Waiting List entries via the <guimenu>Waiting List</guimenu>menu.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile View.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>My profile page of skillsOnCourse</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile Update Password.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reset your skillsonCourse Password</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Updating AVETMISS Details</title>
			<para>If a student is undertaking an RTO Course, they can provide / update the required
				AVETMISS information via the profile page.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal My Profile Census Info.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Student AVETMISS Information</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Navigating skillsOnCourse</title>
		<para>Students and Tutors are able to navigate their way around skillsOnCourse via the left hand
			menu options. By clicking on the 'skillsOnCourse' logo in the top left hand corner of the
			page, they can return to the home page of the site. Because the site is built using modern
			html techniques, the user can safely use the back button on their browser or bookmark any page
			they like. When they return to a bookmarked page they will be asked to log in and will then be
			redirected to the page they bookmarked.</para>
		<para>If a student or tutor is updating their profile, they must submit their changes before
			navigating away from that page. If they leave the page without saving the changes, those
			changes are lost.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Timetable Information</title>
		<para>The user timetable can be viewed as either a list of sessions or as a month or calendar
			view. The timetable will display all classes on a given day, by clicking on a given day the
			session information will display at the bottom of the page, including course name, room, venue
			and tutor information. Timetables are applicable either to classes a student is enrolled in,
			or to sessions being taught by a tutor.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal Timetable View.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>skillsOnCourse timetable by month view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Calendar Subscriptions</title>
			<para>Skills onCourse allows both Students and Tutors to subscribe to a Calendar for their
				Classes. To add this Calendar feed to your own Calendar, simply click on the
					<guibutton>Subscribe to Calendar</guibutton>button within the portal then add
				this to your own Calendar.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/CalendarLink.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Calendar Link</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Once the subscription has been set, any amendments made to the timetable for the Classes
				you are either teaching or enrolled in will automatically flow through to your
				Calendar.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/PortalCalendarSubscription.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>URL link generated by the Portal which can be added to your own Calendar</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Class information</title>
		<para>Students can access up to date class information such as the date of the next session, venue
			and room information, as well as a link through to the Class Description which outlines
			the content to be covered within the Class.</para>
		<para>Tutors are also able to access Class information, including total number of enrolments,
			venue and room information. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Details Tab.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Students can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<tip>
			<para>Despite Tutors and Students both accessing the skills onCourse via the same log in page,
				the information displayed to these two groups is different. </para>
		</tip>
		<section>
			<title>Getting Directions to a Classroom</title>
			<para>The skills OnCourse class detail view provides a link to Google maps, providing detailed
				directions for getting to the venue. Simply click on the <guibutton>View on
					Map</guibutton>link within the Class details view.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Location Tab.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Students can access Google Map directions via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Manage Waiting Lists and Mailing Lists</title>
			<para>A student can view what waiting lists they are on by clicking on Subsciptions -> Waiting
				List. This page with allow you to find out more information about the waitings lists
				you are subscribed to along with the option of deleting your name off that
				list.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscriptions Menu Waiting Lists.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Manage your Wait List entries</para></caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>A student can view what mailing lists lists they are being subscribed to by clicking on
				Subsciptions -> Mailing Lists. You have the option of choosing what method you would
				like to received the information by (E-mail, SMS, Post) and which of the designated
				mailing lists you wish to subscribe to.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal Subscription Menu Mailing Lists.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Add or remove yourself from Mailing Lists</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>History</title>
		<para>......</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Finance.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>..........</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal History Enrolments.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>............</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
		<para>Some features are only visible to tutors, including real time marking of the attendance
			roll for a given class.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Viewing and Marking a Class Roll</title>
			<para>Tutors can access the attendance roll for the class they are teaching, updating the
				attendance records in real time. The attendance roll can also list contact details
				such as mobile and email addresses for students, allowing the tutor to easily
				contact students who have not shown up for their scheduled classes.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Marking Roll.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Live attendance tracking via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<tip>
				<para>A College can set whether or they wish the Tutor to see the contact details of the
					students via the Website CMS under the <guimenu>Site Settings</guimenu> menu. Whether this
					information is displayed is dependent upon the individual policies of Colleges
					and the management of student records. </para>
			</tip>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Approving Class Information</title>
			<para>Tutors can confirm their availability for a given Class using the Portal. To access any
				Classes that a Tutor has not yet confirmed their availability for, simply click on
				the <guimenu>To Confirm</guimenu> menu within the Portal. There is also a dialog box available to the
				tutor so they can send in comments and or suggested amendments to the course copy.
				College staff then approve and update the changes via the onCourse Client. Tutors
				cannot edit the course schedule or description themselves, since it needs to be
				properly approved by College staff.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
						fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Tutor_Class_Approval.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Tutors can confirm availability for a given Class via the Portal</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Viewing Student Results</title>
			<para>Placeholder text for new feature</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Results Tab.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Student Assessment Sorted by Unit of Competency</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Class Resources and Files</title>
			<para>Placeholder text for new resources feature</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%"
						fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Resources Tab.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Available teaching resources and documents for a Class</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	
</chapter>
