<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="tutor">
    <title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
    <section>
        <title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
        <para>Some features are only visible to tutors, including real time marking of the attendance
            roll for a given class.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing and Marking a Class Roll</title>
            <para>Tutors can access the attendance roll for the class they are teaching, updating the
                attendance records in real time. The attendance roll can also list contact details
                such as mobile and email addresses for students, allowing the tutor to easily
                contact students who have not shown up for their scheduled classes.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Marking Roll.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Live attendance tracking via the skillsonCourse portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <tip>
                <para>A College can set whether or they wish the Tutor to see the contact details of the
                    students via the Website CMS under the <guimenu>Site Settings</guimenu> menu. Whether this
                    information is displayed is dependent upon the individual policies of Colleges
                    and the management of student records. </para>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Approving Class Information</title>
            <para>Tutors can confirm their availability for a given Class using the Portal. To access any
                Classes that a Tutor has not yet confirmed their availability for, simply click on
                the <guimenu>To Confirm</guimenu> menu within the Portal. There is also a dialog box available to the
                tutor so they can send in comments and or suggested amendments to the course copy.
                College staff then approve and update the changes via the onCourse Client. Tutors
                cannot edit the course schedule or description themselves, since it needs to be
                properly approved by College staff.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Tutor_Class_Approval.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Tutors can confirm availability for a given Class via the Portal</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing Student Results</title>
            <para>Tutors have the ability to view a list of results for each unit of competency for their
                students. They will be marked either PASS, FAILED OR NO RESULT.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Results Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Student Assessment Sorted by Unit of Competency</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Class Resources and Files</title>
            <para>Tutor also have access to a list of resources and files for each individual class they
                teach.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
                        fileref="images/Tutor Portal Classes Menu Resources Tab.png" format="png" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Available teaching resources and documents for a Class</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
