<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="tara_overview">
	<title>skillsOnCourse</title>
	<section>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>skillsOnCourse is a web site for tutors and students which allows them to interact with your
			college and with each other. Every student and tutor is automatically given a login when their
			record is created in onCourse or when they enrol online. skillsOnCourse has been optimised for
			mobile and touch pad devices, as well as desktop browsers.</para>
		<para>skillsOnCourse gives tutors the information they need without having to contact you
			regularly. "Is my class full?", "Will my class go ahead?", "Can I get a class roll", "I need
			to get a message out to my students before the next session." These are all things that your
			teaching staff will ask you every day; now you have a 24 hour assistant to help tutors get the
			answers they need.</para>
		<para>Students will also enjoy the skillsOnCourse portal. They can quickly and easily get the
			information they need about their classes and timetable, as well as interact with other
			students and their tutors.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating accounts and logging in</title>
		<para>All students when they are created in onCourse, will automatically have a skillsOnCourse
			account set up for them. The first time a student enrols in your college, they will be sent an
			email which allows them to log into skillsOnCourse and set their password. Tutors are also
			given an account when their record is created in onCourse.</para>
		<para>The skillsOnCourse login screen will prompt the student or tutor to enter their details.
			Like the onCourse enrolment process, a student is identified by name and email address to
			avoid forcing students and tutors remember another user id.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
					fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_login.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>skillsOnCourse web login page </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Recovering and Resetting Passwords</title>
			<para>The main login screen for the skillsOnCourse portal includes a 'forgot password' link. The
				user will need to provide a name and valid email address in order to initiate the process.
				If the student or tutor does not have an email address in onCourse then they must contact
				the college so that you can manually update their record. It is important that you implement
				an appropriate set of policies around how to authenticate users over the phone when they
				request that their email address be changed or added, since that email address will give
				them access to the full profile and history of the user. </para>
			<para>If the user clicks on the forgot password link and enters the other details, an email will
				be sent to them with a link to enable them create a new password. This link will be valid
				for 24 hours only, after that time the link within the email will not work. Once the student
				has reset their password, they can continue using skillsOnCourse.</para>
			<para><programlisting>Dear {name},

To reset your SkillsOnCourse password, simply click the link below. That will take you to a web page
where you can create a new password. Please note that the link will expire 24 hours after
this email was sent.
				
  {recoveryLink}

If you weren't trying to reset your password, don't worry - your account is still secure and no
one has been given access to it. Most likely, someone just mistyped their email address
while trying to reset their own password.</programlisting></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Updating Your Details</title>
			<para>Once logged in, users are able to update their contact details via the 'My Profile'
				menu. This screen also enables them to update their password and subscribe to receive
				marketing material via email SMS or post, as well as signing up to receive a regular
				newsletter. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
						fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Student_Profile.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>My profile page of skillsOnCourse</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Updating AVETMISS Details</title>
			<para>If a student is undertaking an RTO Course, they can provide / update the required
				AVETMISS information via the profile page.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
						fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Student_AVETMISS_Info.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Student AVETMISS Information</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Navigating skillsOnCourse</title>
		<para>Students and Tutors are able to navigate their way around skillsOnCourse via the left hand
			menu options. By clicking on the 'skillsOnCourse' logo in the top left hand corner of the
			page, they can return to the home page of the site. Because the site is built using modern
			html techniques, the user can safely use the back button on their browser or bookmark any page
			they like. When they return to a bookmarked page they will be asked to log in and will then be
			redirected to the page they bookmarked.</para>
		<para>If a student or tutor is updating their profile, they must submit their changes before
			navigating away from that page. The same logic applies to any new posts / messages to the
			forum and if a student is submitting a rating for a given class. If they leave the page
			without saving the changes, those changes are lost.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Timetable Information</title>
		<para>The user timetable can be viewed as either a list of sessions or as a month or calendar
			view. The timetable will display all classes on a given day, by clicking on a given day the
			session information will display at the bottom of the page, including course name, room, venue
			and tutor information. Timetables are applicable either to classes a student is enrolled in,
			or to sessions being taught by a tutor.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
					fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Timetable_Month_View.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>skillsOnCourse timetable by month view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The timetable can also be displayed as a list. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
					fileref="images/Skills_onCourse_Timetable_List_View.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>skillsOnCourse timetable by list view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Class information</title>
		<para>Students can access up to date class information such as the date of the next session,
			venue and room information, download course materials in advance of the course, as well as
			receive course related messages from Tutors and fellow students. </para>
		<para>Tutors can submit the course materials documents to the College in advance of the class in
			order for them to be made available to students. Class materials will be uploaded by College
			staff via the onCourse client as attachments (PDF is the best format for ease of use on many
			systems) and flagged as 'web visible (private)'. Both tutors and students will be able to
			access and download these PDF documents from skillsOnCourse. At this stage it is not possible
			for tutors to directly upload attachments for their class, since the college needs to review
			content to ensure it is appropriate and has the appropriate copyright clearance.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
					fileref="images/tara_web_class_detail_view_student.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Students can access detailed class information via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Getting Directions to a Classroom</title>
			<para>The skillsOnCourse class detail view provides a link to Google maps, providing detailed
				directions for getting to the venue.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Tutor Specific Features</title>
		<para>Some features are only visible to tutors, including real time marking of the attendance
			roll for a given class.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Viewing and Marking a Class Roll</title>
			<para>Tutors can access the attendance roll for the class they are teaching, updating the
				attendance records in real time. As skillsOnCourse is enabled for mobile devices and touch
				pads, this makes it even simpler to update attendance rolls in real time. The attendance
				roll can also list contact details such as mobile and email addresses for students, allowing
				the tutor to easily contact students who have not shown up for their scheduled
				classes.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
						fileref="images/tara_web_class_attendance_roll_tutor.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Live attendance tracking via the skillsOnCourse portal</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Approving Class Information</title>
			<para>Class tutors have the ability to sign off course and class content. There is also a
				dialog box available to the tutor so they can send in comments and or suggested amendments
				to the course copy. College staff then approve and update the changes via the onCourse
				client. Tutors cannot edit the course schedule or description themselves, since it needs to
				be properly approved by College staff.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="40%" contentdepth="40%"
						fileref="images/tara_web_class_approval_tutor.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Tutors can amend and approve class content</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Student Specific Features</title>
		<para>Students have their own feature set, including the ability to update their account
			details, access forums and message boards, as well as complete an online survey for a class
			that they have completed. It is also an invaluable resource for accessing and downloading
			class materials in advance of a given class.</para>
		<para>If a student enrols in a class that has an online forum, the College will specify the
			amount of time students within that class will have access to that forum after the completion
			of the class. If for example the tutor wishes to send the students additional information and
			or continue with a discussion, the forum can remain open to allow that communication to take
			place.</para>
		<para>The skillsOnCourse account will remain open for the student to access indefinitely, even if
			a forum is no longer available to the student. </para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Guide to Managing the skillsOnCourse for college staff </title>
		<para>skillsOnCourse provides a range of new functionality for college staff, providing a number
			of improvements to communication methods between students and college staff, as well as
			between college staff and their tutors</para>
		<section>
			<title>Uploading of PDF Documents </title>
			<para>College staff will be able to upload a PDF document or other documents via the class or
				course edit window of onCourse. Each attachment can be flagged as 'web visible (private)' in
				order to make it visible only to student enrolled in the class. Setting the attachment as
				'web visible (public)' means that it is visible to everyone browsing the main college
				website. Use this option for things students will need before making a decision to enrol.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
