<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="what_the_student_sees">
    <title>What the student sees</title>
    <para>onCourse has a password free purchasing process meaning that students don't have to
        remember obsure student identification details from their last enrolment. Where a student
        has enrolled previously they can move immediately to the payment process, automatically
        matched to their previous record.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Student Details</title>
        <para>After a student has selected which class/es they want to enrol in and clicked on the
            button 'PROCEED TO CHECKOUT' they will see the same page below. All the student need to
            enter here is their first name, last name and email address.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/your_details_page.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Student details landing page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Previously Enrolled Students</title>
            <para>If the student enrolling in the class/es has already enrolled in a previous class,
                (therefore their details are already stored in your database) then after they have
                entered their first name, last name and email address and clicked on the OK button
                then it will jump them straight to the summary page.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/your_details_page_with_info.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Enrolling a previously enrolled student</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>New Students</title>
            <para>If this is the first time the student is enrolling then after they have entered
                their first name, last name and email address it will take them to an additional
                page where more details need to be captured. All the details on this page can be
                made mandatory or optional within the CMS setting. As you can see below the only
                question that is mandatory is their postcode which is marked with a '*' symbol.
                There is also a marketing question, along with a dropdown for the student to choose
                whether they have any concessions.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                        fileref="images/new_student.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>New student questions page</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a Friend</title>
            <para>Once a student has entered all their details they will be directed to a summary
                page. In this page they have the option of adding another contact/student to this
                order. The button can be found below the class/es that are being enrolled in and
                above the field where they can add a promotional code, gift certificate or voucher.
                If they click on it then it will take them back to the 'YOUR DETAILS' page allowing
                them to enter the addtional students details.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/adding_another_student.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Add another student button</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Summary</title>
        <para>Once a student has entered all their details they will be directed to a summary page. </para>
        <para>This page includes the following information:</para>
        <para>* Full name and Email Address of the student/s enrolling or paying</para>
        <para>* Class/es enrolling in</para>
        <para>* Price before and after discount of each class along with a total at the bottom right
            of the page</para>
        <para>* A option to add another student (please see the section above called 'Adding a
            Friend' for more information)</para>
        <para>* A field to enter promotional codes, gift certificates or vouchers (more information
            on this can be found in the Payment Options chapter of the manual)</para>
        <para>Once the student has read the summary of information and is happy with the details
            entered, they can proceed to the payment page by clicking on the 'Proceed to Payment'
            button at the bottom of the page.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/summary_page.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Summary page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Adding a Parent or Guardian</title>
        <para>Within the CMS, if you have choosen whether a student below a certain age needs to
            supply their Guardian or Parents details then they will see a similiar screen as shown
            below. In the example below, student Alicia Badgery, is trying to enrol in 'Course
            22435' however since she is below a certain age the following message appears at the
            bottom of the page 'We require the details of a parent of guardian for billing and
            emergency conatct.' They will also not have an option to proceed to the payment screen,
            however instead the button changes to say 'Add parent or guardian'. They will also
            notice that there is a new step at the top of the page called 'PARENT'. Once they have
            clicked on the 'Add parent or guardian' button then they will be directed to the same
            initial 'YOUR DETAILS' page where the parent or guardian can enter their details.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/needing_to_add_a_parent.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>What happens when a student is below a certain age and needs to add their
                    parent or guardian details</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once the guardian or parents details have been captured the 'PARENT' step will be
            removed from the top of the page. There will also be a message informing the student
            that since they are below a certain age (in this case 18) the parent or guardian that
            has been entered has been set as the payer. They can now proceed to payment page as
            normal.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/parent_has_been_added.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Summary page after the student has added their parent or guardians
                    details</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Payment</title>
        <para>Once the student is on the 'PAYMENT' page there are two main ways to pay for their
            class/es, these are:</para>
        <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Pay using a credit or debit card</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Click on the 'CorporatePass' option then they can enter their CorporatePass code
                    in the field to complete the transaction without the need for a payment at this
                    time (more information on this can be found in the Payment Options chapter of
                    the web manual). </para>
        </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/payment_credit_card.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Payment page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Confirmation</title>
        <para>After the student has clicked on the 'Confirmed purchase' button at the bottom of the
            PAYMENT page, then they will be directed to a confirmation page with a message informing
            them that their online enrolment was either successful or rejected. If successful, at
            the bottom of the page there will be a continue button that if pressed will take them to
            a previously created post enrolment page that you would have created within the CMS. If
            you have not created a post enrolment page then they will just get re-directed to the
            courses page.</para>
        <para>If the students enrolment goes through successfully and their credit card is accepted
            they will see a page similar to the screen shot shown below.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/credit_card_successful.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>What the student sees if their credit card has been accepted</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>If the students credit card is not accepted they will see a page similar to the screen shot shown below. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/credit_card_failed.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>What the student sees if their credit card has been rejected</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
