<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="what_the_student_sees">
    <title>What the student sees</title>
    <para>onCourse has a password free purchasing process meaning that students don't have to
        remember obsure student identification details from their last enrolment. Where a student
        has enrolled previously they can move immediately to the payment process, automatically
        matched to their previous record.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Student Details</title>
        <para>After a student has selected which class/es they want to enrol in and clicked on the
            button 'PROCEED TO CHECKOUT' they will see the page below. All the student need to enter
            here is their first name, last name and email address.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/your_details_page.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Student details landing page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <section>
            <title>Previously Enrolled Students</title>
            <para>If the student enrolling in the class/es have already enrolled in a previous class
                (therefore their details are already stored in your database) then after they have
                entered their first name, last name and email address it will jump straight to the
                summary page.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/your_details_page_with_info.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Enrolling a previously enrolled student</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>New Students</title>
            <para>If this is the first time the student has enrolling in a class then after they
                have entered their first name, last name and email address then it will take them to
                an additional page where more details need to be captured. All the details on this
                page can be made mandatory or optional within the CMS. As you can see below the only
                question that is mandatory is their postcode which is marked with a '*' symbol. The
                student can also answer a marketing question along with choose whether they have any
                concessions.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
                        fileref="images/new_student.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>New student questions page</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a Friend</title>
            <para>Once a student has entered all their details they will be directed to a summary
                page. In this page you have the option of adding another student to this order. The
                button can be found below the class/es that are being enrolled in and above the
                field where you can add a promotional code, gift certificate or voucher. If clicked
                on then it will take you back to the 'YOUR DETAILS' page allowing you to enter the
                addtional students details.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/adding_another_student.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Add another student button</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Summary</title>
        <para>Once a student has entered all their details they will be directed to a summary page. </para>
        <para>This page includes the following information:</para>
        <para>* Full name and Email Address of the student/s enrolling</para>
        <para>* Class/es enrolling in</para>
        <para>* Price before and after discount of each class along with a total at the bottom right
            of the page</para>
        <para>* A option to add another student (please see the section above called 'Adding a
            Friend' for more information)</para>
        <para>* A field to enter promotional codes, gift certificates or vouchers (more information
            on this can be found in the Payment Options chapter of the manual)</para>
        <para>Once the student has read the summary of information and is happy with the details
            enter, they can proceed to the payment page by clicking on the 'Proceed to Payment'
            button at the bottom of the page.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/summary_page.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Summary page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Payment</title>
        <para>Once on the student is on the 'PAYMENT' page there are two main ways to pay for the
            class/es, these are:</para>
        <para>* Pay using a credit or debit card</para>
        <para>* Click on the 'CorporatePass' option then they can enter their CorporatePass code in
            the field to complete the transaction without the need for a payment at this time (more
            information on this can be found in the Payment Options chapter of the manual). </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/payment_credit_card.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Payment page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Confirmation</title>
        <para>After the student has confirmed the purchase of their online enrolment then they will
            either be directed to a confirmation page that includes the following
            information:</para>
        <para>*</para>
        <para>Or they will be re-directed to a post enrolment page that you have created within the
            CMS.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/payment_credit_card.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Confirmation page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
