<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-0.8b3">

  <info>
    <title>Release 0.8b3</title>
    <pubdate>22 Feb 2008</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Improved memory usage and caching which reduces memory footprint of the server
      considerably. This has proved very successful for a college with 150,000 records in their
      database.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>The upgrade process in beta 2 was sometimes failing when upgrading from 0.7</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Each system user now has a email field which will tie into future features and
      notifications. This can be set by going to Preferences -> User</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>When viewing a tutor record where list of classes being taught by the tutor were not
      displaying correctly</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Improvements to default views to improve performance with large numbers of records</para>
     <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Student window: lists currently enrolled students</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Tutor window: lists tutors currently teaching classes</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
    <listitem><para>Currency symbol ignored the locale settings and always used $ in emails</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Deleted sessions were still appearing in the calendar</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Enrolment confirmation emails sometimes not sent out</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Improved visibility split pane on Sessions on Windows platform – this split pane separates
      the timetable view from the list of sessions on the bottom. Prior to this fix, the split pane
      icon could not be seen easily.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Further improvements to importing from external systems via xml</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Opening invoice window or creating a new invoice could hang the onCourse client</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Improved the appearance of printed certificates</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Profit and Loss reports for classes were not displaying balances corre</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Improved memory usage and caching which reduces memory footprint of the server
      considerably. This has proved very successful for a college with 150,000 records in their
      database. </para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>The upgrade process in beta 2 was sometimes failing when upgrading from 0.7 </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Each system user now has a email field which will tie into future features and notifications. This
      can be set by going to Preferences -> User </para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>When viewing a tutor record where list of classes being taught by the tutor were not displaying correctly </para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>Improvements to default views to improve performance with large numbers of records </para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>** Student window: lists currently enrolled students</para></listitem> 
          <listitem><para>** Tutor window: lists tutors currently teaching classes</para></listitem> 
      <listitem><para>Currency symbol ignored the locale settings and always used $ in emails </para></listitem> 
     <listitem><para>Deleted sessions were still appearing in the calendar</para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>Enrolment confirmation emails sometimes not sent out </para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>Improved visibility split pane on Sessions on Windows platform - this split pane separates the timetable view from the list of sessions on the bottom. Prior to this fix, the split pane icon could not be seen
      easily </para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>Further improvements to importing from external systems via xml </para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Opening invoice window or creating a new invoice could hang the onCourse client </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Improved the appearance of printed certificates </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Profit and Loss reports for classes were not displaying balances correctly</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
