<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../src/docbook.xsd"
         version="5.0" xml:id="release-1.0.1">

  <info>
    <title>Release 1.0.1</title>
    <pubdate>30 Jul 2008</pubdate>
  </info>

  <section role="important">
    <title>Important changes</title>
    <para>Over the past month, we've been working on a number of issues that were present in our 1.0
      release. We strongly recommend that people update both server and client to 1.0.1 to enjoy the
      improvements.</para>
  </section>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <para>When using QE to enrol a student in a class that had only a single place left, there was a
      bug that would not allow that last place to be enrolled. This has been resolved and onCourse
      now correctly allows the last place to be filled.</para>
    <para>The quick search in the contacts list now allows correctly searching for student first
      names by either using either "Smith, James" or "James Smith" as originally intended. </para>
    <para>A number of individual reports did not print correctly in 1.0. These now print
      correctly.</para>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed a problem which prevented the opening of a list view</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed the problem with counting places left in the QE, simplified the code</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Quick search is smarter now accepts ',' and space for contact list, allowing first
            names to be used again.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Avoiding issues with sorting records when printing. still one report does not work
            (funding)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Better information when printing fails.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed problem where QE was applying the discount twice.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed two things: </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>pressing next/prev is now consistent with opening new view for payment
                in/out</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>payment out validation on amount is now correct</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixing queued enrolments (awaiting confirmation) not being picked up for
            processing</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Better fixes for NPE that's causing postprocessing to fail.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>List of final statuses was incomplete – and was thus stopping the replication of
            cancelled/refunded enrolments</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improved wording of the error messages caused by exceptions in oncourse-willow
            communication</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed another problem with class tutor list report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed problem with class tutor list report</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Greatly simplified Money.getCents code</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The 1c off bug fixed.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixing logic for whether payment is success.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensuring payments with zero dollars are not sent + enrolments are not set to
            corrupted status if payment obtained this status. Enrolments can try again</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed problem wih invoice with no queued enrolments but still was picked up for cc
            processing</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Windows service runs correctly with external db URIs</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Ensure firstName, lastName, email addresses are trimmed when setting values</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Data-upgrade to ensure that firstName, lastName, email fields do not start or end
            with whitespace</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Spelling mistake corrected: 'To get into another course of study'</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fixed tagging issues where core filters were not always displaying correctly</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Optimizations in server frame for display of data path / uri</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Network dabatase uris, to include host, port, database name, user and
            password</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>