<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="release-7.10">

  <info>
    <title>Release 7.10</title>
    <pubdate>8 Sep 2015</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="major">
    <title>Major features</title>
    <section>
      <title>3rd Party Integration preferences</title>
      <para>A new window to create integration preferences has been added to onCourse for the
        following popular commercial tools:</para>
      <para><link xlink:href="https://moodle.org/">Moodle</link> – A free, open-source PHP web
        application for producing modular internet-based courses that support a modern social
        constructionist pedagogy</para>
      <para><link xlink:href="http://mailchimp.com/">Mailchimp</link> – Online email marketing
        solution to manage contacts, send emails and track results</para>
      <para><link xlink:href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/">SurveyMonkey</link> – Create and
        publish online surveys in minutes, and view the results graphically in real time.
        SurveyMonkey provides free online questionnaire and survey software</para>
      <para><link xlink:href="https://www.surveygizmo.com/">SurveyGizmo</link> – An exceptionally
        powerful survey tool designed to make even the most advanced survey projects fun, easy and
        affordable</para>
      <para>These integrations allow you to create your own links to external services and products
        you have purchased, and define with a corresponding script how onCourse utilises these
        services. </para>
      <para>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata
              fileref="images/integrations.png"
            />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>New preferences windows</title>
      <para>All onCourse preferences settings have been moved into a single window with a more
        intuitive layout. Under File > Preferences > General… you'll find all the general
        preferences previously available (College, Licences, Messaging, Class Defaults, LDAP,
        Maintenance &amp; AVETMISS).</para>
      <para>Financial general preferences has been merged into this window and a new preference has
        been created for adding Holidays (unavailabilities) for your whole of business timetable and
        scheduling availability. </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section role="scripts">
    <title>Reports and scripts</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A new Certificate template has been added for Skills Sets.
              <systemitem>#24920</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Class details report sorts in chronological order by default <systemitem>#25624</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Add capacity to define the name of the export file inside a script <systemitem>#25654</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Sales improvements</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>People > Purchased memberships list view has had additional columns and core filters
          added to the window to make it more readable and sortable <systemitem>#25246</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>A new edit purchased membership view has been added to the Purchased Memberships and
          Sales windows. When you double click on a membership that has been purchased you can
          change the expiry date and view the enrolments it has been used for <systemitem>#25249</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Date purchased column added to Sales window <systemitem>#25787</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>'Delivered' status and cog wheel function to set status to delivered added to product
          sales and products filter in Sales window <systemitem>#25788</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Other improvements</emphasis></para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add to invoice advanced search options the invoice line description <systemitem>#21185</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add onCourse student number to user choice of retention/replacement options in the
          contact merge feature <systemitem>#22694</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Suppress the send credit note email option and send cancellation message option when
          using the enrolment transfer wizard <systemitem>#25398</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pre-populate Quick Enrol with the course from the transferred enrolment, along with
          the payer and student details <systemitem>#25398</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>For new users, all windows open by default to 65% of their screen size, until they
          adjust their own layout and preference settings <systemitem>#25704</systemitem></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>When cycling through enrolment records using the 'next' and 'previous' option, the
            VET Fee Help fee charged value updates to show the current record value as expected
            <systemitem>#25343</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>VET Fee Help charged value automatically calculates to be inclusive of any discounts
            or tax applied to the enrolment fee <systemitem>#25513</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Improvement to the Class Budgets CSV export to make the values exported consistent
            with the values displayed in the class budget view <systemitem>#25384</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>When creating a new manual tutor payslip, only allow clairvoyant lookup of contacts
            marked as tutors <systemitem>#25489</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Invoice manual payment plan view row height increased to make values readable during
            edit <systemitem>#25512</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>CONTRA payments now display on the contact financial record summary to calculate the
            correct totals when a payment is reversed <systemitem>#25526</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Time limitations on credit card payments out have been removed <systemitem>#13396</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>A range of advanced search fixes to remove any instances of case sensitivity
            <systemitem>#25674</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fix to the cancel voucher UI to allow a cancellation fee to be charged <systemitem>#25790</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Exclude any outcomes with Outcome Status – National 'Did not start – 66' from
            AVETMISS exporting except in NSW Department of Education and NSW Smart and Skilled
            export flavours <systemitem>#25549</systemitem></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
