<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook file://../../src/docbook.xsd"
         version="5.0" xml:id="release-1.7.14">

  <info>
    <title>Release 1.7.14</title>
    <pubdate>01 Jan 2010</pubdate>
  </info>
  <section role="minor">
    <title>Minor features</title>
    <para>Re-enables the ability to define via a checkbox whether a discount is automatically
      applied to users via Quick Enrol. Previously discounts were always automatically applied if
      the student was eligible to receive that discount.</para>
  </section>
  <section role="fixes">
    <title>Fixes</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes a bug where the tag assignments could be relinked to refer to the tag group
          (e.g., Subjects) if redefining the tag definition.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes the export of xml for class prices over $999 (removing comma separators)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes mysql binary data storage definitions to allow attachments over 32kB.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes a problem where message sending could send multiple emails to some contacts when
          one or more of the contacts on the list had invalid data. Emails are now sent and tracked
          individually.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes a server-side problem where refunds could fail (the banks would somtimes reuse
          their tracking numbers).</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes the contact list view tag filtering for ‘Currently enrolled’ and ‘Currently
          teaching’</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Fixes a problem where the quit button in the login window didn’t quit the
          application.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Extensive improvements to the AVETMISS export for State specific export formats in
          NSW, QLD, Tasmania and (almost) Victoria. You can now export AVETMISS for specific classes
          in any of these formats.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
