<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="accounting">
	<title>Accounting</title>
	<para>The following chapter provides an overview of the principles of the onCourse financial
		process, as well as clear explanations as to how you get the information you need from
		onCourse in order to obtain your monthly / weekly reports. </para>
	<section>
		<title>Relationship between the Student and the Debtor within onCourse</title>
		<para>onCourse has a clear separation between financial data and enrolment data. Students enrol
			in classes. Students may not be a company, since only natural people can enrol in a class. The
			contact linked to an invoice (the debtor) may however be a company or a natural person. The
			student and the debtor may be the same person; this often happens for a simple enrolment of
			one person into one class. The student and the debtor could be two different people, or in
			fact a debtor could pay for the enrolment of multiple students on one invoice.</para>
		<para>In the following example of a basic enrolment, there are 2 students Peter and Amy, and the
			invoice is issued to the the debtor Geoff (1). Geoff then pays the full amount (2).</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Student_and_Debtor_Simple_Enrolment.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Simple Enrolment for Student and Debtor</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If an enrolment needs to be cancelled for whatever reason, the cancellation process will
			generate a credit note to the debtor. It is important to note that although Peter might phone
			to cancel his enrolment, the credit can only be issued back to Geoff in onCourse.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Student_and_Debtor_Refund_Process.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Student and Debtor refund process</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>As the credit note is attached to the debtor, it can be applied to another enrolment for
			the same student or a different student. In the following example, Peter wishes to cancel his
			enrolment so the credit note is issued to Geoff as the debtor. Geoff is then able to enrol
			another person (Sue) into another course using the credit note that has been issued. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Student_and_Debtor_Cancellation_and_New_Enrolment.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Original student cancels, allowing the credit note to be applied by the debtor (Geoff)
					to a new student (Sue)</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="accounting_principles">
		<title>Principles of Accrual Accounting</title>
		<para>onCourse works on the principle of accrual accounting, which means that the income is
			recorded to the General Ledger (GL) at the point the invoice has been generated,
			irrespective of when the payment is received. The following diagrams illustrate the
			difference between accrual accounting and cash accounting and the point at which income
			is recorded against the GL.</para>
		<para> You will note also that the income that is received will initially be assigned to a
			liability account, then transferred to the income account once the class commences. For
			further information see the Deferred Income section of the user handbook.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Updated_Accrual_vs_Cash_Accounting.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Comparison of accrual and cash accounting standards</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Explanation of Financial Transactions Generated by the System</title>
		<para>onCourse follows the basic concepts of double-entry accounting: all financial transactions
			are written to the general ledger in balanced pairs. Asset and expense sit on the left, and
			liability and income on the right. So an increase in Asset could be matched with an equal
			decrease in another Asset. An increase in Expense might be matched by an equal increase in
			Liability.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Basics_of_onCourse_Accounting.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Basic principles of double-entry accounting</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Financial Transactions generated by Enrolment and Payment Process</title>
			<para>Within the Transaction window of onCourse, you can clearly see the individual transaction
				lines that are generated by an enrolment. In this first example, a user creates an enrolment
				for one student into a class with no GST.<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $300 is added to the Pre Paid Fees Liability Account linked to the Class being
						enrolled in,</member>
					<member>(2) $300 is added to Trade Debtors which is a record of the money owed to the
						college.</member>
					<member>(3) Now the payment reverses the $300 in Trade Debtors,</member>
					<member>(4) and $300 is credited to the cheque account where your income is
						receipted</member>
					<member>(5) deferred income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account to Income account
						once the Class commences</member>
				</simplelist></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/simple_enrol_pymt_with_deferred_income_non_gst.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment Non GST Class including deferred income</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>For a class fee that includes GST, this would add 2 x additional transaction lines for the
				GST component of the class fee as shown.<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $350 is added to the liability account linked to the Class being
						enrolled in,</member>
					<member>(2) $350 is added to Trade Debtors which is a record of the money owed to
						the college. </member>
					<member>(3) $35 is added to Trade Debtor which is a record of the GST amount
						owing,</member>
					<member>(4) $35 is the GST amount to be received from the Customer (shown as a
						liability)</member>
					<member>(5) Now the payment reverses the total amount owing (Fee + GST component) in
						Trade Debtors</member>
					<member>(6) and $385 is credited to the cheque account where your income is
						receipted </member>
					<member>(7) deferred income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account to
						Income account once Class commences</member>
				</simplelist></para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/simple_enrol_pymt_with_deferred_income_gst_inc.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment GST Class including deferred income</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Transactions created when a discount is applied</title>
				<para>Discounts in onCourse are charged to a Cost of Sale (COS) account called Discounts Given.
					The transactions processed to this account, and balance of this account allow
					you to keep an accurate track of the cost to the business of the discounts given
					during the sales process.</para>
				<para> Discounts given do not reduce the income recorded in the income account(s) of
					your college. To determine the income earned, you can deduct the balance of the
					COS accounts(s) from the income account(s)</para>
				<para>This works in conjunctions with the standard enrolment transaction posting
				process, and the deferred income posting for income.</para>
				<para>For example, for a $300 (GST free) enrolment fee, with a $100 discount applied at time of
					enrolment, the student owes and pays the balance of $200 in full during
					enrolment. </para>
				<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $200 is recored as pre-paid fees liability. This is the income for the full
						enrolment, excluding the discounted amount</member>
					<member>(2) $200 is recorded as owing in the trade debtors account. </member>
					<member> (3) $100, the value of the discount, is posted to the classes set income account </member>
					<member> (4) $100, the value of the discount is posted to the COS sale account Discounts Given </member>
					<member> (5) The student pays the balance of the enrolment fee, $200 and the
						cheque account is credited with the Trade Debtor account is debited. The
						student has now paid in full and owes no further money.</member>
					<member> (6) When the class commences (or other choice of setting) the remaining income, $200,
						from the enrolment is debited from the pre-paid fees liability and credited
						to the income account set for the class. </member>
				</simplelist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Invoice_and_Discount_transactions.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment GST Class including deferred income</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Financial Transactions Generated by Enrolment Cancellation Process</title>
		
		<para>When canceling an enrolment a credit note is issued, this results in the opposite effect
			to the original invoice. Note that this does not automatically generate a payment out to the
			student since they might use that credit against a further enrolment or choose to have it paid
			to them in one of a number of ways.</para>
		<para>If you need to cancel an enrolment or enrolments for a Class that has not yet commenced, the
			cancellation process will trigger the deferred income held in the Prepaid Fees Liability
			Account to be transferred to the income account. This transfer is the first part of the
			cancellation process. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>If an enrolment or enrolments are cancelled after the Class has commenced, the remainder /
				balance of funds will be transferred from the Prepaid Fees Liability Acocunt to the
				Income account, this is triggered by the cancellation process.</para>
		</tip>
		<simplelist>
			<member>(1) Deferred income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account to Income account </member>
			<member>(2) $300 is removed from your income</member>
			<member>(3) and $300 is deducted from the trade debtor account since you are reversing the
				debt this person had to you</member>
		</simplelist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/class_cancellation_non_gst_with_deferred_income.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Transactions generated by the cancellation of a GST free enrolment including transfer of deferred income</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>If a refund is to be given to the original debtor, the resulting financial transactions
			are as follows.</para>
		<simplelist>
			<member>(1) When you pay the debtor their refund, $300 goes out of the cheque account
				and</member>
			<member>(2) $300 of trade debtors is removed</member>
		</simplelist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/simple_refund_non_gst.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Transactions generated by refund for a non GST Class</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Here is an example of the transactions generated for an enrolment cancellation and refund
			for a class with GST.<simplelist>
				<member>(1) Deferred income is transferred from Prepaid Fees Liability account to Income account</member>
				<member>(2) $350 is deducted from the trade debtors account since you are reversing the debt
					this person had to you,</member>
				<member>(3) and $350 is removed from your income.</member>
				<member>(4) The $35 GST portion of the debt is expunged and</member>
				<member>(5) your $35 debt to the ATO for this GST is also removed.</member>
				<member>(6) When you pay the debtor their refund, $385 goes out of the cheque account
					and</member>
				<member>(7) $385 of trade debtors is removed.</member>
			</simplelist></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/cancellation_refund_with_deferred_income_gst_inc.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Transactions generated by a GST inclusive class cancellation and refund including deferred
					income</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Transactions created when a discount is applied</title>
				<para>For example, for a $300 (GST free) enrolment fee, with a $100 discount applied at time of
					enrolment, the student owes and pays the balance of $200 in full during
					enrolment. When this enrolment is cancelled and the student is refunded, the
					following transactions are processed:</para>
				<simplelist>
					<member>(1) $200 is reversed from the income account. This is the income for the full
						enrolment, excluding the discounted amount</member>
					<member>(2) $200 is recorded as owing to the student/payer in the trade debtors account. </member>
					<member> (3) $100, the value of the discount, is also reversed from the classes set income
						account </member>
					<member> (4) $100, the value of the discount is reversed from the COS sale account Discounts
						Given </member>
					<member> (5) The student is refunded $200 and the cheque account is debited and the Trade
						Debtor account is credited. The student has now been paid in full and the
						college owes them no further money.</member>
				</simplelist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Reverse_Invoice_and_Discount_transactions.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Transactions generated by simple enrolment GST Class including deferred income</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Contra Payment Types for Refunds</title>
			<para>A contra payment is a special type of payment that debits the balance outstanding on an invoice with the balance of an available
			credit note. It saves you from having to look at the total balance of a student's debits and credits and works out what their end position
			is. It may be especially useful for companies who process multiple students in an invoice and have some students cancel and credited.</para>
			<para>This works automatically for a credit note and is created through the enrolment cancellation process. For example, if the student had enrolled, but not 
			paid their class, which was later cancelled and you issued them a credit note, automatically both the credit note and their original invoice
			would have a $0 balance, as they would cancel each other out.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/create_contra_via_invoice_window.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Create a contra invoice via the invoice window advanced function cogwheel</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Alternatively, you can do this manually in the invoice window for manual credit notes too.
				For example, if a student had an invoice for $100 for an enrolment that they have
				not made a payment against, so have a balance outstanding of $100, and there then
				issued a credit note for $70 for a manual refund for a different class that they had
				paid for, you could choose to 'contra' the $70 credit note balance against the $100
				outstanding balance on the invoice. This would then show their credit note as having
				a $0 balance (as though you had refunded them, or they had used the credit note for
				another enrolment) and their invoice as having a balance of $30 outstanding that
				they need to pay. </para>
			<para>You can only use credit notes to contra invoices for the same contact. You can't take a
				credit note from Student A and use it to 'pay off' an invoice that was issued to
				Student B.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/contra_invoice_edit_view.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Edit view of a Contra Invoice</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/invoice_detail_showing_contra_payment.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Invoice detail showing a contra payment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Deferred Income</title>
		<para>In this section we provide an overview of how deferred income works within onCourse and how
			the system deals with adjustments and or cancellations to a Class.</para>
		<para>
<mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
		<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
			fileref="images/Deferred_Income_Diagram.png" format="png" />
	</imageobject>
	<caption>
		<para>Transfer of funds from Liability Account to Income Account at time of Course Delivery</para>
	</caption>
</mediaobject>			
		</para>
		<section>
			<title>How Deferred Incomes Works</title>
		<para>When an invoice is generated within onCourse, those funds are initially listed within the GL
			against the Pre Paid Fees (Liability account). These funds are then transferred to the
			income account of the GL at the commencement of the Class. </para>
		<para>As you can see from the above diagram, the method by which onCourse determines how the
			deferred income is transferred across from the Pre Paid Fees (liability) account is as
			follows.<simplelist>
				<member>(1) First session of class is run</member>
				<member>(2) At approximately 1am the following morning, the system will run a comparison between
					the amount of funds in the liability account and the amount of funds in the
					income account for that Class.It will also check how many hours of the overall
					Class have been run and how many are yet to be run</member>
				<member>(3) Based on the above comparison, onCourse automatically transfers an instalment of
					funds from the Pre Paid Fees account to the Income account.</member>
				<member>(4) This nightly comparison will continue for the duration of the Class until all
						remaining funds are transferred from the Pre Paid Fees account to the Income
						account.</member>
			</simplelist></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>What Happens If I have to Cancel or Add a Session to a Class? </title>
			<para>As you would have noted within the previous section, onCourse runs a nightly comparison of
				the amount of funds in the Pre Paid Fees account against the amount of funds in the
				Income account.</para>
			<para>If for example you have to cancel a session within a given Class, the next time the system
				does an overnight check of the status, it will allow for this cancellation and
				transfer all remaining funds to the Income account. </para>
			<para>Alternatively, if you have to add additional sessions to a Class, the system will
				adjust the nightly installment of funds being transferred to allow for the increased
				number of total hours in the given Class. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>What if I want all funds to be transferred at the commencement of the Class?</title>
			<para>A College may decide that they do not wish to transfer income incrementally across the
				duration of a given Class.</para>
			<para>If you don't want to use this feature within onCourse, you can easily deactivate this
				within the Financial Preferences of your onCourse client.</para>
			<para>By choosing to not assign funds from liability to income in nightly increments, the system
				will instead transfer all funds from the Pre Paid Fees account to the Income account
				the night after the first session of the Class is run. </para>
			<para>Please note that this setting is universal, so all Classes are either assigned
				funds incrementally across the duration of the Class, or the funds are transferred
				in one installment after the first session of the Class is completed. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Assigning Account Codes within onCourse</title>
		<para>The standard onCourse set up comes with a number of generic Account Codes that can be
			assigned to a given Class within onCourse. An organisation also has the ability to add to that
			Account Code list and customise that list to your organisations' requirements. There are no
			limits to the number of Account Codes that can be set up.</para>
		<para>You can add to the standard list of Account Codes via the Financial menu of
			onCourse</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Account_Code_Menu.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select Account from onCourse Financial menu</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Within the Account Code window, you can then add a new Account Code to the System, that
			new code will then be available to be added to any given Class that you create. When adding
			the code, you will need to stipulate what type of account code it will be, either asset,
			liability, equity, income, COS or expense.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Create_New_Account_Code.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Create a new account code</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once you have set up all your Account Codes, you can then assign those codes to a given
			Class via the budget tab of the individual Class, the following example shows how to select
			the relevant income account code for the Class.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Assign_Account_Code_to_Class.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select the required income account code for the given Class</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Remember also that the relevant expense account for Payroll will be brought across from
			the Tutor roles and how they have been set up. For example, the role of Helper could be
			assigned to the expense code of 6000 and the role of Lecturer could be assigned the expense
			code of 6400. </para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Accessing Financial Information from onCourse</title>
		<para>When running any kind of query against onCourse to extract financial information, keep in
			mind that enrolment information is attached to the student and all financial information (such
			as invoices / payments / credit notes) are attached to the debtor within the system. Therefore
			there is no direct data relationship between the student and the debtor.</para>
		<para>There are multiple methods you can use to extract / examine financial information within
			onCourse;</para>
		<section>
			<title>Locating data using related records</title>
			<para>In all onCourse windows, you can track through the relationships between the data using the
				'Find related' function in the cogwheel in the top right hand corner. For example,
				if you wanted to find all the invoices related to the payments in taken on a given
				day, you can select all the payment in records for the day, go to the cogwheel,
				selected 'Find related...' and select invoices. This will open all the related
				invoices in a new window.</para>
			<para>In the new Invoices window, you can run additional queries and or print reports.
				This window has opened in a special state that only ever shows the maximum set of
				results as being the list the generated from your original find related search, so
				all your searches, filters and reports will only relate to this subset of data until
				you close the Invoice list window.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Printed Financial Reports</title>
			<para>onCourse comes with a number of different Financial Reports and each of these are
				looking at one particular aspect or area of the database such as Invoices. You may also wish
				to analyze the financial information that is being generated and you can do this by
				comparing information from one report to the next. </para>
			<para>For example, a data comparison that will enable you to verify the accuracy of the financial
				information is that the Cheque account balance = Payment in - Payment out for the
				same time period.</para>
			<para>New Custom Reports can be developed upon request, just bear in mind the rules of how the
				data is structured within onCourse when considering what kind of information you want to
				have appear on the Report.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Copying info within list view windows to Excel</title>
			<para>Copy and paste list view records into excel. Run your desired query within a given
				window, hi-light the records you want in the list window and copy. Open excel to paste
				records.</para>
			<para>The benefit of this approach is that it allows you to copy information from a number of
				different windows on to the same excel worksheet in order to better compare and verify the
				data.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>CSV Exports</title>
			<para>onCourse enables you to export data directly from onCourse. As is the case with the
				printed reports, these exports are essentially flat tables of data, which means that you are
				only looking at one specific area such as invoices .</para>
			<para>For more information regarding exporting financial data from onCourse, refer to the chapter
				on <link xlink:href="ImportExport">Importing and Exporting</link>.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Exporting to MYOB</title>
			<para>onCourse allows you to generate a text file export of your Financial Data in order to
				import this information directly into MYOB. For more information regarding exporting
				data for MYOB, refer to the following section of the Import Export Chapter on <link xlink:href="#MYOB">Exporting to MYOB.</link></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Running Queries Directly from the Database</title>
			<para>It is possible within onCourse to run queries on information directly from the database
				server. Whether the server runs on Apache Derby or MySQL or MS SQL all of these relational
				databases allow you to query the database directly.</para>
			<para>This allows you write and edit your own custom reports on demand. Instructions are
				available <link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/2.0/manual/reports.html">
					in the reports documentation </link> for downloading an installing a free SQL tool for
				writing your own reports. A high level of familiarity with SQL is required to use this
				function - it is not part of the standard onCourse product support, but an advanced option
				which is also available for your own use. If you do not have these skills in house, custom
				reports can be created for you on request by ish. A quote will be provided for each report. </para>
			<para>From an accountancy perspective, what type of relational database you use is not
				important, the thing you want to be clear about is knowing exactly what data you need to see
				and how you want to see it. </para>
			<para>As an example, if your company wants to run a monthly query against the database which
				tells you all payments received, for which enrolments within a give timeframe, you would
				follow these 4 basic steps.</para>
			<simplelist>
				<member>(1) Define the data you wish to include in your query. It could be the invoice
					number, invoice date, course code and enrolled student first name and last name.</member>
				<member>(2) Define how you want this query to appear, which is as simple as setting up your
					columns within an excel worksheet. By defining this, you are determining the relationship
					between the data.</member>
				<member>(3) Define the date range of the query (in other words, set the date range)</member>
				<member>(4) Run the resulting query against the database</member>
			</simplelist>
			<para>If you run the same query on a monthly basis, once you have worked out Step 1 and 2, the
				only thing you need to do to run the query each month is to update the date range. Once this
				query has been run, you can then import this directly into an excel document and you are
				ready to go.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Banking and Reconciliation</title>
		<para>As funds are received for course payments, onCourse, via the Accounts tab of the onCourse
			client, allows you to bank these funds in your nominated account. You also have the ability to
			run a Reconciliation Statement, to verify that the payments into onCourse match your banking
			report. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Banking</title>
			<para>As onCourse is integrated with a credit card payment gateway, the system will
				automatically settle bank funds received via the credit card gateway. This settlement
				process is automatically done between approximately 7pm and 9pm each evening and will be
				settled into your nominated account the following business day. If a payment is processed
				after the nightly settlement cut off time, the payment will not appear in your nominated
				account until the day after. </para>
			<para>If you have an EFTPOS terminal that you use in conjunction with, or instead of the onCourse
				credit card gateway, ensure you select EFTPOS, rather than EFT or credit card, as
				the payment in type. EFTPOS transactions will be marked as banked on
				creation.</para>
			<para>For all other payments received via Cheque, Electronic Funds Transfer, Money Order or Cash,
				will need to be banked by your accounts department. The 'Deposit Banking' function
				within the onCourse client allows you to track the date of settlement, method of
				payment, payment amount and staff member who performs this function. It also ensures
				that you do not 'double count' any funds to your nominated bank account.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/onCourse_Deposit_Banking_Window.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Deposit Banking Window within Accounts tab of onCourse Client</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Cheque payments would of course be subject to your own banks' timelines on the
				processing of cheques, with the funds not appearing in your account until several days after
				being banked. For Cash Payments and Electronic Funds Transfers, these settlement times are
				more immediate, please check with your bank for exact timelines for processing funds.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Reconciliation</title>
			<para>The reconcile statement function within onCourse client accounts tab allows you to
				verify that onCourse payments match your bank statements. The Reconciliation Report that is
				generated can be run on a weekly or monthly basis, dependent upon your own internal
				financial procedures. The reconciliation report function will provide a line by line
				itemization of all funds that have been reconciled, listed by the relevant income account. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/onCourse_Reconciliation_Statement_Window.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reconciliation Statement Window within Accounts tab of onCourse Client</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
