<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="AVETMISS">
	<title>AVETMISS Reporting</title>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-whatIs">
		<title>What is AVETMISS?</title>
		<para>AVETMISS stands for Australian Vocational Education and Training Management
			Information Statistical Standard.</para>
		<para>In the ASQA Standards for RTO's 2015 - Standard 7, clause 7.5 states "The RTO provides
			accurate and current information on its performance and governance consistent with the
			Data Provision Requirements as updated from time to time." Currently, this means
			mandatory RTO reporting is in line with the <link
				xlink:href="http://www.comlaw.gov.au/Series/F2013L00160Data">Data Provision
				Requirements 2012</link> via both the AVETMISS standard and Quality Indicator data
			for all vocational training learners (both funded and fee for service), unless it is
			exempt under the National VET Provider Collection Data Requirements Policy.</para>
		<para>If you are using onCourse, you're in luck - onCourse is the only free AVETMISS compliant
			student management database currently available to the Australian RTO market that
			exports both to the NCVER National standard and each state's AVETMISS variation for
			funded training. onCourse exports AVETMISS data compliant with the AVETMISS 7 and 8
			standards, including the USI requirements.</para>
		<para>The AVETMISS data you are required to submit are made up of a series of files with
			names like NAT00120. These files must be supplied as plain text in a fixed width format.
			These files are not very easy to create or read by a human as if one character is in the
			wrong place, the whole file can be rejected. The courses, classes, students and outcomes
			you create in onCourse will be exported out of onCourse into these files for you, ready
			to lodge as required.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/AVETMISS_NAT120.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>This is what the NAT000120 file looks like when ready for submission.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>"</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-Lodging">
		<title>What do I have to lodge?</title>
		<para>NCVER publishes the National <link
			xlink:href="https://www.ncver.edu.au/publications/publications/all-publications/statistical-standard-software/avetmiss-vet-provider-collection-specifications-release-8.0">AVETMISS VET Provider
				Specifications and AVETMISS Data Element Definitions.</link> If you don't have a
			copy of these, we recommend downloading them for your reference. Depending on the state
			where you are lodging, you will also need to meet some state specific variations. These
			can be found here: </para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.training.nsw.gov.au/smartandskilled/index.html">New South
				Wales Smart and Skilled</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link
				xlink:href="http://www.training.qld.gov.au/training-organisations/detconnect/index.html"
				>Queensland DETConnect</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link
				xlink:href="http://www.education.vic.gov.au/training/providers/rto/Pages/datacollection.aspx"
				>Skills Victoria</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link
				xlink:href="http://www.dtwd.wa.gov.au/dtwcorporateinfo/wavetenrolementdatastandard/Pages/default.aspx"
				>Western Australia Department of Training and Workforce Development (DTWD)</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link
				xlink:href="http://www.skills.sa.gov.au/for-training-providers/contracting-through-workready"
				>South Australia Department of State Development</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.skills.tas.gov.au/providers/rtos">Skills Tasmania</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.skills.act.gov.au/">Australia Capital
				Territory AVETARS</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="https://nt.gov.au/learning/adult-education-and-training/for-registered-training-organisations-rtos/vet-data-obligations">Northern Territory DET</link>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>The AVETMISS Reporting Standard and File Specifications</title>
		<para>For a detailed explanation of the NCVER Standard AVETMISS 8 Export Standard, and how it relates to onCourse, refer to the <link
			xlink:href="AVETMISS8.html">AVETMISS 8 Chapter.</link>.</para>
		<para>Most states extend and modify the AVETMISS standard, and that information is included
			in this chapter.</para>
		<para>onCourse includes a variety of AVETMISS 'Flavours' to ensure you choose the right type
			of AVETMISS data depending on who you need to give your data to. The specifics about
			these flavours are explained below.</para>
		<para>onCourse flavours are usually related to Funding Contracts in onCourse. You should
			review the <link
				xlink:href="fundingContract.html">Funding Contracts chapter</link> to ensure you have enabled and set up the funding
			contracts and AVETMISS reporting flavours that are required in your training
			organisation.</para>
			<section>
				<title>NCVER (Standard AVETMISS)</title>
				<para>This export is to the AVETMISS VET Provider Collection Specifications National Length
				only, for each of the NAT file specifications. This is the option you should choose
				when reporting directly to NCVER. There are no state 'below the line fields'
				included in this export standard.</para>
			<para>If you require a standard AVETMISS export option with the state specific record
				length, we recommend using the Skills Tasmania export option. There are no special
				below the line rules in Tasmania.</para>
				<para>The standard export option stops at the National Record Collection point for
					each file and doesn't include any of the state specific fields.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>CSO (Community Colleges)</title>
				<para>AVETMISS CSO reporting is for Adult and Community Education customers who receive funding
				under the ACE Provider Contract to deliver the Adult and Community Education
				Community Service Obligation Program (ACE CSO Program) and/or the Tech Savvy Seniors
				(TSS) and Tech Saavy Small Business (TSB) program.</para>
				<para>Although this program is a subset of the NSW Smart &amp; Skilled program it is not
				reported via the usual STSOnline portal. ACE colleges are also expected to lodge the
				entirety of their training data for total VET Activity reporting, where it will be
				collated and sent to NCVER as a sector wide report. Non-VET training activity data
				can also be lodged and it is encouraged that ACE providers do so.</para>
				<para>State specific funded training (e.g. Smart &amp; Skilled) must also be reported via the
				State Training Service portal for that state. Reporting this data elsewhere does not
				exclude you from your reporting requirements for other contracts.</para>
				<para>Customers reporting CSO data are advised to choose this export option in the AVETMISS
				export process. This export option includes the standard below the line
				fields.</para>
				<para>Outcomes code Did Not Start - 66 will export a 66 code if reporting in CSO Flavour. </para>
				<para>Additional export overrides are in place to assist with the correct reporting
					of CSO and TSS data.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>When 'Funding source - state training authority' code begins with CS
							or TSS, then always export 'Fee exemption/concession type identifier' as
							Y and 'Funding source - national' as 11.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>When 'Funding source – state training authority' is equal to CSO, then export CSD (CSO
						is not a valid reporting code, it is the acronym for the project)</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>STSOnline (NSW)</title>
				<para>Smart and Skilled specific reporting requirements are discussed <link
					xlink:href="smartandSkilled.html">Funding Contracts chapter</link>
				</para>
			</section>
		<section>
			<title>DETConnect (Queensland)</title>
			<para>In QLD, AVETMISS reporting is against your State RTO ID, rather than your
				National RTO ID. The National ID must be recorded in onCourse in the AVETMISS
				'Identifier' field for the USI validation process to work. Your QLD RTO ID
				should be entered in the AVETMISS preferences field 'Queensland RTO ID'. This
				value will export in the NAT00010, NAT00020 and NAT00130.</para>
			<para>onCourse will export the Unique Learner Identifier in the NAT00080 where it
				has been provided</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the delivery mode of 90 in the NAT00120
				where the outcome has not been set by the user</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will Only export Hours Attended data where the
				student outcome is marked as withdrawn</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the Full Time Learning option where this
				has been set in the student's enrolment.</para>
			<para>To report for the Certificate 3 Guarantee Program the following fields can be
				used:</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the state specific funding source code
				as it has been entered into the field 'Funding source state' on either the class
				VET tab (for all outcomes in that class), or into the outcome directly (for a
				single outcome).</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the fee exemption code C or N where it
				has been selected in the enrolment record from the QLD only options, for all
				outcomes linked to that enrolment.</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the outcome status 65 (Superseded
				Qualification) where it has been selected for each outcome.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>STELA (South Australia)</title>
			<para>onCourse complies with the SA export standard.</para>
			<para>onCourse will export the value @@ for the Delivery Mode in the NAT00120 if the
				outcome is set as Did Not Start</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120 file, the 'Outcome Identifier - Training Organisation' will be
				exported from the value set in the enrolment.</para>
			<para>In the NAT00120 file the 'Associated Course Identifier (SACE Student ID' will
				be exported from the value set in the enrolment.</para>
			<para>The NAT00120 value for the School Location ID can be set at the outcome level
				in the Hours Attended field as described in the SA AVETMISS variations
				document.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Skills Tasmania</title>
			<para>onCourse will export the client Title in the NAT00085 as Mr if male or Ms if
				female, if not otherwise specified (this was added specifically for Tasmania,
				but applies to all exports)</para>
		</section>
			<section>
				<title>Skills Victoria</title>
				<table frame="all">
					<title>Victorian Specific Data Fields</title>
					<tgroup cols="6" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
						<thead>
							<row>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">NAT file</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">State Description</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">Location in onCourse</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">Can Customer Edit?</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">What is exported</emphasis></entry>
								<entry><emphasis role="bold">Plain English</emphasis></entry>
							</row>
						</thead>
						<tbody>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00010</entry>
								<entry>Software product name</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>Lists the Software product as 'onCourse'</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria you use onCourse for your SMS</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00010</entry>
								<entry>Software Vendor E-mail Address</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry> Lists the contact email 'info@ish.com.au'</entry>
								<entry>Provides a contact details for SkillsVictoria to contact
									ish</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00080</entry>
								<entry>Victorian Student Number (VSN)</entry>
								<entry>Contact Record VET Tab</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>The VSN is exported if entered into onCourse</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria the VSN for that Student ID</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00080</entry>
								<entry>Client Industry of Employment</entry>
								<entry>Contact Record VET Tab</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>The Industry of Employment is exported if entered into
									onCourse</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria the industry the student works in, if
									they work</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00080</entry>
								<entry>Client Occupation Identifier</entry>
								<entry>Contact Record VET Tab</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>The Occupation Identifier is exported if entered into
									onCourse</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria the student's occupation, if they
									work</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00100</entry>
								<entry>Prior Educational Achievement Recognition Identifier</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>Always A for Australian. </entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria if the previous qualification is
									Australian or International</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Program Commencement Date</entry>
								<entry>Class</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>Start date of the class the student is enrolled in</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria when the student's started their
									program</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Eligibility Exemption Indicator</entry>
								<entry>Enrolment</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>The code for the student's eligibility exemption</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria what exemption the student has, if there
									is one</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>VET FEE-HELP (Income Contingent Loan) Indicator</entry>
								<entry>Enrolment</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>Indicates if the student is on VET FEE HELP</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria that student is using VET FEE
									HELP</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Industry Code (ANZSIC)</entry>
								<entry>Class</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>onCourse will only export the ANZIC code only when VET
									Funding Source State data is either LSG, PSG or SSG</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria the ANZSIC for the course based of the
									details on Training.gov.au</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Enrolment Date</entry>
								<entry>Enrolment</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry> the date the enrolment was processed into onCourse, or the
									course start date, which ever is earlier.</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria when the student enrolled in the
									course.</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Enrolment Identifier</entry>
								<entry>Outcomes</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>the record ID of the outcome. This value is not visible or
									editable in the onCourse user interface. NOTE: Once you have
									reported a student via AVETMISS you should not cancel and
									re-enrol in the same unit of competency as their unique ID will
									change.</entry>
								<entry>Gives SkillsVictoria a unique ID for Units of Competency so
									they can track individual units.</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Client Fees-Other</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>Always exported as $0. There is no corresponding field for
									this value in onCourse.</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria if there are fees in addition to the
									course fee. </entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Delivery Provider ABN</entry>
								<entry>General Preferences</entry>
								<entry/>
								<entry>The ABN listed in general preferences. </entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria your RTO's ABN</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00120</entry>
								<entry>Funding Eligibility Key</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>Always exported as blank. There is no corresponding field for
									this value in onCourse.</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria the specific funding eligibility key for
									specific programs such as Skills First</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00130</entry>
								<entry>Program Commencement Date</entry>
								<entry>Class</entry>
								<entry>Yes</entry>
								<entry>Start date of the class the student is enrolled in</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria when the student's started their
									program</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00130</entry>
								<entry>Program Supervised Teaching Activity Completion Date</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>The date of the last session in the student's program</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria when the student finished their training
									delivery.</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>NAT 00130</entry>
								<entry>Program Unique Supervised Hours</entry>
								<entry>System Generated</entry>
								<entry>No</entry>
								<entry>Total Number of hours for all classes attached to the
									certificate.</entry>
								<entry>Tells SkillsVictoria the total planned delivery in hours, as
									opposed to the nominal hours. </entry>
							</row>
						</tbody>
					</tgroup>
				</table>
				<para>This export option is used to report against the Victorian VET Student
					Statistical Collection Guidelines - 2015 v 2015.</para>
				<section>
					<title>Variations on Standard AVETMISS Fields for Skills Victoria</title>
					<para>The RTO ID is prefixed with leading zeros in the NAT0010, NAT00020 and
						NAT0030 as required in Victoria only</para>
					<para>The addresses of your training venues in the NAT00020 are broken into
						building name, flat details, street number and street name fields, like
						student addresses in the NAT00080/85</para>
					<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will Only export Hours Attended data where the
						student outcome is marked as withdrawn</para>
					<para>In the NAT00120 the tuition fee field will be calculated as a per hour
						value, based on the fee charge during enrolment divided by the total nominal
						hours of the course</para>
					<para>The NAT00130 will automatically create a record for a student enrolled in
						a qualification, but not yet complete or issued with a Year Program
						Completed value of @@@@ and Qualification issued flag of N</para>
				</section>
			</section>
		<section>
			<title>STARS (Western Australia)</title>
			<para>WA use a whole different standard again, called RAPT. The files you generate
				when you choose WA RAPT are quite different to the AVETMISS files that are
				generated in other states and territories. See the chapter <link
					xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/rapt.html"
					>about RAPT</link>
			</para>
		</section>
			<section>
				<title>Northern Territories VET Provider Portal &amp; AVETARS (ACT)</title>
				<para>NT &amp; ACT do not have any additional requirements, but they do require the below the
				optional below the line fields to be completed and reported on. </para>
			</section>
	</section>

		<section>
			<title>State Specific NAT000120 fields</title>
			<para>Some states have added extra fields to the AVETMISS standard. These are the ones
				were have added to onCourse. Please let us know if you are asked to provide
				something else that is not in the list below so we can add it to onCourse.</para>
			<section>
				<title>(NSW) Booking ID and (NSW) Course Site ID</title>
				<para>These are set in the Class window on the VET tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(NSW) Training Plan Developed</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(QLD) Full Time Learning Option </title>
				<para>In the Enrolment window on the General Tab there is a Full Time Flag
					(QLD).</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC &amp; QLD) Hours Attended</title>
				<para>This is only used when a student withdraws from a unit without completing it.
					If you need to set the hours attended you can find the field in the Outcome
					record on either the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes Tab. Double
					click the outcome to see this field called 'Reportable Hours'.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Course Commencement Date</title>
				<para>The class start date is always exported here.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Eligibility Exemption indicator</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) VET FEE-HELP (Income Contingent Loan) Indicator</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Industry code (ANZSIC)</title>
				<para>Export the ANZIC code only when VET Funding Source State data is either LSG,
					PSG or SSG</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC and QLD) Student number - VSN or LUI</title>
				<para>This is entered on the contact record AVETMISS tab in the field labelled
					Government Student Number (VIC/QLD)</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/VSN_location.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Enter a VSN or LUI in this field. Data here will only export if you
							are reporting in VIC or QLD</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-CCOS">
		<title>Competency Completion Online System (CCOS)</title>
		<para>With the introduction of national VET reporting for all RTOs, there is no longer a
			requirement for RTOs to report competency completions via CCOS. The tool for this
			reporting is still available in onCourse, however, in case you need to export data for
			previous years under this standard.</para>
		<para>The files required to submit via the CCOS are a little like a cut down version of
			AVETMISS, showing summary data of your training organisation's enrolment and completion
			rates.</para>
		<para>Some users are required to submit these directly, while other RTOs have this data
			extracted from their AVETMISS lodgement data automatically and do not need to submit any
			additional data.</para>
		<para>If you do need to submit this data each year, the three text files can be exported
			from onCourse to upload into the CCOS system as per the import data file format
			requirements outlined in the <link
				xlink:href="http://rto.ncver.edu.au/documents/Competency_Completion_Online_System_Guide.pdf"
				>Competency Completion Online System Guide PDF</link></para>
		<para>You can find this export option in the AVETMISS 6.1 export menu, under the AVETMISS
			flavour 'AQTF Competency Completions'.</para>
		<para>As per other AVETMISS exports, select the data range required and the location where
			you want the export files saved.</para>
		<para>A folder will be created in your chosen location with the files illustrated below. You
			can open these files in a plain text editor, like notepad, if you wish to check and
			confirm the content prior to uploading them.</para>
		<para>The two main files show the enrolments and completions in complete qualifications, and
			the enrolments and completions in single units of competency. Students who enrol in a
			full qualification will also be counted as an enrolment in each unit of competency that
			makes up their qualification.</para>
		<para>Only students who have enrolled in courses marked as 'satisfies complete qualification
			or skill set' are counted as qualification enrolments. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/CCOS_files.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Competency Completion files and example data</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Special default Outcome Status and overrides</title>
		<para>You never need to set an outcomes of 70, 81 or 85 in onCourse. </para>
		<para>In the AVETMISS runner you will see information about outcome statuses that will be set by
			default during the export.</para>
		<para>Any VET outcome that is currently 'in progress' i.e. the end date is in the future,
			will be automatically exported with an outcome of 70, no matter the value set in the
			onCourse database. If the outcome status is unset, a 70 will be exported. If an outcome
			value like a 20 is set, a 70 will be exported. This is because the only valid value for
			an in progress outcome is 70.</para>
		<para>Any non-VET outcome with no status set will be exported as 81. You can manually set a
			non-vet outcome status within onCourse as 82 when it is needed, but there is no need to
			set 81, unless you have a business process that requires it.</para>
		<para>Any outcome that starts in the future will be exported with 85 - Not Yet Started. These
			outcomes are often only included in AVETMISS exports for funding purposes.</para>
		<para>If you have any outcomes where the end date is in the past, and a final outcome status
			has not yet been set, you can use the export runner to locate these outcomes and open
			the list in a new window, so you can set the value.</para>
		<para>Alternatively you can check the option in the export runner that says 'report these as
			continuing enrolment (70) ending 7 days from now' and the export runner will set the end
			date to the outcome to the future and set the value to 70. This saves you having to
			manually change end dates, when a student was predicted to, but didn't actually complete
			an outcome in the expected time frame.</para>
		<para>The information showed in the runner won't change the value stored in onCourse, only
			export the value you need in the AVETMISS files. The onCourse outcome status value will
			remain 'not set' or the other value already set in the database. A count of each of the
			special overrides is displayed in the AVETMISS runner so you can check the outcomes it
			applies to by clicking the open related record icon next to the count.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Automatic Validation errors onCourse fixes for AVETMISS Reporting</title>
			<para>We have also added some global rules to AVETMISS exporting to assist in reducing validation
				errors. These includes things like:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not exporting birth dates for clients younger than 6 or older than 94,
						even where set in the database</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Automatically exporting OSPC as the postcode for students you have
						recorded as international students</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not exporting a value for Proficiency in Spoken English (even when set in
						the database) if you reported the student speaks English as their main
						language</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Export the option 'neither Aboriginal or Torres Straight Islander' for
						Indigenous status for all students born in a country other than Australia
						(or Australian Territory), regardless of their response in the AVETMISS
						questions, as 'neither' is the only option allowed according to AVETMISS
						validation rules. </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Defining the client as Still in School when they are younger than 16 and
						not reporting Still at School for clients who are older than 16 and reported
						as being employed</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Export the training location address as your head office if the training
						is self paced</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Automatically parse student's addresses into the building name, unit
						number, street number and street name components</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Exporting NOT PROVIDED where no suburb has been entered in the student's
						address record</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Exporting NOT PROVIDED for the student's home address where a PO or GPO
						Box address has been provided instead</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setting the delivery mode in the NAT00120 automatically to 90 where the
						outcome is reported as RPL, RCC or credit transfer</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setting the delivery mode in the NAT00120 to 10 - classroom based if it
						has not been set to another value the outcome</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Reporting all scheduled hours as 0 where the outcome is a credit
						transfer</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Automatically calculate the Commencing Course Enrolment Identifier based
						on the students other enrolments</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not report a Study Reason Identifier if the course is non-VET or not a
						full qualification enrolment</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Exporting all non-VET outcomes that have not been set with a status of 81
						and any outcome ending after your chosen reporting period will be exported
						as a 70, regardless of what it has been set as in your data.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Allow user to optionally select to export an outcome of 81 or 90 for any
						VET outcome which is currently not set when exporting their AVETMISS
						data.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Export the client Title in the NAT00085 as Mr if male or Ms if female, if
						not otherwise specified</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Always export at school flag as N if employment status is full time</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Suppress the export of outcomes with status 66 - Did not start unless
						reporting to NSW State Training Services, or South Australia </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Explaining the AVETMISS runner choices</title>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Export to folder: </emphasis> Select a location where a
				folder containing the 10 AVETMISS text files will be created . The location MUST be
				on a local drive, you can not export to a folder on a network drive.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Flavour: </emphasis>This AVETMISS variation type you want to
				export. Often these variations are based on State</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Select enrolments from: </emphasis>This directs the export
				runner to chose certain enrolments based on their Funding Source. If you haven't set
				any funding sources, all your courses will be Fee for service VET (non-funded) by
				default. For 'Fee for Service', you can further refine by delivery state. You can
				select multiple options here.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Date range: </emphasis>The options available here are date
				based and will collect the OUTCOMES that fall into this date range: </para>
			<para><emphasis>commenced outcomes</emphasis> - all outcomes that have a start date in
				the past from the chosen enrolments. Be careful choosing this with 'Fee for service
				VET' or 'Non VET' as you will export every outcome ever created in your onCourse
				database. It is better chosen in combination with a specific Funding Source.</para>
			<para><emphasis>Previous calendar year</emphasis> - this will show in the drop down as a
				date range like '2017 year'</para>
			<para><emphasis>Previous calendar quarter</emphasis> - this will show in the drop down
				as a date range like '1 Jan 2018 - 30 April 2018'</para>
			<para><emphasis>Custom date range</emphasis> - this will display two text fields where you can
				enter your own start and end dates. </para>
			<para>NOTE: AVETMISS reporting is designed to report data in the past, so your date
				range end should be no later than today. </para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Checkbox - Include all outcomes linked by enrolment:</emphasis> When
				running a funded export, you often need to select this option as this collects the
				additional outcomes associated with the funded enrolment that may fall outside the
				outcome date range selected. For example. when reporting to Smart and Skilled, you
				must always report all outcomes associated with the funding, even if they haven't
				yet commenced, or completed in the past. This option is only available when you run
				the AVETMISS export from File > Import/Export. It doesn't display when running from
				the cogwheel, as all outcomes from enrolments are always included.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Checkbox - xxx completed VET outcomes need a status. report these as
					continuing enrolment (70) ending 7 days from now:</emphasis> If the AVETMISS
				pre-run checks find outcomes that ended in the past where you haven't set a final
				status, you can automatically push the outcome end date forward by 7 days and report
				a 70. This does not change the outcome end date in onCourse, only for the data in
				the export file. The find related icon here also allows you to open the records in
				question and actually set a final outcome status if required. Note that if you have
				set an export end date in the future, this setting will not make much sense. e.g. If
				I have an outcome that was due to end next week, it would be reported today as an in
				progress 70. If I set an outcome end date of the end of the calender year, the
				outcome is considered to have been completed, but not properly finalised. Moral to
				the story - don't set an export end date after today's date unless you want some
				funky data issues.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">xxx completed non-Vet outcomes have no status and will be reported as
					satisfactorily completed (81): </emphasis> If you have included non-VET outcomes
				in your export set, then an 81 will be reported for all unset outcomes. Where you
				have manually set another value like 82, that will be reported. The find related
				icon here also allows you to open the records in question and check where this
				override will be applied.</para>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">xxx outcomes will be exported: </emphasis>This is the total
				number of outcomes that the pre-run checks have found that meet your criteria. You
				should check this number matches the value you are expecting, and where needed, use
				the find related icon to view in a list the outcomes about to be exported.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/AVETMISS_override_counts.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Ensure you select the right 'AVETMISS flavour' for the export</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-AVETMISSExports">
		<title>AVETMISS Exports</title>

		<subtitle>How to get your AVETMISS data out of onCourse to submit to the government funding
			body of your choice</subtitle>
		<para>There are four ways to export your data:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export all the total activity data using the file > import/export > AVETMISS</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export all the data for one or more funding contracts using the file > import/export >
					AVETMISS</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export the data related to a class or group of classes, using the
					cogwheel</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export the data related to an enrolment or group of enrolments, using the
					cogwheel</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
					fileref="images/AVETMISS_export_menu.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select AVETMISS export from the menu</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to export data for Total VET Activity Reporting</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the file menu, select <guimenuitem>import/export</guimenuitem> and choose
							<guimenuitem>Export AVETMISS</guimenuitem> and then
							<guimenuitem>AVETMISS 8</guimenuitem></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose an export location. The location MUST be on a local drive, you can
						not export to a folder on a network drive. The 10 text files will then be
						created here in a folder ready to be submitted to the government reporting
						agency of your choice.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the AVETMISS Flavour you wish to report. Total VET Activity will be NCVER
						(Standard AVETMISS).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the funding courses and fee for services state training you wish to include. Not
						all state require you to lodge your Total VET Activity with NCVER,
						particularly if you already have a funding contact. The NCVER (Standard
						AVETMISS) Flavour is only accepted by NCVER and NT. Every other state has
						its own variations.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the date range for your AVETMISS data. By default, the dates will be
						the recent or previous calendar year. You may also select a custom date
						range if you wish.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you run both VET and non-VET training, you may choose to export only VET courses.
						Non-VET training can be exported under the AVETMISS standard as needed, by
						ticking the 'non VET' checkbox but for Total VET Activity Reporting it can
						usually be excluded.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>If running Total VET activity, do not check the option 'include all
					outcomes linked enrolment'. This is used for funded training.</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can optionally select to export all completed but not yet set outcomes with
						continuing enrolment (70) by pushing the end date forward by 7 days. This is
						useful if you have students who have not completed their training on time
						according to their original schedule. However, for Total VET Activity, these
						students should have completed or actually have their end dates manually
						moved. You can use the find related icon next to "x completed VET outcomes
						need a status' to open a list of the outcomes affected and modify the end
						date manually or set a final status if available. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>Outcomes that are still in progress will be automatically exported as 70.
					A count of these is provided.</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The export runner will also indicate the total number of outcomes you have selected. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click Export to complete.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/AVETMISS_export_GUI.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Ensure you select the right 'AVETMISS flavour' for the export</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for a funding contact</title>
			<para>If you have activated a default or custom funding contract in onCourse, you can use this to
				pre-select the enrolments during export.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the file menu, select <guimenuitem>import/export</guimenuitem> and choose
							<guimenuitem>Export AVETMISS</guimenuitem> and then
							<guimenuitem>AVETMISS 8</guimenuitem></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose an export location. The location MUST be on a local drive, you can
						not export to a folder on a network drive. The 10 text files will then be
						created here in a folder ready to be submitted to the government reporting
						agency of your choice.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the AVETMISS Flavour for the lodgement e.g. STSOnline(NSW)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The AVETMISS export flavour chosen will auto select all Funding contract enrolments from
						the contracts associated with that funding. You can tick additional
						checkboxes as needed. Funding Contract types are discussed further in the
							<xref linkend="fundingContract"/> Chapter</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A note on non VET data: Some training contracts, like CSO include non Non-VET training
						courses. If you have set the Funding Source for these courses, the VET and
						non-VET data will be included . However, if you tick 'Non-VET' training
						here, you will export all your non-VET data - not just the non VET data
						attached to the funding source. It would be rare that you want to do this. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the date range for your data. 'Commenced outcomes' is usually the preferred choice
						for funding contract data.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>When running a funded export, you often need to select 'include all outcomes linked by
					enrolment' as this collects the additional outcomes associated with the funded
					enrolment that may fall outside the outcome date range selected. </listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>You can optionally select to export all completed but not yet set outcomes with continuing
						enrolment (70) by pushing the end date forward by 7 days. This is useful if
						you have students who have not completed their training on time according to
						their original schedule. You can use the find related icon next to "x
						completed VET outcomes need a status' to open a list of the outcomes
						affected and modify the end date manually or set a final status if
						available. </para>
					</listitem>
				<listitem>Outcomes that are still in progress will be automatically exported as 70.
					A count of these is provided.</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The export runner will also indicate the total number of outcomes you have selected. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click Export to complete.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example><example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for one or more classes</title>
			<para>You should use the Funding Contract feature instead of this method for exporting, however
				if you need to export a small specific group of records, this feature may be
				useful.</para>
			<para>Sometimes you may wish to export one or a select group of classes only. You can do
				this from the class window.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the class window and run the query or filter to return the classes
						you wish to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight from this list the classes you want to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cog wheel, select AVETMISS export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the funding contract or requirement you are exporting for. You can
						choose to define a date range for the export at this point, or leave it
						blank. Choosing a date range will restrict to exporting the outcomes from
						the class that start or end between the date range. If you leave the dates
						field blank, all outcomes from the class will be exported. Note: Outcomes
						from cancelled classes or enrolments will be exported, if their outcomes
						were retained during the cancellation process.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your files will be saved in a folder in the location you have chosen.
						Locate your files and then upload them to your funding provider.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for one or more enrolments</title>
			<para>You should use the Funding Contract feature instead of this method for exporting, however
				if you need to export a small specific group of records, this feature may be
				useful.</para>
			<para>Sometimes you may wish to export one student's enrolment only, or a selected group
				of enrolments. You can do this from the enrolment window.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the enrolment window and run the query or filter to return the
						enrolments you wish to export. You can search on items like contains 'NSW
						Commitment ID', to find all Smart &amp; Skilled enrolments, or Funding
						source - state begins with CS to find all CSD/CSR coded enrolments for the
						CSO program.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight from this list the enrolments you want to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cog wheel, select AVETMISS export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the State or requirement you are exporting for. You can choose to
						define a custom date range for the export at this point, or leave it blank.
						Choosing a date range will restrict to exporting the outcomes from the
						enrolments that start or end between the date range. If you leave the dates
						field blank, all outcomes from the enrolments will be exported. Note:
						Outcomes from cancelled classes or enrolments will be exported, if their
						outcomes were retained during the cancellation process. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your files will be saved in a folder in the location you have chosen.
						Locate your files and then upload them to your funding provider.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Funding Uploads</title>
		<para>When you run an AVETMISS export, a history of the upload is stored in the funding upload
			window. This history allows you to change the status of the export to record if it was
			successfully exported (and uploaded) to NCVER or your funding provider, or if it failed.
			By adding this information to onCourse, you will have a history stored of each time you
			export your data as is required under various contractual arrangements.</para>
		<para>You can fund the funding upload window under Training > Funding Uploads.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/funding_upload.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The funding upload window showing the history of AVETMISS exports run</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Each funding upload record shows how many outcomes were exported. You can use the find
			related option to look at the outcomes that were exported. Please note: the outcomes may
			have been changed in onCourse since the export was run - when you use the find related
			option you are looking at the outcome values as they exisit right now - not at the time
			of the export.</para>
		<para>By default, each AVETMISS export that successfully completes from onCourse will be set to
			status SUCCESS. If you want to change the status to EXPORTED or FAILED, double click on
			the record in the list view and change the value in the drop down menu.</para>
		<para>An access right control exists for this feature, so each user who needs permission to
			view or edit these records must have the appropriate access right assigned.</para>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>How to give your AVETMISS data to the people who want to pay you</title>
			<para>Either of the methods above will have created a folder on your computer with text files,
			all with file names like NAT00080 and NAT00130. These are things you need to give to the
			government to get paid. Often, you will need to upload them to a website where they will
			be validated.</para>
		<para>NCVER provide a validation tool called AVS (AVETMISS Validation Software) that is often used
			to verify files before submission. You can find this tool at <link
				xlink:href="https://avs.ncver.edu.au/avs/">https://avs.ncver.edu.au/avs/</link>.
			This is also where you need to lodge your Fee For Service Training Activity each year or
			quarter. </para>
			<para>For some types of lodgement you will also need to supply the NAT00085 file. This is
			essentially the same as the NAT00080 but with your students personal addresses and other
			contact details. It will be automatically generated when you create an AVETMISS export.
			Be aware of the privacy implications of supplying this file to third parties. We suggest
			only supplying it when it is a requirement of your funding.</para>
			<para>Your local friendly funding body can help you from here on in if you encounter
				difficulties with their lodgement process. Customers with onCourse support plans can
				also log a task in squish for additional assistance.</para>
		</section>
	<section>
		<title>Validating and correcting AVETMISS errors</title>
		<para>Prior to exporting your AVETMISS data, you may wish to run some reports inside
			onCourse to check the values you have set. These reports can also be useful
			organisational data for other reporting and segmenting of your VET delivery.</para>
		<para>From the classes window, two CSV exports are available. CSV files can be opened in
			Microsoft Excel or other spreadsheet applications. If you ever wished you could easily
			open and read NAT00120 files in Excel, consider this the next best thing.</para>
		<para>Begin by opening the classes window and locating the classes you wish to export,
			through the usual sorts, searches and filters. Once you have located and highlighted the
			classes in the list view choose File > Import/Export > Export Classes</para>
		<para>From the export format list options, choose either 'class outcomes CSV report' or
			'extended outcomes CSV'.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Class Outcomes CSV</title>
			<para>The purpose of this export is to show you all the outcomes and the outcome status
				of the enrolments associated with the classes you've exported. This can be a useful
				way to locate outcomes where the end date has passed but a final result has not yet
				been entered into onCourse.</para>
			<para>This report contains the onCourse student number, student first and last name,
				course-class code, unit of competency code and name, outcome start and end date and
				outcome status.</para>
			<para>Keep in mind this report is showing you the actual data in the onCourse records -
				when you export actual AVETMISS data from onCourse, the export runner values will
				set outcome status 90 for outcomes in progress, and outcome status 70 for outcomes
				that end in future calendar years. The value inside the database will remain as not
				set.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/outcomes_export_excel_output.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Excerpt of student outcomes export viewed via excel </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Extended Outcomes CSV (like NAT00030, NAT00060 &amp; NAT00120)</title>
			<para>This export shows additional data to that listed above, specifically, the
				student's USI, the name of the onCourse course they are enrolled in, onCourse
				subject tags, the qualification code and name if applicable, the course VET flag
				status, the outcome delivery mode, National funding source, state funding source and
				Smart &amp; Skilled Commitment ID.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/extended_outcomes_export.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Excerpt of extended outcomes export viewed via Numbers </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Contact CSV Export (like NAT00080, NAT00085, NAT00090 &amp; NAT00100)</title>
			<para>If you would like to view the data that comprises the student contact records
				(NAT00080, NAT00085, NAT00090 &amp; NAT00100) in a CSV format, you can jump the
				contact records from the class list view to see this information.</para>
			<para>From the list of classes you commenced with in the section above, using the
				cogwheel to Find related to xx selected classes > Enrolled students. This will open
				a list of de-duplicated contact records showing all the students from all of the
				classes in the original selection.</para>
			<para>From this window, choose File > Import/Export > Export Contacts and select Contact
				CSV from the export format list.</para>
			<para>This CSV shows all the student contact details as supplied, as well as their
				response to all of the AVETMISS questions on the student contact VET tab, such as
				their country of birth, labour force status and USI. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Certificate CSV Export (like NAT00130)</title>
			<para> As your Certificate Registrar, onCourse contains all the details of the
				certificates you have issued, be they Statements of Attainment, Skill Set
				Completions or complete Qualifications. The NAT00130 AVETMISS file shows the full
				Qualifications you have created in onCourse for a particular date range.</para>
			<para>To find your certificates in onCourse, open the Certificate window and search for
				the certificate date awarded in the range you require.</para>
			<para>Then with those certificates selected, go to File > Import/Export > Export
				Certificates and choose Certificate CSV Export. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-FAQs">
		<title>AVETMISS FAQ</title>
		<section>
			<title>Can I stop a class and all it's students being exported for AVETMISS?</title>
			<para>Yes. In the class VET tab, select the option 'Do not report for AVETMISS'.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How about a single enrolment, can't I stop that also?</title>
			<para>Yes. In the enrolment general tab, select the option 'Do not report for AVETMISS'.
				This is something you may need to do if reporting a withdrawn Smart &amp; Skilled
				student in NSW.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I get my State Accredited Modules added to onCourse?</title>
			<para>We add custom modules on request for customers with a commercial support contract.
				We need to add them manually to onCourse as they are not published by TGA. You can
				send an Excel file to ish with the following information: Unit code, Unit Title and
				the Field of Education ID (6 characters).</para>
			<para> Once these have been added by us, your onCourse server will download the changes within 48
				hours, and they will be available in the Unit of Competency list with the other
				included units. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Add_manual_units.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>You can provide the list of Units to add to onCourse in an excel
						spreadsheet</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Where do I enter the State Funding Codes in onCourse for the state where I am
				reporting to?</title>
			<para>There are two places where you can set your State Funding Source codes. The first
				in on the VET tab of the class. This is a useful place to set the code when all (or
				most) of the students in the class have the same funding source applying to
				them.</para>
			<para>First you will need to make sure you have an up to date list of the appropriate
				State Funding Codes to use within your reporting state. onCourse doesn't maintain a
				list of these codes, you will need to contact your local reporting officer to obtain
				this information.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Class_State_funding.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enter your State Funding Source code in the field highlighted.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If a student has a different funding code which applies to them, you can just
				change their enrolment funding codes to make it different to the one set at the
				class level. If all students in the class have different funding codes, you don't
				need to set anything at the class level, but can set each outcome separately on the
				enrolment general tab. </para>
			<para>Where the value populates from a record level above, you will see the value in the
				lower level record with the lock icon. In this case, it means the enrolment is
				inheriting the value from the level above, the class. You can click the unlock icon
				to change the value and break the inherited linked value from the class.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/state_field_override_enrolment.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The value of some fields have been inherited from the values set in the
						class, while the Funding Source - State value has been overridden in the
						enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also override these values in the outcome, where needed, for example if
				the student had funding to complete some outcomes but not others, by going to the
				outcome tab and double clicking on an outcome.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/outcome_state_funding.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Funding Source State value for this outcome has been inherited from
						the value set at the enrolment level</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I record a student's outcome who has completed a different elective from
				the rest of class?</title>
			<para>Once you have set up the outcomes at the Course level, every student enrolling in
				a Class from that Course will have all of the outcomes applied to their record. If a
				student chooses a different elective from the one you have set a the course level
				you can change their outcome so it is linked to a different Unit of
				Competency.</para>
			<para>You can do this by going into Class Outcome tab and double clicking on the outcome
				you wish to change. Type the Module code or Module name into the field and click OK
				to link to a new outcome.</para>
			<para>If you wish to add or delete an outcome from the student's record, you need to do
				this from the Enrolment Outcome tab. You will see a + and a - button in the top
				right hand corner. Use these to add or delete outcome records as required. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Adding_outcome.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding an additional Outcome via the student's Enrolment record.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I record information about a clients traineeship?</title>
			<para>When a student is completing a traineeship, you will have been given a 'Training
				Contract Identifier' and a Client 'Identifier' by your state funding body. They may
				call them by different names, but the important thing to confirm is that they are
				the data that exports into the NAT000120 in positions 70 &amp; 80
				respectively.</para>
			<para>This data is entered into the onCourse enrolment window. This data will need to be
				entered after enrolment by going to the Enrolment window, locating the student's
				enrolment record and double clicking on it. On the general tab you will find these
				fields.</para>
			<para>In NSW, you will need to put your Training Contract ID into BOTH of these fields,
				as NSW doesn't issue a separate Client Identifier for trainees.</para>
			<para>If you have broken the traineeship into multiple enrolments, each with one or more
				units of competency, you will need to enter this information into each enrolment
				record for the student that relates to the traineeship. This information is not
				recorded as part of the student's master contact record, as the student may also
				have other enrolment records which don't form part of this traineeship.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/trainee_fields.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Highlighted trainee fields in the student's enrolment record.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why do some outcomes in the NAT000120 export with start and end dates of
				00000000?</title>
			<para>This is a date that has not been defined, e.g. instead of exporting an eight digit
				date like 01012012, it has exported no date, or a string of zeros as
				placeholders.</para>
			<para>What this means is that the class the outcome belongs to has no sessions defined.
				With no sessions, there are no start or end dates available. Also, if you have a
				self paced class where you have not defined the duration, the start date will be the
				date of enrolment as usual, but the end date will default to 12 months after the
				start date.</para>
			<para>Look for any unscheduled or self paced classes in your onCourse records, and add
				either some session information or manual start and end dates to each outcome in the
				class.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why, in the AVETMISS export, do my non-VET courses have codes like ISH123?</title>
			<para>In onCourse version 5.0 we increased the Course Code field length to 32
				characters, to give onCourse Web users more SEO choices for the URL that was created
				for their course page.</para>
			<para>The AVETMISS standard NAT00060 allows for up to 12 characters in the 'subject identifier
				text'. We also have some users who have to report to other government bodies which
				further restrict them to using 8 or 10 of these available characters only as they
				append their own codes to this field.</para>
			<para>While we require course codes in onCourse to be unique, if we only exported the
				first 8 characters of user defined course code, we could very easily end up
				exporting two courses with duplicate codes that then causes an AVETMISS validation
				error. Take, for example course codes ComputerClassSeniors and ComputerClassOpen,
				both which are valid in onCourse and create good URLs like
				www.mycollegename.com.au/course/ComputerClassSeniors and
				www.mycollegename.com.au/course/ComputerClassOpen. </para>
			<para>Exporting the first 8, 10 or 12 characters for these courses would give us the
				identical code 'Computer', 'ComputerCl' or 'ComputerClas', all of which would be
				duplicates. Instead of this possible duplication, we export a made up code that will
				look something like ISH123 and will not ever create duplicate records in the export. </para>
			<para>Keep in mind, that for courses that aren't linked to training packages, the code
				reported in AVETMISS here has no meaning at all - it just has to be a unique
				identifier within your organisation. These 'made up' codes only affect your non-VET
				courses - real VET enrolments are always referenced to the unit(s) of competency
				they student enrolled in</para>
			<para>This does mean if you need to follow up another sort of validation error
				referencing an enrolment in ISH123 you'll need to check your NAT00060 export file to
				see that ISH123, for example is the export code for the course with the name
				'Introduction to Computers for Seniors'.</para>
			<para>As always, we walk the line in meeting the best business, sales and marketing
				functions for your college AND meeting the AVETMISS requirements in the most
				non-onerous way we can. Where these two needs conflict, we will try and code our way
				around it in the export process so we that don't stop you doing what you want in the
				onCourse software.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How does prior learning affect AVETMISS reports?</title>
			<para>Prior learning records only export from AVETMISS exports run from the file >
				import/export >export AVETMISS menu option. They will not export from the cogwheel
				option in the classes or enrolments window, because they are not associated with
				either a class or an enrolment, but instead are attached directly to the
				student.</para>
			<para>When you create a prior learning record with one or more outcomes attached, and the start
				and end dates of the prior learning outcomes fall into the 'outcomes after' to
				-'outcomes before' date range set in the AVETMISS export runner, then the data
				associated with the prior learning record will export.</para>
			<para>At a minimum, to create successful AVETMISS files your prior learning outcomes
				need, in addition to a start date and end date, an outcome status. All other values
				are optional.</para>
			<para>If a Delivery Mode is not set, 'classroom based' will export as the default,
				unless the outcome has an RPL status, in which case the delivery mode ' not
				applicable' will export.</para>
			<para>If the Funding Source - national is not set, then the default funding source set
				in the college preferences will be applied.</para>
			<para>If the prior learning record was linked to a qualification or skills set, then the
				Commencing Program Identifier will export as '3 - commencing enrolment', otherwise
				it will export as '8 - module only enrolment'. </para>
			<para>If the prior learning record was linked to a qualification or skills set, then the
				Study Reason Identifier will export as '11 - other reasons'.</para>
			<para>The VET in Schools flag will always export as No.</para>
			<para>The training location for all prior learning outcomes will be set to your college
				default administration site address.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
