<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="AVETMISS8">
	<title>AVETMISS</title>
	<section><title>Navigation</title>
		<para>Below is the AVETMISS runner window where you select your type of reporting you need to
			do--known in onCourse as 'Flavour'--as well as confirming the data you need included in
			the export. Click the 'Flavour' box to show a drop-down of all the possible
			selections.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS8_blank.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The new-look AVETMISS runner is functionally the same as before</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>You need to ensure you select a date range from the 'Outcomes in progress during' box. You
			can select from a preset date range or year, or choose 'custom date range' and choose
			your own date range. You can also choose to include all outcomes that might be outside
			your selected date range, but are linked to the same enrolment.</para>
		<para>Once you've selected your flavour, the data sets to be included and chosen a date
			range, the 'Find' button will become active. Once you select this, the button will
			change into a loading spinner and the query will run.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS8_selections.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>Example of a custom date range being requested and the active Find button</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once the query has run, you will be presented with a breakdown of all the query's findings.
			You can review the findings here, and if you're happy with them, hit Export. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_results.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption><para>The query results will show the total number of outcomes and enrolments, along with lots
				of other information</para></caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The export itself can take some time to run and varies from database to database depending
			on size. Once it's complete, a small dialogue box wil open asking you to name the .zip
			file that has been created, and where you'd like to save it. Choose an easily
			accessible/easy to remember location and hit Save. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_save.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption><para>After the export has run, name your export .zip file and choose a place to save it</para></caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>VET Provider Collection Specifications</title>
		<section>
			<title>Training Organisation (NAT00010) file</title>
			<para>All the data in this file is collected in the onCourse general preferences window.
				Go to File > Preferences > General. Select the AVETMISS tab and enter the contact
				details of your business. It is important your RTO Identifier and name match the
				details recorded on training.gov.au</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Training Organisation Delivery Location (NAT00020) File</title>
			<para>These are your onCourse sites. Set up each site where you deliver training and
				enter the address details. You can ignore the latitude and longitude fields.
				onCourse will require you to create at least one room for each site (this has
				nothing to do with AVETMISS, it is part of our timetabling feature) so to make it
				simple, give each site a room with a generic name like 'default'.</para>
			<para>It is important that each Australian site you create has an address with a State,
				Suburb and Postcode that matches a value in the Australian Postcode data file. Sites
				in other countries will automatically export OSPC for the postcode value.</para>
			<para>The site you have designated as your Admin site in onCourse will be the site any
				self paced classes will be reported at.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Program (NAT00030) File </title>
			<para>This information comes from the Qualification data entered into the Course VET tab
				where the option 'Satisfies complete qualification or skill set' is ticked.
				Qualification Certificates you create in onCourse also will add records to the
				NAT00030 file. Each Qualification or Skill Set will only be added once.</para>
			<para>If your delivery includes any locally recognised skill sets, qualifications or
				courses (i.e. not from training.gov.au) then a NAT00030A file will be generated
				instead of a NAT00030. This file contains the same rows, but each record has
				additional fields. If you are delivery includes a Smart and Skilled Skills Group,
				for instance, you will generate a NAT00030A file.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Subject (NAT00060) File</title>
			<para>Records that form this AVETMISS file are collected from the units or modules you
				add to your courses, or manually add to student's enrolment records or prior
				learning records. Each unit you deliver is only added once to the NAT00060 file,
				regardless of how many times you deliver it. </para>
			<para>Non-accredited courses, both VET flagged and not VET flagged also add records to
				this file, using their course name and a random ISH code designator. You will also
				see these 'dummy' modules added to the student enrolment record. On the VET tab of
				these courses, you can set the Reportable Hours (Nominal hours in the export) for
				these courses and a six digit Field of Education ID. If you don't set these values,
				the nominal hours will be calculated from the class delivery hours and FoEID
				reported as 129999. Only some types of providers are required to report this
				non-accredited enrolment data under the AVETMISS standard. If you are not required
				to report this data, then there is no need to add Reportable Hours or Field of
				Education data to your course.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Client (NAT00080 &amp; NAT00085) File </title>
			<para>Client AVETMISS files are created from onCourse contact records who have an
				outcome whose dates match the reporting period you've selected on export. Unique
				client identifiers are auto assigned and called 'Student Numbers' in onCourse. You
				don't see these in the contact detail other than in the header bar, but you can
				search on them from the contact window advanced search if you later get a validation
				error for one of your clients.</para>
			<para>The Unique Student Identifier (USI) is reported in the NAT00080 file for each
				student engaged in Vocational Education and Training. Students who have only
				attended non-vocational courses do not need to have a USI supplied for AVETMISS
				reporting. As of 1 January 2017, students studying AQF units will be required to
				have a valid USI. If you do not have a value in the USI field of the NAT00080 file
				the AVS Validation will generate an error. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Disability (NAT00090) File</title>
			<para>This information is taken from the disability info on the student's contact record.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Prior Educational Achievement (NAT00100) File</title>
			<para>Information for this is taken from the prior learning field on the student contact record.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolment (NAT00120) File</title>
			<para>Student specific information is taken from the enrolment, other information is taken from
				the preferences, class, course or funding contract as per above.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Program Completed (NAT000130) File</title>
			<para>This information is taken from the certificates crated in onCourse. Some states will include information from the enrolment as well.</para>

		</section>
	</section>

</chapter>
