<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="AVETMISS">
	<title>AVETMISS Reporting</title>
	<section>
		<title>Explaining the AVETMISS runner choices</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Flavour: </emphasis>This AVETMISS variation type you want to export.
			Often these variations are based on State</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Select enrolments from: </emphasis>This directs the export
			runner to chose certain enrolments based on their Funding Source. If you haven't set any
			funding sources, all your courses will be Fee for service VET (non-funded) by default.
			For 'Fee for Service', you can further refine by delivery state. You can select multiple
			options here.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Date range: </emphasis>The options available here are date based
			and will collect the OUTCOMES that fall into this date range: </para>
		<para><emphasis>commenced outcomes</emphasis> - all outcomes that have a start date in the
			past from the chosen enrolments. Be careful choosing this with 'Fee for service VET' or
			'Non VET' as you will export every outcome ever created in your onCourse database. It is
			better chosen in combination with a specific Funding Source.</para>
		<para><emphasis>Previous calendar year</emphasis> - this will show in the drop down as a
			date range like '2017 year'</para>
		<para><emphasis>Previous calendar quarter</emphasis> - this will show in the drop down as a
			date range like '1 Jan 2018 - 30 April 2018'</para>
		<para><emphasis>Custom date range</emphasis> - this will display two text fields where you
			can enter your own start and end dates. </para>
		<para>NOTE: AVETMISS reporting is designed to report data in the past, so your date range
			end should be no later than today. </para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Checkbox - Include all outcomes linked by enrolment:</emphasis>
			When running a funded export, you often need to select this option as this collects the
			additional outcomes associated with the funded enrolment that may fall outside the
			outcome date range selected. For example. when reporting to Smart and Skilled, you must
			always report all outcomes associated with the funding, even if they haven't yet
			commenced, or completed in the past. This option is only available when you run the
			AVETMISS export from File > Import/Export. It doesn't display when running from the
			cogwheel, as all outcomes from enrolments are always included.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Checkbox - xxx completed VET outcomes need a status. report
				these as continuing enrolment (70) ending 7 days from now:</emphasis> If the
			AVETMISS pre-run checks find outcomes that ended in the past where you haven't set a
			final status, you can automatically push the outcome end date forward by 7 days and
			report a 70. This does not change the outcome end date in onCourse, only for the data in
			the export file. The find related icon here also allows you to open the records in
			question and actually set a final outcome status if required. Note that if you have set
			an export end date in the future, this setting will not make much sense. e.g. If I have
			an outcome that was due to end next week, it would be reported today as an in progress
			70. If I set an outcome end date of the end of the calender year, the outcome is
			considered to have been completed, but not properly finalised. Moral to the story -
			don't set an export end date after today's date unless you want some funky data
			issues.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">xxx completed non-Vet outcomes have no status and will be
				reported as satisfactorily completed (81): </emphasis> If you have included non-VET
			outcomes in your export set, then an 81 will be reported for all unset outcomes. Where
			you have manually set another value like 82, that will be reported. The find related
			icon here also allows you to open the records in question and check where this override
			will be applied.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">xxx outcomes will be exported: </emphasis>This is the total
			number of outcomes that the pre-run checks have found that meet your criteria. You
			should check this number matches the value you are expecting, and where needed, use the
			find related icon to view in a list the outcomes about to be exported.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/AVETMISS_override_counts.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Ensure you select the right 'AVETMISS flavour' for the export</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-AVETMISSExports">
		<title>AVETMISS Exports</title>

		<subtitle>How to get your AVETMISS data out of onCourse to submit to the government funding
			body of your choice</subtitle>
		<para>There are four ways to export your data:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export all the total activity data using the file > import/export > AVETMISS</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export all the data for one or more funding contracts using the file > import/export >
					AVETMISS</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export the data related to a class or group of classes, using the
					cogwheel</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Export the data related to an enrolment or group of enrolments, using the
					cogwheel</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
					fileref="images/AVETMISS_export_menu.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select AVETMISS export from the menu</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to export data for Total VET Activity Reporting</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the file menu, select <guimenuitem>import/export</guimenuitem> and choose
							<guimenuitem>Export AVETMISS</guimenuitem> and then
							<guimenuitem>AVETMISS 8</guimenuitem></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose an export location. The location MUST be on a local drive, you can
						not export to a folder on a network drive. The 10 text files will then be
						created here in a folder ready to be submitted to the government reporting
						agency of your choice.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the AVETMISS Flavour you wish to report. Total VET Activity will be NCVER
						(Standard AVETMISS).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the funding courses and fee for services state training you wish to include. Not
						all states require you to lodge your Total VET Activity with NCVER,
						particularly if you already have a funding contact. The NCVER (Standard
						AVETMISS) Flavour is only accepted by NCVER and NT. Every other state has
						its own variations.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the date range for your AVETMISS data. By default, the dates will be the recent or
						previous calendar year. You may also select a custom date range if you wish.
						Then push the Find button to run your initial query.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you run both VET and non-VET training, you may choose to export only VET courses.
						Non-VET training can be exported under the AVETMISS standard as needed, by
						ticking the 'non VET' checkbox but for Total VET Activity Reporting it can
						usually be excluded.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>If running Total VET activity, do not check the option 'include all
					outcomes linked enrolment'. This is used for funded training.</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can optionally select to export all completed but not yet set outcomes with
						continuing enrolment (70) by pushing the end date forward by 7 days. This is
						useful if you have students who have not completed their training on time
						according to their original schedule. However, for Total VET Activity, these
						students should have completed or actually have their end dates manually
						moved. You can use the find related icon next to "x completed VET outcomes
						need a status' to open a list of the outcomes affected and modify the end
						date manually or set a final status if available. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>Outcomes that are still in progress will be automatically exported as 70.
					A count of these is provided.</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The export runner will also indicate the total number of outcomes you have selected. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click Export to complete. You will be asked to select a location where a folder
						containing the 10 AVETMISS text files will be created . The location MUST be
						on a local drive, you can not export to a folder on a network drive.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/AVETMISS_export_GUI.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Ensure you select the right 'AVETMISS flavour' for the export</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for a funding contact</title>
			<para>If you have activated a default or custom funding contract in onCourse, you can use this to
				pre-select the enrolments during export.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the file menu, select <guimenuitem>import/export</guimenuitem> and choose
							<guimenuitem>Export AVETMISS</guimenuitem> and then
							<guimenuitem>AVETMISS 8</guimenuitem></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose an export location. The location MUST be on a local drive, you can
						not export to a folder on a network drive. The 10 text files will then be
						created here in a folder ready to be submitted to the government reporting
						agency of your choice.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the AVETMISS Flavour for the lodgement e.g. STSOnline(NSW)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The AVETMISS export flavour chosen will auto select all Funding contract enrolments from
						the contracts associated with that funding. You can tick additional
						checkboxes as needed. Funding Contract types are discussed further in the
							<xref linkend="fundingContract"/> Chapter</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A note on non VET data: Some training contracts, like CSO include non Non-VET training
						courses. If you have set the Funding Source for these courses, the VET and
						non-VET data will be included . However, if you tick 'Non-VET' training
						here, you will export all your non-VET data - not just the non VET data
						attached to the funding source. It would be rare that you want to do this. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the date range for your data. 'Commenced outcomes' is usually the preferred choice
						for funding contract data.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>When running a funded export, you often need to select 'include all outcomes linked by
					enrolment' as this collects the additional outcomes associated with the funded
					enrolment that may fall outside the outcome date range selected. </para></listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>You can optionally select to export all completed but not yet set outcomes with continuing
						enrolment (70) by pushing the end date forward by 7 days. This is useful if
						you have students who have not completed their training on time according to
						their original schedule. You can use the find related icon next to "x
						completed VET outcomes need a status' to open a list of the outcomes
						affected and modify the end date manually or set a final status if
						available. </para>
					</listitem>
				<listitem><para>Outcomes that are still in progress will be automatically exported as 70.
					A count of these is provided.</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The export runner will also indicate the total number of outcomes you have selected. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click Export to complete.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example><example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for one or more classes</title>
			<para>You should use the Funding Contract feature instead of this method for exporting, however
				if you need to export a small specific group of records, this feature may be
				useful.</para>
			<para>Sometimes you may wish to export one or a select group of classes only. You can do
				this from the class window.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the class window and run the query or filter to return the classes
						you wish to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight from this list the classes you want to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cog wheel, select AVETMISS export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the funding contract or requirement you are exporting for. You can
						choose to define a date range for the export at this point, or leave it
						blank. Choosing a date range will restrict to exporting the outcomes from
						the class that start or end between the date range. If you leave the dates
						field blank, all outcomes from the class will be exported. Note: Outcomes
						from cancelled classes or enrolments will be exported, if their outcomes
						were retained during the cancellation process.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your files will be saved in a folder in the location you have chosen.
						Locate your files and then upload them to your funding provider.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for one or more enrolments</title>
			<para>You should use the Funding Contract feature instead of this method for exporting, however
				if you need to export a small specific group of records, this feature may be
				useful.</para>
			<para>Sometimes you may wish to export one student's enrolment only, or a selected group
				of enrolments. You can do this from the enrolment window.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the enrolment window and run the query or filter to return the
						enrolments you wish to export. You can search on items like contains 'NSW
						Commitment ID', to find all Smart &amp; Skilled enrolments, or Funding
						source - state begins with CS to find all CSD/CSR coded enrolments for the
						CSO program.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight from this list the enrolments you want to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cog wheel, select AVETMISS export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the State or requirement you are exporting for. You can choose to
						define a custom date range for the export at this point, or leave it blank.
						Choosing a date range will restrict to exporting the outcomes from the
						enrolments that start or end between the date range. If you leave the dates
						field blank, all outcomes from the enrolments will be exported. Note:
						Outcomes from cancelled classes or enrolments will be exported, if their
						outcomes were retained during the cancellation process. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your files will be saved in a folder in the location you have chosen.
						Locate your files and then upload them to your funding provider.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Funding Uploads</title>
		<para>When you run an AVETMISS export, a history of the upload is stored in the funding upload
			window. This history allows you to change the status of the export to record if it was
			successfully exported (and uploaded) to NCVER or your funding provider, or if it failed.
			By adding this information to onCourse, you will have a history stored of each time you
			export your data as is required under various contractual arrangements.</para>
		<para>You can fund the funding upload window under Training > Funding Uploads.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/funding_upload.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The funding upload window showing the history of AVETMISS exports run</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Each funding upload record shows how many outcomes were exported. You can use the find
			related option to look at the outcomes that were exported. Please note: the outcomes may
			have been changed in onCourse since the export was run - when you use the find related
			option you are looking at the outcome values as they exisit right now - not at the time
			of the export.</para>
		<para>By default, each AVETMISS export that successfully completes from onCourse will be set to
			status SUCCESS. If you want to change the status to EXPORTED or FAILED, double click on
			the record in the list view and change the value in the drop down menu.</para>
		<para>An access right control exists for this feature, so each user who needs permission to
			view or edit these records must have the appropriate access right assigned.</para>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>How to give your AVETMISS data to the people who want to pay you</title>
			<para>Either of the methods above will have created a folder on your computer with text files,
			all with file names like NAT00080 and NAT00130. These are things you need to give to the
			government to get paid. Often, you will need to upload them to a website where they will
			be validated.</para>
		<para>NCVER provide a validation tool called AVS (AVETMISS Validation Software) that is often used
			to verify files before submission. You can find this tool at <link
				xlink:href="https://avs.ncver.edu.au/avs/">https://avs.ncver.edu.au/avs/</link>.
			This is also where you need to lodge your Fee For Service Training Activity each year or
			quarter. </para>
			<para>For some types of lodgement you will also need to supply the NAT00085 file. This is
			essentially the same as the NAT00080 but with your students personal addresses and other
			contact details. It will be automatically generated when you create an AVETMISS export.
			Be aware of the privacy implications of supplying this file to third parties. We suggest
			only supplying it when it is a requirement of your funding.</para>
			<para>Your local friendly funding body can help you from here on in if you encounter
				difficulties with their lodgement process. Customers with onCourse support plans can
				also log a task in squish for additional assistance.</para>
		</section>
	<section>
		<title>Validating and correcting AVETMISS errors</title>
		<para>Prior to exporting your AVETMISS data, you may wish to run some reports inside
			onCourse to check the values you have set. These reports can also be useful
			organisational data for other reporting and segmenting of your VET delivery.</para>
		<para>From the classes window, two CSV exports are available. CSV files can be opened in
			Microsoft Excel or other spreadsheet applications. If you ever wished you could easily
			open and read NAT00120 files in Excel, consider this the next best thing.</para>
		<para>Begin by opening the classes window and locating the classes you wish to export,
			through the usual sorts, searches and filters. Once you have located and highlighted the
			classes in the list view choose File > Import/Export > Export Classes</para>
		<para>From the export format list options, choose either 'class outcomes CSV report' or
			'extended outcomes CSV'.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Class Outcomes CSV</title>
			<para>The purpose of this export is to show you all the outcomes and the outcome status
				of the enrolments associated with the classes you've exported. This can be a useful
				way to locate outcomes where the end date has passed but a final result has not yet
				been entered into onCourse.</para>
			<para>This report contains the onCourse student number, student first and last name,
				course-class code, unit of competency code and name, outcome start and end date and
				outcome status.</para>
			<para>Keep in mind this report is showing you the actual data in the onCourse records -
				when you export actual AVETMISS data from onCourse, the export runner values will
				set outcome status 90 for outcomes in progress, and outcome status 70 for outcomes
				that end in future calendar years. The value inside the database will remain as not
				set.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/exports/outcomes_export_excel_output.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Excerpt of student outcomes export viewed via excel </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Extended Outcomes CSV (like NAT00030, NAT00060 &amp; NAT00120)</title>
			<para>This export shows additional data to that listed above, specifically, the
				student's USI, the name of the onCourse course they are enrolled in, onCourse
				subject tags, the qualification code and name if applicable, the course VET flag
				status, the outcome delivery mode, National funding source, state funding source and
				Smart &amp; Skilled Commitment ID.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/extended_outcomes_export.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Excerpt of extended outcomes export viewed via Numbers </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Contact CSV Export (like NAT00080, NAT00085, NAT00090 &amp; NAT00100)</title>
			<para>If you would like to view the data that comprises the student contact records
				(NAT00080, NAT00085, NAT00090 &amp; NAT00100) in a CSV format, you can jump the
				contact records from the class list view to see this information.</para>
			<para>From the list of classes you commenced with in the section above, using the
				cogwheel to Find related to xx selected classes > Enrolled students. This will open
				a list of de-duplicated contact records showing all the students from all of the
				classes in the original selection.</para>
			<para>From this window, choose File > Import/Export > Export Contacts and select Contact
				CSV from the export format list.</para>
			<para>This CSV shows all the student contact details as supplied, as well as their
				response to all of the AVETMISS questions on the student contact VET tab, such as
				their country of birth, labour force status and USI. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Certificate CSV Export (like NAT00130)</title>
			<para> As your Certificate Registrar, onCourse contains all the details of the
				certificates you have issued, be they Statements of Attainment, Skill Set
				Completions or complete Qualifications. The NAT00130 AVETMISS file shows the full
				Qualifications you have created in onCourse for a particular date range.</para>
			<para>To find your certificates in onCourse, open the Certificate window and search for
				the certificate date awarded in the range you require.</para>
			<para>Then with those certificates selected, go to File > Import/Export > Export
				Certificates and choose Certificate CSV Export. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISS-FAQs">
		<title>AVETMISS FAQ</title>
		<section>
			<title>Can I stop a class and all it's students being exported for AVETMISS?</title>
			<para>Yes. In the class VET tab, select the option 'Do not report for AVETMISS'.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How about a single enrolment, can't I stop that also?</title>
			<para>Yes. In the enrolment general tab, select the option 'Do not report for AVETMISS'.
				This is something you may need to do if reporting a withdrawn Smart &amp; Skilled
				student in NSW.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I get my State Accredited Modules added to onCourse?</title>
			<para>We add custom modules on request for customers with a commercial support contract. We need
				to add them manually to onCourse as they are not published by training.gov.au. You
				can send an Excel file to ish with the following information: Unit code, Unit Title
				and the Field of Education ID (6 characters).</para>
			<para> Once these have been added by us, your onCourse server will download the changes within 48
				hours, and they will be available in the Unit of Competency list with the other
				included units. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Add_manual_units.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>You can provide the list of Units to add to onCourse in an excel
						spreadsheet</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Where do I enter the State Funding Codes in onCourse for the state where I am
				reporting to?</title>
			<para>There are two places where you can set your State Funding Source codes. The first
				in on the VET tab of the class. This is a useful place to set the code when all (or
				most) of the students in the class have the same funding source applying to
				them.</para>
			<para>First you will need to make sure you have an up to date list of the appropriate
				State Funding Codes to use within your reporting state. onCourse doesn't maintain a
				list of these codes, you will need to contact your local reporting officer to obtain
				this information.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Class_State_funding.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enter your State Funding Source code in the field highlighted.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If a student has a different funding code which applies to them, you can just
				change their enrolment funding codes to make it different to the one set at the
				class level. If all students in the class have different funding codes, you don't
				need to set anything at the class level, but can set each outcome separately on the
				enrolment general tab. </para>
			<para>Where the value populates from a record level above, you will see the value in the
				lower level record with the lock icon. In this case, it means the enrolment is
				inheriting the value from the level above, the class. You can click the unlock icon
				to change the value and break the inherited linked value from the class.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/state_field_override_enrolment.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The value of some fields have been inherited from the values set in the
						class, while the Funding Source - State value has been overridden in the
						enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also override these values in the outcome, where needed, for example if
				the student had funding to complete some outcomes but not others, by going to the
				outcome tab and double clicking on an outcome.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/outcome_state_funding.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Funding Source State value for this outcome has been inherited from
						the value set at the enrolment level</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I record a student's outcome who has completed a different elective from
				the rest of class?</title>
			<para>Once you have set up the outcomes at the Course level, every student enrolling in
				a Class from that Course will have all of the outcomes applied to their record. If a
				student chooses a different elective from the one you have set a the course level
				you can change their outcome so it is linked to a different Unit of
				Competency.</para>
			<para>You can do this by going into Class Outcome tab and double clicking on the outcome
				you wish to change. Type the Module code or Module name into the field and click OK
				to link to a new outcome.</para>
			<para>If you wish to add or delete an outcome from the student's record, you need to do
				this from the Enrolment Outcome tab. You will see a + and a - button in the top
				right hand corner. Use these to add or delete outcome records as required. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Adding_outcome.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding an additional Outcome via the student's Enrolment record.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I record information about a clients traineeship?</title>
			<para>When a student is completing a traineeship, you will have been given a 'Training
				Contract Identifier' and a Client 'Identifier' by your state funding body. They may
				call them by different names, but the important thing to confirm is that they are
				the data that exports into the NAT000120 in positions 70 &amp; 80
				respectively.</para>
			<para>This data is entered into the onCourse enrolment window. This data will need to be
				entered after enrolment by going to the Enrolment window, locating the student's
				enrolment record and double clicking on it. On the general tab you will find these
				fields.</para>
			<para>In NSW, you will need to put your Training Contract ID into BOTH of these fields,
				as NSW doesn't issue a separate Client Identifier for trainees.</para>
			<para>If you have broken the traineeship into multiple enrolments, each with one or more
				units of competency, you will need to enter this information into each enrolment
				record for the student that relates to the traineeship. This information is not
				recorded as part of the student's master contact record, as the student may also
				have other enrolment records which don't form part of this traineeship.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/trainee_fields.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Highlighted trainee fields in the student's enrolment record.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why do some outcomes in the NAT000120 export with start and end dates of
				00000000?</title>
			<para>This is a date that has not been defined, e.g. instead of exporting an eight digit
				date like 01012012, it has exported no date, or a string of zeros as
				placeholders.</para>
			<para>What this means is that the class the outcome belongs to has no sessions defined.
				With no sessions, there are no start or end dates available. Also, if you have a
				self paced class where you have not defined the duration, the start date will be the
				date of enrolment as usual, but the end date will default to 12 months after the
				start date.</para>
			<para>Look for any unscheduled or self paced classes in your onCourse records, and add
				either some session information or manual start and end dates to each outcome in the
				class.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why, in the AVETMISS export, do my non-VET courses have codes like ISH123?</title>
			<para>In onCourse version 5.0 we increased the Course Code field length to 32
				characters, to give onCourse Web users more SEO choices for the URL that was created
				for their course page.</para>
			<para>The AVETMISS standard NAT00060 allows for up to 12 characters in the 'subject identifier
				text'. We also have some users who have to report to other government bodies which
				further restrict them to using 8 or 10 of these available characters only as they
				append their own codes to this field.</para>
			<para>While we require course codes in onCourse to be unique, if we only exported the
				first 8 characters of user defined course code, we could very easily end up
				exporting two courses with duplicate codes that then causes an AVETMISS validation
				error. Take, for example course codes ComputerClassSeniors and ComputerClassOpen,
				both which are valid in onCourse and create good URLs like
				www.mycollegename.com.au/course/ComputerClassSeniors and
				www.mycollegename.com.au/course/ComputerClassOpen. </para>
			<para>Exporting the first 8, 10 or 12 characters for these courses would give us the
				identical code 'Computer', 'ComputerCl' or 'ComputerClas', all of which would be
				duplicates. Instead of this possible duplication, we export a made up code that will
				look something like ISH123 and will not ever create duplicate records in the export. </para>
			<para>Keep in mind, that for courses that aren't linked to training packages, the code
				reported in AVETMISS here has no meaning at all - it just has to be a unique
				identifier within your organisation. These 'made up' codes only affect your non-VET
				courses - real VET enrolments are always referenced to the unit(s) of competency
				they student enrolled in</para>
			<para>This does mean if you need to follow up another sort of validation error
				referencing an enrolment in ISH123 you'll need to check your NAT00060 export file to
				see that ISH123, for example is the export code for the course with the name
				'Introduction to Computers for Seniors'.</para>
			<para>As always, we walk the line in meeting the best business, sales and marketing
				functions for your college AND meeting the AVETMISS requirements in the most
				non-onerous way we can. Where these two needs conflict, we will try and code our way
				around it in the export process so we that don't stop you doing what you want in the
				onCourse software.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How does prior learning affect AVETMISS reports?</title>
			<para>Prior learning records only export from AVETMISS exports run from the file >
				import/export >export AVETMISS menu option. They will not export from the cogwheel
				option in the classes or enrolments window, because they are not associated with
				either a class or an enrolment, but instead are attached directly to the
				student.</para>
			<para>When you create a prior learning record with one or more outcomes attached, and the start
				and end dates of the prior learning outcomes fall into the 'outcomes after' to
				-'outcomes before' date range set in the AVETMISS export runner, then the data
				associated with the prior learning record will export.</para>
			<para>At a minimum, to create successful AVETMISS files your prior learning outcomes
				need, in addition to a start date and end date, an outcome status. All other values
				are optional.</para>
			<para>If a Delivery Mode is not set, 'classroom based' will export as the default,
				unless the outcome has an RPL status, in which case the delivery mode ' not
				applicable' will export.</para>
			<para>If the Funding Source - national is not set, then the default funding source set
				in the college preferences will be applied.</para>
			<para>If the prior learning record was linked to a qualification or skills set, then the
				Commencing Program Identifier will export as '3 - commencing enrolment', otherwise
				it will export as '8 - module only enrolment'. </para>
			<para>If the prior learning record was linked to a qualification or skills set, then the
				Study Reason Identifier will export as '11 - other reasons'.</para>
			<para>The VET in Schools flag will always export as No.</para>
			<para>The training location for all prior learning outcomes will be set to your college
				default administration site address.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I add the outcome 85 to my AVETMISS data?</title>
			<para>This outcome is not available in the drop down list to set in onCourse because it is a
				transactional outcome status, not a final status. Transitional statuses are outcomes
				that change over the duration of the student's study and just have meaning related
				to the outcome start and end date, like 'in progress' or 'not yet commenced'. 85
				means 'Not Yet Started' therefore, the outcome start date is after the day you run
				the export. If your start and end dates are set to represent the student's intended
				traning plan, 85 will export automatically where it is the only correct value. The
				same process applies to '70 - Continuing Activity', where the outcomes start date is
				before today and end date is after today.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>I set an outcome status in onCourse, but something different came out in the AVETMISS export. Why?</title>
			<para>onCourse includes advanced error correction in the AVETMISS export process to reduce the
				error rate during the reporting process. For example, if you have an outcome end
				date after the export end date (or today, if you have entered no export end date),
				then the only valid outcome is '70 - Continuing Activity' because the outcome is
				still in progress. If you have set a final outcome, like '20 - Competency Achieved'
				but the end date is in the future, then 70 will be exported because it is the only
				valid status for the date range.</para>
			<para>Note that if your tutors use the SkillsOnCourse portal to set outcomes, it will
				automatically set the outcome end date to the day a final status is set, reducing
				the instance of this issue.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why can I add the outcome 70 to my AVETMISS data if it applies automatically when it's required? </title>
			<para>For the management purposes of enrolments with complex and changing training plans, some
				organisations like to manually set 70 to indicate a student has actually commenced
				their scheduled training, and leave the outcomes that are yet to commence as 'not
				set'. This can be a second process check along with ensuring the training plan dates
				in onCourse are accurate.</para>
			<para>There is no need to ever set 70 in onCourse for accurate AVETMISS reporting, but
				you can set 70 for other, intenal data management, reasons.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
