<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="AVETMISS">
	<title>AVETMISS Reporting</title>
	<section>
		<title>What is AVETMISS?</title>
		<para>AVETMISS stands for Australian Vocational Education and Training Management
			Information Statistical Standard.</para>
		<para>In the AQTF 2010, Condition 6 Certification &amp; Issuing of Qualifications &amp;
			Statements of Attainment states: "The RTO must have a student records management
			database in place that has the capacity to provide the registering body with AVETMISS
			compliant data." and the Standard for NVR Registered Training Organisations 2012 in SNR
			12: Strategy for certification, issuing and recognition of qualifications and statements
			of attainment, "SNR 12.4 require the applicant to identify how it will provide returns
			of its client records of attainment of units of competence and qualifications to the
			National VET Regulator on a regular basis. "</para>
		<para>If you are using onCourse, you're in luck - onCourse is the <link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/node/1538">only free AVETMISS compliant</link>
			student management database currently available to the Australian RTO market. onCourse
			exports AVETMISS data compliant with the 6.1 VET Provider specifications and the
			AVETMISS 7 standard, including the USI requirements in effect as of January 1
			2015.</para>
		<para>The AVETMISS data you are required to submit are made up of a series of files with
			names like NAT00120. These files must be supplied as plain text in a fixed width format.
			These files are not very easy to create or read by a human as if one character is in the
			wrong place, the whole file can be rejected. The courses, classes, students and outcomes
			you create in onCourse will be exported out of onCourse into these files for you, ready
			to lodge as required.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_NAT120.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>This is what the NAT000120 file looks like when ready for submission.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>"</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>What do I have to lodge?</title>
		<para>NCVER publishes the National <link xlink:href="http://www.ncver.edu.au/avetmiss/21055.html">AVETMISS VET Provider
				Specifications and AVETMISS Data Element Definitions.</link> If you don't have a
			copy of these, we recommend downloading them for your reference. Depending on the state
			where you are lodging, you will also need to meet some state specific variations. These
			can be found here: </para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="https://www.training.nsw.gov.au/training_providers/training_market/doing_business/index.html">New South Wales</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.training.qld.gov.au/training-organisations/detconnect/index.html">Queensland</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.education.vic.gov.au/training/providers/rto/Pages/datacollection.aspx">Victoria</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.dtwd.wa.gov.au/dtwcorporateinfo/wavetenrolementdatastandard/Pages/default.aspx">Western Australia</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.skills.sa.gov.au/for-training-providers/skills-for-all-training-providers/skills-for-all-training-provider-contract">South Australia</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.skills.tas.gov.au/providers/rtos">Tasmania</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.det.act.gov.au/training/vet_admin">Australia Capital
				Territory</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.education.nt.gov.au/rto">Northern Territory</link>
		</para>
		<para>
			<link xlink:href="http://www.ncver.edu.au/wps/portal/vetdataportal/ncversupport/supportsubsupport/NCVER-Standard-Support">National Competency Completion Online System (CCOS)</link>
		</para>
		<section>
			<title>Training Organisation (NAT00010) file</title>
			<para>All the data in this file is collected in the onCourse general preferences window.
				Go to File > Preferences > General. Select the AVETMISS tab and enter the contact
				details of your business.</para>
			<para>In Queensland, you are required to report your QLD Provider ID in place of the
				National ID. You will need to enter this number in the 'Identifier' field prior to
				your export. You may wish to change this field back to your National ID after
				export, as the data from here is also used to generate your Certificates.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Training Organisation Delivery Location (NAT00020) File</title>
			<para>These are your onCourse sites. Set up each site where you deliver training and
				enter the address details. You can ignore the latitude and longitude fields.
				onCourse will require you to create at least one room for each site (this has
				nothing to do with AVETMISS, it is part of our timetabling feature) so to make it
				simple, give each site a room with a generic name like 'default'.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Course (NAT00030) File and Module/Unit of Competency (NAT00060) File</title>
			<para>This information comes from the onCourse Course detail (what we call a 'course' in
				onCourse is different to what AVETMISS calls a course). When you create a new course
				in onCourse, go to the VET tab and add the Qualification and Unit(s) that you are
				delivering as part of this program. All the TGA (training.gov.au) data is built in
				so when you start typing the code, the rest of the unit information will appear to
				select from the list. You can set up full qualification courses here or short
				courses with one or more units. </para>
			<para>As you add the units, add the nominal hours information to each unit. </para>
			<note>
				<para>Currently TGA doesn't record or publish the module details of state accredited
					courses. If you would like us to add the accredited course modules you deliver
					to onCourse, please contact us and we will import them for you at no additional
					charge. This service is available for customers on any of our commercial support
					plans.</para>
			</note>
			<para>To get students enrolled into courses, you will next need to create one or more
				classes, then use Quick Enrol to enrol your students. </para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/courses.html">More instructions on how to create a course</link>
			</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/classes.html">More instruction on how to create classes</link>
			</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/processingEnrolments.html">More instruction on how to enrol students</link>
			</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://trainingsupport.otte.vic.gov.au/p_trgpck.cfm">Link to
					Victorian Nominal Hours</link>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Client (NAT00080) File and Client Postal Details (NAT00085) File and Disability
				(NAT00090) File and Prior Educational Achievement (NAT00100) File </title>
			<para>Client files in onCourse are called contacts. Create each of your students as
				contacts in onCourse, ensuring you fill in their address details and the data on the
				AVETMISS tab. Unique client identifiers are auto assigned. You don't see these in
				the contact detail, but you can search on them from the contact window if you later
				get a validation error for one of your clients.</para>
			<para>To meet the AVETMISS 7 changes, onCourse automatically splits addresses into the
				required building name, unit name, street number and street name fields for export.
				In the user interface, the address field remains the same - enrolling students and
				administrative staff only need to enter the data in a single field.</para>
			<para>The Unique Student Identifier (USI) is reported in the NAT00080 file for each
				student engaged in Vocational Education and Training. Students who have only
				attended non-vocational courses do not need to have a USI supplied for AVETMISS
				reporting. </para>
			<para>You are required to validate each student's USI against their first name, last
				name and date of birth with the USI Registry System. If you have an onCourse support
				plan and have supplied us with your AusKey, onCourse will do this automatically for
				each USI supplied.</para>
			<para>For more information on creating and validating USIs, please refer to the <link xlink:href="#usi">USI chapter.</link></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolment (NAT00120) File</title>
			<para>This is the biggest and most critical file - all the detail about what students
				have enrolled in and completed and whether or not your going to get payment for it.
				This information comes from a variety of locations in onCourse, so field by field
				we'll cover it here:</para>
			<section>
				<title>Training Organisation Delivery Location Identifier</title>
				<para>This is a reference back to the site you have set up.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Identifier</title>
				<para>This is a reference back to the student you have set up.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Module/Unit of Competency Identifier</title>
				<para>If you set the unit in the course, and have enrolled your student in a class,
					an outcome record will be created for each unit. But if you have a student who
					chooses a different elective or you need to add or remove units for an
					individual student, open the enrolment window, find the enrolment you want to
					modify and on the outcome tab, make the appropriate changes.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Qualification/Course Identifier</title>
				<para>This is a reference back to the course you have set up. This field is only
					populated if you marked the course as a 'full qualification' in onCourse.
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enrolment Activity Start Date and Enrolment Activity End Date</title>
				<para>This is set in the class you have enrolled the student in. When you set up a
					class in onCourse, set a start date and time and end date and time on the
					General tab. If you need to modify the start or end date for an individual
					student, you can do it through the enrolment (as described above) or through the
					class window by looking on the Outcome tab and changing the date in the field
					for the student/unit combination of your choice. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Delivery Mode Identifier</title>
				<para>This is set in the Class on the VET tab. You can also make changes for
					individual students on the Outcome list or through their individual
					enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Outcome Identifier - National</title>
				<para>You can set the outcome identifier (we call it status) on the Outcomes tab in
					the Class window. If you select all the records in the list and right click on
					them, you can set them all to 'Successful (20)' and then go back and change the
					others that should be other statuses (like RPL or Not Yet Competent) one by one.
					Or you can set them all one by one, whichever you prefer.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Scheduled Hours</title>
				<para>The scheduled hours reported are the nominal hours that you set in the unit of
					competency. If you added the nominal hours when setting up the course it will
					report here. You can override the Scheduled Hours in the individual
					outcome.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Funding Source - National</title>
				<para>You can set this in the class window on the VET tab, but change it for each
					outcome in the class Outcomes tab or for each student in their Enrolment record
					on the General tab. Double click the outcome to see this field.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Commencing Course Identifier</title>
				<para>If the student was enrolled in a class linked to a course marked as a full
					qualification, then we output the value 3 - Commencing enrolment in a
					qualification or course. If the enrolment was not linked to a course marked as a
					full qualification, then this will export as 8 - Unit of competency or module
					only enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Training Contract Identifier - New Apprenticeships and Client Identifier -
					New Apprenticeships</title>
				<para>This information can be entered on the General tab on the student
					Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Study Reason Identifier</title>
				<para>You can provide an answer to this question during the enrolment process, or
					after enrolment by going to the General tab on the student Enrolment.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>VET in Schools Flag</title>
				<para>This is always reported as N (for no)</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Outcome Identifier - Training Organisation</title>
				<para>This field is always exported as blank.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Funding Source - State Training Authority</title>
				<para>You can enter this information in the Class VET tab or in the individual
					student's outcome record on the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes
					tab. Double click the outcome to see this field.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Client Tuition Fee</title>
				<para>This is the fee you charged the student at the time of enrolment, divided by
					the total nominal hours in the course, multiplied by the nominal hours of each
					unit to set a proportional student fee for each unit. To charge a fee, set a
					class fee in the Class General tab. VET courses are usually GST exempt. During
					the enrolment process, you can charge the student the full fee or give them a
					manual discount if they meet fee exemption criteria. The fee they pay here is
					what is reported. Create a full cash payment for each student. Don't worry about
					the invoices that are automatically created here - they have nothing to do with
					AVETMISS.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Fee Exemption/Concession Type Identifier</title>
				<para>This is set in the student's Enrolment record on the General Tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Purchasing Contract Identifier and Purchasing Contract Schedule
					Identifier</title>
				<para>These are set in the class on the VET tab</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Hours Attended</title>
				<para>This is only used when a student withdraws from a unit without completing it.
					If you need to set the hours attended you can find the field in the Outcome
					record on either the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes Tab. Double
					click the outcome to see this field.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>State Specific NAT000120 fields</title>
			<para>Some states have added extra fields to the AVETMISS standard. These are the ones
				were have added to onCourse. Please let us know if you are asked to provide
				something else that is not in the list below so we can add it to onCourse.</para>
			<section>
				<title>(NSW) Booking ID and (NSW) Course Site ID</title>
				<para>These are set in the Class window on the VET tab.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(NSW) Training Plan Developed</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(QLD) Full Time Learning Option </title>
				<para>In the Enrolment window on the General Tab there is a Full Time Flag
					(QLD).</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC &amp; QLD) Hours Attended</title>
				<para>This is only used when a student withdraws from a unit without completing it.
					If you need to set the hours attended you can find the field in the Outcome
					record on either the Class Outcomes Tab or the Enrolment Outcomes Tab. Double
					click the outcome to see this field called 'Reportable Hours'.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Course Commencement Date</title>
				<para>The class start date is always exported here.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Eligibility Exemption indicator</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) VET FEE-HELP (Income Contingent Loan) Indicator</title>
				<para>Exported from the option set the Enrolment record value from the field of the
					same name.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC) Industry code (ANZSIC)</title>
				<para>Export the ANZIC code only when VET Funding Source State data is either LSG,
					PSG or SSG</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>(VIC and QLD) Student number - VSN or LUI</title>
				<para>This is entered on the contact record AVETMISS tab in the field labelled
					Government Student Number (VIC/QLD)</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/VSN_location.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Enter a VSN or LUI in this field. Data here will only export if you
							are reporting in VIC or QLD</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Qualification Completed (NAT000130) File</title>
			<para>To record student completion of a qualification in onCourse, you must create a
				qualification certificate for them.</para>
			<para>onCourse will create AQF compliant certificates for your students, but for the
				purposes of lodging AVETMISS, you don't need to print or issue them. </para>
			<para>To create a Certificate record, open the certificate window and click plus. Type
				the name of the student and the qualification you wish to issue and choose the
				outcomes from the student's record you wish to add to the certificate. Check the
				option 'qualification' and save the record.</para>
			<para>Alternatively, you can do this automatically from the class list or enrolment list
				records by highlighting the records you want to create certificates for and
				selecting the cogwheel 'create certificates' function. If the enrolment or class is
				linked to a course where 'satisfies requirements for a complete qualification' is
				ticked, then a Qualification will be created, otherwise it will default to a
				Statement of Attainment. Only Qualification completions are reported in the NAT00130
				file.</para>
			<para>If you are exporting a NSW DET export, and have set all the outcomes for an
				enrolment (e.g. they are no longer blank) a NAT000130 file will be automatically
				created for you, even if you have not delivered a full qualification to the student.
				This is because NSW DET uses the NAT00130 file for a different purpose than the
				national standard. </para>
			<para>If you are exporting to Victoria, the student intent to complete a certificate
				will be recorded here also. This record is created when a student is enrolled into a
				class linked to a course where 'satisfies requirements for a complete qualification'
				is ticked. Until you create the Certificate record on their successful completion,
				the record will contain an 'N' for not issued.</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/rto.html">More
					information on creating Certificates in onCourse</link>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Competency Completion Online System (CCOS)</title>
		<para>The files required to submit via the CCOS are a little like a cut down version of
			AVETMISS, showing summary data of your training organisation's enrolment and completion
			rates.</para>
		<para>Some users are required to submit these directly, while other RTOs have this data
			extracted from their AVETMISS lodgement data automatically and do not need to submit any
			additional data.</para>
		<para>If you do need to submit this data each year, the three text files can be exported
			from onCourse to upload into the CCOS system as per the import data file format
			requirements outlined in the <link xlink:href="http://rto.ncver.edu.au/documents/Competency_Completion_Online_System_Guide.pdf">Competency Completion Online System Guide PDF</link></para>
		<para>You can find this export option in the AVETMISS 6.1 export menu, under the AVETMISS
			flavour 'AQTF Competency Completions'.</para>
		<para>As per other AVETMISS exports, select the data range required and the location where
			you want the export files saved.</para>
		<para>A folder will be created in your chosen location with the files illustrated below. You
			can open these files in a plain text editor, like notepad, if you wish to check and
			confirm the content prior to uploading them.</para>
		<para>The two main files show the enrolments and completions in complete qualifications, and
			the enrolments and completions in single units of competency. Students who enrol in a
			full qualification will also be counted as an enrolment in each unit of competency that
			makes up their qualification.</para>
		<para>Only students who have enrolled in courses marked as 'satisfies requirements for
			complete qualification' are counted as qualification enrolments. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/CCOS_files.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Competency Completion files and example data</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="AVETMISSreporting-AVETMISSExports">
		<title>AVETMISS Exports</title>
		<subtitle>How to get your AVETMISS data out of onCourse to submit to the government funding
			body of your choice</subtitle>
		<para>There are two ways to export your data. One is via a date based range and the other is
			by selecting one or more particular classes you want to export. The date based export
			will export every outcome in your database (including non-VET outcomes) that have
			activity during the period you have selected. This type of export is useful for
			customers who need to report their entire business activity to a monitoring or funding
			agency. Choosing this type of export will automatically export an outcome of 70 for all
			outcomes which have end dates outside the reporting range you define. You never need to
			set an outcome of 70 in onCourse. All non-VET outcomes will also be exported as 81,
			unless you have manually defined them within onCourse as 82..</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_export_menu.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Select AVETMISS export from the menu</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to export date range AVETMISS data</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the file menu, select <guimenuitem>import/export</guimenuitem> and
						choose <guimenuitem>Export AVETMISS...</guimenuitem></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the state you are exporting to. AVETMISS standard is only accepted
						by NT. Every other state has its own variations. The AQTF Competency
						Completion report is also available to select from this menu. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can optionally select to export all blank outcomes with the value 81.
						This is useful only for testing purposes where you are trying to identify
						lodgement errors other than blank outcomes.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Select the date range you wish to export and where you wish to export the
						files to, e.g. your desktop, and select proceed. The 10 text files will then
						be created ready to be submitted to the government reporting agency of your
						choice.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_export_GUI.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Ensure you select the right 'AVETMISS flavour' for the State where you
					report</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for one or more classes</title>
			<para>Sometimes you may wish to export one or a select group of classes only. You can do
				this from the class window.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the class window and run the query or filter to return the classes
						you wish to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight from this list the classes you want to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cog wheel, select AVETMISS export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the State or requirement you are exporting for. You can choose to
						define a date range for the export at this point, or leave it blank.
						Choosing a date range will restrict to exporting the outcomes from the class
						that start or end between the date range. If you leave the dates field
						blank, all outcomes from the class will be exported. Note: Outcomes from
						cancelled classes can not be exported.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your files will be saved in a folder in the location you have chosen.
						Locate your files and then upload them to your funding provider.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>How to export AVETMISS for one or more enrolments</title>
			<para>Sometimes you may wish to export one student's enrolment only, or a selected group
				of enrolments. You can do this from the enrolment window.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the enrolment window and run the query or filter to return the
						enrolments you wish to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight from this list the enrolments you want to export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the cog wheel, select AVETMISS export</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the State or requirement you are exporting for. You can choose to
						define a date range for the export at this point, or leave it blank.
						Choosing a date range will restrict to exporting the outcomes from the
						enrolments that start or end between the date range. If you leave the dates
						field blank, all outcomes from the enrolments will be exported. Note:
						Outcomes from cancelled or credited enrolments can not be exported.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Your files will be saved in a folder in the location you have chosen.
						Locate your files and then upload them to your funding provider.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<section>
			<title>Validation Rules and State Variations in AVETMISS Reporting</title>
			<para>While there is a National Standard known as AVETMISS, each state in Australia
				tends to use a slightly different variation on that standard. We have also added
				some global rules to AVETMISS exporting to assist in reducing validation errors.
				These includes things like:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not exporting birth dates for clients younger than 6 or older than 94,
						even where set in the database</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Automatically exporting OSPC as the postcode for students you have
						recorded as international students</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not exporting a value for Proficiency in Spoken English (even when set in
						the database) if you reported the student speaks English as their main
						language</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not exporting a value for Indigenous Status (even when set in the
						database) if you reported that the student was born in a country other than
						Australia, or Australian Territory</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Defining the client as Still in School when they are younger than 16 and
						not reporting Still at School for clients who are older than 16 and reported
						as being employed</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Exporting NOT PROVIDED where no suburb has been entered in the student's
						address record</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setting the delivery mode in the NAT00120 automatically to 90 where the
						outcome is reported as RPL, RCC or credit transfer</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Reporting all scheduled hours as 0 where the outcome is a credit
						transfer</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Automatically calculate the Commencing Course Enrolment Identifier based
						on the students other enrolments</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not report a Study Reason Identifier if the course is non-VET</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Exporting all non-VET outcomes that have not been set with a status of 81
						and any outcome ending after your chosen reporting period will be exported
						as a 70, regardless of what it has been set as in your data.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Allow user to optionally select to export an outcome of 81 or 90 for any
						VET outcome which is currently not set when exporting their AVETMISS
						data.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Export the client Title in the NAT00085 as Mr if male or Ms if female, if
						not otherwise specified</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<section>
				<title>AVETMISS Standard</title>
				<para>This export is to the AVETMISS VET Provider Collection Specifications National
					Length only, for each of the NAT file specifications. Customers reporting in NSW
					using the OLIV portal are advised to use this export option. Note that the NSW
					only outcome of 66 will be exported under the standard export, to meet the
					requirements of colleges reporting via OLIV who have also delivered NSW funded
					training during the year. Clients using this export in other states are advised
					not to apply the outcome 66 (Did not start) to their data. SA customers must use
					the SA version to export @@ for a 'Did not start' outcome.</para>
				<para>The standard export option stops at the National Record Collection point for
					each file and doesn't include any of the state specific files.</para>
				<para>If you require a standard AVETMISS export option with the state specific
					record length, we recommend using the TAS export option.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>NSW DET</title>
				<para>This export option is for reporting to the NSW Training Market and meets the
					requirements of the ePayments Factsheet 4.3 - March 2014 Data Specifications.
					This means you will export blank spaces for the outcome where the outcome has
					not been set for this option.</para>
				<para>Any data reported for training delivered from 1/1/2014 will need to be
					reported against the AVETMISS 7 standard. Only training that completed in 2013
					can be reported against the AVETMISS 6.1 Standard.</para>
				<para>NSW has three special NSW only 'below the line' fields that are used in
					reporting. They are the Booking ID (NAT00120 position 143), Course Site ID
					(NAT00120 position 153) and Training Plan developed (NAT00120 position 163). The
					first two fields can be found in the class VET tab, with the Training Plan
					developed field located on the enrolment general tab.</para>
				<para>When reporting, the way your data is set up will determine if the export will
					trigger an initial, midway or final payment.</para>
				<para>An initial payment will be triggered the first time you lodge the data for a
					new student and course combination. Usually you would report some or all of the
					units of competency that the student will be completing during the course, but
					with no outcome status.</para>
				<para>NSW also likes to see that the start and end dates of the various units in the
					course are not all the same i.e. they do not all start and end on the same day.
					We recommend you use the training plan feature in the class timetable to vary
					the start and end dates across the course duration.</para>
				<para>A midway payment is determined when you show progress in the course. This
					could be because you have enrolled the student in additional units of
					competency, or because the student has achieved an outcome for some of the units
					of competency you reported in the initial lodgement.</para>
				<para>If you try to report after the initial, a changed status where all the units
					have an outcome, this will trigger the midway and final payment in one
					action.</para>
				<para>Keep in mind that you will always get an error if you try to report a
					student's final outcome status prior to the outcome end date. If you do have a
					final status you wish to report, then change the outcome end date to a date
					prior the day you want to lodge the data.</para>
				<para>The special difference between a midway and final payment is the generation of
					the NAT00130 (course completion) record. onCourse generates this automatically,
					you don't need to set anything in the student's record.</para>
				<para>The NAT00130 record file is created to indicate the student's enrolment is
					completed. There is a record created for this file either because all their
					outcomes from the class are set and all the outcome end dates are before the end
					date of the export specified. If all of the outcomes have a successful status
					(e.g. competent, RPL granted, credit transfer ect) and the enrolment was in a
					class linked to a course marked as 'satisfies requirement for a complete
					qualification' then the NAT00130 will have a Y, for a successful course
					completion. If any of the outcomes have an unsuccessful status (e.g. withdrawn,
					not yet competent, did not start) for a full qualification enrolment, or the
					enrolment was in a short course then the NAT00130 will output a N for
					non-qualification completion.</para>
				<para>If you are doing a final export you must ensure you choose an end date before
					the day of export but after the last end date of the outcomes when exporting -
					initial and midway exports don't need the outcome start and end dates
					specified.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Victoria</title>
				<para>This export option is used to report against the Victorian VET Student
					Statistical Collection Guidelines – 2014 v 2014.3.2</para>
				<para>At the end of the NAT00010 file, the additional data 'onCourse' is exported
					with our email address, 'info@ish.com.au'</para>
				<para>The addresses of your training venues in the NAT00020 are broken into building
					name, flat details, street number and street name fields, like student addresses
					in the NAT00080/85</para>
				<para>If supplied, you can export the Victorian Student Number in the
					NAT00080</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse automatically exports the Course Commenced Date from
					the start date of the class the student is enrolled in</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will only export the ANZIC code only when VET
					Funding Source State data is either LSG, PSG or SSG</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will Only export Hours Attended data where the
					student outcome is marked as withdrawn</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120 the tuition fee field will be calculated as a per hour value,
					based on the fee charge during enrolment divided by the total nominal hours of
					the course</para>
				<para>The NAT00130 will automatically create a record for a student enrolled in a
					qualification, but not yet complete or issued with a Year Program Completed
					value of @@@@ and Qualification issued flag of N</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Queensland</title>
				<para>onCourse will export the Unique Learner Identifier in the NAT00080 where it
					has been provided</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the delivery mode of 90 in the NAT00120
					where the outcome has not been set by the user</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will Only export Hours Attended data where the
					student outcome is marked as withdrawn</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the Full Time Learning option where this
					has been set in the student's enrolment.</para>
				<para>To report for the Certificate 3 Guarantee Program the following fields can be
					used:</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the state specific funding source code
					as it has been entered into the field 'Funding source state' on either the class
					VET tab (for all outcomes in that class), or into the outcome directly (for a
					single outcome).</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the fee exemption code C or N where it
					has been selected in the enrolment record from the QLD only options, for all
					outcomes linked to that enrolment.</para>
				<para>In the NAT00120, onCourse will export the outcome status 65 (Superseded
					Qualification) where it has been selected for each outcome.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tasmania</title>
				<para>onCourse will export the client Title in the NAT00085 as Mr if male or Ms if
					female, if not otherwise specified (this was added specifically for Tasmania,
					but applies to all exports)</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>South Australia</title>
				<para>onCourse will export the value @@ for the Delivery Mode in the NAT00120 if the
					outcome is set as Did Not Start</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Northern Territory &amp; the Australian Capital Territory</title>
				<para>NT &amp; ACT do not have any additional requirements, but they do require the
					below the optional below the line fields to be completed and reported on. We
					recommend using the TAS export for NT or ACT.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Western Australia</title>
				<para>WA use a whole different standard again, called RAPT. The files you generate
					when you choose WA RAPT are quite different to the AVETMISS files that are
					generated in other states and territories. See the chapter
						<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/rapt.html">about RAPT</link>
					
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How to give your AVETMISS data to the people who want to pay you</title>
			<para>Either of the methods above will have created a folder on your computer with text
				files, all with funny names like NAT00080 and NAT00130. These are things you need to
				give to the government to get paid. Often, you will need to upload them to a website
				where they will be validated.</para>
			<para>For some types of lodgement you will also need to supply the NAT00085 file. This
				isn't outlined above, but is essentially the same as the NAT00080 but with your
				students personal addresses and other contact details. It will be automatically
				generated when you create an AVETMISS export. Be aware of the privacy implications
				of supplying this file to third parties. We suggest only supplying it when it is a
				requirement of your funding.</para>
			<para>Your local friendly funding body can help you from here on in if you encounter
				difficulties with their lodgement process. Customers with onCourse support plans can
				also log a task in squish for additional assistance.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>AVETMISS FAQ</title>
		<para>Want to know something specific about onCourse and AVETMISS? Post your question in
				<link xlink:href="http://forum.ish.com.au/categories/avetmiss">our forums</link>.
			Response to common questions will be added here also.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Can I stop a class and all it's students being exported for AVETMISS?</title>
			<para>Yes. In the class VET tab, select the option 'Do not report for AVETMISS'.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I get my State Accredited Modules added to onCourse?</title>
			<para>We add custom modules on request for customers with a commercial support contract.
				We need to add them manually to onCourse as they are not published by TGA. You can
				send an Excel file to ish with the following information: Unit code, Unit Title and
				the Field of Education ID (6 characters).</para>
			<para> Once these have been added by us, your onCourse server will download the changes
				within 48 hours, and they will be available in the Unit of Competency list with the
				other included units. You may like to also read the information <link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/download-install.html">about Trouble Shooting Connection Problems</link> if the units do not download
				automatically.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Add_manual_units.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>You can provide the list of Units to add to onCourse in an excel
						spreadsheet</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Where do I enter the State Funding Codes in onCourse for the state where I am
				reporting to?</title>
			<para>There are two places where you can set your State Funding Source codes. The first
				in on the VET tab of the class. This is a useful place to set the code when all (or
				most) of the students in the class have the same funding source applying to
				them.</para>
			<para>First you will need to make sure you have an up to date list of the appropriate
				State Funding Codes to use within your reporting state. onCourse doesn't maintain a
				list of these codes, you will need to contact your local reporting officer to obtain
				this information.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Class_State_funding.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enter your State Funding Source code in the field highlighted.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>If a student has a different funding code which applies to them, you can just
				change their outcomes funding codes to make it different to the one set at the class
				level. If all students in the class have different funding codes, you don't need to
				set anything at the class level, but can set each outcome separately. Double click
				on the outcome line in the Class Outcomes tab to set this information. You can also
				access this list from the individual student's Contact or Enrolment record.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Outcome_State_Funding.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enter your State Funding Source code in the field highlighted for each
						outcome.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I record a student's outcome who has completed a different elective from
				the rest of class?</title>
			<para>Once you have set up the outcomes at the Course level, every student enrolling in
				a Class from that Course will have all of the outcomes applied to their record. If a
				student chooses a different elective from the one you have set a the course level
				you can change their outcome so it is linked to a different Unit of
				Competency.</para>
			<para>You can do this by going into Class Outcome tab and double clicking on the outcome
				you wish to change. Type the Module code or Module name into the field and click Ok
				to link to a new outcome.</para>
			<para>If you wish to add or delete an outcome from the student's record, you need to do
				this from the Enrolment Outcome tab. You will see a + and a - button in the top
				right hand corner. Use these to add or delete outcome records as required. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Adding_outcome.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding an additional Outcome via the student's Enrolment record.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I record information about a clients traineeship?</title>
			<para>When a student is completing a traineeship, you will have been given a 'Training
				Contract Identifier' and a Client 'Identifier' by your state funding body. They may
				call them by different names, but the important thing to confirm is that they are
				the data that exports into the NAT000120 in positions 70 &amp; 80
				respectively.</para>
			<para>This data is entered into the onCourse enrolment window. This data will need to be
				entered after enrolment by going to the Enrolment window, locating the student's
				enrolment record and double clicking on it. On the general tab you will find these
				fields.</para>
			<para>In NSW, you will need to put your Training Contract ID into BOTH of these fields,
				as NSW doesn't issue a separate Client Identifier for trainees.</para>
			<para>If you have broken the traineeship into multiple enrolments, each with one or more
				units of competency, you will need to enter this information into each enrolment
				record for the student that relates to the traineeship. This information is not
				recorded as part of the student's master contact record, as the student may also
				have other enrolment records which don't form part of this traineeship.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/trainee_fields.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Highlighted trainee fields in the student's enrolment record.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why do some outcomes in the NAT000120 export with start and end dates of
				00000000?</title>
			<para>This is a date that has not been defined, e.g. instead of exporting an eight digit
				date like 01012012, it has exported no date, or a string of zeros as
				placeholders.</para>
			<para>What this means is that the class the outcome belongs to has no sessions defined.
				With no sessions, there are no start or end dates available. Also, if you have a
				self paced class where you have not defined the duration, the start date will be the
				date of enrolment as usual, but the end date will default to 12 months after the
				start date.</para>
			<para>Look for any unscheduled or self paced classes in your onCourse records, and add
				either some session information or manual start and end dates to each outcome in the
				class.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why, in the AVETMISS 7 export, do my non-VET courses have codes like
				ISH123?</title>
			<para>In onCourse version 5.0 we increased the Course Code field length to 32
				characters, to give onCourse Web users more SEO choices for the URL that was created
				for their course page.</para>
			<para>The AVETMISS 7 standard NAT00060 allows for up to 12 characters in the 'subject
				identifier text'. We also have some users who have to report to other government
				bodies which further restrict them to using 8 or 10 of these available characters
				only as they append their own codes to this field.</para>
			<para>While we require course codes in onCourse to be unique, if we only exported the
				first 8 characters of user defined course code, we could very easily end up
				exporting two courses with duplicate codes that then causes an AVETMISS validation
				error. Take, for example course codes ComputerClassSeniors and ComputerClassOpen,
				both which are valid in onCourse and create good URLs like
				www.mycollegename.com.au/course/ComputerClassSeniors and
				www.mycollegename.com.au/course/ComputerClassOpen. </para>
			<para>Exporting the first 8, 10 or 12 characters for these courses would give us the
				identical code 'Computer', 'ComputerCl' or 'ComputerClas', all of which would be
				duplicates. Instead of this possible duplication, we export a made up code that will
				look something like ISH123 and will not ever create duplicate records in the export. </para>
			<para>Keep in mind, that for courses that aren't linked to training packages, the code
				reported in AVETMISS here has no meaning at all - it just has to be a unique
				identifier within your organisation. These 'made up' codes only affect your non-VET
				courses - real VET enrolments are always referenced to the unit(s) of competency
				they student enrolled in</para>
			<para>This does mean if you need to follow up another sort of validation error
				referencing an enrolment in ISH123 you'll need to check your NAT00060 export file to
				see that ISH123, for example is the export code for the course with the name
				'Introduction to Computers for Seniors'.</para>
			<para>As always, we walk the line in meeting the best business, sales and marketing
				functions for your college AND meeting the AVETMISS requirements in the most
				non-onerous way we can. Where these two needs conflict, we will try and code our way
				around it in the export process so we that don't stop you doing what you want in the
				onCourse software.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
