<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  version="5.0" xml:id="budgets">
  <title>Budgets</title>
  <para>The budget feature is enabled with some paid onCourse support contracts. Check your
    college's support agreement to see if this feature has been enabled for your
    organization.</para>
  <para>Use the Class budget feature to determine whether Classes are profitable, predict how many
    more enrolments they need to break even and create projected budgets across groups of Classes.
    You can compare actuals against projected income and expenses to determine whether your
    marketing planning needs adjustment in some areas of your course delivery.</para>
  <section>
    <title>Budget overview</title>
    <para>The following is a list of common terms and definitions used within the onCourse Budget feature </para>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Enrolment Income</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Class fees paid by students enrolled in a Class</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Other Income</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Income such as fee subsidies that are separate to enrolment income</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Expenditure</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Costs incurred in running the Class</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Sunk Costs</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>A cost that would be incurred even if the Class does not proceed, sunk
            costs can also be referred to as a "fixed" cost. </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Running Cost</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>A cost that is only occurred if the Class proceeds, running costs can also
            be referred to as a "variable" cost.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <example>
      <title>How to create a Class budget</title>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Go to the Budget tab in the Class window. Here you can see a list of income and
            expenses for the Class, plus a summary of the Actual and Projected income and expenses. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>If you have already added a tutor and added a payroll amount, you may already have a
            cost assigned for the tutor wage. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>To add a tutor wage, you need to have already assigned the tutor to the Class. You
            can then define the rate and any associated oncosts. Note that for the tutor wage to be
            automatically calculated, the tutors name has to be ticked for the sessions they are
            teaching in the Class timetable.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Expenses can also be added. These may include items like room hire, student
            textbooks and advertising charges. Some expenses may be considered 'sunk', that is, they
            are incurred even if the Class is cancelled. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>The Actual summary will show the income and expense given the current students
            enrolled in the Class. To set an estimate, or budget, type the number of expected
            students in the Projected field. The income and expenses will then be calculated
            accordingly. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>From the Class list window, a range of budget reports are available to assist you
            with evaluating your program profitability. The Budget Details report shows line by line
            detail of the budget you have created. The Budgets report will show a summary of the
            actual and projected income and expense for a selection of Classes. </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </example>
    
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
          fileref="images/class_budget_tab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>
        <para>The budget tab of the Class displays a summary view of the budget, including projections and break even information</para>
      </caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </section>
  
    <section>
      <title>Adding and Editing Budget Items</title>
 <para>Additional income and wages for a Class can be recorded via the budget tab so the
      profitability of a Class can be accurately calculated for your actual and projected
      enrolments. Clicking on the + sign on the top right hand side will bring you three
      options:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Expense/Cost</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Income/Funding</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Wages</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>For each item you wish to add to the budget, you can choose if the cost is calculated
      based on an hourly amount, a per student contact hour amount (per student per hour), per
      enrolment, per session or fixed. As these reference items change e.g. when another student
      enrols or when you add more time to the Class duration, the budget items will automatically
      adjust.</para>
    <para>Expense items can be capped at maximums and minimums for the Class, have GST applied as
      needed, have oncosts associated with them (e.g. super, on top of wages) and be deemed as sunk
      costs.</para>
    <para>A sunk cost is the cost you will incur even if the Class is cancelled, for example you may
      considering advertising as a sunk cost. Using sunk costs is important in a detailed budget as
      it will assist you in determining if it is financially viable to run a Class even if the sunk
      costs have not been met.</para>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
          fileref="images/add_new_budget_item.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>
        <para>Adding a new budget item</para>
      </caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>As you continue to add items to the Class budget, such as the tutor wage, room hire fees,
      student fee income, applicable government funding income, resourcing costs and others, the
      actual and projected summaries will update automatically.</para>
        <para>If you need to delete a budget line item, simply highight the entry and the click on
      the trash can icon for that line. If you wish to edit a line entry, simply double click on the
      entry to bring up the edit window. </para>
      
      <section>
        <title>Budget as calculation tool</title>
        <para>An important part of the budget calculations are the projected enrolment numbers you
        have estimated. This number is an estimate of how many students you believe will enrol in
        the Class and is used to calculate the figures under the 'Projected' column in the budget
        tab.</para>
        <para>The budget will then calculate the enrolment number required to go ahead (meet your
        refundable costs) and the enrolments required to profit (meet your refundable and sunk
        costs). This information is displayed both on the general and budget tabs of a given Class. </para>
        <tip>
          <para>If you do not enter any expense items for a given Class budget, the information on
          the number of enrolments required to make a profit that is found on the general and budget
          tabs will be suppressed. </para>
        </tip>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
              fileref="images/class_budget_calculation_general_tab.png" /> 
          </imageobject>
          <caption>
            <para>The general tab of the Class provides a top level budget summary and the required
              number of enrolments to cover running costs</para>
          </caption>
        </mediaobject>
      </section>
    <section>
      <title>Tracking Discounts via the Budget tab</title>
      <para>As well as reflecting all fee income within a given Class, the budget tab allows you to
        track discounts. With each discount type listed as a line item within the budget.</para>
      <para>When defining the paramaters of a given discount, you can also enter an estimated
        percentage of students within a given Class who are likely to take up this discount. This
        figure is set within the value tab of the discount and is identified as the default forecast
        take up. </para>
    <para>The default forecast take up of a given discount will be applied to all Classes that have
        that discount, but if you wish to adjust the take up percent figure on one Class, you can do
        this by double clicking on the discount line item within the budget tab of that Class. </para>
      <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
          fileref="images/forecast_uptake_for_discount.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>
        <para>When setting the values of a given discount, you can enter a default forecast take up amount</para>
      </caption>
    </mediaobject>
      
      <para>Once a discount has been assigned to the Class and you have entered a figure for the
        projected number of enrolments that are likely to be received for a given Class via the
        budget tab, the budget will calculate the discount amount based upon the percentage of
        projected enrolments that are likely to take up that discount. </para>
      <para>The dollar value of discounts given during the enrolment process will be visible in the
        budget tab against their corresponding discount strategy.</para>
      <para>If you give a manual discount during enrolment, the balance will be deducted from the
        total income field, but not visible in the discounts section of the budget tab as it is not
        linked to a pre-exisiting discount strategy.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Manual Invoices</title>
    <para>.................. </para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%"
          fileref="images/Manual_invoice_lines.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>
        <para>Adding an invoice line to a manual invoice</para>
      </caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>.................. </para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="90%" contentdepth="90%"
          fileref="images/Manual_invoice.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>
        <para>Adding a manual invoice</para>
      </caption>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>.................. </para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
          fileref="images/budgets_manual_invoices.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>
        <para>What a manual invoice looks like in the Budget tab of a Class</para>
      </caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </section>
</chapter>
