<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
	version="5.0" xml:id="cancellingEnrolments">
	<title>Cancellations, Transfers and Refunds</title>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-single">
		<title>Cancelling a single enrolment</title>
		<para>It is important to remember that within the accrual financial system of onCourse, that
			every action has an opposite. When an enrolment is created, an invoice is generated to the
			payer. When the payer pays the invoice, a payment in record is created. If you want to cancel
			an invoice or refund a payment, you need to generate an equal and opposite record. To reverse
			an invoice, you create a credit note (a negative invoice) and to give someone back their
			money, you need to create a payment out. This section outlines the common processes involved
			in creating credit notes and refunds.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to cancel a single enrolment</title>
			<para>If you need to remove a student from a class, due to them withdrawing or failing to
				attend, you need to cancel their enrolment. If you wish to provide them with a credit note
				or refund (either full or partial) you can do this at the time of the enrolment
				cancellation. </para>
			<para>The first step is to cancel and credit the existing enrolment.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Find the enrolment in the Enrolments window</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight the enrolment by clicking on it</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the cogwheel option in the top right hand corner and choose "Cancel 1
						enrolment". This will bring up a dialog with a checkbox offering to also
						refund the paid enrolment fee. If you keep this ticked, you will create a
						create note as part of this process. If you uncheck it, you will retain all
						the student's fees as part of your business income.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Hit "Proceed".</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>An automatic message window will open for you to email and/or SMS the
						student's to notify them. You can edit this message in the window before
						sending, or close the window to cancel the sending of the message
						altogether.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/cancellation_message.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Automated message text for student's whose enrolments have been cancelled</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This process will cancel the enrolment, and create a credit note in the system for the
				value of the existing enrolment. Note that the credit note will apply to the
				original payer of the invoice. This may not be the student who enrolled in the
				class, but their employer, parent or other third party.</para>
			<para>If the invoice originally issued for this enrolment remains unpaid, the credit
				note created will create an automatic contra payment against that invoice, in effect
				'cancelling' it from requiring payment.</para>
			<para>If the originating invoice was paid in full, the credit note can be used to contra
				pay another outstanding invoice from that debtor, if you choose. You can manually
				select this option from the invoice list window in the cog wheel options.</para>
		</example>
		<tip>
			<para>Please note that a payment back to the student will not be automatically created after
				cancelling an enrolment. That student might want use the credit to enrol into another class.
				Or you may wish to contact the student and arrange a refund. The next sections explain these
				options in detail.</para>
		</tip>
		<para>The ourcomes linked to the enrolment with the status 'not set' will get automatically
			deleted unless you uncheck the checkbox. You can also elect to charge a cancellation fee
			(with or without tax) as per your college policies. The difference between the fee paid,
			and the cancellation fee charged will be available as credit to the student, or can be
			refunded to them. By default the students will also be issued with a credit note email.
			You can select to have this administrative fee deposited into the income account of your
			choice. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/cancel_enrolment.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Cancelling an enrolment and charging a cancellation fee</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-creditNote">
		<title>Creating a manual credit note</title>
		<para>On occasion, you may need to create a credit note of refund for a student with out
			using the enrolment cancellation process. This may be because you wish to offer the
			student a credit to apply to further training (perhaps their was problem with the class
			they attended), because they purchased another product outside of the class enrolment,
			or because you created a credit note for the wrong amount during the enrolment
			cancellation.</para>
		<para>Before you can issue any type of refund, you must create a credit note. You can do
			this manually in the invoice window </para>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a manual credit note</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Begin by opening the Invoice window. In the top right hand corner are a
						plus and minus button. Click on the plus</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the new Invoice record window, type the name of the contact you wish to
						give the credit note/refund too. The contact needs to already exist within
						onCourse. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the invoice lines section of the window, click on the plus button to
						add charges/credits to the record. Give your item a title, select the
						general ledger income account it will be debited from, enter the appropriate
						negative amount in the 'Price Each Ex Tax' field. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter any other relevant information and save the credit note. You will
						now see in the list view window an unbalanced invoice for a negative amount.
						This is the credit note.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Manual_credit_note.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Creating a manual credit note</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-Discounts">
		<title>Manual discounts after enrolment</title>
		<para>Sometimes students enrol in classes and pay the full fee, and after enrolment they
			realise a discount needs to be provided as the student was eligible for a reduced
			enrolment fee.</para>
		<para>In onCourse, when a discount is issued the COS account Discounts Given is credited and
			the chosen income account is debited. </para>
		<para>To create a manual discount, follow the steps above to issue a manual credit note, but
			enter an amount in the Discount Each ex tax field. This will create a credit note, but
			add the cost of the discount to the COS account, just like if it was taken during the
			enrolment.</para>
		<para>Please note that discounts processed manually will not be linked to the class and will
			not show in the class budget.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-usingCredit">
		<title>Using the credited amount as credit towards another enrolment</title>
		<para>Contacts with credit will appear in the invoices window as 'unbalanced' invoices,
			showing with a negative balance. The next time the contact enrols, or pays for another
			student's enrolment, they will automatically be offered their credit to use towards
			their fees in the Quick Enrol process.</para>
		<para>This information will show in the bottom of the quick enrol window next to previous
			owing as a minus amount. The amount due for payment will automatically adjust. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/credit_note_qe.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A student enrolling in a class with a credit note of $132 automatically
					applied to their balance</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-paymentReversals">
		<title>Payment reversals within the payment in window</title>
		<para>If you want to reverse a payment, you can do this in the Payments In window by doing
			the following steps:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>In onCourse go to "Accounts" then "Payment In"</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Highlight the payment in record to be reversed</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click on the cog wheel and select "Reverse payment"</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click reverse of the new pop up window to confirm you want to the record to be
					reversed</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<note>
			<para>Only 1 payment In item can be reversed at one time and the date of reversal will
				be set as today's date</para>
		</note>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/payment_in_reverse_payment.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>View of the payments in window when trying to reverse a payment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/payment_in_reverse_payment_confirmation.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Confirmation window that pops up when trying to reverse a payment</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-PaymentOut">
		<title>Refunding a student via Payment Out</title>
		<para>If you wish to give a contact back their money, you need to create a payment out
			record. You can return cash to the payer, write a cheque, or if they have paid by a
			credit card through onCourse (not via an EFTPOS terminal) you can automatically reverse
			the payment back to their card. Manual credit card reversals can also be done through an
			EFTPOS terminal, but you will need to contact the payer to get their card details first. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>If you refund a fee via an EFTPOS terminal, you will still need to record a
				payment out entry within onCourse, simply select payment type 'EFT'.</para>
		</tip>
		<example>
			<title>How to refund a student</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In onCourse go to "Accounts" then "Payment Out"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the name of the contact who has the credit note</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> You will see the total balance of their credit notes available to be
						refunded. Some contacts may have multiple credit notes. You can refund all
						or a part of their total balance. You can not refund more than the total
						balance.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Chose the method with which you wish to refund the contact. If you choose
						credit card, any available transaction will be available from the list to
						reverse. The list of available transactions is ordered by date with the most
						recent transaction at the top of the list. As shown in the example below.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Save the payment out record. The contacts credit note balance will be
						reduced by the amount you have just refunded.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/payment_out_via_credit_card.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Selecting the credit card transaction to be refunded from the drop down
					list</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>A few notes on onCourse credit card reversals</title>
			<para>onCourse does not store credit card numbers. What it does store is a transaction
				reference number supplied by the bank. This transaction reference number allows you
				to reverse up to the original amount paid during the transaction. This means you can
				refund the payer with complete confidence that the payment is being returned to the
				original credit card that paid for the enrolment.</para>
			<para>There are some limitations that you need to be aware of however:</para>
			<para>1. Credit card transactions are only available to reverse up to three months after
				the initial date of purchase. An attempted refund to a transaction older than this
				will fail.</para>
			<para>2. Each transaction can only be reversed ONCE. This means that if a single
				transaction paid for multiple enrolments, say 3 x $100 enrolments with one
				transaction of $300, and one enrolment is cancelled and refunded to the value of
				$100, the remaining $200 can not be refunded from the same transaction. If you want
				to refund the remaining $200 you will need to contact the person for their card
				number and process it manually though an EFTPOS terminal. This is a limitation
				imposed by the banks, not onCourse.</para>
			<para>3. You can only refund UP TO the original amount of the transaction. You can not
				refund the student more than they paid per transaction. For example, if two $100
				enrolments we paid for in separate credit card transactions by the same contact and
				both cancelled and eligible for a refund, you would need to process two payments out
				of $100 each, once against each transaction.</para>
			<para>4. If the credit card you are attempting to refund has been cancelled by it's
				owner, or expired, the attempt to refund it will fail. You will need to contact the
				student and arrange an alternate refund method.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/accounts_paymentout.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a payment out record for a refund processed</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-cancellingAClass">
		<title>Cancelling A Class</title>
		<para> If your class is not financially viable, or needs to be cancelled for other reasons,
			onCourse has the tools to allow you to cancel the enrolments, notify the students,
			refund the students or provide them with credit notes, and use their credit to book them
			in to another, or the next available class. </para>
		<para>You can use the onCourse communication tools to contact the students and notify them
			that their class has been cancelled, to see what kind of tool are available, see <link
				xlink:href="#messages">messaging</link> to notify students that the class has been
			cancelled go to "Class" and search for the cancelled class , then click on the cog wheel
			on the top right hand side of the window and select "send message to students from 1
			class". You need to do this before you cancel the class. If you wish to print a class
			roll or other report to note student responses against, you should also do this before
			cancelling a class. Once a class is cancelled, all student enrolments are changed from
			'active' to 'cancelled' preventing them from printing on standard reports or being
			contacted as students of the class.</para>
		<para>To cancel the class, select the class in the classes window and from the cogwheel option at
			the top right, select "cancel class". This action will credit the students with any
			amount paid (or the payer of the enrolment, if someone other than the student paid)
			allowing you to refund them, or use the credit towards another enrolment. By default all
			the students will also be issued with a credit note email. You may also choose to apply
			an administrative fee if you wish. </para>
		<para>An automatic message window will open for you to email and/or SMS the student's to
			notify them. You can edit this message in the window before sending, or close the window
			to cancel the sending of the message altogether.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
					fileref="images/cancel_class.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Cancelling a class</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="cancellingEnrolments-Transfers">
		<title>Student Transfers</title>
		<subtitle>How To Transfer A Student From One Class To Another</subtitle>
		<para>If you wish to transfer a student, first you need to cancel their existing enrolment,
			then enrol them into a new class.</para>
		<para>Follow the steps above for cancelling a single enrolment. This will cancel the
			enrolment, and create a credit note in the system for the value of the existing
			enrolment. </para>
		<para>Now open a quick enrol screen and enrol the student into the new class that they wish
			to pursue, as per the instructions above to enrol a student in credit.</para>
		<section>
			<title>What if the value of the new enrolment is more expensive than the old class or
				less expensive?</title>
			<para> As onCourse tracks the amount owing for the student, no money is lost by the system by
				cancelling and refunding (be careful: as just canceling the enrolment will not do
				anything to the amount owing - if you also want to provide credit for a transfer or
				refund you need to tick the checkbox 'create a credit note to refund student for the
				amount charged') </para>
			<para> At the quick enrol stage, you may choose to charge them a transfer fee (click on the '+'
				symbol) next to "Other Charges", or give them a discount or concession if you wish. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Why can't I just edit the existing enrolment? </title>
			<para> onCourse tracks enrolments and financial data in a way which leaves a complete
				audit trail. So at any time you will be able to see all the enrolment history for
				every student, including enrolments they have withdrawn from. This is very important
				for financial auditing and system security reasons which especially when several
				staff might be making changes or looking at the history in the system. </para>
			<para>Furthmore the refund/quick enrol process makes the workflow clearer when the new
				class has a different cost to the old. The operator is explicitly prompted to apply
				transfer fees (as applicable) or inform the student about the different cost. By
				then applying a fee or discount, general ledger adjustments are kept accurate and
				clear. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I fix a mistake I made where I charged the student the wrong amount or
				credited a credit note in error?</title>
			<para>Remember that the opposite of an invoice is a credit note. If the student owes you
				more than you originally charged them, create a manual invoice for the difference.
				If you charged them too much in error, create a manual credit note for the
				difference. If you want to check the balance of a student's account, go to the
				contact window and print a statement report. This will show all invoices, credit
				notes, payments in and payments out at the current balance of their account e.g. do
				they owe you money, do you owe them money, or is everything square? You can also use
				the contra pay feature to use the balance of a credit note to 'pay off' an
				outstanding balance on an invoice. Select the credit note in the invoice window, and
				using the cog wheel option 'Contra Invoice..' locate the invoice you want to pay.
				This only works for credit notes/invoices for the same contact. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> How can I use one contact's credit to pay for another student's enrolment? </title>
			<para> If the contact in credit wishes to use their credit towards another person's
				enrolment, follow the steps for <uri>3rd Party Payments</uri>, ensuring that you
				select the contact in credit as the payer. </para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
