<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="concessions">
	<title>Concessions</title>
	<section>
		<title>Concessions</title>
		<para>Concessions, discounts and promotional codes are a powerful part of onCourse marketing. Find out more about the difference between
			promotions and concessions and why you might choose to use them at your college.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title> Creating a concession </title>
		<example>
			<title>Setting up a concession for a seniors card holder</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select “Concessions” or from the splash screen or Courses menu.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select + from the bottom left of the window.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the new window, enter a name for this concession e.g. Seniors Card Concession (you can define concession types
						here)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>There are three different types of discounts you can create. You can discount the course or purchase by a percentage of it's
						total or by a pre determined dollar value. To set a 10% discount, select the ‘Discount Percent' option and type 10 into the
						discount value field.You can also create an override fee, this fee would be applied instead of the stated fee for the
						Class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can also set a minimum and maximum amount for the concession e.g. min $1 and max $10.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setting a valid from and valid to date is optional. If you want to make the discount apply at all times, leave this field
						blank.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Choose if this concession can be given with other concessions. For example a student could receive this concession and a
						further fee discount by using a special promotional code if you check this box.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/configuration_of_discount_value.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Configuration of discount value</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The next options allow you to select who and how this concession will apply.</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Enrolled within # Days (the student has enrolled at the college in the past # days)</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Age over/under # ages in years</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>With xx concession (student has supplied xx concession card type and reference number on enrolment)</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Postcode or Area (where the student lives)</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
					<para>In this example, you might select the third option ‘With Aged Pensioner concession' or ‘with Seniors card concession' or you
						could set it to ‘Age over 55'.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/configuration_of_discount_application.png"
								format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Configuration of the application of a discount</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The last field allows you to assign this concession to certain available classes. You can add or remove classes by using the
						+ and – signs to the right, including allowing this concession in all current and future classes.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/select_classes_discount_applies_to.png" format="png"
							 />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Select which classes a discount will be applied to</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Promotions</title>
		<example>
			<title>Creating a last minute discount for previously enrolled students.</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a code for your promotion. This will be what students enter on your website to access the promotional discount (or
						can be entered by your enrolment staff with phone, mail or in person enrolments).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Name and describe your promotion.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Set the amount and valid to and from dates as per concession instructions above. In this example we have limited the date to
						a one week range.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>This promotion is for re-enrolling students, so we have set it to students who have “enrolled within 60 days”.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select your eligible classes. Generally promotions are limited to a few select programs, such as those which already are
						over the minimum required, or dance classes or those which are starting in the next two weeks.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>Don't forget, promotional codes only work if you market them. You can always email or sms special promotions to your students to
				get them out there quickly. With most promotions you would not want to set a qualifier, like enrolled within x days, as you want as
				many people as possible to ‘use' the special code to enrol in your classes, and hope the students you market the promotion to assist
				you in your marketing efforts by passing the deal on to their friends. </para>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Concession types</title>
		<para>In many organisations and businesses, discounts are offered to customers based on special
			group membership or criteria such as students, special card holders etc.</para>
		<para>In onCourse, we can use Concession Types to define which groups of people have access to discounts by:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Associating the concession type to contact record by editing contacts/students;
					and</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Associating the concession type to a discount (see documentation on <link
					xlink:href="#discounts">creating
					discounts)</link></para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Some concession types may be available for your students to add to their own record during
			the online enrolment process, for example a Senior's Card. Other types you may want
			to restrict to only allowing the concession to be added to the student record via
			the onCourse client, for example College Staff. </para>
		<para>If you require an expiry date on the concession type, any discounts that apply to
			that concession type will not be available if the student's concession is
			expired.</para>
		<para>You may also choose to make entering a card number mandatory. Please note onCourse
			is not able to validate the authenticity of card numbers due. This is an open test
			field (string type) and will accept letters and numbers.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/create_concession.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Defining the parameters of a concession type for Seniors</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a concession type</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to File -> Preferences -> Concession Types</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click the add button ( + )</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Name your concession type and choose if you want it to be available for self selection
						on the web, if it requires a number or has an expiry date.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>Once you have created the concession type, go to discounts to define who can use it and
				how it can be used.</para>
		</example>
	</section>
</chapter>
