<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="contacts">
	<title>Creating and Modifying Contacts</title>
	<section>
		<title> onCourse contact types</title>
		<para>A contact is any person or organisation your business works with in relation to running classes. There are three categories of
			contact in onCourse:</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/contactCategories.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Contact Buttons to select Student, Tutor or Company</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Student</emphasis> – a person who has or intends on enrolling in your programs. You may need to collect AVETMISS
					data and will need to keep track of their enrolments, outcomes and payments.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Tutor</emphasis> – these are the people that facilitate your classes, supervise assessments or assist your
					instructors. You may want to enter their resume or bio details to display on your website. You want to know what classes they have
					been scheduled to deliver and what payments you have made to them. A tutor can also be a student.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><emphasis>Company</emphasis> – a business that you may need to invoice, who may book their staff into your classes, or you may
					work with in partnership to deliver classes. Tutors can also be companies.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Contacts can be related to each other, e.g. employer and employee, friends, siblings, spouse, child or parent.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Adding a new contact from the list view</title>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Open the contact window and select the plus (+) button. This will create a new record.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select the contact type from the options as described above</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter the contact's name and contact details e.g. address, phone numbers and email.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Add any relevant notes or attachments to the 'notes' tab</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>For students, where needed, collect and enter the AVETMISS data, date of birth and concession card information</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>For tutors, where needed, add the resume information</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/tutorAttachment.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A Tutor's Contact Details</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Adding a new contact in Quick Enrol</title>
		<para>When you look up a student name during the enrolment process, and the name can not be
			found (the student is not an existing student) you are given the option to select 'New'
			from the drop down list.</para>
		<para>Selecting new begins the process of creating a new contact record, as part of the
			enrolment process. </para>
		<para>Just like creating a new contact from the list view, you have the opportunity here to
			collect all the contact details, answer the AVETMISS questions and set their marketing
			contact preferences. By default, all new contacts created during the Quick Enrol process
			are set to be 'students'. You can also add the tutor option to the contact record where
			relevant.</para>
		<note> <para>Please note that if you do not complete the enrolment process and save the record, the new student you were creating will not be saved either.</para></note>
		<para>If you need to add another contact to the Quick Enrol process, you can simply just type in
			the additional contacts name in the 'Enter contact...' field on the left side of the
			window. This will allow you to look up another existing contact, or to add another 'new'
			contact to the enrolment. In the example below I have started typing 'smith' in the
			'Enter contact...' field</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/contact_QE.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Adding another contact to the enrolment process</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
	<title>Modifying contact details</title>
	<para>In the contact record, or when you are processing an enrolment, you can make changes to any of the details you have previously
		collected. Just type the new information into the field.</para>
	<para>Students and Tutors can also update their personal contact details via the Web Portal This saves them having to contact you if
		they move or change their phone numbers.</para>
	<para>If an existing contact changes their relationship with your college, for example, a past student becomes a tutor, there is no need
		to create a separate record – simply modify their current record and add in the additional information. </para>
	<section>
		<title>Setting up Email, Phone and Mail Preferences</title>
		<para>When creating a new contact or amending an existing one, you can also set the preferences
			for whether or not the contact wishes to receive marketing communications via email, SMS
			or via the post. You are also able to flag a contact method as
				<guilabel>(undeliverable)</guilabel>.</para>
	<para>You will note within the <guimenu>General</guimenu>tab of the contact record, each method of
			contact has a cogwheel icon to the left of the entry field. </para>
	<para>
		<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Opt_In_Opt_Out_Options.png" format="png" />
		</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Accessing the marketing options via the cog wheels</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</para>
		<para>In the following example, the operator can set the preferences as to whether the student
			wishes to accept marketing material.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Mail_Opt_In_Out_Preferences.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Setting the marketing material options via the cog wheel</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>If there is a contact method (post, SMS or email) showing with no additional information
				labels underneath the contact field, this means that the client has opted in to
				receive marketing material.</para>
		</note>
		<para>If a client has requested that they not be sent marketing material, by deselecting this option within the cog wheel, the contact method will be labelled as <guilabel>(no marketing)</guilabel></para>
	<para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Phone_Opt_In_Out_Preferences.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Ensuring that the client is not sent marketing material</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</para>
		<para>If a contact method is not able to send an email, SMS or postal item, you can flag the contact method as <guilabel>(undeliverable)</guilabel>. This is also managed via the cog wheel function as shown in the following example.
			</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/Email_Opt_In_Out_Preferences.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>If a client nominates to opt out of receiving marketing material, this does not preclude them from receiving the automatically generated enrolment confirmation and tax invoice emails and SMS messages. </para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="contact-VET">
		<title>Adding VET data to students</title>
		<para>Contacts who are marked as students have a tab labelled AVETMISS. On this tab, you can
			record the answers to the standard AVETMISS student questions regarding their country of
			birth, prior educational achievement and other required detail.  For customers using an
			onCourse website to take enrolments, these questions are asked of the student at the
			time of enrolment. Only valid answers can be entered into these fields, with most fields
			referencing look up data such as the ABS list of countries and languages, or the
			approved list of AVETMISS responses.</para>
		<para>For Victorian and Queensland customers, the field to record the student number is also
			located on the AVETMISS tab.</para>
		<para>For CRICOS providers, additional fields are available to record the students passport,
			visa and health care details. This information is not reported as part of the AVETMISS
			standard.</para>
		<para>Additional information, like the CRICOS student's next of kin, emergency contact or homestay
			provider can be captured using the contacts relationships feature.</para>
		<para>Under the AVETMISS 6.1 requirements, a response to most of these questions is
			optional, so if your students decline to provide information for one or more of these
			fields, we will automatically export the approved 'did not respond' code for that
			question, and also ensure that validation errors, like students speaking English as
			their first language and reporting themselves as speaking it well, are not exported from
			onCourse to cause problems with your funding providers.</para>
		<para>Please note that some student related AVETMISS questions are also located in their
			enrolment record, where the response is particular to that enrolment event e.g. their
			traineeship approval number or reason for study response.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/studentAVETMISS.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The AVETMISS tab of the student record</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Student's enrolment and VET history</title>
			<para>The history of a students enrolments, outcomes and certifications is available in the
				contact Enrolments tab.</para>
			<para>The first list component shows all the classes the student has been enrolled in.
				Some of these classes may have finished, so the enrolment status will show as
				'complete'. Classes which haven't started or are in progress show the status of
				'active'. </para>
			<para>When a student's enrolment has been cancelled and/or credited, the enrolment
				status will show cancelled or credited. </para>
			<para>A complete enrolment history is retained for each student, including classes they
				have withdrawn from, so you will always have a full picture of their engagement with
				your college. Enrolments can not be deleted, but they can be cancelled, a credit
				note created, and that credit applied towards a new enrolment.</para>
			<para>The second list component shows the outcomes for all the units linked to all the
				student's enrolments. For non-VET enrolments, these will include non-assessable
				outcomes for their enrolments. You do not need to set anything for these enrolments,
				even if reporting them via AVETMISS, as an outcomes status of 81 is always exported
				for unset statuses in these types of outcomes. </para>
			<para>VET outcomes will show the national code and unit details and you can double click
				on this outcome to make changes or update the status.</para>
		<note><para>When an enrolment is cancelled, the outcomes linked to the enrolment are deleted, except if
				you have already assigned them a status or used them to create a certificate. These outcomes will be retained on the student's file</para></note>
		<para>The final list component of the enrolment record shows all the certificates (both Statements
				of Attainment and Qualifications) issued to the student. Unprinted certificates can
				be edited by double clicking on them, printed certificates can be revoked, but not
				edited. You can print certificates from the certificate table only.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/contact_enrolment.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Enrolment tab of the student record</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Contact's financial records</title>
			<para>When a contact is invoiced, or makes a payment, an entry is made in the contact's financial
				records. This is visible on the contact Financial tab. </para>
			<para>Often, a student is invoiced and pays for their own enrolment. When this occurs,
				you will see the financial data on the student's Financial tab. When the enrolment
				is paid for by another person (often termed a 3rd party payment) the financial data
				will be on the payer's Financial tab, and not the student's.</para>
			<para>All the financial transactions are shown in creation date order, with a running total that
				shows the contacts balance at any point in time. Invoices, credit notes, payments in
				and payments out, will all show on the Financial tab.</para>
			<para>You will also note from the following example that each payment line of the financial tab
				will identify if it was an incoming or outgoing payment. E.g. 'Credit card payment
				in (office)' reflects a payment in.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/contact_financial.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The financial tab of the contact record</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	<section>
		<title>Adding Pictures to Contacts</title>
		<para>Each contact (student, tutor or company) can have an identifying image attached to their record that is visible as part of their
			general information. </para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>To add an image, open a contact record and click on the image place holder.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/adding_pic_contacts.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Image placeholder: Click on the head and shoulders image to add a photo</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select the image from your computer that you would like to use and press ok.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/adding_pic_contacts2.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Adding a photo to a contact</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<section>
			<title>Gravatar images</title>
				<para>Gravatar images will automatically load for contact records if the user has a avatar
					linked to their email address at https://en.gravatar.com. Gravatar images are
					overriden with locally uploaded profile photos. </para>
				<para>To make sure you have a gravatar licence enabled within onCourse go File -> Preferences -
					> General, and you will see it listed in the Sevices tab (as shown
					below).</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/preferences_gravatar.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Where is check if your gravatar licence is enabled</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
			<para>These images will also display in the tutor portal on the class roll for student
					identification purposes.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/gravatar_portal.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
						<para>What the tutor sees when marking a roll</para>
					</caption>
					</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="contact-Relationships">
		<title>Relationships between contacts</title>
		<para>Relationships between contacts can have relationships with other contacts to assist you with
			billing, contacts and marketing activities. </para>
		<para> For example, a corporate customer may enrol and pay for their staff members to complete training at your college, employer and
			student details can be connected for traineeship management, parents contact details can be collected for minors, for billing and
			emergency contact details, and spouse and friend relationships can be captured for use in marketing campaigns e.g. 20% discount when
			you refer a friend. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Adding a relationship</title>
			<para> In the contact window, you can add a relationship with the plus symbol. This opens a new sheet where you can type in the name
				of the contact you wish to add and define the relationship type. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/add_relationship_1.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding a relationship to a contact</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para> You can also define relationships through the<uri>Quick Enrol process</uri>, so that if the enrolment process connects two
				existing, but unrelated contacts, you can add the new information. When you add a second or subsequent contact to an enrolment, it
				will ask you how they are related to the first contact, or payer. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/add_relationship_2.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Suggesting contact relationship in Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para> All contacts can have multiple types of relationships with many other contacts. Relationships can also be deleted as needed,
				using the minus button in the contact window. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding different types of relationships</title>
			<para>To add a type of relationship between contacts, while in onCourse go to File > Preferences > Contact Relation Types. Here you
			can create different types of relationship like; Parent to Child. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Searching across relationship types</title>
			<para>If you are in the contact window and want to find someone with a relationship to the
				contact currently highlighted, simply click on the cog wheel icon (top right hand
				side) and select "Find records related to x selected contacts" where "x" represents
				the amount of contacts highlighted. This will open a new contact window showing the
				results.</para>
			<para>You can find either all records related to a contact via any relationship, or via
				a specific relationship type. For example, you could find all the students enrolled
				in 'Craft for Kids' and then find all the contacts related to them as
				parents.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Using relationships in Quick Enrol</title>
			<para> When relationships have been defined within contacts, they can be used to build enrolments quickly.</para>
			<para>When a contact is added to quick enrol, the people they have relationships are shown if you
				click on 'CONTACTS' and will appear on the top right hand side of the page. You can
				add these contacts to the same enrolment by clicking on them.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%" fileref="images/using_relationships.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Contact with relationships showing in quick enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finding contacts</title>
			<para> There are multiple ways you can search for contacts in the onCourse database. The simplest
			method is to open the contact window and begin typing the contact's last name in to the
			quick search window. This will find matching contacts based on the text you have
			entered.</para>
		<para>The filters and tag groups in the left hand side of the window are also a quick way to
			find contacts. For example, if you have the core filter 'students currently enrolled'
			ticked, and select a subject tag, like 'computers' you will see a list of results
			returned showing all the students who are currently enrolled in a class for a course
			tagged with a computer tag.</para>
		<para>You will see that some tag groups appear multiple times in the window, for example the
			subject tags (for students enrolled) and the subjects tag (for tutors teaching). You can
			use these tags on their own, or combination with other filters and queries to create a
			powerful range of search options.</para>
		<para>If you wish to search for contacts based on other criteria, you can open the advanced
			search window by clicking on the magnifying glass and choose which criteria you wish to
			search on. You can continue to add criteria to your search options by adding additional
			lines to the query.</para>
		<para>You have the ability to search for such things as Age, First name, Last name, Email,
			Tagged with, Enrolled in, Tutor for, Postcode USI, USI status and much more.</para>
		<para> When you have an advanced query running, you will see the words 'Advanced find' in the
			search window. To remove the query results, click on the red x.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/writequery.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Creating a multi-line query in the advanced search window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/queryresults.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Query results displayed with the words 'Advanced find' shown in the search window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Searching for related information</title>
				<para>You can also search for information related to contacts by using the cogwheel option 'Find
				related records...'</para>
			<para>This option can be useful for finding data related to one of more contact e.g. all
				the invoices for a company, or all the contacts related to a group of contacts with
				a particular relationship e.g. all the parents of a group of children.</para>
			<para>As you can define the types of contact relationships you wish to collect, this
				query can be quite powerful. For example, if you know you regularly deliver training
				to students with additional needs who are supported by agencies, if you have set up
				this relationship type and made relationship joins between agencies and clients, you
				can then find all the agents you worked with recently, and send them information
				about upcoming courses that may interest their clients.</para>
			<para>When you run a 'Find related...' search, the results open in a new list window,
				and you can continue to run searches on that returned list of results to further
				refine your data.</para>
			<para>At a glance, for a single contact, be it a tutor, student or company, you can find
				all their related enrolments, drill down through all their invoices and payments,
				check the printing or revoked status of each of their certificates or analyse the
				mailing lists they have subscribed to. For a group of contacts, this search function
				provides powerful marketing opportunities and the ability to analyse your student
				base in a variety of ways. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/relatedsearch.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>List of search options available from the 'Find related...' cogwheel option in the contacts window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		</section>
</chapter>
