<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="corporatePass" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <title>Corporate Pass</title>
    <para>Corporate Pass is way to allow certain students to enrol online without having to pay up
        front. Instead their company (usually their employer) is sent the invoice. A password/code
        allows the student to bypass upfront payment and allow them to enrol in a set of limited
        classes or your entire range of classes. You can create as many Corporate Passes as you like
        for the same customer, and for as many different customers as you choose.</para>
    <para>
        <tip>
            <para>Corporate passes and their associated discounts <emphasis>can only be used during
                    the online enrolment process</emphasis>. They aren't designed for use within
                Quick Enrol. If a discount has a promotional code and is available for use with a
                corporate pass you will get an error message if you try to use the promotional code
                in Quick Enrol.</para>
        </tip>
    </para>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-settingUp">
        <title>Setting up your Corporate Pass within onCourse</title>
        <para>This section will outline how you can set up your Corporate Pass using the onCourse
            Client:</para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>To create a new Corporate Pass go to Financial > Corporate Pass or click on
                    the Corporate Pass link in the Favourites section of the onCourse dashboard. You
                    can then create a new Corporate Pass by clicking on the <guiicon> +</guiicon>
                    symbol in the bottom right hand corner of the new window.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The minimum required information to create a new Corporate Pass is a contact
                    or Company Name and a Password. The Company or Contact must already exist as a
                    record within onCourse prior to creating the Corporate Pass. If you create a
                    Corporate Pas with these bare minimum requirements, it will be available to use
                    for any class or product.</para>
                <para>You can also specify as to which email address the invoices will be sent to.
                    By default the email address of the contact will be applied. An expiry date can
                    also be set for a given Corporate Pass, but this is not a required field. If you
                    wish to set invoicing terms for a specific Corporate Pass, you can set this on
                    the Financial tab of the Contact you have set as the company/person to
                    invoice.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/CreateNewCorporatePass.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Corporate Pass Edit View</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If you want to restrict the corporate pass to certain classes or products, you
                    can add these in the <emphasis>Limit</emphasis> section by activating the
                    switch, then typing out the name or code of the class you want to add. You can
                    also leave its use unrestricted by leaving the Limit switch inactive. You
                    can:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add a single class, will only be valid for the specified class.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add all classes for a given course.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add a selection of classes from any course.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add a single, or selection, of products.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>
            <tip>
                <para>If you don't specify any classes within your Corporate Pass, this will mean
                    that the Pass can be used to enrol in any classes that are open for enrolment
                    and published on your website. If you choose to link your Corporate Pass to all
                    current and pending classes, this means it will only work for classes that exist
                    today, not new classes you'll create in the future. This would be a very
                    uncommon use case.</para>
            </tip>
            </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-discounts">
        <title>Linking a discount to a Corporate Pass</title>
        <para>Instead of having to provide a company or person with a discount code that only they
            can use to enrol into a class with. You have the ability to link the discount or number
            of discounts to a Corporate Pass so employers or agents enrolling students can have
            access to a special price. To link a new discount to a Corporate Pass:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Open the Corporate Pass record you want to add the discount to</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Type in the name of the Discount you want to add - again this must already
                        be created in onCourse</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Find the right discount from the list and click the Add button. You can
                        add as many as you like.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <note><para>You can only link an existing discount to a Corporate Pass. If you want to add a new discount
                to a Corporate Pass you will need to go to the discounts list view and add in the
                discount you want to link the Corporate Pass to first.</para></note>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                    fileref="images/adding_a_discount_to_a_corporate_pass.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Choosing the discount you want to link to the Corporate Pass</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-products">
        <title>Linking products to Corporate Passes</title>
        <para>You also have the ability to link a product to a Corporate Pass. This feature allows
            you to link products, memberships and vouchers so that they can be purchased using a
            Corporate Pass. This is done under the Sales heading, the same as discounts:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Open the Corporate Pass record you want to add the discount to</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Type in the name of the Product you want to add - this must already be
                        created in onCourse</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Find the right products from the list and click the Add button. You can
                        add as many as you like.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                    fileref="images/adding_a_product_to_a_corporate_pass.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Choosing the product you want to link to the Corporate Pass</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-findRelated">
        <title>Using Find related in the Corporate Pass list view</title>
        <para>Just like on a lot of other list views you can use the find related feature in the cog
            wheel to find related information about a Corporate Pass or number of Corporate Passes. </para>
        <para>You can use the find related feature to find the following information about:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Classes</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Invoices</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Contacts</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Enrolments</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Enrolled Students</para></listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>audits</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
               <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                    fileref="images/corporate_pass_find_related.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Using find related for Corporate Passes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-usingOnline">
        <title>Using the Corporate Pass to Enrol Online</title>
        <para>Once the Corporate Pass has been created and the College notifies the client of the
            password for the Corporate Pass, the client can then use the Corporate Pass to enrol
            online. </para>
        <para>When the enrolment is confirmed and the Corporate Pass has been validated, this will
            automatically send an enrolment confirmation email to the student and an invoice for
            payment to the designated Contact or Company that the Corporate Pass has been issued to. </para>
        <para>The process of enrolling online using a Corporate Pass is quite
            straightforward:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The client will browse and select the Class or Classes they wish to enrol in,
                    then proceed to the check out to complete the enrolment process.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Once you proceed to the checkout, the onCourse website will ask you to confirm
                    the contact details of the student as well as the Class or Classes that you wish
                    to enrol in are correct, you can click on the Proceed to Payment button.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The payment view will you give you two options; pay by Credit Card or pay
                    using a Corporate Pass, simply select payment via Corporate Pass.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Enter the password for the Corporate Pass and press <guibutton>
                        Submit</guibutton>
                </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                            fileref="images/EnterCorporatePassCodeOnline.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Enter the Password to validate the Corporate Pass</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The system will then verify whether a valid code has been entered and specify
                    as to whom will be invoiced for this Class Enrolment, you can then confirm you
                    agree to the enrolment conditions and click on confirm enrolment to complete the
                    process.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                            fileref="images/ValidationOfCorporatePassCode.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Once the password is validated, confirm the enrolment</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <section xml:id="corporatePass-usingOnlineDiscounts">
            <title>Using a Corporate Pass that is linked to a discount to enrol online with</title>
            <para>If a Corporate Pass is linked to a discount then the 'Total' at the top right side
                of the window will only get reduced or increased when the enrollee has entered the
                Corporate Pass reference.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                        fileref="images/enrolling_online_corporate_pass.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>John Smith is trying to enrolling in a $500 class</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                        fileref="images/Corporate_pass_online_positive_discount.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Using a Corporate Pass that is linked to a discount</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>A Corporate Pass can also have a negative discount linked to it. This works
                exactly the same way as if a positive discount is linked one, however instead of the
                'Total' getting decreased it gets increased, as shown below. If a Corporate Pass has
                both a positive and negative discount link to it, the negative discount always takes
                precedent over the positive one.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                        fileref="images/Corporate_pass_online_discount.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Using a Corporate Pass that is linked to a negative discount</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-whenToUse">
        <title>When to Use a Corporate Pass</title>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>You may have a large customer with a number of staff to whom you provide
                    training. Without Corporate Pass your choices are to have the staff enrol online
                    with their own credit card or some corporate credit card, or to process the
                    enrolments by hand in the office in conjunction with your customer's HR
                    department. This involves a lot of co-ordination to check each student's
                    availability. Instead, Corporate Pass allows you to give the customer's HR
                    department a password or set of passwords. They then hand them out to staff
                    according to their own rules and policies. Staff can then enrol in whichever
                    classes are most suitable to their own availability. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Perhaps you are using onCourse to track internal training delivery in your
                    company. You might want to assign a price to classes to help with
                    interdepartmental cost allocation. Corporate Pass gives you the ability to
                    create a separate password for each department, allow staff to book their own
                    training, and then perform the back-end accounting you require. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>You deliver vocational training to the staff of several large mining
                    companies. These staff need to be regularly accredited for some part of their
                    job, but they have some flexibility to do their training around their work
                    shifts.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Students have to complete an audition or interview process to get into your
                    programme of training. Once they are accepted, you would like them to be able to
                    sign up to further training and tie their payments into a monthly billing
                    process you already have in place. Just hand them a password and they can enrol
                    24 hours a day over the internet. </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-controllingUsage">
        <title>Controlling Usage</title>
        <para>There are several ways to prevent abuse of a Corporate Pass. </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each pass can be restricted to one class or a selection of classes, or classes
                    assigned to a specific subject. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Create as many passes as you want, even for the same customer. That way you
                    can limit each pass in different ways and track its usage. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Give the pass an expiry date.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each pass has a special email address to which an invoice will be sent for
                    each enrolment. Typically this is your customer's HR department or staff manager
                    who will be able to monitor the emails and ensure that staff are enrolling in
                    appropriate training. These emails are sent in almost real time, so you
                    typically have plenty of time to review and reject any extraneous
                    enrolments.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-monitoringUse">
        <title>Monitoring the Use of Corporate Passes within onCourse</title>
        <para>Once the Corporate Pass has been created, you can monitor the use of it via the
            Corporate Pass window of the onCourse Client. The list view will give you a heads up on
            how many times a given Corporate Pass has been used. You can also filter the view to
            only show current entries using the Core Filter function of this window.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"  fileref="images/CorporatePassListView.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Summary view of all Corporate Passes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>To view the details of a given Corporate Pass, simply click on the highlighted record
            to open this up in edit view. From this view you can update the parameters of the Pass
            including valid expiry date and or assign different classes to the Corporate
            Pass.</para>
        <para>Apart from utilizing the onCourse Client to monitor usage of your Corporate Passes,
            there are also several onCourse Reports available to help you monitor this aspect of
            your business.</para>
        <para>To access these reports simply highlight the records within the Corporate Pass list
            view, then select <guimenuitem> File -> Print</guimenuitem>to open up the Report
            window.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/CorporatePassReportWindow.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Hitting the Share button on the Corporate Pass window will allow you to print these reports</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
