<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="corporatePass" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <title>CorporatePass</title>
    <para>CorporatePass is way to allow certain students to enrol online without having to pay up
        front. Instead their company (usually their employer) is sent the invoice. A password/code
        allows the student to bypass upfront payment and allow them to enrol in a set of limited
        classes or your entire range of classes. You can create as many CorporatePasses as you like
        for the same customer, and for as many different customers as you choose.</para>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-whenToUse">
        <title>When to Use a CorporatePass</title>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>You may have a large customer with a number of staff to whom you provide
                    training. Without CorporatePass your choices are to have the staff enrol online
                    with their own credit card or some corporate credit card, or to process the
                    enrolments by hand in the office in conjunction with your customer's HR
                    department. This involves a lot of co-ordination to check each student's
                    availability. Instead, CorporatePass allows you to give the customer's HR
                    department a password or set of passwords. They then hand them out to staff
                    according to their own rules and policies. Staff can then enrol in whichever
                    classes are most suitable to their own availability. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Perhaps you are using onCourse to track internal training delivery in your
                    company. You might want to assign a price to classes to help with
                    interdepartmental cost allocation. CorporatePass gives you the ability to create
                    a separate password for each department, allow staff to book their own training,
                    and then perform the backend accounting you require. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>You deliver vocational training to the staff of several large mining
                    companies. These staff need to be regularly accredited for some part of their
                    job, but they have some flexibility to do their training around their work
                    shifts. You can create a special landing page on your website for each of those
                    companies, with links to the courses you deliver that are relevant to them, the
                    password for CorporatePass and all other relevant information. Then students are
                    directed to that page for all their training information. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Students have to complete an audition or interview process to get into your
                    programme of training. Once they are accepted, you would like them to be able to
                    sign up to further training and tie their payments into a monthly billing
                    process you already have in place. Just hand them a password and they can enrol
                    24 hours a day over the internet. </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-controllingUsage">
        <title>Controlling Usage</title>
        <para>There are several ways to prevent abuse of a CorporatePass. </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each pass can be restricted to one class or a selection of classes, or classes
                    assigned to a specific subject. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Create as many passes as you want, even for the same customer. That way you
                    can limit each pass in different ways and track its usage. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Give the pass an expiry date.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Each pass has a special email address to which an invoice will be sent for
                    each enrolment. Typically this is your customer's HR department or staff manager
                    who will be able to monitor the emails and ensure that staff are enrolling in
                    appropriate training. These emails are sent in almost real time, so you
                    typically have plenty of time to review and reject any extraneous
                    enrolments.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-settingUp">
        <title>Setting up your CorporatePass within onCourse</title>
        <para>This section will outline how you can set up your CorporatePass using the onCourse
            Client</para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>To create a new CorporatePass first click on the CorporatePass window within
                    the Marketing Tab of the onCourse Client. You can then create a new
                    CorporatePass by clicking on the <guiicon> +</guiicon>symbol in the top right
                    hand corner of the new window.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                            fileref="images/CorporatePassLinkViaMarketingTab.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>The CorporatePass window can be accessed via the Marketing Tab</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The minimum required information to create a new CorporatePass is a contact or
                    Company Name and a Password. Remember that the Company or Contact must already
                    exist as a record within onCourse prior to creating the CorporatePass. </para>
                <para>You can also specify as to which email address the invoices will be sent to.
                    An expiry date can also be set for a given CorporatePass, but this is not a
                    required field. </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/CreateNewCorporatePass.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Corporate Pass Edit View</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>You can now define as to which class or classes are able to be enrolled in
                    using this CorporatePass in the following ways:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add all of your classes to a CorporatePass, this Pass will be valid
                            for any current or pending classes.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                                    fileref="images/AddAllClassesToCorporatePass.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>Add all classes to the Corporate Pass.</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add a single class to a CorporatePass, this Pass will only be valid
                            for the specified class.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                                    fileref="images/AddSingleClassToCorporatePass.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>Enter Name, Course Code and Class Code</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add all classes for a given course to a CorporatePass.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                                    fileref="images/AddAllClassesForCourseToCorporatePass.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>Add all classes for a given course.</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add all classes from a given subject tag.</para>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                                    fileref="images/AddAllClassesFromTagToCorporatePass.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                            <caption>
                                <para>Add all classes from a given subject tag.</para>
                            </caption>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>
            <tip>
                <para>If you don't specify any classes within your CorporatePass, this will mean
                    that the Pass can be used to enrol in any class that is open for enrolment and
                    published on your website. </para>
            </tip>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-usingOnline">
        <title>Using the Corporate Pass to Enrol Online</title>
        <para>Once the CorporatePass has been created and the College notifies the client of the
            password for the CorporatePass, the client can then use the CorporatePass to enrol
            online. </para>
        <para>When the enrolment is confirmed and the CorporatePass has been validated, this will
            automatically send an enrolment confirmation email to the student and an invoice for
            payment to the designated Contact or Company that the CorporatePass has been issued to. </para>
        <para>The process of enrolling online using a CorporatePass is quite straightforward:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The client will browse and select the Class or Classes they wish to enrol in,
                    then proceed to the check out to complete the enrolment process.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Once you proceed to the checkout, the onCourse website will ask you to confirm
                    the contact details of the student as well as the Class or Classes that you wish
                    to enrol in are correct, you can click on the Proceed to Payment button.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The payment view will you give you two options; pay by Credit Card or pay
                    using a CorporatePass, simply select payment via CorporatePass.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Enter the password for the CorporatePass and press <guibutton>
                        Submit</guibutton>
                </para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                            fileref="images/EnterCorporatePassCodeOnline.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Enter the Password to validate the CorporatePass</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The system will then verify whether a valid code has been entered and specify
                    as to whom will be invoiced for this Class Enrolment, you can then confirm you
                    agree to the enrolment conditions and click on confirm enrolment to complete the
                    process.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
                            fileref="images/ValidationOfCorporatePassCode.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>Once the password is validated, confirm the enrolment</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="corporatePass-monitoringUse">
        <title>Monitoring the Use of CorporatePasses within onCourse</title>
        <para>Once the CorporatePass has been created, you can monitor the use of it via the
            Corporate Pass window of the onCourse Client. The list view will give you a heads up on
            how many times a given CorporatePass has been used. You can also filter the view to only
            show current entries using the Core Filter function of this window.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"  fileref="images/CorporatePassListView.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Summary view of all Corporate Passes</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>To view the details of a given CorporatePass, simply click on the hi-lighted record to
            open this up in edit view. From this view you can update the parameters of the Pass
            including valid expiry date and or assign different classes to the CorporatePass.</para>
        <para>By clicking on the Invoice tab, you can view all Invoices that have been issued for
            that CorporatePass. As well as the date the Invoice was issued, the Invoice # and the
            amount owing for that invoice. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/CorporatePassInvoiceView.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>List of all invoices issued.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>By clicking on an invoice entry, you can then see all of the detailed information for
            the Invoice including the invoice line details and access any payments made against the
            Invoice.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"  fileref="images/CorporatePassInvoiceEditView.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Apart from utilizing the onCourse Client to monitor usage of your CorporatePasses,
            there are also several onCourse Reports available to help you monitor this aspect of
            your business.</para>
        <para>To access these reports simply highlight the records within the CorporatePass list
            view, then select <guimenuitem> File - Print</guimenuitem>to open up the Report
            window.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/CorporatePassReportWindow.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>