<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="courses">
	<title>Creating Courses</title>
	<section>
		<title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Course:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A course is the training product delivered by your organisation. For example:
						Dancing for Beginners, Advanced Jewellery Making or MYOB for Professionals. A course can
						be given any course code to identify that course uniquely.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Class:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A class is the instance of a course run at a particular time and date, led by one or
						more tutors and with a group of students enrolled. Classes may meet for one or more
						sessions depending on the subject outline and timetable. Classes are the things which
						you sell (or give away for free) and into which students enrol.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Timetable:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Each class has a timetable which represents each meeting between the students and
						the tutor(s). The timetable can link to rooms and sites and each session in the
						timetable has the flexibility to be allocated to a different tutor or a different
						room.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Students:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A student is a person enrolled in a class.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Working with Courses</title>
		<subtitle>Navigating the list and record windows</subtitle>
		<para>All records in onCourse can be viewed in either a list view or record view. You need to
			open the list view to access individual records.</para>
		<para>To access the course records go to either the splash screen and click on
				<guibutton>Course</guibutton> or the onCourse menu <menuchoice>
				<guimenuitem>Courses</guimenuitem>
				<guisubmenu>Courses</guisubmenu>
			</menuchoice> . This will open the Course list view window.</para>
		<section>
			<title>The onCourse list view</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Parts of the window -</emphasis> On the right hand
						side of the window are the course records listed in a summary view. The
						title bar shows you how many records you have. The top section of the window
						contains the search function and the add and delete records button. You will
						also find a cog wheel button that allows for special functions for one or
						more records in the list. In the left hand side of the list window are quick
						searches to enable you to work with groups of data. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Record summaries - </emphasis>The list of records in
						this window allows you to enter a record by double clicking, or select the
						record to perform special functions by single clicking. A selected record
						will be highlighted. You can select one or more records in the list by using
						shift-click to select a range, or control-click to select a group of
						individual records. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Columns and sorting -</emphasis> Column headings can
						be used to sort records in the list. Click on the header to sort in
						alphabetical order. Click it again to sort by reverse alphabetical order.
						You can also drag the columns around and modify their width to set your
						preferred layout. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Quick Search -</emphasis> By typing the first few letters of the
						course name into the quick search field, you can reduce the list of records
						to those that match.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Advanced Search - </emphasis>can be accessed by clicking on the
						Magnifying glass image in the quick search field. This will open the query
						editor to allow you to choose which fields and which data you want to search
						on. You can add multiple criteria to your searches.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Saved Searches -</emphasis> After performing an advanced search,
						you can choose to save the search parameters to allow you to quickly run the
						search again. To save a search, click on the cogwheel within the query
						editor and select 'save find'. The saved search will appear in the left hand
						part of the window and behave as a filter.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Tag Groups - </emphasis>Any tag groups you have created that relate
						to courses, like Subject, will appear here. By checking any of these check
						boxes you will see the list of records on the right hand side reduced to
						records that match that criteria. You can tag records in bulk by selecting a
						group of records on the right and right clicking on a tag name on the
						left.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Core filters - </emphasis>reduce the list of records to those that
						match the filter criteria. By default, most onCourse windows open with
						filters applied so you are only working with your current records. You can
						switch core filters on and off by ticking the checkboxes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<tip>
				<para>Filters and searches work together in onCourse. If you run an search and do not see
					the result you expect, this may be because a filter that is checked is preventing the
					record you are searching for from being displayed.</para>
			</tip>
			<para>You can enter a course record by double clicking on it in the window.</para>
		</section>
			<section>
				<title>The course cogwheel</title>
				<para>From the list view, the course cogwheel allows you to Show or Remove courses from your onCourse website in bulk.</para>
			<para>Courses which are not shown on the website appear in a lighter grey font in the
				list view for ease of identification.</para>
			</section>

		<section>
			<title>Creating a new course</title>
			<para>A course is the subject being delivered. Courses are your college's product. They are
				what your business sells. They may be accredited or non-accredited, part time, full time or
				just one time. </para>
			<para>For example, a course might be Jewellery Making for Beginners, a Diploma in Business or
				MYOB for Professionals. A course can have many classes and each class can run for
				one or more sessions. </para>
			<para>By setting up courses, you have something to advertise. You will need to name and
				describe your courses in order to entice your students to enrol. </para>
			<para>Student enrol in classes, but can add themselves to the wait list for
				courses.</para>
			<tip>
				<para>You need only enter the course name and course code to create your courses in
					onCourse, you can return to the record later more information, like a description for your
					website or print marketing. </para>
			</tip>
			<example>
				<title>How to create a new course</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button in the top right hand corner of
							the screen. A new course screen will open on the general tab. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Enter a name for your course and a course code in the relevant fields. Your course code
							must be unique, that is a code not used by any other course already
							created. Please note that the course code must not have any spaces
							between characters. So the course code for 'Dancing for Beginners 1',
							written using the first letter of each word, must be entered as DFB1 and
							not DFB 1. </para>
						<para>The code used will also become the course page URL on your website
							e.g. wwww.mycollege.com/course/DFB1. You can enter up to 32 characters
							in this field, so if you wish to create good URLs for SEO purposes, you
							could make your code longer, for example DanceClassStage1 to create the
							URL www.mycollege.com/course/DanceClassStage1</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can add one or more tags to your course record. The default tag
							group used to drive your onCourse website is subjects. If you add a tag
							from this group, your course will be available to users browsing your
							website. More information about tagging is available in <xref xlink:href="#tagging"/> </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you want students to be able to go on the waiting list for this course check the
								<guilabel>allows waiting lists</guilabel> box. The
								<guilabel>Enabled</guilabel> option will be selected by default.
							This allows you to create classes for this course. If you want to show
							this course on the web, change it to <guilabel>Enabled and visible
								online</guilabel>. If you decide to retire this course from your
							list of offerings you can change this to Course Disabled. Courses that
							are disabled can not have new classes created for them.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>There are two choices of <guilabel>enrolment type</guilabel> that relate to enrolments
							processed over the website. Open enrolment means students can enrol and
							pay directly on the web. This is the default setting. <link
								xlink:href="#applications">Enrolment by application</link> means
							there is an approval required by your office staff before a student is
							offered a place and can enrol and pay on the web. Set the enrolment type
							appropriate to your course. All classes from this course share an
							enrolment type.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Below is the <guilabel>print brochure description</guilabel> box. There are two options
							for entering descriptions: print brochure description on the general
							tab, and web description on the marketing tab. Usually, print materials
							are limited to descriptions of two or three lines, whereas on the web,
							your space is unlimited. If you do not intend to use onCourse to create
							a print based brochure, you do not need to enter any information in the
							print brochure description field. Text entered here can later be
							exported in an XML format ready for import into a print design product
							like Adobe InDesign.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Move to the marketing tab. Text entered in the web description field
							can be written in rich text format. A guide to using rich text can be
							found here <link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/web/richText.html">found here</link> You can preview the text
							by hovering over the blue A at the bottom of the text field. You can
							also attach images, files or documents to the web page. To advertise
							this course online, select <guilabel>Enabled and visible
								online</guilabel> in the general tab.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The Notes tab can be used to add internal notes about the course that
							will not be published to the web.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>During the course set up stage, there will be no information available
							in the timetable tab. After you schedule some classes you will see them
							on this tab.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> When you have entered your information, click <guibutton>save</guibutton> and you
							will be returned to the course list page. Notice that the course you have entered is
							now listed. You can return to edit this course at any time by double clicking on
							it.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
			<caution>
				<title>Field Validation</title>
				<para>You will notice that before entering text, the course and code box is coloured pink.
					Once you have entered valid text the colouring disappears. Should the box remain pink, it
					means that you have not entered the text correctly and need to review your entry. You will
					not be able to save the record as the save button will be disabled. There will be a
					warning icon that will provide you with information as to why the data you have entered is
					not accepted if you hover over it.</para>
			</caution>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Editing and Updating Courses</title>
			<para>After a course has been created, you can create it's classes. Classes can be created from
				the class window as per <xref xlink:href="#classes"/>. You can also create
				classes from inside the course record. Click on the + inside the course general tab
				to create a new class. </para>
			<para>On the course general tab you will see by default all the current and future classes for
				this course. Untick this option will display the past classes also.</para>
			<para>If students have been added to the wait list for a course, a count will appear on
				the general tab. The open related record icon will open the waiting list entries for
				these students, allowing you to contact them or edit their preferences.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/course_general_tab.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The course general tab showing current classes and waitlist numbers</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Creating course and product relationships</title>
			<para>onCourse allows you to link related courses and products to a given Course. This is an invaluable tool from a marketing perspective as it enables you to cross sell related or similar courses.</para>
			<para>You can add related Courses via the following steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to the Marketing tab of the Course and click on the <guiicon>+</guiicon> symbol to create a new Course relationship. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the name of the Course / Course code and click ok within the dialogue box.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>There are no limits to the number of related Courses you can add, but a maximum of 4 courses will display at any one time under the 'Related Courses' heading on the website.</para>
						<para>You can also add related products, vouchers or memberships to a course
							to encourage their purchase. A related product may include the course
							textbook, a related voucher may be a bundled set of courses that
							includes this one for a special price, and a related membership may be
							one that provides a discount on enrolment in this course.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AddingRelatedCourseEditView.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding Related Courses</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				<tip>
					<para>Any related Courses that you set up must be web visible and open to enrolments in order to display with the original course on the website. </para>
				</tip>
			</para>
		</section>
		</section>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Writing course descriptions for the web</title>
			<para>The onCourse website is a powerful marketing tool for promoting your products to the
			public. Your ability to explain your product point of difference and entice students to
			enrol is determined by the copy you write in your course Marketing tab.</para>
			<section>
				<title>
					What does a good course description include?
				</title>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>The first sentence or two of your course description should contain your hook. This is the
						copy that displays in the course list results and 'reels in' the customer,
						enticing them to click on the link [more...] Avoiding using headings in the
						first paragraph for the same reason - it won't render well in list
						views or make sense to readers browsing your site.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Think about all the questions potential students ask about this course, and provide answers in
						the course copy. onCourse already helps answer the 'where and when'
						questions with google maps embedded, and a full class timetable. It's the
						internet - there is no limit to the amount of information you can provide.
						Give students full confidence that this is the right course for them so they can
						click 'enrol now', instead of having to pick up the phone to ask you for
						more information.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Break up your copy with headings. It's difficult to scan large blocks of text, so put your
						rich text skills to good use and separate content with headings like 'What
						to bring', 'What you will learn', 'What past students say'. <link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/web/richText.html">Review rich text
							options here</link> </para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>An image is worth a thousand words. Show, rather than tell, what your students can achieve if
						they enrol in this course. Learning Thai Cooking? Show them a dish they will
						cook in class. There are a thousands of enticing stock photography images
						available for purchase online, and the onCourse <xref xlink:href="#documentmanagement"/> system makes it easy for you to attach
						them to a course and upload them to your website.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Keep the technical language to a minimum. If you are selling vocational training it's easy to
						fall into using acronyms and terms that only make sense to people within the
						industry. Your potential students are here to learn - don't scare them off
						enrolling by assuming they have the same industry knowledge you have.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Avoid negative language. Your course description is not the place to tell people they can't
						access refunds if they change their mind after enrolment. Save it for your
						Terms and Conditions page.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>What is SEO and why is it important?</title>
			<para>SEO stands for Search Engine Optimisation and having a website with 'good' SEO should mean
				your site appears near the top of the list for searches that are most relevant to
				your product. A large part of SEO is technical - i.e. can the Google bots that crawl
				the internet read and understand your website's content? The technical framework
				that underpins the onCourse web engine does most of this hard work for you, but one
				thing we can't automate is the creation of your website content.</para>
				<para>There are plenty of companies out there who will try to sell you an SEO solution, but the
				one thing most of them lack is an experienced copy writer who knows your product and
				your market. </para>
			<para>Writing enticing copy is a skill. Making sure this copy hits on appropriate
				keywords and still reads well is an art. </para>
			<para>Keywords are the terms people use when they are searching for your product. If you have an
					<link xlink:href="https://adwords.google.com.au">AdWords account with
					Google</link>, they have an excellent Keyword Planner tool that allows you
				search for keywords and find related terms people search for, with their relative
				search frequency.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tips for writing SEO copy</title>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
					<para>Your key search term belongs in your course name, which in turn becomes
						your website page title and heading level content in the results pages.
						Words appearing in titles and headings are ranked higher than text on the
						page. For example, the course name 'Learn Microsoft Excel' would be a higher
						ranking course name for SEO purposes than 'Excel 101'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The first paragraph of text on the page should reuse your primary keywords and add in
						your top related keywords, while remaining readable to humans. Say for
						example you chose the primary keyword Microsoft Office Excel with related
						keywords MS excel, formulas, spreadsheets, help, online, free, and your
						generic location. Your first paragraph would read: "Our Canberra CBD courses
						in Microsoft Office Excel are the solution to learning excel formulas and
						other spreadsheet functions. MS Excel training will help progress your
						career in almost any industry. Online classes for Excel are also available
						or you can attend classroom tutorials and then access our online Excel
						course for free."</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you're selling education, keywords like learn, course, class, training
						and tutorial belong in every course description you write. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you're selling face to face training, make sure you use location based
						keywords that relate to your training venues in the course copy, don't just
						rely on the class location to 'sell' to the local market.</para>
				</listitem>
					<listitem><para>Encouraging people to link back to your content is also a great way to improve your native
						page ranks. onCourse websites have <link xlink:href="www.addthis.com">built in tools for AddThis</link>, but to
						encourage links you need to provide content worth sharing. Consider
						providing content beyond the sales pitch - some Excel hints and tips may be
						just the trick to keep visitors returning.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
	<section xml:id="coursesVET">
		<title>VET Courses</title>
		<para>If you are an RTO who offers short accredited programs, or full qualifications, you will
			appreciate the ease in which you can set up your courses with the right unit and qualification
			details. This then flows through to recording outcomes, creating transcripts and
			certifications, and generating AVETMISS compliant data.</para>
		<para>You must ensure that in the File > General > Preferences > AVETMISS you have the 'show RTO
			related screens and menus' option enabled. This makes the VET tabs in the course and class
			records and the AVETMISS tab in the student record visible for data entry.</para>
		<para>In the VET tab of the course record you can select the Qualification and the Units from
			the built in NTIS data for your chosen course. If your course is VET, but not from a training
			package or accredited course, you can also flag it VET here and allocate its Field of
			Education ID. This is something you may need to do as part of your government funding
			requirements for non accredited courses.</para>
		<tip>
			<para>Do you deliver state accredited courses? You will find the course listed in onCourse but
				not the modules that make up the course. This is because they are not publicly
				available on NTIS. You can send us the modules names, codes and field of Education
				IDs in a spreadsheet and we will manually add them to onCourse for you.</para>
		</tip>
		<para>onCourse does not contain the qualification packaging rules, so it is up to you as the RTO
			to ensure that you are compliant with your own scope of registration and the requirements of
			the training packages you are authorised to deliver. You should refer to these requirements
			when creating your courses and only select those units which are allowed to contribute towards
			that particular qualification.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<title>There are a few different ways you can structure VET Courses within onCourse:</title>
			<listitem>
				<para> A full Qualification where you know all the units the students will complete in
					advance i.e. all students will complete the same core and elective units. Students will
					graduate with a complete Qualification.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A full Qualification where all students will undertake the core units, but may all
					select different elective units. Students will graduate with a complete
					Qualification.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A short course which has one or more units of competency embedded within it. The units
					may or may not all contribute to the same Qualification. Students will graduate with a
					Statement of Attainment.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A short course where you know which qualification a student will be working towards in
					advance, but the students in the class will complete a variable number and selection of
					units. Some may achieve a Statement of Attainment, some may be working towards a full
					Qualification, and some may simply receive a non-vet Statement of Attendance.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A course which is not linked to any national or state accredited training packages or
					accredited courses, but has a vocational learning outcome. Depending on your reporting
					requirements, these courses may also contribute towards your annual VET delivery.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>In onCourse outcomes (records of undertaking and achieving a unit of competency) flow down
			from the course to the student via an enrolment in a class. If a course has 15 units attached
			to it, when a student is enrolled in a class for that course, the student will have 15
			outcomes created for them - one for each unit. You can always modify the units for the student
			in their own enrolment, for example if they change to a different elective. What this means is
			that you can save yourself a lot of data entry work if you set your course up with all the
			units to begin with. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/vet_course_tab.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The VET tab of the course, showing a full qualification with selected units</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<caution xml:id="immutableCaution">
			<title>Changing units in a course</title>
			<para>Once a course has a class with an enrolment in it you CAN NOT change the units of
				competency assigned to the course. This is because onCourse has created an immutable
				relationship with this data - if you changed it at the course level, every student ever
				enrolled in a class for this course would have their outcomes changed. You can always retire
				the old course and create a new course to use in the future. The new course can have the
				same name but will have to have a different course code. This type of issue can be tricky,
				so take care when going through the steps. Remember that if an immutable (state cannot be
				modified after it has been set) relationship in onCourse is formed, it is quite hard to
				remove or delete any half of the relationship. Immutable relationships are formed so as to
				restrict or deny any removal of vital database elements, like a course, if a course was
				allowed to be removed at the click of button, things like classes, students, invoices,
				payments etc will be adversely affected.</para>
		</caution>
		<example>
			<title>How to "remove" a unit of competency from a class</title>
			<para>You cannot actually remove a Unit of competency from a course (see the caution above), you
				can only cancel the old course and then create a new course with/without the unit of
				competency you want included/removed. This is because changing the units of
				competency changes the very nature of the course. It isn't the same course as before
				and students enrolling in the new version of your course should be aware that they
				are enrolling into something quite different from the old course</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<title>What to do to achieve this:</title>
				<listitem>
					<para>First go to "Course", from here double click on the course record e.g; Computers -
						Beginners"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once opened, disable the course by selecting "course disabled" from the "status"
						drop down menu in the "general tab" (see screenshot below)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>After the course is disabled, create a new course (see above for more on how to
						create a new course)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>After the new course is created (with a slightly different name from the old course),
					you must give the course a different course code.</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<example>
			<title>Creating a VET Course</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Follow the instructions to create a new course. Open the course record to the
							<guibutton>VET tab</guibutton>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>National Code</guilabel>. The fields are clairvoyant, so as you type
						in them, onCourse will search for and list the qualifications in the built
						in training.gov.au database. Select the qualification by clicking on it. You
						can also search for qualification by name in
							<guilabel>Qualification</guilabel>. Omit the words Certificate in or
						Diploma of in your search. For example, search for the Certificate IV in
						Aged Care by typing 'Aged Care'.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> The qualification information is broken into different fields so the Certificate IV
						Training and Assessment would read <guilabel>National code</guilabel> - TAA40104
							<guilabel>Qualification</guilabel> - Training and Assessment
							<guilabel>Level</guilabel> - Certificate IV </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can then add modules and the units by clicking the <guibutton>+</guibutton>icon
						on the right hand side of the screen. This will open a drop down screen.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>National Code</guilabel> or <guilabel>Title</guilabel> These
						fields are also clairvoyant so make your selection and press ok. You will then be
						returned to the course screen where you will see the modules and units listed. To add
						more units simply click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton>sign and repeat the process. To
						delete any units, click the <guibutton>-</guibutton> sign. When you are done, click
							<guibutton>save</guibutton>. You can also set the nominal hours for the units as you
						attach them to the course.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<section>
			<title>Marking a course as 'Satisfies requirements for complete qualification' </title>
			<para>When a course has the flag 'Satisfies requirements for complete qualification' checked on
				the VET tab, this means that if the student successfully completes all of the
				attached units, they will be eligible for a Qualification, rather than a Statement
				of Attainment. </para>
			<para>Using the automatic 'create Certificates' options from the class or enrolment
				cogwheels will look at the value of this flag and determine what type of
				certification to create.</para>
			<para>This flag, for AVETMISS purposes, also signifies the student's intent to complete
				a qualification. Outcomes linked to a class with this flag checked will be reported
				linked to the parent qualification, where courses where this isn't selected will be
				reported as module only enrolments.</para>
			<para>This value of this checkbox can be changed as needed after the course has been
				created, and even after students have enrolled.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How can I create a VET course where the students are completing a partial unit of
				competency?</title>
			<para>Remember that in onCourse a course is about the product you are selling to your
				students. Sometimes you may break a program of study e.g. full qualification into lots of
				short courses for students to buy, complete and over time, work towards the final outcome of
				a qualification.</para>
			<para>In onCourse, courses don't have to be linked to a qualification or a unit of competency.
				They can just be a non-accredited course.</para>
			<para>If students are working towards a unit of competency that they will complete in another
				course, you may like to indicate this in the program description that you use for marketing
				purposes. If the student only completes this course, they will only be eligible for a
				non-accredited Certificate of Attendance, not a Statement of Attainment.</para>
			<para>You can set up this type of program in onCourse by attaching the Qualification that the
				student will be working towards in the VET tab of the course, but not adding any Units of
				Competency to the course. You do not have to add the Qualification at all - this is
				optional, and would not be appropriate if the program of study never led to any formal
				Qualification outcome.</para>
			<para>When students enrol in this course, they will get a dummy outcome (used for reporting
				purposes in some states) with the name of the course. You can set this dummy outcome to pass
				(81) or fail (82). Using this outcome, you will then know when the student enrols in the
				next course (where the units have been attached) that they have successfully completed the
				part one component.</para>
			<para>When you set up the second part of the course, you will add the qualification and the
				units to the VET tab, so when the student enrols they will get the appropriate units of
				competency added to their record. Then you are able to record their final outcome result as
				per the standard list of VET options.</para>
			<para>In the example below, a student is working towards a cluster of units from the
				Certificate I in IT. Only when they have completed the second course, Understanding Computer
				Basics, are they eligible to be assessed against the unit outcomes. The first course,
				Computing Basics, has no units attached, and the second course has three units attached. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/computing_basics.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>1st course: The Qualification is attached to the course, but the student has not
						completed any units of competency by completing this course</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/understanding_computer_basics.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>2nd course: The Qualification and Units are attached to this course. After
						completing part 1 and 2 the student can now be assessed.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/vet_student_outcomes.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The student record shows a 'dummy' outcome for the course with no units. They have
						completed it successfully. Now they can be assessed against the other units.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
