<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="discounts">
    <title>Discounts</title>
    <para>In an ideal world you'd never have to give students a discount. They would all flock to
        your courses at full price. But discounts can form an integral part of your marketing
        strategy. Used well, they allow you to attract students who would not otherwise have
        enrolled at the full price. Used poorly, they represent income you give away to students who
        would have happily paid full price. In an ideal world, you will sell to each student at the
        maximum price they would have paid. This is called 'differential pricing' and one way to
        achieve it is through well placed discounts. It allows you to set your full price to be
        higher than you would normally, and target those individuals who would be discouraged at
        that price point with special offers.</para>
    <para>This approach has several benefits to some types of colleges: it positions you as a
        premium service, it creates an impression that you are looking after certain special
        customers and it allows you to discount more deeply for certain demographics knowing that
        higher income is coming from others. As an example of this approach look at the airline
        industry: it is very unlikely that the person sitting next to you paid the same for their
        seat as you did. And airlines economic model is a lot like education; your product is
        completely perishable. Once the flight takes off or the class starts, those empty seats can
        never be sold.</para>

    <section>
        <title>Introduction to discounts</title>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>What is a discount? </term>
                <listitem><para>A discount is an onCourse marketing tool allowing you to sell a class at a reduced price.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>What's the value of a discount? </term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A discount value may be applied in dollars, percentage or a change the fee
                        to a set amount (where you specify the same fee that will apply for all
                        classes eligible). All discount values are ex gst. </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Who is Eligible for a discount? </term>
                <listitem>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <title>Discount eligibility may be checked against any or all of the following
                            discount parameters, all of which can be set in the discount feature in
                            onCourse:</title>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Students: Discounts may be offered to anyone, students under or
                                over a certain age, students in a certain postcode, students with
                                particular memberships such as staff member, or students with a
                                concession such as a youth card.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Classes: Discounts may be offered to a Course (and all it's
                                classes), a Class or, all current and pending classes. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Discount values: The discount itself may have a valid from or
                                expiry date, or require students to enter a special promotional
                                code. Discounts can be offered automatically when the student meets
                                the discount requirement and may also be offered in conjunction with
                                other discounts. </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                    
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Different types of Discounts </term>
                <listitem><para>There are two main types of discounts for eligible enrolments. </para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                            <para>Discounts not offered automatically: If a student does not know
                                about a discount, they won't get it. If they know about it, they
                                should enter a Promotional Code. The discount value should include a
                                code and obviously marketing of this promotion will need to include
                                the code. </para></listitem>
                    <listitem>
                            <para>Discounts offered automatically: If a student is eligible for a
                                discount because they met the set criteria, the discount will
                                automatically be offered. The discount value does usually require
                                knowing a promotional code, but may include holding a certain type
                                of concession card or membership.</para></listitem>
                </orderedlist>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <para>Please note that your website may not currently have a place for students to enter a
            promotional code or the ability for students to provide their concession card details
            for automatic discounts because this is something that may not have been required at the
            time of website implementation. However these are features that can be added, should you
            request. </para>            
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>What is a concession?</title>
        <para>These are the discounts you think of when you imagine children, seniors, disability
            card holders or unemployed discounts. These are discounts which can be given either as a
            percentage of the course fee, or as a fixed dollar figure. If you decide to give a
            percentage discount you can also set the minimum and maximum dollar discount which can
            be given. So you might to decide to give 10% off for seniors but cap it at $50 so that
            $800 course doesn't start to be discounted too heavily for you. Or a 2% discount which
            gives at least $5 off that $100 course so it doesn't appear too stingy.</para>
        <para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/concession_edit.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Concession example</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
        <para>Discounts can be given a start and end date. You might want a discount to continue
            indefinitely or you might want it to be a special one time offer valid for a certain
            period. onCourse gives you the choice. </para>
        <para>Next comes the students entitled to a concession. You might find all students who have
            enrolled in the past, are over a certain age, live in a particular suburb or who have a
            seniors card. You aren't locking it to the students who currently fit the requirement:
            any student who later is entered into the system with the right age, suburb or discount
            type will be able to obtain that discount. </para>
        <para>Finally, you are able to set the list of classes which may receive the discount. This
            might be every class you run, just your computer courses, or just one course you choose.
            This gives you flexibility to offer discounts where you think they will be appropriate,
            useful and affordable. You may be able to offer lower discounts to outsourced courses
            given your margins or it may not be helpful to offer seniors discounts to pre-natal
            sessions. </para>
        <para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/concessions1.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Applying a concession automatically to an enrolment</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
        <para>With all this flexibility, you can offer discounts to your students in exactly the way
            you choose. For instance: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>all students under 25 receive 10% off all courses – these are often people
                    with lower disposable income and discounts are a useful way to attract them
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>all students who attended a course last term automatically get 20% off
                    selected courses this term </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>all students with a senior's card receive a $20 discount off any of the
                    daytime arts and craft classes</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Generally, concessions apply on a long term basis and are based on your college's fees
            and charges policy. Concessions are automatically applied to fees on enrolment if a
            student meets the conditions you have set. If you wish to give a special deal to a
            certain group of people for a limited time only, it is more suitable to create a
            promotion. </para>
        <section>
            <title>Defining concession card types</title>
            <para>You can define the concession types that are accepted at your college. Some of
                these may be accepted by student's self identifying their possession of these cards
                during online enrolment, others may only be available by setting the concession card
                against the student's record by an onCourse user.</para>
            <para>To define the cards you accept, go to File > Preferences > Concession Types. By
                clicking on the add + button you can define new types, or modify existing types by
                doubling clicking on the record to edit it.</para>
            <para>When you define a concession type, you have the following options:</para>
            <para>- Available on the website. This means you will allow students to self identify
                the possession of this card. Note the website can not perform validation of card
                types - this is an honour system. </para>
            <para>- Allow entry of concession card number. This makes the supply of a card number
                mandatory. Again, note there is no validation on this field - users can still enter
                any data they like. Useful for ensuring that only card holders self identify - you
                can use this data to conduct random spot checks if required.</para>
            <para>- Has expiry date. Requiring this field means that the concession recorded against
                the student will no longer work automatically for discounts after the identified
                expiry date has past.</para>
            <para>Once you have set your concession card types, you can add them to the discount
                policies you create when defining on the student tab who the discount may apply
                to.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing concession card discounts in onCourse through Quick Enrol</title>
            <para>If you have set the discount to 'apply automatically' and the student and their
                chosen class meet the requirements of the discount, it will be applied by default on
                enrolment. If the student is eligible for multiple discount types, the discount that
                provides the lowest cost to the student will be applied.</para>
            <para>During the enrolment process, discounts that require a promotional code can be
                entered on the payment screen. Again, any eligible classes will have their fee
                reduced.</para>
            <para>Before saving and confirming the enrolment, you can check the discounts that have
                been applied by hovering over the notification icon next to the class fee.</para>
            <para>You can also manually adjust a discount as necessary by replacing the discount
                amount in the enrolment window.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/qediscount.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This student is eligible for a staff discount when they enrol in this
                        class as they have the staff concession card on their record and this class
                        has that discount type available</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Concession card discounts on the web</title>
            <para>If you wish, discount rates and fees can be displayed inline with the class fee on
                the website. When users hover over the discounted fee, they can see who is eligible
                to apply for it. You may choose to combine your discounts so multiple concession
                types can access the same reduced fee. E.g. if both seniors and students are
                eligible for a 10% discount, you may call the discounted fee Seniors/Students and
                holders of either a student card or a seniors card can be eligible to access that
                rate. This prevents you from showing the same discounted fee multiple times in the
                class.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/discount_fee_webdisplay.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A class showing multiple discounts options available to concession card holders</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>When a student is completing the enrolment process, by default they will be
                charged the full fee. If you allow the entry of the concession card details via the
                website, they can then select the option during enrolment to select a concession
                card type and enter the appropriate details you require.</para>
            <para>While concession card numbers and validity can't be checked by the website
                enrolment process, all students must confirm that their claim to access the
                concession is valid and that their details may be checked. You should ensure your
                enrolment policy and procedures includes information about how additional charges
                will be levied if students can not produce their concession card on request.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/online_enrol_concession.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>During website enrolment, students can enter concession card details</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/online_enrol_discountapplied.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The appropriate fee discounts are then calculated prior to the student making payment for their enrolment(s)</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>What is a promotion?</title>
        <para>Promotions are another type of discount with a string attached. The student must know
            a particular word or code in order to obtain the discount. You might decide to perform a
            letterbox drop in a particular area with postcard sized teasers for your new dance
            classes. They explain that the recipient can get a 5% discount by going to the web site
            and typing in ‘WALTZ'. When they do this, the web site alters and shows the courses with
            fees crossed out and the discounted price alongside in red. The idea is to: </para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>create the feeling of an offer targeted to a particular group of people, so
                    the recipient feels special.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>track the effectiveness of your letterbox drop</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>use an expiry date to create urgency</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>micro-market: use different strategies for different demographics</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>You might distribute your promotional codes by using:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>targeted printed material</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>an email mailout to existing or potential students</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>SMS</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>an alliance with a club or user group – such as a deal with a local RSL that
                    gives their members a discount through a code in their newsletter</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>Remember, the point of promotional codes is not to keep the code secret and prevent
            recipients telling their friends about it. The effectiveness of your marketing is
            greatly enhanced by potential students telling as many people as possible about this
            great deal they can get by typing in a ‘secret code'. </para>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing promotional code discounts in onCourse through Quick Enrol</title>
            <para></para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Promotional codes on the web</title>
            <para>Promotional codes are applied differently on the website to discounts that relate
                to concessions. Firstly, you need to ensure that your website design includes a
                specification for the location of the 'My discounts' option. This panel allows
                students to enter a promotional code that will then be applied to all eligible
                classes across your website during their browsing of your programs.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/web_promotionalcode.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Mechanism for students to enter a known promotional code to reduce eligible enrolment fees</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>Once a student has entered a valid promotional code, classes they view will show
                the full fee crossed out and the fee that applies during the promotion displayed
                instead. During enrolment, this discounted fee will be automatically applied.</para>
        </section>
    </section>

	<section>
		<title>Common discount questions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>What is a discount? </term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A discount is an onCourse marketing tool allowing you to sell a class at a reduced
						price.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>What's the value of a discount? </term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A discount value may be applied in dollars, percentage or a fixed dollar amount
						(where you specify the total discounted class fee). All discount values are ex gst.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Who is Eligible for a discount? </term>
				<listitem>
					<orderedlist>
						<title>Discount eligibility may be checked against any or all of the following discount
							parameters, all of which can be set in the discount feature in onCourse:</title>
						<listitem>
							<para>Students: Discounts may be offered to anyone, students under or over a certain
								age, students in a certain postcode, students with particular memberships such as
								staff member, or students with a concession such as a youth card.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Classes: Discounts may be offered to a Course (and all it's classes), a Class
								or, all current and pending classes. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Discount values: The discount itself may have a valid from or expiry date, or
								require students to enter a promo code </para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Different types of Discounts </term>
				<listitem>
					<para>There are two main types of discounts for eligible enrolments. </para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Discounts not offered automatically: If a student does not know about a
								discount, they won't get it. If they know about it, they should enter a Promo Code.
								The discount value should include a promo code and obviously marketing of this
								promotion will need to include the promo code. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Discounts offered automatically: If a student is eligible for a discount, the
								discount will automatically be offered.The discount value does not include a Promo
								Code. </para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<para> Please note that your website may not currently have a box for students to enter a promo
			code because this is something that may not have been required at the time of website
			implementation.However this is something that can be added, should you choose to offer
			discounts only when students enter a promo code. </para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Create a discount</title>
		<para>In this example we will set up a concession for seniors card holders:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select <guilabel>Discount</guilabel> from the splash screen or
						<guimenu>Courses</guimenu> menu.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select <guibutton>+</guibutton> button from the bottom left of the window</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the new window, enter a name for this concession e.g. Seniors Card Concession (you
					can define concession types here)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>There are two different types of discounts you can create. You can discount the course
					or purchase by a percentage of it's total or by a pre determined dollar value. To set a
					10% discount, select the <guilabel>Discount Percent</guilabel> option and type 10 into the
					discount value field.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>You can also set a minimum and maximum amount for the concession e.g. min $1 and max
					$10.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Setting a valid from and valid to date is optional. If you want to make the discount
					apply at all times, leave this field blank.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Choose if this concession can be given with other concessions. For example a student
					could receive this concession and a further fee discount by using a special promotional
					code if you check this box.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>The next options allow you to select who and how this concession will apply:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enrolled within # Days (the student has enrolled at the college in the past #
					days)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Age over/under # ages in years</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>With xx concession (student has supplied xx concession card type and reference number
					on enrolment)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Postcode or Area (where the student lives)</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>In this example, you might select the third option <guilabel>With Aged Pensioner
				concession</guilabel> or <guilabel>with Seniors card concession</guilabel> or you could set
			it to <guilabel>Age over 55</guilabel>.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>The last field allows you to assign this concession to certain available classes. You
					can add or remove classes by using the <guibutton>+</guibutton> and
						<guibutton>–</guibutton> signs to the right, including allowing this concession in all
					current and future classes.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>Promotions</para>
		<para>In this example we will create a last minute discount for our previously enrolled
			students.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create a code for your promotion. This will be what students enter on your website to
					access the promotional discount (or can be entered by your enrolment staff with phone,
					mail or in person enrolments).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Name and describe your promotion.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Set the amount and valid to and from dates as per concession instructions above. In
					this example we have limited the date to a one week range.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>This promotion is for re-enrolling students, so we have set it to students who have
						<guilabel>enrolled within 60 days</guilabel>.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select your eligible classes. Generally promotions are limited to a few select
					programs, such as those which already are over the minimum required, or dance classes or
					those which are starting in the next two weeks.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>Don't forget, promotional codes only work if you market them. You can always email or sms
			special promotions to your students to get them out there quickly. With most promotions you
			would not want to set a qualifier, like enrolled within x days, as you want as many people as
			possible to ‘use' the special code to enrol in your classes, and hope the students you market
			the promotion to assist you in your marketing efforts by passing the deal on to their friends. </para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/concessionValuesTab.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Discount Values Tab</emphasis>
					</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/concessionStudentsTab.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Discount Students Tab</emphasis>
					</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/concessionClassesTab.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Discount Classes Tab</emphasis>
					</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Concessions:</title>
		<para>These are the discounts you think of when you imagine children, seniors, disability card
			holders or unemployed discounts. These are discounts which can be given either as a percentage
			of the course fee, or as a fixed dollar figure. If you decide to give a percentage discount
			you can also set the minimum and maximum dollar discount which can be given. So you might to
			decide to give 10% off for seniors but cap it at $50 so that $800 course doesn't start to be
			discounted too heavily for you. Or a 2% discount which gives at least $5 off that $100 course
			so it doesn't appear too stingy.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Concession_edit.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Concession example</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>Discounts can be given a start and end date. You might want a discount to continue
			indefinitely or you might want it to be a special one time offer valid for a certain period.
			onCourse gives you the choice. </para>
		<para>Next comes the students entitled to a concession. You might find all students who have
			enrolled in the past, are over a certain age, live in a particular suburb or who have a
			seniors card. You aren't locking it to the students who currently fit the requirement: any
			student who later is entered into the system with the right age, suburb or discount type will
			be able to obtain that discount. </para>
		<para>Finally, you are able to set the list of classes which may receive the discount. This
			might be every class you run, just your computer courses, or just one course you choose. This
			gives you flexibility to offer discounts where you think they will be appropriate, useful and
			affordable. You may be able to offer lower discounts to outsourced courses given your margins
			or it may not be helpful to offer seniors discounts to pre-natal sessions. </para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/quickEnrol.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Applying a concession to an enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>With all this flexibility, you can offer discounts to your students in exactly the way you
			choose. For instance: </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>all students under 25 receive 10% off all courses – these are often people with lower
					disposable income and discounts are a useful way to attract them </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>all students who attended a course last term automatically get 20% off selected
					courses this term </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>all students with a senior's card receive a $20 discount off any of the daytime arts
					and craft classes</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Generally, concessions apply on a long term basis and are based on your college's fees and
			charges policy. Concessions are automatically applied to fees on enrolment if a student meets
			the conditions you have set. If you wish to give a special deal to a certain group of people
			for a limited time only, it is more suitable to create a promotion. </para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Promotions:</title>
		<para>Promotions are another type of discount with a string attached. The student must know a
			particular word or code in order to obtain the discount. You might decide to perform a
			letterbox drop in a particular area with postcard sized teasers for your new dance classes.
			They explain that the recipient can get a 5% discount by going to the web site and typing in
			‘WALTZ'. When they do this, the web site alters and shows the courses with fees crossed out
			and the discounted price alongside in red. The idea is to: </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>create the feeling of an offer targeted to a particular group of people, so the
					recipient feels special.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>track the effectiveness of your letterbox drop</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>use an expiry date to create urgency</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>micro-market: use different strategies for different demographics</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>You might distribute your promotional codes by using:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>targeted printed material</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>an email mailout to existing or potential students</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>SMS</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>an alliance with a club or user group – such as a deal with a local RSL that gives
					their members a discount through a code in their newsletter</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Remember, the point of promotional codes is not to keep the code secret and prevent
			recipients telling their friends about it. The effectiveness of your marketing is greatly
			enhanced by potential students telling as many people as possible about this great deal they
			can get by typing in a ‘secret code'. </para>
	</section>

    <section>
        <title>What is a membership?</title>
        <para>Memberships can be purchased and then their related discounts may apply to the membership holder, or people related to the membership holder e.g. all staff or a business who own a corporate membership. These discounts are usually offered automatically on enrolment where someone meets the membership criteria</para>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a membership</title>
            <para>Memberships can be created from the Marketing > Membership option. A membership
                needs a name and should have a description so potential purchasers understand the
                benefits of the membership.</para>
            <para>A membership may have a fee to purchase, or could be given away for free. The
                membership will have a duration of either a set number of days from purchase, the
                beginning of the calendar or financial year or be for life.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/membershipsetup.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A membership product available for sale</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>You can choose to make the membership available for purchase online, or only via
                internal purchase,</para>
            <para>At this point, you may choose to link to existing discount policies, or you may
                prefer to define the discounts that apply to people who hold this membership type
                later.</para>
            <para>An important distinction of membership discounts is that they can also apply
                across relationships. For example, a company could purchase a membership and the
                discount policy for that membership may apply to all staff of that company who
                enrol.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/discountrelation.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A membership discount policy that applies the discount to the staff members of the membership holder</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
        <title>Purchasing a membership</title>
        <para>A membership can be purchased from Quick Enrol, either in conjunction with an
                enrolment or as a standalone purchase.</para>
            <para>If the membership is purchased in conjunction with an enrolment that is eligible
                for a discount for members, then the discount will be applied at the time of
                purchase.</para>
            <para>Memberships can be purchased by choosing the add membership options from the top
                right hand corner of the Quick Enrol window. Type the name of the membership in the
                product field and the rest of the membership record will be automatically filled. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/purchasingmembership.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>A student purchasing a membership and being eligible for the 100% discount policy at the same time.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
    </section>
        <section>
        <title>Redeeming a membership</title>
        <para>For as long as the membership is valid, any applicable discounts will be given
                automatically when the student enrols. Discounts will no longer be given if a
                membership has expired. Current and expired memberships can be seen in the student's
                general tab of their record.</para>
    </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Creating discount campaigns</title>
        <para>Some examples of possible campaigns are outlined below:</para>
        <example>
            <title>Creating a discount for seniors card holders</title> 
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Select <guilabel>Discounts</guilabel> from the splash screen or
                        <guimenu>Courses</guimenu> menu.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Select <guibutton>+</guibutton> button from the bottom left of the
                    window</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>In the new window, enter a name for this concession e.g. Seniors Card
                    Concession (you can define concession types here)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>There are two different types of discounts you can create. You can discount
                    the course or purchase by a percentage of it's total or by a pre determined
                    dollar value. To set a 10% discount, select the <guilabel>Discount
                        Percent</guilabel> option and type 10 into the discount value field.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>You can also set a minimum and maximum amount for the concession e.g. min $1
                    and max $10.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Setting a valid from and valid to date is optional. If you want to make the
                    discount apply at all times, leave this field blank.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Choose if this concession can be given with other concessions. For example a
                    student could receive this concession and a further fee discount by using a
                    special promotional code if you check this box.</para>
            </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        <para>The next options allow you to select who and how this concession will apply:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Enrolled within # Days (the student has enrolled at the college in the past #
                    days)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Age over/under # ages in years</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>With xx concession (student has supplied xx concession card type and reference
                    number on enrolment)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Postcode or Area (where the student lives)</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>In this example, you might select the third option <guilabel>With Aged Pensioner
                concession</guilabel> or <guilabel>with Seniors card concession</guilabel> or you
            could set it to <guilabel>Age over 55</guilabel>.</para>
                <para>The last field allows you to assign this concession to certain available
                    classes. You can add or remove classes by using the <guibutton>+</guibutton> and
                        <guibutton>–</guibutton> signs to the right, including allowing this
                    concession in all current and future classes.</para>
        </example>
        <example>
            <title>How to create a marketing campaign with a promotional code</title>
        <para>In this example we will create a last minute discount for our previously enrolled
            students.</para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Create a code for your promotion. This will be what students enter on your
                    website to access the promotional discount (or can be entered by your enrolment
                    staff with phone, mail or in person enrolments).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Name and describe your promotion.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Set the amount and valid to and from dates as per concession instructions
                    above. In this example we have limited the date to a one week range.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>This promotion is for re-enrolling students, so we have set it to students who
                    have <guilabel>enrolled within 60 days</guilabel>.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Select your eligible classes. Generally promotions are limited to a few select
                    programs, such as those which already are over the minimum required, or dance
                    classes or those which are starting in the next two weeks.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>Don't forget, promotional codes only work if you market them. You can always email or
            SMS special promotions to your students to get them out there quickly. With most
            promotions you would not want to set a qualifier, like enrolled within x days, as you
            want as many people as possible to ‘use' the special code to enrol in your classes, and
            hope the students you market the promotion to assist you in your marketing efforts by
            passing the deal on to their friends. </para>
        </example>
        <example>
            <title>How to create a membership discount</title>
            <para>in this example we will create a membership students can buy to entitle them to a 100% discount for any of our computer classes for the next six months.</para>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Open the membership window and create the membership for purchase. Set a
                        cost for purchase and the duration of the membership in days.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Open the discount window and create the discount policy for computer club
                        members. The discount is for 100% and will be offered automatically.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Go to the students tab of the discount window and select the options
                        'students with' and 'with following memberships' and add the new membership
                        you just set up. In this instance we will choose to apply this discount only
                        to the student who purchased it.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Go to the classes tab on the discount window and add all your current and
                        pending computer classes. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Save and close the record. The membership is now ready for purchase and
                        the discount policy as defined will be applied.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            
        </example>
</section>
<section>
    <title>Reporting on discount use</title>
    <para>The Discounts by Class report is available from the classes menu. This report shows you
            for each class selected, how many enrolments you have processed at full fee and any
            applicable discount, and the total value of any discounts applied.</para>
    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                fileref="images/discountreport.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>An example class where some students have used a discount to reduce their enrolment fees</para>
        </caption>
    </mediaobject>
 </section>
</chapter>
