<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="documentmanagement">
    <title>Document Management</title>
    <para>onCourse provides an effortless way to manage your documents. Documents can be uploaded to onCourse and linked
        to Courses, Classes, Enrolments, Contacts, Tutors, Students, Sites and Rooms. Because all documents are version controlled you will never lose any historic information, making RTO compliance easy.</para>
    <para>Document management in onCourse can be used for lots of purposes:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Displaying images and other content on your website</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Storing compliance documentation such as tutor resumes and
                    qualifications</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Maintaining a history of assessment and other enrolment related
                    compliance</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Distributing information to tutors through the skillOnCourse portal</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Distributing assessments and course material to students</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    <section>
        <title>Adding new documents</title>
        <para>You can add new documents directly in the edit view from many places in onCourse. For
            example below you can see a Course "Accounting with MYOB" to which we want to add a
            picture of a duck. To do this click the plus symbol above the attachments area.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/documentManagement/adding_attachments.png"
                    format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Adding an document in the Marketing tab of the edit view inside a
                    Course</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>You will now be given a choice to find an existing document or upload a new file.
            Let's say we want to upload that duck picture from your computer. You can either click
            on the 'Select file...' button or drag-and-drop the file onto the box below that says
            'Or drop here from desktop'.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/documentManagement/attach_document.png"
                    format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Attaching a new file</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once a file has been selected you will notice a message at the top right of the next
            window saying 'Uploading to the cloud' with a percentage next to it showing you the
            progress. When the file has finished uploading the message will change to 'Done'</para>
        <para> There are a number of fields when adding a new document, they are:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Name - Allows you to change the name of the document.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>'duck45.png' - In this field you can change the name of the file.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Access - This drop down box allows you to choose what access rights you want
                    to give to the document. For more information please refer to the Access rights
                    section of this chapter.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Description - You have the ability to write a short description about this
                    document.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Adding a tag to this document can be done by clicking on the tag icon on the left side
            of the sheet.</para>
        <para>You can also choose whether duck is allowed to be attached to other records. If you
            select this option it will appear in the clairvoyance name lookup when you are trying to
            attach an existing document to another record.</para>
        <para>For attachments like contact profile pictures, you may choose not to allow them to be
            attached to other records.</para>
        <para> Below this there are radio buttons which let you state whether duck is attached to
            course ABC or whether it will get attached to all current/future classes for course ABC.
            You will only see this option if you are attaching a resource at the course level.
            Sometimes you'll have a resource which relates to course advertising, or a shared
            resource for all students and tutors in all classes from this course, like an assessment
            submission form.</para>
        <para>However, if you are attaching a resource like a new assessment task that is to be
            distributed to students enrolled in the class, and may change from class to class from
            the course, you can select the second option and attach it to the current and future
            classes from the course, without making it available to students previously enrolled in
            classes from this course.</para>
        <para>If you choose to attach the document to the class, but you began this process in the
            course record, when you complete and close the attachment sheets, you will not see the
            attachment listed in the course attachments as above. Instead, it will be visible in the
            class attachment lists where it has been applied.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/documentManagement/upload_document.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Uploading a new file</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Attaching existing documents</title>
        <para>If you wish to attach an existing document (one which has previously been uploaded in
            onCourse) to a record, you will click + in the attachment list and the sheet below will
            open. To fins an existing document, named duck, to course ABC you would start typing the
            name duck in the clairvoyance field on the left side of the sheet. A list will then
            appear with all existing documents in onCourse that contain the word duck in them. If
            there aren't any documents that are already stored in onCourse with the name duck, then
            no results will be returned.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/documentManagement/attach_document.png"
                    format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Attaching an existing document that is already stored in onCourse</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once you have found and selected the correct document a new sheet will appear that
            allows you to define the relationship between the course ABC and the document 'duck'.
            You'll see the following information:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The name of the document, duck, will appear in the top left hand side of
                        the page. To open the document or edit the information about the document,
                        click the open related record icon next to the name.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A short description of duck will appear below the name.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Below the description you will see any tags attached to this
                        document.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The checkbox below this allows you to freeze course ABC to a specific
                        version of duck. If you check this box then the buttons below named 'frozen'
                        will appear, allowing you to select the version. More information on
                        freezing can be found in the freezing section of this chapter.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Below the heading 'VERSIONS' will list all the previous versions of this
                        document along with when they were created, by whom and if they're frozen to
                        this record. You also have the ability to open any of these previous
                        versions of the document by clicking the on the 'open' button. If the
                        checkbox 'Freeze this course to a specific version' is checked you can
                        change which of the previous versions of the documents you want to freeze
                        this course to by simply click on the 'frozen' button next to the user
                        name.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The image of the latest version of the document will appear on the top
                        right hand side of the page (this can be useful to make sure you have chosen
                        the correct document in the case of an image type document). Below this will
                        be the name, format and size of the file.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The access rights of the document will also be displayed on the right
                        sided of the page, in this case the document has been give public access,
                        for more information on this please refer to the Access rights section of
                        this chapter.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/documentManagement/edit_document.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Editing an existing document</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            </section>
    <section>
        <title>Editing an existing document</title>
        <para>Once documents have been stored in onCourse you can edit their properties in the
            Document list view. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/documentManagement/document_list_view.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Document list view</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>You can view or edit any of the documents in the list by double clicking on the
            document you want to open.</para>
        <para> There are a number of fields in the general tab, they are:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Name - Allows you to change the name of the document.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>'duck45.png' - In this field you can change the name of the file.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Access - This drop down box allows you to choose what access rights you want
                    to give to the document. For more information please refer to the Access rights
                    section of this chapter.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Description - You have the ability to write a short description about this
                    document.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>You also have the ability to add tags and view the 12 records that are linked to duck
            by clicking on the open related record icon next to the text 'Currently attached to 12
            records'. The check box below lets you know whether this document has been allowed to be
            able to be attached to multiple records. This option can't be changed when editing an
            existing document if it is already attached to more than one record.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/documentManagement/edit_attachment_general.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>General overview of the document</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>By clicking on the 'History' tab you have the ability to view previous versions of the
            document 'duck' and view either the records linked to them or open a previous version of
            duck. You also have the ability to upload a new version of duck by clicking on the
            'Upload new version' button at the bottom left side of the sheet. More information on
            this can be found on this in the next section Versioning.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/documentManagement/edit_attachment_history.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Version history of the document</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>    
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Versioning</title>
        <para>onCourse keeps a history of all files you upload, allowing you to link records to
            specific older versions and review the history of your documents at any time. This makes
            it easy for you to comply with ASQA auditing requirements as well as ensuring you never
            lose an important document again.</para>
        <para>Upload a new version of the document from the edit view shown in the previous section.
            You will be given the opportunity to find the file you wish to upload and replace the
            existing document. In this scenario you are trying to upload a new version of the
            document duck, you are then shown the following options:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Freeze this attachment to the previous version to 8 past/completed classes
                        or enrolments - This means that there are 8 past/completed classes or
                        enrolments that have been linked to the previous version of duck. If you
                        check this box then the previous version of duck will be frozen to the 8
                        past/completed classes or enrolments. In the case of uploading a new version
                        of an assessment task, for example, you would freeze the past/completed
                        records to the version that applied to them.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Freeze this attachment to the previous version to 2 current/in progress
                        classes or enrolments - This means that there are 2 current/in progress that
                        have been linked to the previous version of duck. If you check this box then
                        the previous version of duck will be frozen to the 2 current/in progress
                        classes or enrolments. Depending on the change made between versions, you
                        may sometimes choose to update the current records, and sometimes
                        not.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Freeze this attachment to the previous version to 1 future classes or
                        enrolments - This means that there is 1 future class or enrolment that have
                        been linked to the previous version of duck. If you check this box then the
                        previous version of duck will be frozen to that 1 future class or enrolment. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Below these check boxes will be the total number of classes and enrolments
                        that will be attached to the new version of duck. This number will change
                        accordingly if some of the above boxes are checked.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Description of this change - you can write a short description explaining
                        the reason or differences of this change.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The name of the file can be changed in the field below the image on the
                        right side of the page, in this case it has been named swan.png.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can also use the open related record icons to find out more
                        information about the records linked to the versions of this document</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>When uploading a new version of a document it is good practice to make a
                        short note describing the change between the previous version and this
                        version. This 'description of change' is available in the document history
                        version list.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>Once you have finished with the above information you can save the changes made by
            clicking the 'Store' button at the bottom right hand side of the page.</para>
        <para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/documentManagement/upload_new_version.png" format="png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Uploading a new version of a document</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Freezing</title>
        <para>The term freeze and frozen is used in this chapter to describe when either records
            have been attached to a specific version of a document or when a specific document has
            been attached to past/completed, current/in progress, or future classes or enrolments. </para>
        <para>When a record is frozen to a specific version of a document it means that even if you
            update the document the record will still have the previous frozen version of the
            document attached to it, and won't receive the update. </para>
        <para>When you upload a new version of a document to certain record types you will have the
            choice to freeze the previous version to past/completed, current/in progress, and future
            classes or enrolments.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Special documents</title>
        <para>Some parts of onCourse have special handling of documents. At the moment the only publicly visible
            example of this is the contact picture. If you open a contact record (company, tutor, student) in edit
            view double click on the image at the top left, you can add your own photo of that person.
            A file dialog will appear and you will be able to choose a photo to add. It will be automatically
            resized to thumbnail sizes before being stored.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Access rights</title>
        <para>Each document can have one of several levels of access:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Public - This gives everyone access to the document and will appear on
                        your onCourse public website, as part of the sales and marketing
                        material.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Private - This means this document will not replicate to the website or
                        the skillsOnCourse portal. It will only be available to administrative users
                        of the onCourse software.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Tutors and enrolled students - Both Tutors and enrolled students of the
                        related course or class can view this document in their skillsOnCourse
                        portals.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Tutors only - This means only the tutors of the related course or class
                        can view this document in their skillsOnCourse portal.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/documentManagement/access_rights.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Various access rights options</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
