<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="downloadinstall">
	<title>Downloading and installing onCourse</title>
	<para>onCourse is free to download and use and is available for download at <link
			xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/download"> http://www.ish.com.au/download </link>. </para>
	<para>You will need to download two applications: onCourse Client and onCourse Server. The Server
		application manages your data and the Client application allows you to log in, edit and view
		your data. You will usually only need one onCourse Server application running, and onCourse
		Client installed on every workstation which needs access. </para>
	<tip>
		<para>There are no limits to the number of clients you connect to your server. There is no
			'single-user' version of onCourse, but you can run the server and client on the same
			machine.</para>
		<para>You should normally only run <emphasis>one</emphasis> onCourse Server on your network to
			avoid problems that arise from having multiple databases.</para>
	</tip>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Requirements">
		<title>System requirements</title>
		<para>One of the following operating systems is required to run onCourse Client.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Windows XP or later. Windows Vista, Windows 7 and Windows 8 are supported, and all desktop
					and server versions of Windows should work fine.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Mac OS X 10.6 or later</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Linux/BSD or any other unix running Gnome or KDE.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>One of the following operating systems is required to run onCourse Server.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Windows XP or later. Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows Server (all versions)
					are supported, and all desktop and server versions of Windows should work fine.
					You don't need Windows Server to run onCourseServer.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Mac OS X 10.6 or later </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>FreeBSD/BSD/Solaris either with a desktop or headless</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Java 7 or Java 8 are required for both the client and the server. You can install the
			latest Java from http://www.java.com at no cost. You do not need a Java plugin for your
			browser.</para>
		<para>The actual operating system configuration is largely irrelevant to onCourse. onCourse will
			not run any better or worse on a 'server' operating system. Use any operating system you feel
			comfortable in supporting.<tip>
				<para>Although the operating system isn't that important, make sure that you are running the
					most recent version of Java available for your system and keep it updated.</para>
			</tip></para>
		<para>onCourse Client requires a minimum of 512Mb of free RAM to run. onCourse Server will run
			in 1024Mb of RAM, however we recommend 1.5Gb as a minimum and more RAM is beneficial for the
			Server application in larger installations. Note that if you are running a 32bit operating
			system you are limited to 1.5Gb and we recommend running onCourse Server on a 64bit operating
			system. Note that the above RAM requirements are the RAM needed for onCourse itself; you
			require more RAM to run other applications and the operating system itself.</para>
		<para>onCourse will run with less RAM than the minimums above, however the performance will suffer
			if the application has to write to swap memory on disk.</para>
		<para>If you want to utilise more than the minimum amounts of RAM for the onCourse Server you
			must change the server configuration to allow it to take advantage of your extra RAM. See
				<xref xlink:href="#serverconfigurationfile" /></para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Network">
		<title>Network requirements</title>
		<para>onCourse Client makes a network connection to onCourse Server, by default on port 8181
			(unencrypted) or 8182 (encrypted). One or both of these ports must be open on any
			firewall you have in place. By default onCourse Server sets the Windows firewall to
			allow those ports inbound: in other operating systems you may need to put a manual rule
			in place if you have a server-based firewall.</para>
		<para>onCourse will work fastest if you have a gigabit or better ethernet connection from the
			client to the server, but it will also work acceptably over slower connections. Depending on
			your data size you may be able to work from an onCourse Client on an ADSL connection, but you
			need to ensure that the onCourse Server has a good <emphasis role="bold">outbound</emphasis>
			data link. Many consumer grade ADSL connections have a slow outbound data speed so you need
			SHDSL or at least ADSL with Annex M. Ask your ISP about these things.</para>
		<para>onCourse Server also requires outbound access to oncourse-replicate.ish.com.au on port 443.
			This allows the server to download the latest TGA course data, send SMS and synchronise
			data to your website. onCourse Server will connect to LDAP or AD if you have that
			configured and it will try to send email to a mail server on port 25. You can configure
			that within the preferences window to point to your preferred SMTP mail server.</para>

	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Cloud">
		<title>Cloud</title>
		<para>onCourse has been optimised for the cloud and ish offer different hosting packages to run,
			maintain, upgrade and backup the server. You can do the same within your own data centre
			or with a virtual hosting environment such as AWS or Rackspace.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Virtualisation">
		<title>Virtualisation</title>
		<para>onCourse will run perfectly fine in a virtualised environment such as VMWare. Ensure that
			you have sufficient RAM and CPU allocated to onCourse and consult your VMWare expert for
			tuning. onCourse Client will rarely write to disk and onCourse Server only writes log files to
			disk unless you are using the built-in database option.</para>
		<para>Many colleges choose to run onCourse Client under Terminal Services. This is a good option
			if you use Terminal Services to manage your client deployment and can give you better
			performance if your client workstations are at the other end of a slow network link.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Database">
		<title>Database considerations</title>
		<para>onCourse Server can be used with its built-in database, or for larger installations with
			an external database. You can choose between the following databases:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Built-in</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>MySql (minimum requirement is version 5.5)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Microsoft SQL Server (minimum requirement is version 2008)</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Most users should choose the built-in database option as it is by far the simplest and
			performs very well even for databases of over 100,000 students and a dozen simultaneous users.
			The other database choices will require an Enterprise support plan from ish (see our onCourse
			services and web site pricing guide for further information <link
				xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/oncourse/features/pricing">onCourse Price Guide </link>),
			and could be more appropriate if you already have existing database skills and infrastructure
			and have more advanced reporting and auditing requirements.</para>
		<para>When setting up or upgrading a database on MS SQL, the simplest approach is to create a
			new user, which will have db owner level of security permissions. If you instead use the SA
			user the upgrade will not work.</para>
		<caution>
			<para>If you use the built-in database, make sure that you put your data file on a disk
				connected directly to the computer onCourse Server is running on. That is, do NOT put the
				data file on a disk which is shared over the network (eg. on a NAS device or file
				server).</para>
		</caution>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Installation">
		<title>Installation</title>
		<para>Download the server version for your operating system from the website: <link
				xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/download">www.ish.com.au/oncourse/download
			</link>. You can mix platforms within the one installation, so for example the server could be
			running on Linux, some clients on Windows and others on Mac.</para>
		<section os="windows" xml:id="downloadinstall-installwindows">
			<title>onCourse on Windows</title>
			<section>
				<title>onCourse Server Download and Installation</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Download the server version for Windows: <link
								xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/node/72">www.ish.com.au/oncourse/start
							</link>.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You will have the option to open the zip file or save it to your computer. Select
							your preferred option. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once the file has downloaded, extract the file to somewhere on your computer you
							want to save the onCourse program, for example 'Program Files'</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Double click on the server application onCourse Server.exe to start it </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">For new users:</emphasis>If this is the first time that you've
					run the onCourse server, you will be prompted to either create a new database from scratch
					or run with a sample database. Using the sample database will let you get a feel of the
					onCourse software with some pre-populated data, like Courses, Classes, Tutors and
					Students. Selecting <emphasis role="italic">New File</emphasis> will let you start adding
					your own data for your College. We recommend you select the <emphasis role="italic">Sample
						File</emphasis> database to use until you get the hang of onCourse. It's easy to remove
					the sample database when you are ready to start using your own data. Which ever option you
					choose, you will be asked to choose a location to store the database. The location can be
					anywhere on your computer where you wish to keep the data and can be changed later.
					onCourse will create a folder called onCourse.iocdata wherever you choose to store your
					data file.</para>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">For existing users:</emphasis>If you already have created a data
					file during a previous installation of onCourse, you will not be asked to create a new
					data file. onCourse will continue to use your previous data file unless you have moved or
					deleted it. This location will be confirmed each time the server starts. If onCourse does
					not automatically find your data file it will ask you to select from three options. Choose
						<emphasis role="italic">Existing File</emphasis> and point it to the storage location of
					your data file. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>onCourse Client Download and Installation</title>
				<orderedlist arch="">
					<listitem>
						<para>Download the client for Windows: <link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/node/72"
								>www.ish.com.au/oncourse/start </link>. You can put it on the same computer as the
							server or a different computer. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You will have the option to open the zip file or save it to your computer. Select
							your preferred option</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once the file has downloaded, extract the file to somewhere on your computer you
							want to save the onCourse program, for example 'Program Files'</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Double click on the client application onCourse.exe to run it (you need to have
							the server already running)</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The initial user name is "admin". Enter the password "admin"</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the "advanced" button to see the server details</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the "Find Server" button that appears, then click "login"</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para>By default, the host appears as "localhost" and the port as 8181. If you are using
					Windows Vista or have a firewall installed, you may need to allow traffic through that
					port for onCouse to run. </para>
				<para>If the login failed, you will need to manually find the host name or IP address of the
					computer you started ish onCourse Server on. If they are running on the same computer, you
					can use "localhost". If the Server is on another computer, it might have an IP addrress
					which looks like "192.168.0.10". You can find the IP address in "Control Panels>Network
					connections" under Windows. </para>
				<para>If you start the onCourse client before the onCourse server has finished loading, you
					will get an error message. If it is your first time starting the server, it may take a few
					minutes as the data file populates. Check the status of the server, wait a few minutes and
					try again. </para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section os="macosx">
			<title>onCourse on Mac OS X</title>
			<section>
				<title>onCourse Server Download and Installation</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para> Download the server version for Mac: <link
								xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/node/72">www.ish.com.au/oncourse/start
							</link>.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> You will have the option to open the zip file or save it to your computer. Select
							the preferred option. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Mount the disk image by double clicking on it, Copy onCourse Server from the
							window that pops up into your "Applications" folder. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Double click on the server application onCourseServer.dmg to start it </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">For new users:</emphasis>If this is the first time that you've
					run the onCourse server, you will be prompted to either create a new database from scratch
					or run with a sample database. Using the sample database will let you get a feel of the
					onCourse software with some pre-populated data, like Courses, Classes, Tutors and
					Students. Selecting <emphasis role="italic">New File</emphasis>will let you start adding
					your own data for your College. We recommend you select the database to use until you get
					the hang of onCourse. It's easy to remove the sample database when you are ready to start
					using your own data. Which ever option you choose, you will be asked to choose a location
					to store the database. The location can be anywhere on your computer where you wish to
					keep the data and can be changed later. onCourse will create a folder called
					onCourse.iocdata wherever you choose to store your data file. </para>
				<para><emphasis role="bold">For existing users:</emphasis>If you already have created a data
					file during a previous installation of onCourse, you will not be asked to create a new
					data file. onCourse will continue to use your previous data file unless you have moved or
					deleted it. This location will be confirmed each time the server starts. If onCourse does
					not automatically find your data file it will ask you to select from three options. Choose
						<emphasis role="italic">Existing File</emphasis> and point it to the storage location of
					your data file. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>onCourse Client Download and Installation</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para> Download the client version for Mac OS X. It can be on the same computer as the
							server or a different computer. This will be a file called onCourse.dmg </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> You will have the option to open the zip file or save it to your computer. Select
							your preferred option </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> Mount the disk image by double clicking on it. Copy onCourseClient from the
							window that pops up into your "Applications" folder</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Double click on the client application onCourse.dmg to run it (you need to have
							the server already running)</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The initial user name is "admin". Enter the password "admin"</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the "advanced" button that appears, click "login" </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para> By default, the host appears as "localhost" and the port as 8181. If the login
					failed, you will need to manually find the host name or IP address of the computer you
					started the ish onCourse Server. If they are running on the same computer, you can use
					"localhost". If the server is on another computer, it might have an IP address which looks
					like "192.168.0.10". You can find the IP address in "System Preferences > Network" on a
					Mac. </para>
				<para>If you start the onCourse client before the onCourse server has finished loading, you
					will get an error message. If it is your first time starting the server, it may take a few
					minutes as the data file populates. Check the status of the server, wait a few minutes and
					try again. </para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Running onCourse</title>
			<section>
				<title>Running the Server</title>
				<section>
					<title>For new users:</title>
					<para>
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/serverChooseDatabase.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject>
					</para>
					<para>If this is the first time that you've run onCourse server, you will be prompted to
						choose one of the following: <simplelist>
							<member>"New File" - for new database which will let you start adding your own data
								for your College.</member>
							<member>"Sample File" - pre-populated with a range of sample records to allow you to
								get a feel for the onCourse software without needing to enter lots of data.</member>
							<member>"Existing File" - used to locate a onCourse database you previously
								created.</member>
						</simplelist></para>
					<para>We recommend you select the "Sample File" until you get the hang of OnCourse. It's
						easy to remove the sample database when you are ready to start using your own data.
						Which ever option you choose, will be asked to choose a location to store the database.
						The location can be anywhere on your computer where you wish to keep the data and can be
						changed later. onCourse will create a folder called "onCourse.iocdata" wherever you
						choose to store your data file. </para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>For existing users</title>
					<para>If you already have created a data file during a previous installation of OnCourse,
						you will not be asked to create a new data file. OnCourse will continue to use your
						previous data file unless you have moved or deleted it. If OnCourse does not
						automatically find your data file it will ask you to select from the three options.
						Choose "Existing File" and point it to the storage location of your data file. </para>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Running the Client</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/adminlogin.png"
						 />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The relationship option, click "select" to choose a type of relationship between
							contacts</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<orderedlist arch="">
					<listitem>
						<para>Username is "admin". Password is "admin". </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click the on the "advanced" button to see the server details </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on "Find Server" button that appears, then click "login"</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<para> If you have a workstation firewall installed, you may need to allow traffic through
					that port for OnCourse to run. </para>
				<para> If the login failed, you will need to manually find the host name or IP address of
					the computer where ish onCourse Server is running. If they are running on the same
					computer, you can use "localhost". If the server is on another computer, it might have an
					IP address which looks like "192.168.0.10". You can find the IP address in "Control Panels
					> Network connections". </para>
				<tip>
					<para>If you see a line on the Server that says "Application service running" with a
						twirling busy icon next to it, this means the server is busy and will be unable to
						accept client connections. Wait until the icon goes away before connecting a client. If
						you start the OnCourse client before the OnCourse server has finished loading, you will
						get an error message. If this is your first time starting the server, it may take a few
						minutes as the data file populates. Check the status of the server, wait a few minutes
						and try again. </para>
				</tip>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Installing onCourse Server on other platforms</title>
			<section os="freebsd">
				<title>onCourseServer on FreeBSD</title>
				<section>
					<title>Installing</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Download the FreeBSD server package (onCourseServer.tgz) onto your FreeBSD box.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Run as root:
								<programlisting language="shell">
pkg_add onCourseServer.tgz
echo 'onCourseServer_enable="YES"' >> /etc/rc.conf</programlisting></para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<para>Our package places onCourse Server into the FreeBSD default location and creates a
						startup script to run when the machine reboots.</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Uninstalling the server</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para> Type the following command as root in a shell:
								<programlisting language="shell">pkg_delete onCourseServer-&lt;version></programlisting></para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<para>then press enter to safely remove all components of onCourse Server except for your
						very valuable data. </para>
					<tip>
						<para> You can figure out what packagename and version of onCourse Server is installed
							by running
							<programlisting language="shell">pkg_info -v | grep -i oncourse</programlisting></para>
					</tip>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Starting and stopping the server</title>
					<para> onCourse Server is not started immediately after the install, you will need to
						execute as root:
						<programlisting>/usr/local/etc/rc.d/onCourseServer start</programlisting></para>
					<para> And of course stopping the server is just:
						<programlisting>/usr/local/etc/rc.d/onCourseServer stop</programlisting></para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Upgrading</title>
					<para> In order to upgrade to a newer version of onCourse Server, run as root:
						<programlisting>
/usr/local/etc/rc.d/onCourseServer stop
pkg_delete onCourseServer-&lt;package version>
pkg_add onCourseServer.tgz
/usr/local/etc/rc.d/onCourseServer start</programlisting></para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Other notes</title>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para> You will need Java installed. Consult the FreeBSD docs on how to best do that.
								You can set the amount of memory that Java will allocate to onCourse Server by
								adding to /etc/rc.conf: <programlisting>onCourseServer_mem="768M"</programlisting>
								replacing 768 with however much memory you wish. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> Make sure you have the latest timezones installed via the ports system, which
								can be done by installing the "zoneinfo" port.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> You will also need to add an argument to the startup parameters of
								onCourseServer in rc.conf along the lines of
								<programlisting>onCourseServer_flags="-Duser.timezone=Australia/Sydney"</programlisting>
								replacing Australia/Sydney with the timezone that you wish the server to be in.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section os="unix">
				<title>Linux, Solaris and any other Unix</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>You will need a recent JVM installed in order to run onCourse. Please review the
								<link xlink:href="#requirements">requirements.</link></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Download the unix package and transfer this file onto your server.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Extract the contents of the package into the /opt directory using the tar command line
							utility, ie:</para>
						<programlisting>sudo tar xvzf onCourseServer.tgz -C /opt</programlisting>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>This should extract a directory onCourse with two files in it. <simplelist>
								<member> onCourseServer.sh </member>
								<member> onCourseServer.jar </member>
							</simplelist></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Run the onCourseServer.sh script to start the server (Please read the onCourseServer.sh
							carefully as this will explain how to start successfully).</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<programlisting>sudo bash /opt/onCourse/onCourseServer.sh</programlisting>
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Upgrading">
		<title>Upgrading onCourse</title>
		<para>How to install a new version of onCourse</para>
		<section>
			<title>What is an onCourse upgrade?</title>
			<para>Periodically, ish release new versions of the onCourse client and server software. These
				new releases may include new features, new reports or important fixes from previous version. </para>
			<para>When we release a new version we also publish release notes outlining the changes we
				have made in plain English. All onCourse releases or product updates are available freely to
				download for all users on both paid and free plans. We will send a message to all users on
				our onCourse mailing list and also publish information about the release on our blog. </para>
			<para>Users can choose how and when to upgrade their business software. Both the server and
				client software will need to be upgraded, meaning that you will not be able to
				access your onCourse database during the upgrade process. Usually this will take
				less than 10 minutes. Your onCourse website will continue to function and take
				enrolments during the upgrade process.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Backing up your onCourse datafile</title>
			<para>All the important customer and business information you have entered into onCourse is
				stored in a file called onCourse.iocdata on your server machine. When you first installed
				onCourse you would have specified the location for this file, but if you can't remember
				where you saved it you can search your machine for this file. The file may appear as a
				folder on some operating systems. </para>
			<para>This file is very important. As a general rule, you should ensure you have set the
				internal onCourse backup process to run daily. You then should ensure that the backup file
				is copied to an offsite storage location, like a remote server in another office or taken
				offsite daily on a USB or tape drive.</para>
			<para> In addition to this automatic backup process, you can also manually backup onCourse
				prior to running an upgrade. To do this you need to first make sure all your users have
				logged out of onCourse client and that you have shut down the onCourse server software (or
				stopped the onCourse service if running as a service on a Windows machine). </para>
			<para>1. Shut down the onCourse server </para>
			<para>2. Locate the onCourse.iocdata file </para>
			<para>3. Make a copy of the onCourse.iocdata file and save it in another folder or drive </para>
			<para>4. Rename the copied onCourse.iocdata file something like
				onCourse.manualbackup1-3-10</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Upgrading the onCourse datafile</title>
			<para>Now you have made a backup of your most recent datafile you are ready to upgrade your
				database.</para>
			<para> To upgrade, you first need to have downloaded the most recent onCourse server
				software</para>
			<para>Run the downloaded install package and install the new version of the onCourse server in
				the same location as the previous copy of the onCourse server. This will overwrite the
				server software. </para>
			<para>When you run the new copy of the server software it will automatically upgrade your
				onCourse data to the latest version. This process may take up some time if significant
				changes were made or if you are upgrading from a much older version. </para>
			<para>Please contact us with a copy of your onCourseServer.log file if during this process you
				get a message that the upgrade process has failed.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Upgrading the onCourse clients</title>
			<para>On all machines where your users access onCourse, you will need to make sure that the
				local copy of the onCourse client software is upgraded. </para>
			<para>If an older version of the client attempts to access the server, it will be unsuccessful
				and get a message about the server being a newer version. </para>
			<para>To upgrade the clients, ensure you downloaded the most recent onCourse client
				software</para>
			<para>Run the downloaded install package and install the new version of the onCourse client in
				the same location as the previous copy of the onCourse client on each machine. This will
				overwrite the client software. </para>
			<para>Ensure the server software is back up and running before attempting to log in the new
				client. All user names and passwords will stay the same as prior to the upgrade.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Can I downgrade my onCourse software?</title>
			<para>No, after you have upgraded you can not then downgrade your onCourse data file. This is
				because structural changes will have been made as part of any upgrade process which means
				the data is no longer compatible with the previous version.</para>
			<para> If you need to downgrade or run a previous version of onCourse for any reason, you can
				use the manual backup file you made prior to upgrade. Please note that any new data you have
				entered after the upgrade will not be available from your backup. You can request copies of
				previous versions of the onCourse software installation files from ish at any time.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Starting a new data file</title>
			<para>I have been running the onCourse sample file, now I want to start my own new datafile. How
				can I do this?</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>On the machine running the onCourse server, ensure the server software is shut down. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Find the location of the onCourse.iocdata (most likely in C/Program Files/onCourse on a
						Windows machine) </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Rename the onCourse.iocadata file something like
							onCourse.iocdata.olddata. Changing the file extension means the server
							software won't recognise or open the file when it next starts up.
						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Run the onCourse server. Because you hid the old datafile it will
							ask you if you want to start a new, sample or existing datafile. Choose
							new and save the datafile in the same location as before. This will
							create a new onCourse.iocdata file 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once the server has completed the start up process, connect an
							onCourse client. Allow about 5 minutes for the TGA data to download. You
							can check it has completed by looking in the 'Unit of Competency'
							window. It will say 0 shown of 52000 odd records in the window header
							bar when it has completed. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>
				You are now ready to start the process again of setting up your
							sites, courses, classes, students and enrolments.

			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Running multiple versions of the onCourse Server</title>
			<para>If you have an onCourse website it is very important that you never run two copies of
				your onCourse datafile simultaneously or attempt to revert to an onCourse backup without
				contacting ish first. We can ensure your backup datafile does not try to override your
				website data when you run it. This includes customers who wish to run a test or training
				installation of a new onCourse software version using their current datafile.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="downloadinstall-Troubleshooting">
		<title>Troubleshooting connection problems</title>
		<para>When you run into problems with connecting a client to the server, the login window will
			often display some messages in red text to inform you of difficulties. Here some common causes
			for each error message.</para>
		<qandaset>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>A connection to the server could not be established.</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is generally a networking issue or onCourse server may not be running. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Your workstation or the server may not be connected to the network.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You have ticked Secure connection (SSL) in the advanced options, but the server
								is not running in SSL mode.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You have not ticked Secure connection (SSL) in the advanced options, but the
								server is running in SSL mode only.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>The server and client versions are incompatible. The "client/server" is a more
						recent build.</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>You are attempting to connect an older client with a newer server.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>You are attempting to connect a newer client with an older server.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<para>Ensure the client and server are the same versions. Download them from <link
							xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/onCourse/download"
							>http://www.ish.com.au/download</link>
					</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Authentication failed.</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Either the password is incorrect or the username is incorrect or both.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>If you have never logged in before, try "admin" as the username and "admin" as
								the password.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>None of the TGA Qualifications or Units of Competency have downloaded, or there seem to
						be some missing.</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>The mechanism within onCourse that is utilised by our clients with an onCourse managed
						webservice is also used to poll our webserver periodically for any changes
						to the TGA data, including customers using the free onCourse community
						version, to ensure you have the latest version of the data (and also to save
						us packaging this data within our application download - the first time your
						sever connects you will have downloaded the 52,000 odd unit of competency
						records) </para>
					<para>Your server makes a connection once a day to https://oncourse-replicate.ish.com.au on
						port 443. If this port is blocked by your firewall, you won't be able to
						access any of the TGA data updates. Make sure you can visit this URL and
						that the firewall allows traffic.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
		</qandaset>
	</section>
</chapter>
