<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	version="5.0" xml:id="emailTemplates">
	<title>Email Templates</title>
	<section xml:id="emailTemplates-emailTemplates">
		<title>Email Templates</title>
		<para>The best way to define a message template is that it is a predefined and pre-constructed
			message that are sent out manually or automatically when on an event has occurred. An
			event that sends a message is defined by a <link xlink:href="scripts.html"
			>script</link>. An example would be that a student has just enrolled into a class via
			the website or through the office, so the 'send enrolment script' will email the
			'Enrolment Confirmation' template to the enrolling student. </para>
		<para>Inside the email template, fields like ${enrolment.student.contact.firstName} in the
			template will insert the relevant data from onCourse into the message.</para>
		<para>onCourse makes it easy to access and update your templated messages by keeping them in the one place. You can use the templates as
			they are or you can personalise them to your specific needs and requirements. You can also create additional templates, and where
			necessary, accompanying scripts, specific to your business requirements.</para>
		<para>onCourse default templates include both a plain text and HTML version of the template. If make changes to the template wording you
			should change both versions of the template for consistency. The receiver's mail client preferences will determine if they receive the
			plain or HTML version of the message.</para>
		<para>The content of the plain text and HTML templates should be the same, the HTML template
			just includes additional information for the styling of the message so it renders inside
			email clients.</para>
		<para>Be careful when changing the names of the email templates. If the template is used by
			a script, you will need to change the reference to the template name in the script
			also.</para>
		<para>The default templates included in onCourse are listed in the sections below.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolment cog wheel templates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Class cancellation</emphasis> - triggered by the script
						'Send class cancellation' to advise students their class was cancelled, send
						them a link to the website showing other options for the class, and requesting
						they contact you to request a transfer or refund. This email template can be
						sent manually from the enrolment list view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Enrolment Confirmation</emphasis> - triggered by the
						script 'Send enrolment' to advise students their enrolment was successful, and
						of the details of their class sessions. This email template can be sent manually
						from the enrolment list view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Enrolment notification</emphasis> - triggered by the
						script 'Send enrolment notice for tutors' to advise a tutor or third party each
						time an enrolment is received into their class. This email template can be sent
						manually from the enrolment list view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Student notice of class commencement</emphasis> - triggered by the
						script 'Send student class commencement notice' and the script 'send student
						class commencement notice 7 days' 'to remind students their class is commencing
						soon. This email template can be sent manually from the enrolment list
						view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">USI reminder email</emphasis> - triggered by the script
						'Send USI reminder' to remind VET enrolled students to provide their USI before
						their class completes. This email template can be sent manually from the
						enrolment list view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem xml:id="emailTemplates-VETcourseCompletion">
					<para><emphasis role="bold">VET course completion Survey </emphasis>-
						triggered by the script 'VET course completion Survey' to advise VET
						learners of the Learner Questionnaire.  </para>
				</listitem>	
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Course completion survey </emphasis>- triggered by the script 'Send
						class completion survey' to send an email to each student requesting they complete
						the skillsOnCourse survey. This email can also be sent manually from the enrolment
						window.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Schedule Change</emphasis> - Can only be triggered
						manually via the cogwheel. Sends an email worded very similarly to the
						Enrolment Confirmation except details the subject of a schedule
						change.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Invoice cog wheel templates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Tax invoice</emphasis> - triggered by the script 'Send
						invoice' to the invoice payer on enrolment, or via checkbox on manual invoice
						creation. This email template can be sent manually from the invoice list
						view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Payment reminder</emphasis> - triggered by the script
						'Send payment plan reminder' to advise debtors their payment is due and send
						them a link to make payment. This email template can be sent manually from the
						invoice list view.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
				<section>
					<title>Payment In cog wheel templates</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para><emphasis role="bold">Payment receipt</emphasis> - triggered by the script
								'Send payment receipt' to advise debtors their payment has been received. This
								email template can be sent manually from the payment in list view</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</section>
		<section>
			<title>Payment Out cog wheel templates</title>
			<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis role="bold">Refund advice</emphasis> - triggered by the script 'Send
				refund advice' to advise contacts a refund has been processed for them.</para>
		</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Application cog wheel templates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Enrolment application received</emphasis> - triggered by
						the script 'Send application received notification' to advise students their
						application has been received and if send them a link to complete additional
						application questions, or complete the USI portal process if they are applying
						for a VET course. This email template can be sent manually from the application
						list view. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Enrolment application accepted</emphasis> - triggered by
						the script 'Send application decision' to advise students their application has
						been accepted and include a link so they can proceed to enrol and pay. This
						email template can be sent manually from the application list view.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Enrolment application rejected</emphasis> - triggered by
						the script 'Send application decision' to advise student their application has
						been rejected and why. This email template can be sent manually from the
						application list view.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Sales cog wheel templates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem xml:id="emailTemplates-Voucheremail">
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Voucher email</emphasis> - triggered by the script 'Send voucher' to
						send the voucher code for redemption. This email template can be sent manually
						from the voucher or Sales list view</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Membership Notification Renewal </emphasis>- triggered by the script
						'Membership Notification Renewal' to advise current members to renew before
						their membership expires. This email can also be sent manually from the Sales
						window.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Waitlist cog wheel templates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Waiting list notification </emphasis>- This template is not linked
						to a script. It is designed to be sent manually to students on a waiting list to
						suggest they enrol in a class that may have limited vacancies available.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>System Templates</title>
			<para>These templates are either embedded within other templates, or can only be triggered from scripts. They can not be sent manually.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Header</emphasis> - this email template is embedded into
						all other email templates, to include your college name and optionally, the
						logo.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Footer</emphasis> this email template is embedded into
						all other email templates to include your college contact details.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Certificate available</emphasis> - triggered by the script 'Send
						certificate VET created notification' and 'Send certificate created
						notification' to advise students certificates are available in the portal and
						include a link to complete the class survey and download their certificate. This
						email template can not be run manually and should not be linked to an
						entity.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Tutor notice of class commencement </emphasis>-
						triggered by the script 'Send tutor class commencement notice' to remind tutors
						their class is commencing. This email template can not be run manually.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Waiting list reminder </emphasis>- triggered by the
						script 'Send waiting list reminder' to advise students of classes available,
						when a student has subscribed to a waiting list. This email template can not be
						run manually.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Payment reminder </emphasis>- triggered by the script
						'Send payment plan reminder' to advise debtors of unpaid invoices, or students
						on payment plans that their payment is overdue, or due within the next 7 days.
						Included in the email is a link where the debtor can click to make a credit card
						payment via the onCourse portal.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Survey invitation</emphasis> - triggered by the
						integration scripts 'SurveyMonkey send invite on enrolment', 'SurveyMonkey send
						invite on enrolment completion', 'SurveyGizmo send invite on enrolment' and
						'SurveyGizmo send invite on completion'. This email template can not be run
						manually.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Editing an existing message template</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Go to File > Preferences > Email templates</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Double click on a message from list to open it in edit view. The top half of the window is the plain text version of the
						message, the lower half the HTML version.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can add and remove text from this message. Any text that appears inside a field reference ${like.this} is drawing data
						from the onCourse database. Modify these fields with care.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Make your change to both the plain text and HTML version of the message then save and
						close. We suggest copying and pasting the text from the HTML portion of the
						template into an HTML editor like <link xlink:href="https://www.sublimetext.com/download"
							>Sublime Text</link>. Sublime will colour code the
						HTML and content making it simpler for you to make the changes you wish
						without breaking the HTML.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/email_template.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Enrolment Confirmation" template window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/sublime_email_template.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Editing HTML content in sublime. Note the email body text in white font</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Email headers and footers</title>
			<para>The default template list includes a header and footer template, which contains both a
				plain text and HTML layout.</para>
			<para>These templates are used inside every other email template.</para>
			<para>If you look at the template text you'll see that most of the data used to create
				these templates is drawn from the AVETMISS preferences tab settings. Even if you
				don't report AVETMISS you should complete these fields so the data used in your
				templates is correct.</para>
			<para>The HTML version of the header and footer can insert your businesses logo and use
				your style guide colour scheme with some minor adjustments. If you do not have a web
				designer available you can contact ish to request custom changes to these, and other
				templates.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Creating new templates</title>
			<para>New templates can be created at your convenience. Click on the + in the top right hand corner of the template window to create a
				new template.</para>
			<para>If your organisation has the appropriate IT skills in house, you can create your own custom templates or you can request an ish
				developer create them for you. The development of custom templates is quoted on request.</para>
			<para>To understand the entities, objects and attributes available to use in building a template, we recommend you download Cayenne
				Modeler and read the section about <link xlink:href="#dataModel">using the onCourse data model</link>. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Writing Groovy in email templates</title>
			<para>The templates are written in a programming language called Groovy which is a Java based language that can run inside the
				onCourse application. An overview of the language can be found at <link xlink:href="http://groovy.codehaus.org"
					>http://groovy.codehaus.org</link>. </para>
			<para>The onCourse API documentation, explaining the database structure is available <link
					xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/api/">on the onCourse
					support page</link></para>
			<section>
				<title>Examples of Groovy in the templates</title>
				<para>Both onCourse email templates and scripts are written in Groovy. onCourse templates are created using the <link
						xlink:href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/Groovy+Templates">GStringTemplateEngine</link>, storing the template files within the
					onCourse database.</para>
				<para>The key to creating a successful template is to ensure you begin with the most appropriate onCourse entity for the task. This
					will make the process of locating and joining other data from the database straightforward.</para>
				<para>If your template is to send information to a student in relation to a particular enrolment, then the enrolment entity would be
					the correct starting point, rather than the student or the contact.</para>
				<para>The entity name you select as the starting point of the template determines the path you use to join to attributes of other
					onCourse entities. For example if you were starting with the entity enrolment and wanted to insert the student's first name, you
					would join the enrolment to the student, then the contact as below:</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">${enrolment.student.contact.firstName}</programlisting>
				<para>However if you wanted to show the same information from a template linked to the invoice entity you would join via the
					enrolment, as the invoice is linked directly to the payer contact, who might be a different person to the student. This example
					would give me the first name of the student enrolled in the class linked to an invoiceLine on an invoice.</para>
				<programlisting>${invoice.invoiceLine.enrolment.student.contact.firstName}</programlisting>
				<para>Where this join would give you the name of the invoice payer contact.</para>
				<programlisting>${invoice.contact.firstName}</programlisting>
				<para>For some fields you may wish to add formatting, such as showing a date in a particular style. The first example shows a short
					date format and the second shows a date time and long date format. This page outlines all the <link
						xlink:href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/i18n/format/simpleDateFormat.html">Java Simple Date formats</link>
					available.</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">${invoice.createdOn.format("d/M/yy")}
${enrolment.courseClass.startDateTime.format("h:mm a EEEE d MMMM yyyy zzzz")}</programlisting>
				<para>The results you wish to display may be the result of a calculation of field values. This example subtracts one field from
					another.</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">Total Paid ${invoice.totalIncTax.subtract(invoice.amountOwing)}</programlisting>
				<para>Inside a template you may wish to include some content that is displayed based on the property of an attribute from the joined
					object. A simple example of this is only displaying a label and value if the value is not null in the database, like the optional
					customer reference field.</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">&lt;% if (invoice.customerReference) { %>
Your reference: ${invoice.customerReference}
&lt;% } %></programlisting>
				<para>A more complex example is this condition which switches the content of the enrolment confirmation based on whether the class
					is self paced or has sessions.</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">&lt;% if (enrolment.courseClass.startDateTime == null) { %>
Start: On enrolment
Expected duration: ${enrolment.courseClass.expectedHours ?: "not specified"} hours
&lt;% } else { %>
Start: ${enrolment.courseClass.startDateTime.format("h:mm a EEEE d MMMM yyyy zzzz")}
End: ${enrolment.courseClass.endDateTime.format("h:mm a EEEE d MMMM yyyy zzzz")}
&lt;% } %>                </programlisting>
				<para>You can also create a loop inside a template to iterate through a list of joined entities. To list the invoice lines joined to
					an invoice you would start with the entity invoice and for each invoice line display the Title, PriceTotalIncTax and Description.
					More examples of collections can be found on <link xlink:href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/Collections">the Groovy website.</link>
				</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template"> &lt;% invoice.invoiceLines.each { %>
${it.title}    ${it.priceTotalIncTax}
${it.description}
&lt;% } %></programlisting>
				<para>To display an image in a email template you can first of all add the image to the onCourse
					document management system then add the following syntax to the email templates
					html body:</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">${image "imagename"}</programlisting>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Adding links to portal pages in the templates</title>
				<para>Inside email templates, you may wish to include direct links to parts of the student
					portal, for example to allow students to access their class resources without
					having to log in using the format</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">portalLink(target, timeout)</programlisting>
				<para>This format creates a signed URL that is accessible until a certain date. If no date or
					time is defined, the URL will be accessible for 7 days. A timeout can be
					definded as an absolute date (format is 'yyyy-MM-dd') or as a number, which is a
					relative date from the day the email is sent e.g. 14.</para>
				<para>Records that are linking to objects, such as specific class pages are written
					without speechmarks, where links to portal URL pages are defined as strings by
					writing them inside speech marks.</para>
				<para>If a student click on a signed link, it will limit them to accessing that page
					within the portal. For example, if you include a standard unsubscribe link in
					your emails like:</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">To remove yourself from the waiting list and unsubscribe to these notices, 
please visit ${waitingList.student.getPortalLink("subscriptions")}</programlisting>
				<para>and the user clicks on the menu item in the portal to access their outcome results, they
					will be returned to the login screen. In this way, the security of the portal is
					maintained, and the documents or timed links sent can't easily be distributed to
					others or exponse potentially confidental information.</para>
				<para>If sending from an email template linked to an enrolment, example options available
					include:</para>
				<programlisting language="groovy-template">${enrolment.student.portalLink(courseClass)} -> link to class page
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(enrolment)}  -> link to class page
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(document)}  -> link to download file directly
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(invoice)}  -> link to one invoice
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink("USI")}  -> link to USI portal page
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink("timetable")}  -> link to the timetable portal page
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink("results")}  -> link to results portal page
${enrolment.student.getPortalLink("subscriptions")}  -> link to the subscriptions portal page
</programlisting>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Sending a manual message using a template</title>
			<para>While many emails may be sent automatically based on their associated <link xlink:href="scripts.hmtl">scripts</link>, template emails
				may also be sent manually, or new templated created just to send manual messages. This allows you to resend important information
				like a Tax Invoice that may have been misplaced by the student or filtered as junk mail. The send option will use the contacts
				current email address, so this tool can also be used to resend messages that bounced due to an incorrectly entered email.</para>
			<para>Template emails can be sent using the appropriate cogwheel option 'send custom email'. The custom emails available are those
				linked to the same entity. For example, in the Enrolment Confirmation screenshot above you can see it is linked to the entity called
				Enrolment. This makes the template available in the enrolment window cogwheel list. </para>
			<para>You can send a email template from the following list views</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enrolment</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Contact</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Class</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Voucher</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Waiting List</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Invoice</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Application</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Payment In</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Payment Out</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>You can select one or more contacts from the list of records before selecting the cogwheel tool to send the message.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/send_custom_email.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Email templates available to send from the enrolment window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Default templates</title>
			<para>The default plain and html text templates, in onCourse, can be found in our <uri
				xlink:href="https://github.com/ari/oncourse-scripts/tree/master/email"
				>GitHub documentation.</uri> </para>
			<para>The text can be copied back into onCourse should you wish to revert to the
				onCourse default template for any message.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
