<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="feedback">
    <title>Feedback and Surveys</title>
    <section>
        <title>Class completion surveys in onCourse</title>
        <para>The onCourse student feedback and survey tool is designed to capture some simple data
            that can be used to track the rating of your courses, venues and tutors over time, by
            rating them out of five. In addition, the students can complete a Net Promoter Score
            (rating out of 10) where they indicate how likely they are to recommend you to a friend
            and provide free-form text feedback you can use to improve your services or publish to
            the website as a testimonial.</para>
        <para>This survey is expected to be used at the end of a training program, and a link sent
            to the students via email. The students complete their survey response in the
            SkillsOnCourse portal, and tutors are able to see a feedback summary in their portal
            also. More detailed views and reports regarding survey completion are available to admin
            users of the onCourse application.</para>
        <para>The questions available in this feedback form can not be modified. If you are looking
            to send your students a custom survey, we suggest you use specialised customisable tool
            like Survey Monkey. More information about setting up these tools can found in <xref linkend="externalintegrations"/></para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
                    fileref="images/feedback/feedback_positive.png" format="png" />
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Completed student survey</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Requesting Feedback from Students</title>
        <para>Email tools to send students to the survey tool.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Completing the survey - Student Portal View</title>
        <para>What the students see</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Viewing survey results - Tutor Portal View</title>
        <para>What the tutors see</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Viewing survey results - onCourse and print reports</title>
        <para>What the admin users see</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Editing and approving feedback for online testimonial use</title>
        <para>Process for approval</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Student Testimonials in web marketing copy</title>
        <para>How does it look on the web</para>
    </section>
</chapter>