<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="feedback">
    <title>Feedback and Surveys</title>
    <section>
        <title>Class completion surveys in onCourse</title>
        <para>The onCourse student feedback and survey tool is designed to capture some simple data
            that can be used to track the rating of your courses, venues and tutors over time, by
            rating them out of five. In addition, the students can complete a Net Promoter Score
            (rating out of 10) where they indicate how likely they are to recommend you to a friend
            and provide free-form text feedback you can use to improve your services or publish to
            the website as a testimonial. You can also add additional questions of your own using
            custom fields, or delete any of the default questions should they be unwanted.</para>
        <para>These Surveys can be set to display at set points through out a Course, or triggered
            'on demand' via a custom script. The students complete their survey response in the
            SkillsOnCourse portal, and tutors are able to see a feedback summary in their portal
            also. More detailed views and reports regarding survey completion are available to admin
            users of the onCourse application.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/feedback_positive.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Completed student survey</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>How to Edit/Remove Survey Questions</title>
        <para>To edit, remove, or add survey questions:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>in onCourse go to <emphasis role="bold">File > Preferences >
                            General</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/data_collection/feedback_default_form.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>The default field form for Student Feedback</caption>
        </mediaobject> 
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>In the left hand panel, under 'Data Collection Forms', you'll find a form
                        called <emphasis role="bold">Default Field Form (Student
                            Feedback)</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist><para>From here you can edit any of the Fields to say whatever you like. </para>
        <para>Keep in mind that the 'Comment' block is only a free standing text block and should
            not be edited (however it can be deleted), while all other blocks ask for a Star Rating. </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>How to Add Custom Survey Questions</title>
        <para>You can add your own custom questions to the survey by using the Custom Fields
            section. These questions will not use the same format as the default questions and don't
            display the Stars to respond with, instead adding a free text field for users to type
            their answers in, or a drop down menu with pre-entered answers you can set when creating
            the field. To add a question:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>in onCourse go to <emphasis role="bold">File > Preferences >
                            General</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Scroll the left-hand panel to the bottom and click <emphasis role="bold"
                            >Custom Fields</emphasis></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Hit the <emphasis role="bold">(+)</emphasis> button to add a new field and
                        set the Record Type as 'Survey'</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist> 
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/data_collection/feedback_customfield_record_type.png" format="png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>The beginning of creating a new Custom Field for a survey</caption>
                </mediaobject>   
            <itemizedlist>    
            <listitem>
                    <para>Name the field the question you wish to ask i.e. Rate the relevance of the
                        provided course materials</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If you wish to have pre-prepared answers for students to choose from,
                        enter these answers into the Default Value field and separate them with a
                        semi-colon (;)</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem><para>The custom key you choose must be unique. Make the Custom Key something
                    short and simple to reference later and enter it here.</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Requesting Feedback from Students</title>
        <para>As of onCourse 9.7 you can now request feedback from students at different points
            during a course:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">On Enrolment</emphasis> - This will make the survey
                        available to students upon enrolment into a course</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">On Start</emphasis> - This will make the survey
                        available from midnight the day the course begins</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Midway</emphasis> - This will make the survey
                        available from midnight the middle day of the course</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">At Completion</emphasis> - This will make the survey
                        available from the moment the course is completed</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">On Demand</emphasis> - This setting will require a
                        custom script to define the time's at which this survey will be sent to
                        student's to fill out.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>There are two default scripts and associated templates available as standard to
            communicate survey completion requests to students. These can be modified as required to
            suit your business requirements. More information about onCourse customising scripts can
            be found in <xref linkend="scripts"/></para>
        <para>'Send Certificate created notification' and 'Send class completion survey' both send a
            loginless link using the parameter ${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(enrolment)}. This
            link has a default time-to-live of 7 days, meaning that if the user clicks the link in
            the email within 7 days of it being sent, they can complete the feedback survey without
            logging in. You can extend the time to live by adding an additional parameter e.g.
            ${enrolment.student.getPortalLink(enrolment, 30)} means the link lasts for 30 days
            before login is required.</para>
        <para>By default the scripts trigger the day after the final class session, allowing you to
            collect feedback as soon as practical after the event is over, however if you change
            this setting within the form, it will send at the corrected time.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/standard_email_cert_and_feedback.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Sample student email sent to request feedback and supply a certificate of attendance</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Completing the survey - Student Portal View</title>
        <para>When the student clicks on the survey link in a email, they are taken directly to the
            class page where they can see their attendance results and click on the feedback link to
            complete the survey. By default the feedback link shows as five unfilled stars if the
            student has not yet provided a response.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/class_view_feedback_required.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>What the student sees when they click on the email link</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>When the student clicks on the Feedback stars, the Survey element expands. The
            response to the first question displayed 'How likely are you to recommend us to a
            friend', also known as a Net Promoter Score, determines the text that appears in the
            free text field. If the student provides an NPS of 7 or less, then the field text is
            'Please tell us how we could have improved your experience'. If the NPS is greater than
            7, the label switches to 'What did you most enjoy about your experience'.</para>
        <para>The responses in the >7 range are most likely to be those useful for marketing
            testimonial data, while responses in the =&lt; 7 range will become quality improvement
            opportunities. Best practice recommends you close the loop for Net Promoter Scores of 6
            or less, and actively follow up with the customers who provide negative feedback, using
            it as an opportunity to turn a detractor into a promoter.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/low_NPS_improve_message.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>What the student sees if they provide a low Net Promoter Score</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/high_NPS_testimonial_message.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>What the student sees if they provide a high Net Promoter Score</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>If a student has not been sent a link to the survey, they will see a link to complete
            a survey for their last completed class when they first log in to the portal. This link
            is will display in a dashboard element. Clicking this link will take them to the same
            page as clicking the direct link from an email.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/portal_feedback_student_dashboard.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Portal dashboard notification requesting feedback</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section><title>Viewing survey results - Tutor Portal View</title>
        <para>When tutors log in to their skillsOnCourse portal they can see the feedback results
            from their class, with the results showing the average responses for the starred
            ratings. There is no student identifying data displayed to the tutors, in relation to
            student feedback.</para>
        <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
                fileref="images/feedback/tutor_feedback_view.png" format="png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>
            <para>Tutor view of feedback summary</para>
        </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section><title>Viewing survey results - onCourse, exports and print
            reports</title><para>Feedback received can be viewed within onCourse by going to the
                <emphasis role="bold">Activity</emphasis> Menu and selecting <emphasis role="bold"
                >Student Feedback</emphasis>. This will open the feedback list view.</para><para>The
            advanced search will allow you to build complex searches on survey results, i.e. search
            for net promoter scores over 8, or venues with a score under three.  </para>
        <para>You can
        export the results into spreadsheet or business intelligence programs using the Student
        Feedback CSV export.</para><para>Using the find related function from within the Feedback list
            view, you can jump to related records associated with the class feedback. In others list
            views, such as classes, courses, tutors, sites you can use the find related function to
            view all the feedback for that record.</para><para>There are three reports currently
            available from the class list view for feedback called 'Course Completion Survey',
            'Course Completion Survey Summary' and 'Course Completion Survey Tutor'. Examples and
            instructions on how to print these reports can be found in <xref linkend="reports"
            /></para><mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
                    fileref="images/feedback/feedback_list_view.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Feedback list view in onCourse</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject></section>
    <section>
        <title>Editing and approving feedback for online testimonial use</title>
        <para>By default, all new feedback responses will be classified as 'Waiting review' so you
            can then review the comment and mark it as 'not testimonial' i.e. it is feedback you
            will use for quality improvement processes or set it to 'public testimonial' to use the
            feedback in your marketing materials. </para>
        <para>When a testimonial is set to 'public testimonial' the comment made by the student is
            copied into the testimonial field, so you can edit it as needed to remove any spelling
            or grammatical errors or remove personally identifying data they may have inadvertently
            included.</para>
        <para>Only feedback set to 'Public testimonial' status will be included in the testimonials
            visible within the course description on your website.</para>
        <para> </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/feedback_edit_for_testimonial.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Editing a feedback to create a testimonial</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Student Testimonials in web marketing copy</title>
        <para>Testimonials set to 'Public testimonial' status will automatically be included in the
            course marketing copy on your onCourse website. If more than one testimonial exists for
            the course, the testimonials will auto scroll or can be scrolled through by the website
            visitors. This content is visible on the course page only - it is not shown in the
            course list views or on class pages.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%" fileref="images/feedback/feedback_on_course_page_web.png" format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Example student feedback included in the course page</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
