<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="fundingContract">
	<title>Funding Contracts</title>
	<section xml:id="fundingContracts-whatIs">
		<title>What are Funding Contracts?</title>
		<para>Funding Contract allows you to connect additional funding to an enrolment. Whether this is
			from a state funding source or private agreement, funding contract allows you to create
			a default payer and payment that will be used to fund all or part of an enrolment. It
			allows you to easily locate a report on one or more funding contract types to your
			funding agency.</para>
		<para>Funding contracts encompass state funding sources linked to Smart and Skilled or CSO, but
			also allows you to set up custom funding contracts. The funding contract can also be
			linked to the AVEMTISS Reporting type required for that contract. </para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="DefaultFundingContracts">
		<title>Default Funding Contracts</title>
		<para>onCourse has created default templates for the State based funding contracts, and
			integrated them with your AVETMISS reporting options. On higher level subscriptions, you
			are able to create custom funding contracts for any source of funding that supports the
			student enrolment, such as grants, department co-payment or even private contracts with
			large organisation. </para>
		<para>All subscribers have access to the make the default funding contracts active. Default
			funding contracts are available for the major state funding sources.</para>
			<section xml:id="fundingContracts-enable">
				<title> Funding Contracts and AVETMISS exporting</title>
				<para>Many Funding Sources have their own reporting requirements, and for State
					Training Authorities, this is often a modified version of the AVEMTISS standard. </para>
				<para>AVETMISS reporting is discussed in detail in our <xref linkend="AVETMISS"/>
					chapter. </para>
				<para>State funding contracts often have their own reporting requirements. You should contact the 
					relevant department for your state to learn more about their specific requirements.</para>
			</section>
		<section>
			<title>Funding Contract List View</title>
			<para>To view the funding contract list view, go to File > Preferences > General, then scroll the
				left-hand panel until you see Funding Contracts.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingcontracts_prefs.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Funding Contract List View</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Activating a default funding contract</title>
			<para>To activate a default funding contract, open the funding contract list view and then double
				click on the funding contract you wish to activate . Tick the box 'Active' to active
				the contract and then save. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractActive.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding the default Funding Contract to a class</title>
			<para>Once a Funding Contract is active, you can add it as a default funding type to the class.
				If you add the funding contract at the class level all enrolments in the class will
				have the funding contract added to their enrolment. You can remove the Funding
				Contract from individual enrolments if needed, for example, if a fee for service
				student joins a class that which is funded under CSO.</para>
			<para>The funding contract drop down on the class will only let you select from active contracts. </para>
			<para>If you tick 'Assign the same value to the VET Fields' when you duplicate a class, the funding contract will be duplicated to the new class.</para>
			<para>Changing the funding contract on a class will not changing the funding contract applied to
				any enrolments already processed. It will only apply to enrolments created after the
				change is made.</para>
			<para>The default funding contract setting for all new classes is 'Fee for service
				(non-funded).' By default these enrolments will export using the AVETMISS standard
				flavour.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractAddtoClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding a Funding Contract as the default on the Class VET tab</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/courses.html"
					>More instructions on how to create a course</link>
			</para>
			<para>
				<link xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/classes.html"
					>More instruction on how to create classes</link>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding or Editing the Funding Contract on an Enrolment</title>
			<para>Once a Funding Contract is active, you can add to an enrolment on the General Tab of the
				enrolment record. An enrolment will have the Funding Contract that was active on the
				class record at the time the student was enrolled. </para>
			<para>The Funding Contract drop down on the enrolment will only let you select active contracts. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/fundingContractAddtoEnrolment.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adding or editing the funding Contract at the Enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				<link
					xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/latest/manual/processingEnrolments.html"
					>More instruction on how to enrol students</link>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Searching for Funding Contracts</title>
			<para>In the enrolments and classes list view, Funding Contract is available as an
				advanced find option.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/advanced_search_funding_contract.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Creating custom Funding Contracts</title>
		<para>If your subscription allows you to create a custom Funding Contract, you can create them in
			the Funding Contract section in the General Preferences window. </para>
		<para>You may use this feature to create different contracts for specific program types, for
			funding streams within state funding, or for additional funding sources outside the
			normal state contracts, such as grants or commercial agreements.</para>
		<para>To create a new contract, click on the "+" button to create a new record.</para>
		<para>You will need to name the funding contract appropriately. It's a good idea to include the
			type of funding or source.</para>
		<para>If there is a reporting requirement you can select the AVETMISS Flavour appropriate to the
			funding type. If there is no specific flavour you should select NCVER (AVETMISS
			Standard) as the AVETMISS Flavour.</para>
		<para>Lastly, you need to ensure the Active box is checked, otherwise the funding contract won't
			be available for selection in the application.</para>
		<para>Click save to complete the new contract.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/fundingContract_Custom_Contract.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Custom Funding Contract Record in General Preferences</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
</chapter>
