<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="generalPrefs">
	<title>General Preferences</title>
	<para>When you begin onCourse with a new database the setup wizard set up will take you through
		the steps required to set up onCourse for the first time. You will be guided step by step and
		prompted to enter the relevant information you need to set up onCourse to ensure it runs
		efficiently and effectively. You can also return to modify your general preferences at any time
		in the future.</para>
	<tip>
		<para>You can save your changes as you work through the preferences tabs by clicking
			<guibutton>save</guibutton> This will also close the window, but you can open it again from
			File > Preferences > General </para>
	</tip>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-Terms">
		<title>General Preferences Terms and Definitions</title>
		<para> The General Preferences screen is where you set up the basic administration functions of
			onCourse. Starting here provides the initial set up for onCourse.</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Services</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The services tab is an important part of general preferences as it displays what
						kind of features your organisation have available (depending on which support plan you
						have), you will also be able to input your organisation URL address on the services tab.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Messaging</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The messaging tab allows you to set preferences for mail.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Class Defaults</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This tab allows you to set the defaults for minimum and maximum number of places, the delivery mode and funding source of a Class. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>LDAP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Stands for Light Directory Access Protocol and allows users to be authenticated by either
						LDAP or AD (Active Directory). If you don't know what this is, then you definitely don't
						need it.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Maintenance</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The maintenance tab allows you to set backup preferences and change whether you
						would like automatic logout on or not. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>AVETMISS</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Stands for the Australian Vocational Education and Training Management Information
						Statistical Standard which is the national reporting standard for Australian Registered
						Training Organisations, it is essential that these fields are all filled out fully and
						correctly as it is a major part of AVETMISS reporting.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-setting">
		<title>Setting your General Preferences</title>
		<para>In onCourse go to
			<guimenuitem>file</guimenuitem><guisubmenu>preferences</guisubmenu><guisubmenu>general</guisubmenu>
			This is the main page of General Preferences. You will notice that the services tab is
			highlighted which is where we will begin. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>Entry fields coloured pink are the only places that need information entered in order to
				activate onCourse. Fields coloured white do not require any data to be entered, they are
				optional and the onCourse system will run smoothly if they are not filled in. The pink
				coloured box will change to white once you have entered your information correctly and
				pressed enter. If the box does not change to white then you will need to review your
				information and try entering again.</para>
		</tip>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>On the Services tab, Enter the <guilabel>College Name </guilabel>e.g. Rosewood College
					This is a required field and you will not be able to proceed with the set up process
					without first entering a college name.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>To the right enter the <guilabel>ABN</guilabel> e.g 18 123 456 789</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Now enter the <guilabel>College Website URL</guilabel> e.g. rosewoodcollege.com.au
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Below you will see Features not enabled. You need to purchase an onCourse support contract
					to enable these additional features. onCourse is still fully functional as an enrolment
					system without these services. If you have purchased an onCourse support agreement we will
					enable the services for your plan.<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/services_tab.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The "Services" tab</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-merchantId">
			<title>Linking your credit card merchant ID</title>
			<para>In order to use the onCourse integrated credit card gateway you need to contact ish with
				your merchant details from your bank. ish will be able to then link your account to
				onCourse and provide a quick way to take payments both in the office and your
				onCourse powered website.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Visit this page <link
						xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/oncourse/documentation/administrator-guide/internet-merchant-number-guide"
						> here</link> to learn how to request your merchant/terminal ID from your bank to
						allow internet payments and see specific banking details for different australian
						banks.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Contact ish on 02 9550 5501 or email sales@ish.com.au if you have any further
						questions or don't quite understand everything.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="generalPrefs-enablingGateway">
			<title>Enabling the credit card gateway in onCourse</title>
			<para>To enable the credit card gateway in onCourse you would need to follow these
				steps:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>in onCourse got to File > Preferences > General, you will land on the "services"
						tab by default.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From the "services" tab make sure the "enable credit card processing from onCourse
						client" is checked so that the credit card details can go through successfully to your
						chosen bank. If this checkbox is not checked, onCourse will assume that you are using
						an alternative method of processing any credit cards like an eftpos terminal, you can
						still choose credit card in Quick Enrol, however you won't be able to enter the credit
						card details. As you can see in the image below, the checkbox is checked, thus
						allowing credit card processing.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/creditCardProcessing.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "enable credit card processing from onCourse client" is checked, allowing
						credit card processing.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-messaging">
		<title>Messaging</title>
		<para>onCourse makes it easy to send emails and SMS to the students and teachers that are listed
			on your contacts list. In order to do this you first need to configure the email settings. </para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>It is important to configure an outbound mail server in order for email from onCourse to
					be delivered. This includes enrolment confirmations, invoices and other outbound
					messages.  Enter the host name or IP address of the mail server in
						<guilabel>Outgoing Mail Server Address SMTP</guilabel>. Optionally you can
					add authentication settings if your mail server requires it.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the <guilabel>Email from address</guilabel> enter the address from which you want
					contacts to see that emails are sent from. ie. info@rosewoodcollege.com.au</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <guilabel>System Administrator Email Address</guilabel> is the address that
					undeliverable mail and bounces will go to (if you don't use VERP). You will need a valid
					email account that will be accepted by that mail server. You should contact your mail
					administrator to verify that these details are correct. </para>
			</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>Underneath is the <guilabel>emails queued</guilabel> notification. This field will
					notify you of how many emails are in the queue waiting to be sent. Say you are sending out
					a bulk email to prospective students to remind them of the start date of the new term, the
					number in this feild will tell you how many emails have yet to be sent, ie. how many
					remain in the queue. You can not enter any data into this field.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<section>
			<title>Handing bounced emails (VERP)</title>
			<para>VERP - Variable Envelope Return Paths is a feature which automatically handles bounced
				emails from onCourse. When this is enabled, emails are sent out with a special From address
				that looks like "bounces+124673@rosewoodcollege.com.au". The Reply-To address is set
				normally with the standard from address you have defined in "Email from address", so a user
				can reply without any problems. The number after the plus sign is used to identify the
				Contact in onCourse to whom this email was originally sent: this is important because emails
				could be forwarded several times in remote mail systems and the bounce may not come from the
				address you expect.</para>
			<para>This "plus addressing" notation is a standard internet protocol and most mail servers
				support it. You simply define the base email account (eg. "bounces@rosewoodcollege.com.au")
				and the mail server will ignore the part after the plus. </para>
			
			
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you wish to activate this function then tick the option, <guilabel>detect and process
						bounced emails</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>incoming mail server address (POP3)</guilabel> then enter the
						<guilabel>email address to where the bounced emails are sent</guilabel> eg.
						bounces@rosewoodcollege.com.au. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>account name</guilabel> followed by the <guilabel>account
						password</guilabel>. This will be used to retrieve mail from that account by
						POP.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/messaging_tab.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "Messaging" tab</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para> The SMS box enables you to send texts. You may want to text students a reminder for the
				new term start date or for a change of venue or contact tutors about their hours or pay. You
				can send bulk texts direct from the onCourse program. What you enter into the <guilabel>SMS
					from</guilabel> field is what the receivers of your SMS messages will see as the sender
				details. Put in a mobile number for people to reply to or, if you do not have an inbound SMS
				number, you can put the name of your organisation. (eg. 'Rosewood') <caution>
					<para>Only use a mobile number in this field if you have an inbound mobile account intended
						for this purpose. If you use the name of your business it will be clear to the receiver of
						your SMS who the message came from, but they will be unable to press 'reply' on their
						mobile phone to send you a response.</para>
				</caution></para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-classdefaults">
		<title>Class Defaults</title>	
		<para>The Class Defaults tab allows the user to set the defaults for minimum and maximum places in
			a given Class, as well as the delivery mode and funding source.</para>
		<para>Note that these defaults can be manually overidden at the individual Class level.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/class_defaults_tab.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-ldap">
		<title>LDAP </title>
		<para> LDAP - stands for Light Directory Access Protocol and allows users to be authenticated by
			either LDAP or AD (Active Directory), tying your onCourse user accounts and log ins to
			the account and logins your staff use to access other IT resources on your network. This
			is a feature that is enabled as part of a purchased onCourse support plan. Contact us if
			you need help on setting this up. <mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/LDAP_tab.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "LDAP" tab</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject></para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-maintenance">
		<title>Maintenance</title>
		<para>The maintenance screen controls how often and where your data is backed up. This feature is
			recommended for users who are not connecting onCourse to an external server such as MySQL or
			SQL Server, as these external servers have their own daily scheduled backup routines. </para>
		<para>With the amount of information you will eventually have stored on your onCourse program,
			the backing up of this data is essential. onCourse is designed to enable you to schedule when
			and where the back ups take place. You can also set onCourse to have an automatic logout. This
			means that if onCourse is left open on the computer but no one is using it, after a specified
			amount of time it will automatically logout and save any recently entered data. </para>
		<para>Prior to setting up your backup schedule, you need to determine which folder location you
			are going to save these backup files to. It is important to ensure that you save the backups
			on a different drive to the one where you have installed your onCourse server, that way if
			your hardware / drives do fail, your backup files are safe. You also need to ensure that you
			create the folders that you have specified in the file path, otherwise the backup files that
			are created will not be able to be found. </para>
		<caution>
			<para>Running an onCourse back up to a location on your server is not the only step you need
				to take to secure your data. You should also make sure that the backup file is saved to an
				offsite location on a regular basis in case of hardware of other physical failure of your
				computer.</para>
		</caution>
		<para>An example file extension for a Mac could be as follows:</para>
		<para>/Users/Shared/</para>
		<para>[Note: the Mac file path uses the unix system of a forward slash to separate directory and
			file components and make sure you have a forward slash at the front of the file path].</para>
		<para>An example file extension for Windows could be as follows:</para>
		<para>C:\onCourse\backups\</para>
		<para>[Note: the Windows backup directory uses a back slash to separate directory and file
			components. It is also recommended that you do not save your backups to your Program File
			folder within Windows as this is not designed for data files].</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<para>The process for setting up your maintenance preferences is the same for both Mac and
				Windows users, follow these instructions to set up onCourse to backup your important
				data:</para>
			<listitem>
				<para>Navigate to File > Preferences > General > Maintenance tab </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Automatic Logout: If you select this option, it will give you a field on the right
					hand side. Place an amount of minutes e.g; 15 to set the amount of time onCourse can be
					left idle before it shuts itself down and saves all recently made changes and
					additions.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Server backup directory: type the Windows or Mac path to the folder you wish to backup to
					as per the examples above.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Days of week: choose how often you want to backup.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Backup time: choose the time you want to run a backup. We recommend a time when the least
					amount of network traffic is occurring but with enough time to complete the backup before
					the next work day starts. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Maximum backups kept: choose how many backups you want to keep before deleting the oldest
					ones. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Next backup number: this is appeneded to the name of the backup file and is automatically
					incremented on each backup. For example, onCourseBackup_00001.zip </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click "Save". Note that changes to the backup schedule may not take effect until you
					restart onCourse server.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/maintenance_tab.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The "Maintenance" tab</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="generalPrefs-avetmiss">
		<title>AVETMISS</title>
		<para> The AVETMISS screen is where you record your organisation's details that will be used for
			all AVETMISS report lodgements. If you are not an RTO you can uncheck <guilabel>Show RTO
				related screens and menus</guilabel> to hide windows in onCourse that aren't relevant to
			your organisation. You should still enter your organisation address and contact details in
			this window, even if you aren't an RTO as onCourse uses them to populate data in templated
			email messages.</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter your legal <guilabel>training organisation name</guilabel> and from the drop down
					menu <guilabel>type</guilabel>select by the type of training organisation. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>In the <guilabel>Identifier</guilabel> field enter your NTIS RTO id in the
					field.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter your organisations <guilabel>Address</guilabel>, <guilabel>Suburb</guilabel>,
					<guilabel>State</guilabel> and <guilabel>postcode</guilabel> in the appropriate
					fields.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Optional contact details: Here you have the option to enter a <guilabel>contact
					name</guilabel>, a <guilabel>fax</guilabel> number, <guilabel>email address</guilabel>
					and <guilabel>telephone number</guilabel>.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/AVETMISS_tab.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The "AVETMISS" tab</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also choose to limit your staff to creating courses only from pre-approved units
				and qualifications that you mark within onCourse as 'offered'. This assists you in
				ensuring your AQTF requirements of only delivering current approved courses on your
				scope. To use this feature, first flag those you are approved to deliver in the
				qualifications and module/units table, then come back to this window and check
				<guilabel>Show only 'offered' qualifications and modules</guilabel>. We do not
				recommend checking this option as part of your initial setup as it will lock you out
				of all the embedded units. </para>
		<para>If later, after building your courses and setting the units and qualifications on your
			scope as 'offered', you choose to come back here and select this option. This means for
			future courses created, the user will only be able to select from the units you have
			already marked 'as offered' during the course building process. You will need to restart
			your onCourse server for this change to take effect.</para>
		<para>You can still make changes to any individual student's enrolment outcomes to add any
			unit from training.gov.au, even if you have this preference selected. You may need to
			access units not on your scope during a credit transfer process.</para>
		
		<para>On this tab you can also set the signatory name and post-nominals. This name will print on
			the signature line for all onCourse certificate reports. If you leave it blank, the word
			'Principal' will print.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
