<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="gettingStarted">
	<title>Getting Started</title>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-onCourseInterface">
		<title>How to get around the onCourse interface</title>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-gettingAround">
			<title>Getting around</title>
			<para>This part of the onCourse manual will focus on the basics of the onCourse
				interface like windows, records and lists To know how to use onCourse comfortably
				you need to know what all the windows, lists, records and cogwheels mean. onCourse
				is a customisable interface that can be tweaked to your liking. You can have
				multiple windows open in onCourse at any one time, allowing you to switch between
				processes on the fly, for example, you may be halfway through processing an
				enrolment when a colleague asks for some information on the class running in Room 3
				today. You can open a new window to find the answer, without losing the information
				you are currently working on. Let's begin our journey of the onCourse
				interface.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-homeScreen">
			<title>The onCourse home screen</title>
			<para>The home screen is the opening window of onCourse, it is the first thing you will
				see on your screen after you successfully login. The home screen is split into five
				tabs: Course setup, Customer Service, Accounts, Marketing and Dashboard. You will
				find many buttons duplicated on each tab. The idea of these tabs is to group
				together the most common functions you would use if you worked primarily in one of
				these departments. You can switch between tabs as required.</para>
			<tip>
				<title>Popup messages on the right hand side</title>
				<para>It's important to read these popup messages on the right hand side of the
					window when you hover over each tab as they contain some valuable information
					that assists in your understanding of onCourse and it's components</para>
			</tip>
			<section>
				<title>Course Setup</title>
				<para>This tab contains everything related to getting courses set up, this is a good
					place to start once you've gone through everything in the first part of this
					manual. It's important to get all the settings and configurations ready before
					you do anything of importance in onCourse.</para>
				<para>The following tabs are what you should expect to find in course setup. </para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Course : Courses are the product you provide. They describe what is
							taught and any accreditations which are achieved. If these
							accreditations change, then you should create a new course. Students do
							not enrol in a course directly, but can go on a waiting list for a
							course.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Class : Classes represent a group of students progressing through a
							class. A class has a cost, student enrolments, one or more tutors and
							start and end dates. You can easily duplicate classes ready for the next
							intake of enrolments.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Timetable : The timetable allows you to view all your scheduled class
							sessions plus see at a glance which rooms and tutors are available for
							additional classes. You can also set whole college unavailability, or
							unavailability for a particular site, room or tutor if they have
							bookings or commitments outside of your classes.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Site : Sites are a grouping of one or more rooms in a single location.
							Driving and public transport directions are associated with sites and
							web users may use them to narrow their shortlist courses.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Room : Rooms are the specific locations where sessions are held. They
							might be actual rooms in a building, a part of a hall or an outdoor
							space.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor : Tutors are people or companies who teach or operate a
							class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Qualification : Qualifications (also called Accredited courses) can be
							either regional or national and represent a formal achievement gained by
							a student and recognised by other training institutions.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Unit of competency : Units of competency (also called modules) are
							single achievements, each resulting in an outcome for a student. Several
							units of competency make up a qualification as defined by national
							training packages. You can create courses which are single units,
							clusters of units or full qualifications.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Certificate : A certificate is documentary evidence of outcomes
							achieved by a student. They might represent a full qualification earned
							or be a statement of attendance in several units of competency.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>AVETMISS Export : To export data to the Australian AVETMISS standard,
							choose this option. You can export a range of data. If you wish to
							export for just some classes, choose those classes from the class list
							and export from the cog wheel.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Traineeship course : These are the courses you offer specifically to
							trainees. You'll need to set up one of these before you can enrol
							someone in a traineeship.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Traineeship : These are the individual enrolments by students in a
							Traineeship programme.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/course_Setup.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "course setup" tab on the onCourse splash screen</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Customer service:</title>
				<para>This tab contains everything related to the customer side of onCourse, when a
					user inputs data on your website, most of the information they provide will end
					up in records, which can be found in the "Customer Service" tab. Note that there
					are a few tabs that can be found in other areas like "Course", as you can access
					these windows from different places in onCourse.</para>
				<para>The following tabs are what you should expect to find in customer
					service:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Course: Courses are the product you provide. They describe what is
							taught and any accreditations which are achieved. If these
							accreditations change, then you should create a new course. Students do
							not enrol in a course directly.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Class : Classes represent a group of students progressing through a
							class. A class has a cost, student enrolments, one or more tutors and
							start and end dates. You can easily duplicate classes ready for the next
							intake of enrolments.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Timetable : The timetable allows you to view all your scheduled class
							sessions plus see at a glance which rooms and tutors are available for
							additional classes. You can also set whole college unavailability, or
							unavailability for a particular site, room or tutor if they have
							bookings or commitments outside of your classes.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Contact : Contacts include both tutors and students as well as other
							companies and people who are prospective leads, lenders or any other
							contacts.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Student : Students may enrol in classes or wait for a place to become
							available in a course.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor : Tutors are people or companies who teach or operate a
							class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Waiting list : Waiting lists are students who wish to be notified of a
							place becoming available in a course of their choice. This may be
							because existing classes are full or held at a site or time they do not
							wish to attend.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Enrolment : An enrolment represents a student attending a
							class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Invoice : Invoice represents income, either for enrolment into a class
							or for other goods or services provided.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Payment In : Payments to the college usually from students or other
							customers.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Quick Enrol : Take enrolments, create and edit students, take money,
							sell products and more. All from one easy to use window. Each enrolment
							processed through quick enrol creates a single invoice. Students can
							enrol in multiple classes at once, or have their enrolment paid for by a
							3rd party, such as their employer.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/customer_service.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "customer service" tab on the onCourse splash screen</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Accounts</title>
				<para>This tab contains everything related to accounting, some of the tabs present
					in Accounts are for accountants only, and although anyone can edit these types
					of tabs, it is recommended that someone with some sort of formal accounting
					training handles this side of onCourse.</para>
				<para>The following tabs are what you should expect to find in Accounts:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Invoice : Invoice represents income, either for enrolment into a class
							or for other good or services provided.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Payment In : Payments to the college usually from students or other
							customers.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Payment Out : A payment out usually represents a refund to a student
							or other customer.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Account : For accountants only. This is where you can define the
							general ledger setup for your organisation.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Transaction : For accountants only. Display all the transactions
							against the general ledger.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor : Tutors are people or companies who teach or operate a
							class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Class : Classes represent a group of students progressing through a
							class. A class has a cost, student enrolments, one or more tutors and
							start and end dates. You can easily duplicate classes ready for the next
							intake of enrolments.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Pay : Show payslips from here. Before you can create a payslip,
							you'll need to have created a class with a wage budget type.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Deposit banking : Just what it says. Deposit banking for each
							administration centre you define.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Reconcile Statement : Each month you'll want to verify that onCourse
							payments match your bank statement.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/accounts.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "Accounts" tab on the onCourse splash screen</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Marketing</title>
				<para>This tab contains everything related to marketing, onCourse has the aim of
					promoting your organisation to potential customers and these tools are what you
					will use to maximise your chances of success.</para>
				<para>The following tabs are what you should expect to find in Marketing:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tag : Tags are an extremely powerful way to categorise data in
							onCourse. You can group courses by subject, tutors by skills, political
							leads by interest level, students by loyalty or anything you
							choose.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Course : Courses are the product you provide. They describe what is
							taught and any accreditations which are achieved. If these
							accreditations change, then you should create a new course. Students do
							not enrol in a course directly.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Class : Classes represent a group of students progressing through a
							class. A class has a cost, student enrolments, one or more tutors and
							start and end dates. You can easily duplicate classes ready for the next
							intake of enrolments.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Timetable : The timetable allows you to view all your scheduled class
							sessions plus see at a glance which rooms and tutors are available for
							additional classes. You can also set whole college unavailability, or
							unavailability for a particular site, room or tutor if they have
							bookings or commitments outside of your classes.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Mailing list : Mailing lists might be an email list to which you send
							regular newsletters or a list to which you post brochures or pretty much
							any other list of people you want to maintain.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Waiting list : Waiting lists are students who wish to be notified of a
							place becoming available in a course of their choice. This may be
							because existing classes are full or held at a site or time they do not
							wish to attend.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Contact : Contacts include both tutors and students as well as other
							companies and people who are prospective leads, lenders or any other
							contacts.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Discount : Discounts are marketing tools, allowing price reduction for
							selected products and customers. A discount may be linked to a
							concession type, a promotional code, a membership or more. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Membership : Memberships are another flexible grouping of people, with
							expiry dates. You can sell a membership for money and they could be
							linked to a discount. A membership might represent shareholders or
							simply people who purchased unlimited training (at 100% discount) for a
							fixed period of time.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Attachment : Attachments are images, PDFs, or other documents which
							can be attached to courses, classes, tutors, students or sites. You can
							use them to attach images to a course on the website, a PDF of class
							notes or internal reference check on tutors.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/marketing.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "Marketing" tab on the onCourse splash screen</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Dashboard</title>
				<para>The onCourse dashboard provides a ready reference for users to check recent
					activity regarding enrolments, revenue and wait lists. </para>
				<para>The dashboard provides instant updates on the following information.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Graphs indicating the enrolment activity and revenue generated over
							the last 28 days</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>A breakdown of enrolments and revenue for the day, the week, the month
							and the perecentage of enrolments and revenue that were received via the
							College website</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>A breakdown of the number of Classes in development, open for
							enrolment, commenced, cancelled and completed</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The total number of Contacts and Enrolments for your College</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Recent wait list activity including the most wait listed
							Courses</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Up to the minute information on the most recent enrolments that have
							been received</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/onCourse_dashboard.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "onCourse Dashboard" tab on the onCourse splash screen</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Menu Bar</title>
			<para>The menu bar (found at the top of the screen on mac and at the top of the window
				for Microsoft windows) is another way you can access various onCourse functions and
				areas like courses, contacts and students. It is important to note that if you see
				something like this: File > Preferences > General , in the documentation, it means
				go to File (from the menubar) followed by clicking on preferences and so on. This is
				an effective way of communicating directions to someone, if you are teaching someone
				how to use onCourse and decide to write some of your own steps, try it!</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/menuBar.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Mac version of the onCourse menu bar</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>The Menubar has the following structure:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>onCourse Client</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>About onCourse client</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Preferences </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Services</para>
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>More features</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Hide onCourse client</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Hide Others</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Show All</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Quit onCourse client</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/menuBarFile.png" format="png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The File menu</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Preferences</para>
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>General...</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Financial</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Tags</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Custom fields</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Concession types</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Contact relation types</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Users</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Access</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Reports</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Email Templates</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Tutor roles</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Import/Export</para>
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>Import XML</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Import students from AVETMISS 80/85</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Export AVETMISS</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Close window</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Logout</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarEdit.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Edit menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>Cut</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Copy</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Paste</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarCourses.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Courses menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>Courses</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Classes</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Discounts</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Traineeship courses</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Traineeships</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Training packages</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Qualifications</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Modules</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarPeople.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The People menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>All contacts</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Students</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Tutors</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enrolments</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Certificates</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Mailing lists</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Waiting listss</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Quick Enrol</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarResources.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Resources menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>Sites</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Rooms</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Memberships</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Attachments</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarFinancial.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Financial menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>Invoices</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Payments In</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Payments Out</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Tutor pay</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Deposit banking</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Reconcile statement</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Taxes</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Accounts</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Transactions</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create GL Journal entry</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarWindows.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Windows menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>This menu option is special in that if you have multiple onCourse windows
						open, it will allow you to choose which one to bring to the front (make
						active).</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/menuBarHelp.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Help menu</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<listitem>
					<para>Search - This is a very useful tool, just search a term like "courses" and
						a few options will come up, some will be to open the courses window, some
						will be documentation based.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setup wizard - This is a great way to set up your onCourse without having
						to guess where to start.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Documentation - links to the support page on the ish website</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Community support - links to online discussions, use this to grow the
						knowledgebase, onCourse community version users most welcome!</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-listView">
			<title>List View</title>
			<para>The onCourse list view appears when you open a window. For example you click on
				"Class" from the home screen and in this list view will be a list of the classes
				created. The list view will contain columns relevant to the window you have opened,
				e.g; you opened the "class" list view, so you will see columns with headers like
				"sessions" "fee" and "tutor".</para>
			<para>On the left of this window will be the filters, these filters allow you to sort
				the data in the list according to characteristics that you have specified like
				"Current Classes", this will show all classes whose last day have not yet been
				surpassed.</para>
			<para>On the right of the class list window, you will find the actual records. Click on
				a header to sort by that column alphabetically. You can click the column heading
				again to sort by reverse alphabetical order. Some columns can't be sorted by,
				because they are calculation results e.g. the column Enrolments in the class list is
				a calculation of all the current active enrolments in the class.</para>
			<para>You can also drag and drop columns in the list view to re-order them into a
				display of your preference. Your preferences are saved as part of your unique user
				log in.</para>
			<para>Advanced and simple searches are also available from the list view, and all record
				printing happens from the list view. The cog wheel function in the top right hand
				corner also has list view specific functions available. </para>
			<para>In the list view, you can add and delete records. On the top right hand corner of
				most list views, you will see both an add and remove symbol, as you can see below.
				Click on the add symbol to add a new record, you will most likely need to fill out
				fields and check boxes to fill the criteria needed for that particular
				record.</para>
			<para>To remove a record, simply highlight the record you want to remove, click on the
				remove button and the record will disappear, of course if you do this, you can
				corrupt data in onCourse especially if they have immutable relationships. See (red
				caution box) for more on immutable relationships, so take the utmost care when
				removing anything in onCourse.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/addButton.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "add" button</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/removeButton.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "remove" button</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>An example of not being able to remove something with an immutable relationship or
				data would be if you tried to delete a class with 1 or more enrolments in it (even
				if those enrolments have been cancelled), you would get a message like this:</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/immutableClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Trying to remove a class with an enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>However, if you tried to remove a class without any enrolments, you would receive
				something like this, after you select "delete" the record will disappear:</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/removeClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Trying to remove a class with no enrolments</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>When in the list view, you can select single or multiple records, why is this
				useful you ask? Well, if you want to print a report for multiple classes for
				example, you can just highlight which classes you want and go to File > Print > and
				select the type of report you want. You could also highlight a few records to delete
				them.</para>
			<para>Obviously, to choose one record you just click on it. For multiple selections
				follow this:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Windows: Control plus left mouse click on each record you want to
						select.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Mac: Command plus left mouse click on each record you want to
						select.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-filtersAndQuery">
		<title>Filters and query</title>
		<para>With so much data and information available to you in onCourse, it can sometimes get a
			little overwhelming. You need a way to organise and structure your data, this is where filters
			and queries come into play. </para>
		<para>The simplest way of organising your data is to sort by column. When you open a list view,
			you will see columns with different values. An example would be the "tutor" field in
			"class". This column will list the name of the tutor for the class. To sort a column you
			simply click onto it to sort by what type of values they are, so if the column contains
			names, then the column will be organised alphabetically, clicking on it again will sort
			it reverse alphabetically. See the screenshot below to get an idea of how this
			works.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/tutorSorted.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A column that has been sorted.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>You could also expand the size of a column by hovering over the left or right side of the
			column until a black cross appears, then dragging left or right to expand or shrink.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Core Filters</title>
			<para>Core filters are a way to sort your data on a larger scale, an example of these would be
				in the "class" list view, you will find core filters like:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Current classes</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Future classes</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Unscheduled classes</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Past classes</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Cancelled classes</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>By combining these with a another smaller filter, like "subject" you can have a list of
				Past classes that are tagged with Computing. On the title bar of the window you will see
				something like Classes (XX shown of XXX), where X represents numbers. In the screenshot
				below this has been done, look at the left to get a clear idea of how this works.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/coreFilters.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>A core filter working with tags.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Tag Groups</title>
			<para>Tag groups are basically a family of tags. The best way to think of them is to imagine a
				tree, you have a "root" tag like Subjects, then you have "branches" like "Computing" and
				then you'd have the leaf "Computing - Animation". You can set these tags by going to File >
				Preferences > Tags. To learn how to create tags see <xref xlink:href="#tagging" />. Tags you
				have created become filters in the relevant list view window.</para>
			<para>For example, a tag group which applies to courses will be available in the classes
				window, and as a filter mean 'show the classes belonging to courses tagged with...' This
				means you do not also have to tag classes with subject tags to filter on them. In the
				students window, the meaning of the subject tag group as filter will change again to mean
				'show the students enrolled in classes linked to courses tagged with...'</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-queryTask">
			<title>Simple Queries</title>
			<para>As many advanced searching and sorting features as there are, sometimes you just want to
				search for something quick, this is where you would use the quick query search option. It's
				extremely simple, just like searching in a search engine, you type what you want in the
				search field in the top left hand side. But do make sure it is clear and doesn't say
				anything in it like "advanced find" as this indicates there is already a query running. </para>
			<para>Queries and filters work together, so if you have the core filters in the class window
				running, 'current classes' and 'future classes', this means that any query you run is only
				being run on the records already displayed in the list by your filters. If you want to query
				across all the records in the table, uncheck any running filters first.</para>
			<para>The simple query field works on record names and codes. If you type "b" then any record
				with a name or code starting with "b" will be brought up in the list, typing something else
				like "a" will put the first letter and second letter together and search for records
				beginning with "ba", see the screenshot below for a clearer idea of how this works.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/quickQuery.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Using the quick query search option.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Advanced Queries</title>
			<para>Advanced queries are used when you need to search on more than the filters or quick
				search options. For example, you may wish to find all the classes that started within a
				particular date range.</para>
			<para>To open the Advanced Search option, click on the magnifying glass icon in the search
				window in the top left hand corner of the screen. This will display the query editor.</para>
			<para>When you write a query, you have the option of choosing to find records matching <guimenuitem>All</guimenuitem> or
				records matching <guimenuitem>Any</guimenuitem> of the following. It is important that you choose the right
				option for the results you are expecting. The all query means that each line of your
				query will have an AND meaning e.g. Find class starting after 1/1/11 AND classes
				starting before 1/4/11. If you choose the <guimenuitem>Any</guimenuitem> option, your query lines will have
				an OR meaning. Find class starting after 1/1/11 OR classes starting before 1/4/11
				will return a different list of results to the first example.</para>
			<para>You can add as many lines as you require to your query. The list of fields available
				will be all the fields from the table. Some special cross table fields may also be
				available, like 'tagged with'.</para>
			<para>Depending on the field type, you will have different options to choose from. For example,
				text fields will include options like begins with, ends with, is, is not and
				contains. You can also add wildcard character to your text field searches by using
				%. For example, if I wanted to exclude all classes with a code starting with CS I
				could choose, code is not CS%. Note that many text based searches, like course and
				class code are case sensitive.</para>
			<para>You can also run an advanced search on Classes by State of Site, simply by selecting <guimenuitem>Site State</guimenuitem>within the advanced search options. </para>
			<para>Some fields are date fields and you can either type the date in by short date format
				e.g. 1/1/11 or choose the date from the calendar. Date fields can also be relative, for
				example, you can write the word today or +7 for the date seven days after today. This is
				particularly useful if you want to create a saved find for what is happening this week. Even
				though the dates will resolve to a particular date in the query editor, the find will
				continue to run as a relative search. If you run it today, it will show the results for
				today, if you run it again next week, it will show the results for the day you have run it. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Saved Finds</title>
			<para>Saved finds are a way to have your most commonly used queries available to you every
				time you need them, without having to resort to the advanced find feature every time. To
				create a saved find, follow these steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In a list view, you will find a search field with a magnifying glass icon in the top
						left hand side. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the magnifying glass and the advanced find window will appear.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Populate the fields with your preferences then click on the cogwheel on the bottom
						of the advanced find window and click on "save find", give your find a name and it will
						be saved into the left side of the window for your easy access. It will be under "custom
						filters"..</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You will notice the words "Advanced find" in the text field, this means an advanced
						search has been executed and is running that query. This can cause results issues if you
						have tags and filters on as well so do be careful to hit the cross button when you do
						not require that particular advanced find.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/savedFind.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Setting the parameters for the advanced search</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/saveFindButton.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "save find" button</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-cogwheel">
		<title>Cogwheel special functions</title>
		<para>The cogwheel is a powerful and very useful tool in onCourse, it can do a range of complex
			tasks that would otherwise take a while to achieve manually. </para>
		<section>
			<title>Bulk add or remove classes from website</title>
			<para>With the cogwheel function, you can add or remove multiple classes in one go. Follow
				these steps to accomplish this:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In onCourse go to "Class"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From the Class list view, highlight as many classes as you wish.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the cogwheel icon on the right hand side and choose "Show X classes on
						website" or "Remove X classes on website" where X represents the amount of classes you
						highlighted. This way, you don't have to go into every individual class to take them off
						and or put them on the website!</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/showClassWeb.png"
						format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Showing classes on website in bulk</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/removeClassWeb.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Showing classes on website in bulk</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-cancelClasses">
			<title>Cancel classes</title>
			<para>You can quickly cancel a class with the cogwheel function, which stops all future
				enrolments and creates credit notes for all students currently enrolled. Please note that
				you can not bulk cancel classes as each class has vital information and must be checked
				thoroughly before cancelling. We also recommend you contact all the students before
				cancelling the class to advise them of the change of class status, as once the class has
				been cancelled, and the enrolments are not longer active, they will no longer automatically
				be included in a mailing attempt from the class cog wheel.</para>
			<example>
				<title>How to cancel a class using the cogwheel</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>In onCourse go to "class"</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once in the "class" list view, highlight the class (single) you want to
							cancel</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the cogwheel icon on the top right hand side and select "cancel
							class"</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/cancelClass.png" format="png" />
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Cancel a class from the cogwheel menu</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>After you select "cancel class" you will have to place an amount to charge a
							student then press "proceed". You would rarely charge students a cancellation fee if
							you were cancelling the class however, this is more useful if you have a single
							enrolment you wish to cancel because a student has optionally withdrawn. An enrolment
							cancellation happens from the Enrolment window, not here.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Credit notes will have automatically been created for the payers of each student's
							enrolment. The credit notes can be found in the invoices window, and used to refund or
							re-enrol students. Each enrolment in the class will have it's status changed to
							'cancelled'.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
			<section xml:id="gettingStarted-duplicateClasses">
				<title>Duplicate classes</title>
				<para>You can also duplicate one or many classes with the cogwheel. This is a useful way to move
					all your programs forward in time. For example, if you want to offer the same
					series of classes again in 3 months time, you can duplicate them all in one go,
					and work out the start date 3 months from the start date of your first class you
					are duplicating from. E.g. the original series started on Monday 4th July and
					you want the next series to start on Monday 3rd September. You can enter either
					the date or number of days, and the other field will calculate. Ensure the days
					count is divisible by 7 if you want the Monday classes to stay on a Monday and
					so forth. </para>
				<para>When duplicating classes, the class code will be increased by 1, to the next available
					number. E.g. class ABCD-123 will become ABCD-124. If ABCD-124 is already taken, it will
					give it the next available number. You can change the class code to anything you like
					after duplication (provided it remains unique) if you have a business rule attached to
					your class coding system.</para>
				<example>
					<title>How to duplicate a class</title>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>In onCourse go to "class"</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Once in the "class" list view, highlight a class or group of classes and click
								on the cogwheel icon</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>From the menu select "Duplicate X classes" where X represents numbers</para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/duplicateClass.png" format="png" />
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>Duplicate a class from the cogwheel menu</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>After this there are a number of fields and options, fill them out and click
								"Duplicate". Newly duplicated will not be web visible, even if the classes you
								copied them from were. You can now go an make changes to individual classes as
								needed before displaying them online, or delete the classes you don't need provided
								you have not yet taken any enrolments.</para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/duplicateClassDetails.png" format="png" />
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>Details to fill out before commencing duplication of class</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</example>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-contactStuTut">
			<title>Contacting tutors and students</title>
			<para>You can also contact tutors and students with the cogwheel function. This is most useful
				when you need to get an email, SMS or post to all students enrolled in a class or group of
				classes but don't want to go through each one individually. You can do this from the class
				or contact window. The instructions below are for the contact window, but in class they work
				similarly.</para>
			<example>
				<title>How to use the cogwheel to contact tutors and students</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>In onCourse go to Contact (you can also go to 'student' or "tutor').</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>In the list view, highlight the contact(s) you wish to message.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once the contact(s) are highlighted click on the cogwheel and select "Send message
							to X contact" where X represents the number of records you have highlighted.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/messageStuTut.png" format="png" />
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Message tutors and students from the cogwheel menu</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Fill out the messaging window (see <xref xlink:href="#messages" /> for more on
							messaging) and click "send".</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Finding related records</title>
			<para>This feature in the cog wheel allows you to search and locate records for reporting,
				marketing and much more. This feature is inside every window in onCourse, allowing
				you to find related records, and then perform further searches, filters, reporting
				or exporting on that data set. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/find_related_records.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Finding enrolled students related to a class from the cogwheel menu</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>For example, to locate all the employers of all the students aged 18 to 25 in the last
				three months of VET programs to send the Employer Satisfaction Survey to you can
				search for all classes with a particular tag or use the advanced search VET course
				flag. Once you have those classes, you can highlight those delivered in the last
				three months, and select from the cogwheel 'Find related….' > Enrolled students.
				Once the student list has opened, you can search that list of results for students
				aged 18 to 25. With the reduced list of students, you can use the cog wheel 'Find
				related…' to select contacts related as Employer. From this new window, you can use
				the cog wheel to send a message to the student's employers.</para>
			<note><para>Find related can only be run on a max of 1000 records</para></note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/find_related_records_search.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Finding enrolled students related to a class results</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-createCerts">
			<title>Create certificates.</title>
			<para>If you want to create Qualifications, Statements of Attainments or Certificates of
				Attendance for one or multiple classes, you can do it with the cogwheel. If the course the
				class is linked to is a VET course where the 'Satisfies requirements for complete
				qualification' option is checked, you will get qualifications. If the course does not have
				this option selected, but has units of competency attached, you will get Statements of
				Attainment. If the course has neither qualification or units of competency, you will get
				Certificates of Attendance. </para>
			<para>Statements of Attainment and Qualifications create certificate records in the
				Certificate window in onCourse. These need to be checked and confirmed before being printed
				(or deleted when the student isn't eligible) from the Certificate window. Certificates of
				Attendance print directly to the printer or PDF and do not create a record of their printing
				in onCourse.</para>
			<example>
				<title>How to create a certificate of attendance</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>In onCourse go to "class"</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>In the list view, highlight the class(es) you wish to create certificates
							for.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Click on the cogwheel and select "Create certificates", note that you can create
							certificates for multiple classes by highlighting them in the list view.</para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
									fileref="images/createCerts.png" format="png" />
							</imageobject>
							<caption>
								<para>Creating a certificate of attendance with the cogwheel menu</para>
							</caption>
						</mediaobject>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Fill out the details on the next window then click "proceed".</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-recordView">
		<title>Record detail view</title>
		<para>The onCourse record view appears once you open (double click) on a record in a list view.
			It is how you edit things like contacts, courses, classes etc and contains tab groups.
			Depending on what kind of window you're in, there will be different tabs present. Let's take a
			class record view as an example.</para>
		<para>To see a record view simply go to a window like "class" and double click on a record in
			the list view. The screenshot below shows you what to expect in a typical class record view,
			remembering this varies depending on what kind of window you are in. All windows are laid out
			similarly in onCourse, with tabs to group related data and navigate inside the record.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/recordTabs.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A typical tab layout in an onCourse record view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>But the class record view alone is not enough to get an idea of how tabs work, throughout
			this documentation, there are detailed explanations of what each record view tab means, for
			example see <xref xlink:href="#classesCreating-recordTabs" /> to learn about class record view
			tabs in detail, or see <xref xlink:href="#tutors-recordTabs" /> to learn about tutor record
			view tabs.</para>
		<para>In a record view, you will see these buttons on the bottom:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Next: If you press this, the very next record in the list will load its data into the
					record view, this will basically close the record you were just looking at and replace the
					data with the next record in line. Note that this could take a few seconds as it is
					bringing up a lot of data from the record. Its a faster way than closing the current
					record view and opening another record view. If you have made any changes to the record,
					you will promoted to save before moving forwards.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Previous: Like the "next" button, pressing on the previous button will load the
					previous record or the record before the record you are currently viewing. You may be
					prompted to save first.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Cancel: After clicking on this button, you will be asked if you want to discard
					changes or save changes. Discarding means you are not saving you changes on closing. This
					will only occur if you have made any changes, otherwise the window will just close.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Save: This button will save your changes to the record and close, it won't ask you for
					anything unlike the "cancel" button. When you close a record view, you will returned to
					your previous list view.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/cancelButton.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>If you make any changes to the record, you will see this dialogue</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-openRelatedRecords">
			<title>Open related records</title>
			<para>The open related records icon will appear in carious windows throughout onCourse. This
				little icon is very useful, as it opens the record in a new window. The best way to define
				it is to give you an example of what it is used for:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you are confirming class details for a student on the phone, they may want to
						know more about the units of competency assigned to the course. This little icon will
						appear to the right for the name of the course, simply click, check the course VET
						details in the window that pops up, and choose cancel when you have completed viewing
						the record. The screenshots below illustrate this process.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedIconImage.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "open related record" icon</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This icon is actually very small in the onCourse interface, so we blew it up a bit to
				get an idea of what you are looking for in onCourse. When you see this icon, click on it to
				open the related record. For example, if this icon is near a students name "John Smith",
				then click on it and "John Smith" record will appear for you to edit.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedIcon.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "open related record" icon on the right hand side</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This is an example of the open related records icon in action, as you can see it is
				small and to the right of the row.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedCourse.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The related course record will open in a new window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>In this screenshot, the "Course" record has been opened while editing a class. It
				creates an interlacing experience, once you get used to using it, it can prove to be a very
				useful and powerful tool.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Clairvoyant fields and drag and drop</title>
			<para>Many text fields inside onCourse are clairvoyant, or look up fields. This means when you
				start typing in them, a list of matching drop down options appears for you to select. In
				Quick Enrol, this lets you easily work out if the student enrolling is a new or returning
				student, or allows you to quickly find all the courses starting with 'Cook..'</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/clairvoyanceQE.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Clairvoyance in action in Quick Enrol, looking up all existing students with surname
						of Smith</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can also drag and drop data from other windows into clairvoyant fields.</para>
			<para>To do this, have both windows open side by side. Click and hold down on the record you
				will to use to populate your clairvoyant screen and drag it across. Drop the record in the
				field, and the clairvoyance will load it.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/dragdropbefore.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Two onCourse windows open side by side before dragging and dropping the student name
						into Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/dragdropafter.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Two onCourse windows open side by side after dragging and dropping the student name
						into Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
