<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="gettingStarted">
	<title>Getting Started</title>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-onCourseInterface">
		<title>How to get around the onCourse interface</title>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-gettingAround">
			<title>Welcome to ish onCourse</title>
			<para>Welcome to ish onCourse. To help you use onCourse comfortably, this section will
				demonstrate the various windows, lists, records and other icons you'll see. onCourse
				is designed to be and flexible and easy to use, and you can have it set up to help
				you complete your tasks.</para>
			<para>onCourse is customisable, so you can tweak the windows and layout for your
				own use. Once once you find something you like, you can keep using it. To help
				you with this, onCourse will  open using the layout as your preference the next
				time you open it.</para>
			<para>onCourse has been designed as a process oriented
				software program, which means its set up to help you complete your work as
				efficiently as possible. onCourse has many functions to assist providers in completing
				their tasks, including financial, marketing and reporting functions. Each of these
				functions has its own area, and will be discussed in more details below.  </para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-homeScreen">
			<title>The onCourse Dashboard</title>
			<para>The dashboard is the opening window of onCourse; it is the first thing you will see on your
				screen after you successfully login. The dashboard is made up of a three-column view
				window with a quick access column containing two sub-tabs on the left (Favourites
				and All), a latest activity column in the middle, and an enrolments &amp; revenue
				column on the right. There is also a logout button, a button to change your visual
				themes and, in some cases, and an Upgrade to onCourse Pro button for anyone using
				the free version of the software.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/dashboard_new.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The onCourse Dashboard</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section><title>Quick Access column</title><para>This column is the best way to gain fast access to almost all the different areas of the
					application. It contains two tabs; Favourites and All. In the All tab, you'll
					see a comprehensive list of shortcuts to almost every section of onCourse. If
					you hover your mouse over a choice, a heart will appear next to it; click the
					corresponding heart to add that shortcut to your favourites.</para>
				<para>Quick Enrol will <emphasis role="underline">always</emphasis> appear in
					Favourites.</para><mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dashboard_quickaccess.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Quick Access column on the dashboard, with the All tab activated.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject></section>
			<section>
				<title>Latest Activity</title>
				<para>This column will save and then display a history of the windows you've opened or records
					you've interacted with, including during previous logins. You can click any of
					the displayed windows or records to go directly to it.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dashboard_latest.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Latest Activity column</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enrolments &amp; Revenue</title>
				<para>This column will give you a simple, graphical representation of your recent enrolments and
					revenue from the past four weeks in an easy-to-read graph. As well as the visual
					graph, you'll also see the raw numbers of enrolments and revenue, as well as a
					breakdown of the number of courses you have set up in the system.</para>
				<para>The course breakdown will show you the last courses enrolled in, the number of
					courses open for enrolment, and a detailed look at the number of courses
					currently classed as in development, cancelled, commenced and completed.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/enrolments_revenue.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>The Enrolments &amp; Revenue Column</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section><title>Find Anything</title>
				<para>At the top of the Dashboard, you'll find a powerful new search box called Find Anything.
					Here you can find all manner of data in onCourse and have it accessible at your
					finger tips with only a few keystrokes. Simply type in what you're looking for,
					be it a contact's last name, a course code or even an invoice number and the
					search results should populate as you type, filling out with any matching
					result. </para>
				<para>Feel free to experiment with what you can search for, it covers <emphasis>a
						lot</emphasis> of data!</para><mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/find_anything.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>Find Anything will help you find almost anything within onCourse quickly</caption>
				</mediaobject></section>
			<section><title>Themes &amp; Log Out</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/themes_and_logout.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>The Themes and Logout icons.</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>In the top-right of the Dashboard there are two new icons, Themes and Log Out. Log Out is
					self-explanatory, click this to log yourself out of the system and return to the
					main login window.</para>
				<para>Themes will allow you to select from the two currently available, Light and
					Dark. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dark_theme.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>The Dashboard as it looks with the Dark theme</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-listView">
			<title>List View</title>
			<para>onCourse's list views appear when you open a window. For example, if you click on "Class"
				on the home screen a list view will be opened showing a list of the current classes
				in onCourse. This list is filtered by core filters that by default, hide classes
				that are complete or cancelled. In the header bar of the window you will see how
				many records are displaying in the list based on any filters or search options
				running e.g. Classes (38 shown of 267).</para>
			<para>The list view contains columns relevant to the window you have opened, e.g; if you
				open the "Class" list view, you will see columns with headers like "sessions" "fee"
				and "tutor". Click on a header to sort by that column alphabetically. You can click
				the column heading again to sort by reverse alphabetical order. Some columns can't
				be sorted by, because they are calculation results e.g. the column 'Enrolments' in
				the class list is a calculation of all the current active enrolments in the
				class.</para>
			<para>Column size can be adjusted to your preferred width. You can also drag and drop
				columns in the list view to re-order them into a display order of your preference.
				Your window size and layout preferences are saved as part of your unique user log
				in.</para>
			<para>On the left panel of the list view window are filter options. These filters allow you to
				search for data in the list according to characteristics like "Current classes", or
				subject tags you have defined. You can resize this panel by clicking on the
				separator line and dragging it either left or right within the window.</para>
			<para>Many list views will allow you to choose between a two-column and three-column view. The
				three-column view will give you a detailed look at a specific record, while the
				two-column view will give you a better overview of more data. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/3_column_view.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Qualifications page using a three-column view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/2_column_list.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Qualifications page using a two-column view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Within the two-column view you can customise the columns visible to you by clicking
				the eye icon that appears, and then selecting the columns you want to be
				visible.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/column_select.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The column select pop-up visible in the two-column view.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Advanced and simple searches are also available from the list view, and all record printing
				or exporting happens from the list view. </para>
			<para>The cog wheel function also has list of specific functions available when inside this list.
				You can select one record from the list, or a group of records in the list and using
				the cogwheel, perform a bulk action on the records you have chosen.</para>
			<para>The list view is also where you can add and delete records. On most list views, you will
				see both an add (+) and remove (-) symbol. Click on the add symbol to create a new
				class and fill out the fields and options fulfill the criteria needed for that
				particular record.</para>
			<para>To delete a record, highlight the record you want to remove, click on the remove button and
				the record will be deleted. Some records in onCourse can not be deleted because they
				have formed relationships with other onCourse records, and it doesn't make sense to
				be allowed to delete half of a record relationship.</para>
			<para>For example, if you try to delete a class with one or more enrolments in it (even
				if those enrolments have been cancelled), you will get a message like the one below.
				In this instance, you would need to cancel the class instead of deleting it.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/immutableClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Trying to remove a class with an enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>However, if you tried to delete a class without any enrolments, you will see a message like
				the one below. Once you select 'delete' the record will be permanently removed from
				the database. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/removeClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Trying to remove a class with no enrolments</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Printing and Export from the list view</title>
				<para>In a list view, you can select single or multiple records. To highlight a
					single record, single click on it. </para>
				<para>To choose a series of records, single click on the first record, hold down the Shift key
					and single click on the last record. The list of records you have chosen will be
					highlighted.</para>
			<para>To choose multiple non-sequential records you can do the following:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Windows: Control plus left mouse click on each record you want to
						select.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Mac: Command plus left mouse click on each record you want to
						select.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
				<para>For all printing of report or exporting of data you need to first select the
					records in one of these ways.</para>
				<para>Once you have selected the records you wish to work with, choose the share icon from the
					list view to export the data.</para>
				<para>Once you click on the icon you will see a list of print or export options
					available in that window.</para>
				
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/listViewIcons.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Records highlighted and ready to print or export</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			<para>In the list window, you can also sort by multiple columns at once, by holding down the
					shift key and clicking on multiple column headers. The sort order is determined
					by the order the column headers are clicked upon i.e the first column clicked is
					the primary sort order, followed by the second column clicked and so on.</para>
				<para>Your sort record is the order used to print or export data in most ungrouped
					onCourse reports.</para>
		</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-cogwheel">
		<title>Cogwheel special functions</title>
		<para>The cogwheel is a powerful and very useful tool in onCourse, as it can execute a range of
			complex tasks on groups of records that would otherwise take a while to achieve
			manually. </para>
		<para>The cogwheel appears on most screens in onCourse, and the options that appear under it
			will largely be contextual to the screen you're viewing. You can manually execute
			scripts, duplicate classes and courses, send messages to contacts, add or remove classes
			from your website and whole lot more. </para>
		<para>To use the cogwheel, highlight a record on the window you're viewing, then click the
			cogwheel icon to see your options.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-recordView">
		<title>Record detail view</title>
		<para>The onCourse record view appears once you open (double-click) on a record in a list view. It
			is how you edit things like contacts, courses, classes etc and contains tab groups.
			Depending on what kind of window you're in, there will be different tabs present. Let's
			take a class record view as an example.</para>
		<para>To see a record view, go to a window like "class" and double click on a record in the list
			view. The screenshot below shows you what to expect in a typical class record view,
			remembering this varies depending on what kind of window you are in. All windows are
			laid out similarly in onCourse, with tabs to group related data and navigate inside the
			record.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/recordTabs.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A typical tab layout in an onCourse record view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>But the class record view alone is not enough to get an idea of how tabs work, throughout
			this documentation, there are detailed explanations of what each record view tab means, for
			example see the <link xlink:href="classes.html">Classes chapter</link> to learn about class record view
			tabs in detail, or see the <link xlink:href="tutors.html#tutors-recordTabs">Tutors chapter</link> to learn about tutor record
			view tabs.</para>
		<para>In a record view, you will see these buttons on the bottom:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Next: If you press this, the very next record in the list will load its data into the
					record view, this will basically close the record you were just looking at and
					replace the data with the next record in line. Note that this could take a few
					seconds as it is bringing up a lot of data from the record. It's a faster way
					than closing the current record view and opening another record view. If you
					have made any changes to the record, you will promoted to save before moving
					forwards.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Previous: Like the "next" button, pressing on the previous button will load the
					previous record or the record before the record you are currently viewing. You may be
					prompted to save first.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Cancel: After clicking on this button, you will be asked if you want to discard
					changes or save changes. Discarding means you are not saving you changes on closing. This
					will only occur if you have made any changes, otherwise the window will just close.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Save: This button will save your changes to the record and close, it won't ask you for
					anything unlike the "cancel" button. When you close a record view, you will returned to
					your previous list view.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/cancelButton.png"
					format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>If you make any changes to the record, you will see this dialogue</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-openRelatedRecords">
			<title>Open related records</title>
			<para>The open related records icon will appear in carious windows throughout onCourse. This
				little icon is very useful, as it opens the record in a new window. The best way to define
				it is to give you an example of what it is used for:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you are confirming class details for a student on the phone, they may want to
						know more about the units of competency assigned to the course. This little icon will
						appear to the right for the name of the course, simply click, check the course VET
						details in the window that pops up, and choose cancel when you have completed viewing
						the record. The screenshots below illustrate this process.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedIconImage.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "open related record" icon</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This icon is actually very small in the onCourse interface, so we blew it up a bit to
				get an idea of what you are looking for in onCourse. When you see this icon, click on it to
				open the related record. For example, if this icon is near a students name "John Smith",
				then click on it and "John Smith" record will appear for you to edit.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedIcon.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "open related record" icon on the right hand side</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This is an example of the open related records icon in action, as you can see it is
				small and to the right of the row.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedCourse.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The related course record will open in a new window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>In this screenshot, the "Course" record has been opened while editing a class. It
				creates an interlacing experience, once you get used to using it, it can prove to be a very
				useful and powerful tool.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
