<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="gettingStarted">
	<title>Getting Started</title>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-onCourseInterface">
		<title>How to get around the onCourse interface</title>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-gettingAround">
			<title>Welcome to ish onCourse</title>
			<para>Welcome to ish onCourse. To help you use onCourse comfortably, this section will
				demonstrate the various windows, lists, records and other icons you'll see. onCourse
				is designed to be and flexible and easy to use, and you can have it set up to help
				you complete your tasks.</para>
			<para>onCourse is customisable, so you can tweak the windows and layout for your own
				use. onCourse will open using the last layout used as your preference the next time
				you open it.</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-homeScreen">
			<title>The onCourse Dashboard</title>
			<para>The dashboard is the opening window of onCourse; it is the first thing you will
				see on your screen after you successfully login. The dashboard is made up of a
				three-column view window with a quick access column containing two sub-tabs on the
				left (Favourites and All), a latest activity column in the middle, and an enrolments
				&amp; revenue column on the right. There is also a logout button, a button to change
				your visual themes and, in some cases, and an Upgrade to onCourse Pro button for
				anyone using the free version of the software.</para>
			<para>Columns can be resized by hovering your mouse over one of the cut-off lines, then
				clicking and dragging either left or right to decrease or increase the size of the
				column.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/dashboard_new.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The onCourse Dashboard</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Favorites</title>
				<para>This column is the best way to gain one-click access to almost all the
					different areas of the application. Initially, Favorites will only show Quick
					Enrol, however if you click the Edit button it will change to say 'Save' and all
					the windows you can reach from this section will be displayed. If you hover your
					mouse, you'll see a heart icon appear next to it. Click it to add that window to
					your Favorites window, and click it again to remove it. Click 'Save' to save
					your changes.</para>
				<para>Quick Enrol will <emphasis role="underline">always</emphasis> appear in
					Favourites.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dashboard_quickaccess.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Favorites column on the dashboard</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Latest Activity</title>
				<para>This column will save and then display a history of the most recent records
					you've interacted with and their list views, including during previous logins,
					acting as a quick way to revisit screens you were just using. You can click any
					of the displayed windows or records to go directly to it.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dashboard_latest.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The Latest Activity column</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enrolments &amp; Revenue</title>
				<para>This column will give you a simple, graphical representation of your recent
					enrolments and revenue from the past four weeks in an easy-to-read graph. As
					well as the visual graph, you'll also see the raw numbers of enrolments and
					revenue, as well as a breakdown of the number of courses you have set up in the
					system.</para>
				<para>The course breakdown will show you the last courses enrolled in, the courses
					with the highest number of people on a waiting list, the number of courses open
					for enrolment, and a detailed look at the number of courses currently classed as
					in development, cancelled, commenced and completed.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/enrolments_revenue.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>The Enrolments &amp; Revenue Column</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Quick News</title>
				<para>This section shows the latest posts in the onCourse blog, and will also be updated 
				with news about everything onCourse.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dahsboard_blog.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>Find Anything will help you find almost anything within onCourse
						quickly</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>	
			<section>
				<title>Find Anything</title>
				<para>At the top of the Dashboard, you'll find a powerful new search box called Find
					Anything. Here you can find all manner of data in onCourse and have it
					accessible at your finger tips with only a few keystrokes. Simply type in what
					you're looking for, be it a contact's last name, a course code or even an
					invoice number and the search results should populate as you type, filling out
					with any matching result. </para>
				<para>Feel free to experiment with what you can search for, it covers <emphasis>a
						lot</emphasis> of data!</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/find_anything.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>Find Anything will help you find almost anything within onCourse
						quickly</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Themes &amp; Log Out</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/themes_and_logout.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>The Themes and Logout icons.</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>In the top-right of the Dashboard there are two new icons, Themes and Log Out.
					Log Out is self-explanatory, click this to log yourself out of the system and
					return to the main login window.</para>
				<para>Themes will allow you to select from the two currently available, Light and
					Dark. This setting is saved for each user, so if multiple users use onCourse on
					the same computer, it will remember their preferred setting.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/dark_theme.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>The Dashboard as it looks with the Dark theme</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-listView">
			<title>List View</title>
			<para>onCourse's list views appear when you open a window. For example, if you click on
				"Class" on the home screen a list view will be opened showing a list of the current
				classes in onCourse. This list is filtered by core filters that by default, hide
				classes that are complete or cancelled. In the header bar of the window you will see
				how many records are displaying in the list based on any filters or search options
				running e.g. Classes (38 shown of 267).</para>
			<para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Will display columns relevant to the window you've opened. Select a
							record by clicking on it, or select multiple records by holding shift
							and clicking on each.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Add new records by clicking the + button.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Column size can be adjusted by clicking and dragging the edges of a
							column from side to side. You can also customise the columns that appear
							by clicking the 'eye' icon and selecting your preferred columns.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Filters can be applied in the left-side column. <link
								xlink:href="tagging.xml#tagging-filter_tool">Learn more about
								creating these filters using Tags.</link></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can sort columns by clicking their header. You can sort by
							multiple columns by holding down the shift key and clicking each
							columns. The sort will prioritise based on the order of the columns you
							click.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>List views offer a two-column and three-column view. The three-column
							view will give you a detailed look at a specific record, while the
							two-column view will give you a better overview of more data. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Advanced Search will let you find records using a combination of conditions. You can
							learn more about Advanced search in our <link
								xlink:href="search.xml#search-advanced">Search
							chapter</link>.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/3_column_view.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Qualifications page using a three-column view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/2_column_list.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Qualifications page using a two-column view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>Within the two-column view you can customise the columns visible to you by
				clicking the eye icon that appears, and then selecting the columns you want to be
				visible.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/column_select.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The column select pop-up visible in the two-column view.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Help icon</title>
				<para>This circular question mark icon can be found all throughout onCourse, and
					when clicked, will open up the relevant section of the user manual for this
					window in your web browser.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/find_in_manual.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The help icon</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Full Screen Edit icon (three-column view only)</title>
				<para>When using three-column view, you can edit a highlighted record in full screen by clicking
					the Full Screen Edit icon. This will expand the current record view to take up
					the whole of the window. You can return to three-column view without saving your
					changes by clicking Close in the top right corner, or you can save your changes
					by clicking Save.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/full_screen_edit_icon.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The full screen edit icon</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Searching in List Views</title>
			<para>Advanced and simple searches are also available from the list view, and all record
				printing or exporting happens from the list view. <link
					xlink:href="search.xml#search-listView">Learn more about searching
				here</link>.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding and removing records in List View</title>
			<para>The list view is also where you can add and delete records. On most list views,
				you will see both an add (+) and remove (-) symbol. Click on the add symbol to
				create a new class and fill out the fields and options fulfill the criteria needed
				for that particular record.</para>
			<para>To delete a record, highlight the record you want to remove, click on the remove
				button and the record will be deleted. Some records in onCourse can not be deleted
				because they have formed relationships with other onCourse records, and it doesn't
				make sense to be allowed to delete half of a record relationship. E.G. if you try to
				delete a class with one or more enrolments in it (even if those enrolments have been
				cancelled), you will get a message like the one below. In this instance, you would
				need to cancel the class instead of deleting it.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/immutableClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Trying to remove a class with an enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>However, if you tried to delete a class without any enrolments, you will see a
				message like the one below. Once you select 'delete' the record will be permanently
				removed from the database. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/removeClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Trying to remove a class with no enrolments</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Printing and Exporting from the list view</title>
				<para>You can print a report PDF or export CSV from any list view by selecting the
					records you'd like to include, then hitting the Share button. You can then
					select the type of file you want to print, the template and the background. </para>
				<para>To learn more about the specific types of files you can print, click <link
						xlink:href="reports.xml#reports">here for PDF reports</link> and <link
						xlink:href="importExport.xml#importExport-Export">here for CSV
						exports</link>.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/listViewIcons.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Records highlighted and ready to print or export</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-cogwheel">
		<title>Cogwheel special functions</title>
		<para>The cogwheel is a powerful and very useful tool in onCourse, as it can execute a range
			of complex tasks on groups of records that would otherwise take a while to achieve
			manually. </para>
		<para>The cogwheel appears on most screens in onCourse, and the options that appear under it
			will largely be contextual to the screen you're viewing. You can manually execute
			scripts, duplicate classes and courses, send messages to contacts, add or remove classes
			from your website and whole lot more. </para>
		<para>To use the cogwheel, highlight a record on the window you're viewing, then click the
			cogwheel icon to see your options.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="gettingStarted-recordView">
		<title>Record detail view</title>
		<para>The onCourse record view appears once you open (double-click) on a record in a list
			view. It is how you edit things like contacts, courses, classes etc and contains tab
			groups. Depending on the records you're viewing, the information displayed and how its
			shown can vary a lot.</para>
		<para>To see a record view, go to a window like "class" and double click on a record in the
			list view. The screenshot below shows you what to expect in a typical class record view,
			remembering this varies depending on what kind of window you are in. All windows are
			laid out similarly in onCourse, with tabs to group related data and navigate inside the
			record.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/recordTabs.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A typical tab layout in an onCourse record view</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>But the class record view alone is not enough to get an idea of how tabs work,
			throughout this documentation, there are detailed explanations of what each record view
			tab means, for example see the <link xlink:href="classes.html">Classes chapter</link> to
			learn about class record view tabs in detail, or see the <link
				xlink:href="tutors.html#tutors-recordTabs">Tutors chapter</link> to learn about
			tutor record view tabs.</para>
		<para>In a record view, you will see these buttons on the bottom:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Next: If you press this, the very next record in the list will load its data
					into the record view, this will basically close the record you were just looking
					at and replace the data with the next record in line. Note that this could take
					a few seconds as it is bringing up a lot of data from the record. It's a faster
					way than closing the current record view and opening another record view. If you
					have made any changes to the record, you will promoted to save before moving
					forwards.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Previous: Like the "next" button, pressing on the previous button will load
					the previous record or the record before the record you are currently viewing.
					You may be prompted to save first.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Cancel: After clicking on this button, you will be asked if you want to
					discard changes or save changes. Discarding means you are not saving you changes
					on closing. This will only occur if you have made any changes, otherwise the
					window will just close.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Save: This button will save your changes to the record and close, it won't ask
					you for anything unlike the "cancel" button. When you close a record view, you
					will returned to your previous list view.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/cancelButton.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>If you make any changes to the record, you will see this dialogue</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<section xml:id="gettingStarted-openRelatedRecords">
			<title>Open related records</title>
			<para>The open related records icon will appear in carious windows throughout onCourse.
				This little icon is very useful, as it opens the record in a new window. The best
				way to define it is to give you an example of what it is used for:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you are confirming class details for a student on the phone, they may
						want to know more about the units of competency assigned to the course. This
						little icon will appear to the right for the name of the course, simply
						click, check the course VET details in the window that pops up, and choose
						cancel when you have completed viewing the record. The screenshots below
						illustrate this process.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedIconImage.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "open related record" icon</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This icon is actually very small in the onCourse interface, so we blew it up a bit
				to get an idea of what you are looking for in onCourse. When you see this icon,
				click on it to open the related record. For example, if this icon is near a students
				name "John Smith", then click on it and "John Smith" record will appear for you to
				edit.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedIcon.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The "open related record" icon on the right hand side</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>This is an example of the open related records icon in action, as you can see it
				is small and to the right of the row.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/openRelatedCourse.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The related course record will open in a new window</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>In this screenshot, the "Course" record has been opened while editing a class. It
				creates an interlacing experience, once you get used to using it, it can prove to be
				a very useful and powerful tool.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
