<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="kiosk">
    <title>Kiosk Mode for Sites and Rooms</title>
    <section>
        <title>Kiosk Mode for Sites</title>
        <para>The onCourse kiosk mode is designed to show on a real time display monitor the classes
            that are running at a particular venue today. Given the increasingly lower costs of
            smart TVs and tablets, this technical solution provides an intervention free option to
            ensure tutors and students entering a venue know where their class is scheduled.</para>
        <para>The kiosk display is available both at the site and room level, so you can use the URL feeds to display the venue schedule in the site foyer, or outside a particular training room at a site.</para>
        <para>Clicking on the TV icon in the top right hand corner of the site will generate a URL
            that looks like www.mycollege.com.au/site/kiosk/111 where www.mycollege.com is the URL
            in your general preferences College Website URL and 111 is the onCourse unique site
            ID.</para>
        <para>Once you have clicked on the link to open the URL and can confirm it is displaying as
            expected, this is the URL you need to copy to display on your monitor. This URL will
            stay the same and auto update every 15 minutes. Once you have set the URL once there is
            nothing more you need to do to keep it updating.</para>
        <para>You may also wish to have your admin or site coordinators bookmark the link for the
            site they manage. This way, for example, all staff at a particular location can quickly
            check in their web browser what classes are scheduled for today when they first arrive
            in the morning to ensure the resources are ready for the trainers as they arrive.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/kiosk/site_kiosk_link.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption><para>The TV icon in the top right hand corner shows the link to the site kiosk view</para></caption>
            </mediaobject>
        <para>The data shown in kiosk mode will be the real time data of today's classes that are either in
            progress, or yet to commence. The data is sorted by start time order, and then
            alphabetically.</para>
        <para>The kiosk mode displays the course name, course-class code, tutor(s) name, start and
            end times and room allocation.</para>
        <para>Classes currently in progress are shown in red font with the start time appended with
            'commenced'. As classes complete, they automatically drop off the list.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/kiosk/kisok_site.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption><para>The kiosk view for a site</para></caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>When there are no classes scheduled for the day, or all the day's classes are
            complete, in both the site or room mode the kiosk view will display "There are no more
            classes scheduled for today." </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                    fileref="images/kiosk/kiosk_no_more_classes.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption><para>Default display when they are no more classes scheduled for the day in the site or room</para></caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Kiosk Mode for Rooms</title>
        <para>A kiosk view is also available for each room of a site, to display the classes running
            today. This is the URL you would access if you wish to display the details for all
            classes scheduled in a particular room, for example, to display on a tablet located near
            the room's door.</para>
        <para>Click on the TV icon in the top right hand corner of the Room edit view to access the
            URL for that room. The URL will be your college URL appended with something like
            /room/kiosk/469 where "469" is the onCourse unique ID for the room.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/kiosk/room_kiosk_link.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption><para>The TV icon in the top right hand corner shows the link to the room kiosk view</para></caption>
            </mediaobject>
        <para>Like the kiosk view for a site, the room view will only show classes in progress and scheduled for today. As the class session completes, it will drop off the list automatically. </para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="80%" contentdepth="80%"
                        fileref="images/kiosk/kiosk_room.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption><para>The kiosk view for a room</para></caption>
            </mediaobject>
    </section>
</chapter>
