<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="mailingLists">
	<title>Mailing lists</title>
	<section xml:id="mailingLists-whyUse">
		<title>Why use mailing lists</title>
		<para>Mailing list can be used to group like-minded contacts to allow you to contact groups
			of people easily. Mailing lists are a special type of tag (see also <xref xlink:href= "#tagging"></xref> ) and work very
			similarly. </para>
		<para>Students can subscribe and unsubscribe to mailing lists from your website and
			subscriptions can be manually managed from within onCourse. </para>
		<para>Mailing lists are particularly effective when used in combination with the HTML
				newsletter function.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="mailingLists-Creating">
		<title>Creating a mailing list</title>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Go to the menu People and select Mailing Lists.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Click the plus <guibutton>+</guibutton> button to create a new mailing list.
					Give you list a name and description (which will be available on your website)
					and select if you wish to allow online subscriptions, or limit the mailing list
					to tutors only.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/creating_mailing_list.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>creating a new mailing list </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>Mailing lists could be used for various purposes such as:</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>Focus on classes or local events in a specific category your college offers
					e.g. Art </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Provide a regular newsletter to your staff</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Advertise special promotions and deals, or new courses – a whole college
					newsletter</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Regularly contact students who meet a particular criteria, such as those aged
					over 60, to promote specialised courses, such as Senior's programs.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="mailingLists-sendingEmails">
		<title>Sending Emails and SMS Messages to Clients on your Mailing List</title>
		<para>onCourse allows you to hilight a given Mailing List via the Mailing List window and then send an email to all clients who are on that particular Mailing List. To create an email or SMS message is quite simple:</para>
<orderedlist>
	<listitem>
		<para>Select (hilight) the relevant Mailing you wish to send a message to.</para></listitem>
	<listitem>
		<para>Go to the cogwheel function of the Mailing List window and select 'send email'.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/EmailMailingListClientsViaCogwheel.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Send Email via Mailing List Cogwheel</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
		<para>This will then bring up the Message edit view where you can determine whether you wish to send an email or SMS (or both), select the recipients for the email and send. </para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
				fileref="images/SendMessageToMailingList.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>Send emails and or SMS to Mailing List Clients</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	</listitem>
</orderedlist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="mailingLists-selfSubscriptions">
		<title>Student self subscriptions</title>
		<para>Students and clients can subscribe and unsubscribe to your Mailing Lists either via
			your College website and current students can update their mailing list preferences
			using the Skills onCourse portal.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Signing up to Mailing Lists via the Website</title>
			<para>All your active mailing lists will appear automatically via the link
				/enrol/mail</para>
			<para>In the following example, the URL would be
				http://openacademy.sydney.edu.au/enrol/mail</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/enrol_in_mailing_list_via_website.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of how the Mailing List page displays on the website</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>You can configure which fields appear within the mailing list website sign up form
				via the Site Settings / Contact Entry of your website CMS, including specifying
				which fields are required fields.</para>
			<para>This is a great way to collect email addresses for prospective clients and you can
				add in a link to this /enrol/mail URL from anywhere on your website.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Managing your mailing lists via the Skills onCourse Student Portal</title>
			<para>Students can add or remove themselves from Mailing Lists whilst logged into the
				Skills onCourse, Simply click on the Mailing List item on the Skills onCourse menu
				after you have logged in.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/manage_mailing_lists_via_portal.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Unsubscribing from Mailing Lists via a Link within an email</title>
			<para>Any email correspondance that is sent to clients on a given mailing list includes an
				unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email. </para>
			<note>
				<para>Only the emails sent to a given Mailing List will include the unsubscribe link. All other emails generated by onCourse, including enrolment confirmations does not include the Mailing List unsubscribe link.</para>
			</note>
			<para>The following is an example of a typical email sent to recipients of a given Mailing List,
				including the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email..</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/UnsubscribeLinkWithinMailingListEmail.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Unsubcribe Link within Mailing List Email</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>By clicking on the link, the client is redirected to the Skills onCourse Portal where they
				can deselect any mailing lists which they no longer wish to be on and save the
				changes. Unsubscribing via this method does not require the client to log into the
				portal to unsubscribe from a mailing list.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/SkillsOnCourseUnsubcribeOptions.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Skills onCourse Unsubscribe Page</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="mailingLists-addingOrRemoving">
		<title>Manually adding or removing students from a mailing list</title>
		<para>Because mailing lists work just like tags, you can run a query, then select all or
			some of the students returned, and right click on the mailing list name to add the
			students to the list. By selecting the mailing list name in the left column, you will
			search for all the students currently subscribed to the mailing list.</para>
		<para>You can select a group of people and right click on the mailing list name to remove
			the tag, or for individual students, open their contact record and delete the tag by
			clicking on the minus sign.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/manually_add_student_to_mailing_list.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="mailingLists-Unsubscribing">
		<title>Unsubscribing a contact from a mailing list</title>
		<para>Contacting students on a mailing list In the left column of the students window,
			select the mailing list you wish to contact. Highlight the list (You can use <keycombo>
				<keycap>Ctrl</keycap>
				<keycap>A</keycap>
			</keycombo> or highlight by selecting the first record, holding down
				<keycap>shift</keycap>, and selecting the last record).</para>
		<para>Use the cogwheel icon on the top right of the screen to select <guilabel>send message
				to x contacts</guilabel> and proceed to create and send your message as usual.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
