<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="messages">
	<title>Sending messages</title>
	<para>onCourse can send a mix of email, SMS or postal mail messages to the contacts you have
		collected contact details for. Contacts can also manage their subscription and
		un-subscription to your mailing lists via their onCourse web portal.</para>
	<para>Whenever you create a message using the onCourse interface, the collected list of contacts
		is automatically de-duplicated so you don't send someone the same message twice, and the
		list can be sent a combination of email, SMS and postal mail depending on the contact
		details you have available. Selected contacts without the chosen method or methods or
		communication available can be exported into a separate list so you can manually contact
		them.</para>
	<para>Contacts who have asked not to be contacted via particular methods e.g. SMS are
		automatically suppressed from messaging lists. You can override this suppression in the case
		of emergency contact e.g. a message to advise students that their tutor is sick and a
		session is cancelled.</para>
	<para>onCourse messaging is for outbound messages only. Inbound messages will be sent to the
		reply address specified in your message and will not be visible in onCourse.</para>
	<section xml:id="messages-selectingPeople">
		<title>Selecting people to contact</title>
		<section>
			<title>From contact, tutor or student lists</title>
			<para>If you wish to find a group of contacts who have a particular history of interactions with
				your college, onCourse will allow you to perform advanced search functions, then use
				the combined email, SMS and mail messaging tool to contact these clients. For
				example, you can search for all students who enrolled in a course containing the
				word "french" in the last 365 days and then send them all an invitation to enrol in
				your new class, Provence Study Tour, prior to its public release. Any of the
				standard and advanced search mechanisms in the contact list view can be used to
				choose people to send a message to.</para>
			<para>Once you have made your selection, highlight the people you wish to contact and choose
				"send message..." from the cog wheel in the top right. You can send a message in
				this way to 1 person or 20,000 people, and onCourse has special code to optimise
				delivery to very large lists.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>From classes</title>
			<para>Highlight one or more classes from the class list view and choose "send message to
				tutors from..." or "send message to student from..." from the cog wheel in the top right.
				Every tutor or student from those classes will be sent a message.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>From waiting lists</title>
			<para>Highlight one or more records in the waiting list view and choose "send message..." from
				the cog wheel in the top right. Every potential student will be sent a message of
				your creation. A good way to use this is to search for all waiting list records for
				a particular course or group of courses. Then send them a message to let them know a
				new class has just been scheduled and let them know to enrol online or call the
				office. Read <xref xlink:href="#waitingLists"/> for more information about waiting lists.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>From mailing lists</title>
			<para>In the mailing list window, selecting the mailing list name you wish to contact the
				subscribers of and select 'send email' from the cog wheel option in the top right
				hand corner. Read <xref xlink:href="#mailingLists"/> for more information about mailing lists.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="messages-intergratedMail">
		<title>Sending an integrated mail message</title>
		<para>ish onCourse integrates email, SMS and postal export functionality within the database.
			This means that not only can you quickly contact all students who studied with you last term,
			or quickly reschedule a class when the tutor calls in sick, but that a full history of all
			these messages are stored right in the students' records.</para>
		<para>Sophisticated bounce processing is in place for email, notifying you if a message is
			undeliverable.</para>
		<para>After you have selected the list of people you wish to contact using one of the
			methods described in the previous section, you can begin selecting the methods which you
			will use to contact them.</para>
		<para>For example, if you have 26 contacts selected in a message window and of those 26, 22
			have email addresses available to contact, there will be 4 people who are listed as
			'wont be contacted'.  If you have mobile phone numbers for those four people you could
			chose to SMS them only, by selecting the option 'send SMS' and not including people who
			are emailed. By using this combined method you can reach more people via their preferred
			medium, or in the case of emergencies, attempt to reach people via multiple
			mediums.</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/messagingStudents.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> In this example, all 9 contact have an available email address, so no other method of communication is needed to reach them. </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<section>
			<title>Understanding email messaging</title>
			<para>Email messaging in onCourse is managed by your own mail server. In the Preferences >
				General > Messaging window you can set up the email server address and account
				details. You can also set up how bounced emails are processed. More information is
				available in <xref xlink:href="#generalPrefs"/></para>
			<para>Not every email you send from onCourse will reach the intended contact. There are many
				reasons for this and they include:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>The email address you collected from the student was incorrect. This is less likely if
						the student enrolled online and was required to type in their email address
						themselves rather than have a staff member translate it from a handwritten
						form. Common errors include incorrect domain names e.g. bigpond.com.au
						instead of bigpond.com and simple typos. If the user account you are trying
						to send to doesn't exist, you should expect an undeliverable message to the
						'from' address used when you sent the message and the message will be marked
						as failed in onCourse.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The user's account marked your message as spam. onCourse emails are sent one at a time to
						your email server, so if the user has successfully received email from you
						in the past, there is no difference between a message sent out of onCourse
						than one sent directly from your own email account. There is no notification
						to you if the message is marked as spam, and will show as 'sent' in
						onCourse. Their spam filter may have quarantined your message for reasons
						like using keywords in your message body such as 'special offer', 'Dear
						sir/madam' or other negatively scoring terms. Read up on keywords that are
						commonly blocked at <link
							xlink:href="http://spamassassin.apache.org/tests_3_3_x.html">Spam
							Assassin</link></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The user's account is full, or otherwise unavailable for accepting
						messages. The user account may have been disabled by their system
						administrator, i.e. if an employee has left an organisation, or is possibly
						unavailable due to technical issues like their mail server losing it's
						internet connection. Your own mail server may attempt to resend the message,
						depending or the response it has received. You may see the message in
						onCourse remains in a queued state. On the sixth failed attempt the message
						will be discarded and you will see in onCourse the message marked as failed
						and the users email address marked as undeliverable.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Problems with your own mail server sending large numbers of outbound
						messages. If you are sending a large number of emails for an email campaign,
						your own mail server may have some established rules to block potential spam
						activity from inside your network. Before you begin sending 500 or more
						messages, speak to your mail server manager and ensure there are no system
						policies that will prevent you from running your marketing campaign.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<section>
				<title>Plain text and HTML messages</title>
				<para>When sending an email, you can choose to send either a plain text or HTML email message.
					HTML messages are formatted and usually include images, hyperlinks and styled
					font and content. A plain text email message is just that - it contains only
					plain text without any additional styling.</para>
				<para>You may be familiar with the experience of your own email browser blocking the
					images or content of HTML emails. In most instances, the user can choose to show
					these blocked images once they have confirmed that the message is from a trusted
					source. Alternatively, many HTML emails include a link such as 'view this email
					in a browser' for people whose email clients do not allow them to easily view
					HTML.</para>
				<para>It also takes a little more work to layout and format an HTML message, so
					sometimes sending a plain text message when you have a simple and
					straightforward message to convey is all that is required e.g. remember to bring
					your assignments to class tonight. For an email message with a broader reach,
					say a marketing campaign that is aiming to remind clients of your brand, educate
					them about new products you offer and entice them to click through and make a
					purchase, HTML is a more sophisticated choice.</para>
				<para>By default, the onCourse messaging system will open in the plain text message
					mode. If you are sending an HTML message, you will need to prepare the HTML, and then copy and
					paste the HTML into the onCourse message window, or the URL of the HTML message
					into the 'Web URL for HTML Message field'.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/HTML_message.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>An email message with HTML content.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Understanding SMS Messaging</title>
			<para>SMS messaging is available in onCourse and can be a method of communication for
				any contacts with a valid mobile number. Note that only the phone number recorded in
				the mobile phone field is used - if you have recorded a mobile phone number in the
				work or home number fields, it will not be available for SMS.</para>
			<para>There is no requirement for formatting the mobile phone number in onCourse to make
				it accessible. 10 digits are standard for a mobile phone, beginning in Australia
				with 04. Whether or not you format your phone numbers with spaces it up to you -
				onCourse will strip out these characters during the outbound SMS, without modifying
				any of the data you have stored.</para>
			<para>A small charge per use applies to SMS messaging, as per your onCourse contract
				agreement. The outbound message from information is defined in the File >
				Preferences > General > Messaging > SMS from field. Most companies use their
				business name here, so they do not need to identify themselves in the message body.
				Like email, SMS messaging is outbound only, and if you use a name in the from field,
				there is no ability for the customer to respond. Alternatively you could use a valid
				mobile number in your settings, if you wished to accept inbound SMS also, and
				remember to identify your business name in each SMS you send.</para>
			<para>It is important to remember that SMS messages are not delivered in real time, even
				though most peoples experiences of mobile phones work that way. Like email, SMS
				messages are handled through a delivery network but in this case delivery rules are
				all managed by the receiver's mobile phone provider. Most providers give about a two
				day time-to-live on SMS messages. This means if the phone is off the network (no
				coverage or switched off) and re-registers on the network within two days that the
				message was sent, then it will be received. If the phone is off the network for
				longer than that, then the mobile phone provider may discard the message entirely.
				There is no notification back to the sender if the message is successfully delivered
				or discarded.</para>
			<para>Inside the contact record in onCourse, the message is marked as sent if it makes
				it successfully to the outbound SMS gateway. Beyond that point the message can not
				be tracked. Please contact ish if you find SMS messages are failing as there may be
				instances where the SMS gateway is experiencing a fault.</para>
		</section>
			<section>
			<title>Postal mail</title>
			<para>The postal mail option in onCourse exports the mailing address and email addresses of the
				selected contacts into a CSV file. You can then use this file to mail merge the
				address data with your message prepared in a word processing or desktop publishing
				tool, or provide this file to a mailing house distributing your marketing
				materials.</para>
			<para>The name of the postal mail export is recorded in the contacts messages tab for
				future reference. </para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/postal_CSV.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> An example of a postal mail CSV export. </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="messages-Exporting">
		<title>Exporting contact details for other messaging tools</title>
		<para>Using the postal export option as outlined in the previous section is the simplest way
			to export name, address and email data for importing data into other messaging
			tools.</para>
		<para>If you require more information than what is available in this export option, you can
			run a standard CSV export on the contact record table and customise the output as
			required. More information about exports is available in <xref xlink:href="#importExport"/></para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="messages-optInAndOut">
		<title>Messaging opt in and opt out</title>
		<para>Students have the option to opt out of all marketing communication from your organisation,
			or from a particular method of marketing such as SMS. However, if you have urgent information
			to convey, such as a class cancellation, you are still able to use your communication tools to
			contact them quickly while respecting their request not to receive unsolicited marketing
			emails or SMS. </para>
		<para>During the online enrolment process, students can opt of our messaging from any type
			when they are providing their contact details. By default, all types of communication
			are set to allow. Student's can also log into their portal at any time and change their
			preferences.</para>
		<para>onCourse users can also manually reset the availability of each of the postal, SMS and
			email settings using the cog wheels in the contact window.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/message_settings.png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para> In this example, the student accepts postal marketing messages,  has provided a mobile
					phone where SMS messages have failed to be delivered, and opted out of both SMS
					and email marketing. </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>When a contacts address has been marked as undeliverable, either automatically by repeat
			failed sending attempts, or manually e.g. return to sender postal mail, this contact
			will not be sent any further messages using the onCourse integrated messaging tool to
			the undeliverable medium.</para>
		<para>Using the advanced search function, you can search for contacts who have undeliverable
			methods of contact and make an effort to follow them up to obtain up to date contact
			details.</para>
		<para>Mailing lists can also be opted in and out, with out opting out of a method communication
			altogether. For example, a user can opt out of the 'Lifestyle and leisure courses'
			mailing list, without refusing other marketing email communication. More information
			about mailing lists is available in <xref xlink:href="#mailingLists"/></para>
		<para>When an enrolment is cancelled an automatic message template for email and/or SMS is
			generated to advise the student. You can choose to edit, send as is or discard this
			message. By default, it will also be sent to people who have opted out of email or SMS
			marketing as it is an informational message.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/message_cancelled.png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A template email and SMS notification for a student whose enrolment has been cancelled.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="messages-Permissions">
		<title>Message permissions and message history</title>
		<para>Within the onCourse File > Preferences > Access settings, an onCourse user group can be set
			to allow emails and SMSs to over or under 50 contacts. This is to prevent onCourse
			enrolment staff, for example, accidentally sending an email blast to your entire
			database but allows them sufficient permission to contact all the students from a single
			class and advise them of changed conditions.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/message_permissions.png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para> User account settings to allow over or under 50 contacts per message type. </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Each message that is sent from onCourse is also stored within the contacts record. The
			message can be double clicked on to show the content of the message. This can provide an
			added level of security and allow you to quickly follow up any student's query regarding
			a message they received from your college. All automatic messages sent from onCourse are
			also recorded here. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/messages_sent.png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A contact record showing the delivery status of the contacts messages </para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="messages-automaticMessages">
		<title>Automatic messages in onCourse</title>
		<para>When a student enrols in a class and an invoice is created, two automatic emails are sent
			from onCourse. These emails are sent for both online enrolments and enrolments processed
			through the office. Where the payer is a different person to the enrolling student, the
			invoice is emailed to the payer while the enrolment confirmation is emailed to the
			student. If the payer and the student is the same person, they will receive two
			emails.</para>
		<para>onCourse uses standard templates to send plain text emails to payers and students.
			These emails can be resent from the enrolment window cogwheel or the invoice window
			cogwheel. These reports can also be printed in hard copy and mailed to the student if
			required. Note that the format for the printed and emailed invoices and enrolment
			confirmation are different, due to the different mediums they are sent with, but they
			contain the same information.</para>
		<para>The automatic enrolment confirmation email includes a block of text with the class
			start date and time and link through to the full website description, maps, tutor
			profile and other details of the class.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/email_confirmation.png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>A plain text email showing the basic information a student needs to attend class, with a link to more information</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>The tax invoice which is provided to the payer shows the total amount payable, amount paid,
			tax applicable and amount outstanding. For many payers this invoice is also the payment
			receipt where they have paid some or all of the fee on enrolment.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
