<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="messages">
	<title>Sending messages</title>
	<section>
		<title>Selecting people to contact</title>
		<section>
			<title>From contact, tutor or student lists</title>
			<para>If you wish to find a group of contacts who have a particular history of interactions
				with your college, onCourse will allow you to perform advanced search functions, then use
				the combined email, sms and mail messaging tool to contact these clients. For example, you
				can search for all students who enrolled in a course containing the word “french” in the
				last 365 days and then send them all an invitation to enrol in your new class, Provence
				Study Tour, prior to its public release. Any of the standard and advanced search mechanisms
				in the contact list view can be used to choose people to send a message to.</para>
			<para>Once you have made your selection, highlight the people you wish to contact and choose
				"send message..." from the cog wheel in the top right. You can send a message in this way to
				1 person or 20,000 people, and onCourse has special code to optimise delivery to very large
				lists.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>From classes</title>
			<para>Highlight one or more classes from the class list view and choose "send message to
				tutors from..." or "send message to student from..." from the cog wheel in the top right.
				Every tutor or student from those classes will be sent a message.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>From waiting lists</title>
			<para>Highlight one or more records in the waiting list view and choose "send message..." from
				the cog wheel in the top right. Every potential student will be sent a message of your
				creation. A good way to use this is to search for all waiting list records for a particular
				course or group of courses. Then send them a message to let them know a new class has just
				been scheduled and let them know to enrol online or call the office.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Sending SMS, Email and postal (snail) mail</title>
		<para>ish onCourse integrates email, SMS and postal export functionality within the database.
			This means that not only can you quickly contact all students who studied with you last term,
			or quickly reschedule a class when the tutor calls in sick, but that a full history of all
			these messages are stored right in the students' records.</para>
		<para>Sophisticated bounce processing is in place for email and SMS, notifying you if a message
			is undeliverable.</para>
		<para>Do you wish you could send an email to everyone in a class AND send a postal mail in one
			go? Well now you can, if you wish to send a postal (snail) mail to someone, they must not have
			an email in their record (for obvious reasons). To send a person a postal mail, follow these
			steps:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>In onCourse, go to "class" which is under the "customer service" tab</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once in "class", highlight the class that contains a person without an email in their
					record.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Go to the cogwheel at the top and select "Send message to students from X class", the
					X represents the amount of people enrolled into that class.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once the "send message" window appears, you will need to go to the bottom "Export
					postal addresses for mail merge" you can choose "including people are emailed" to send a
					postal mail to a student who already recieves an email. You can even uncheck "send email"
					from the top so as to only send postal mails to people. See screenshot below to get a
					better idea about this.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/messagingStudents.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> The "send message window" </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>No spam please</title>
		<para>Students have the option to opt out of all marketing communication from your organisation,
			or from a particular method of marketing such as SMS. However, if you have urgent information
			to convey, such as a class cancellation, you are still able to use your communication tools to
			contact them quickly while respecting their request not to receive unsolicited marketing
			emails or SMS. </para>
	</section>
</chapter>
