<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="payroll">
	<title>Tutor pay</title>
	<para>In this chapter, we cover how to set up standard rates of pay for your Tutors, how to
		include Tutor costs within the overall class budget, confirming Tutor attendance / hours worked
		and how to generate Tutor pay from onCourse. </para>
	<para>Before you work through this section, you need to ensure you have already set up a class
		with a timetable. You will also need to ensure you have created a Tutor record. </para>
	<section xml:id="payroll-payRates">
		<title>Setting standard pay rates</title>
		<para>onCourse allows you to map standard pay rates to Tutor types. These are used by default,
			but can be overridden per class as needed. Some standard Tutor type names are included by
			default, but these can be changed or deleted as needed.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Types of pay rates available in onCourse</title>
			<para>The rate type of a tutor pay is it's multiplier than answers the questions 'how many times
				will the tutor be paid this amount' and 'when will it be payable'? All of the
				multipliers are relative to other information about the class that has been defined
				elsewhere, such as the timetable and number of enrolments. As the multiplier value
				changes, the amount payable to the tutor changes automatically.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Fixed</emphasis></para>
					<para>A fixed pay rate is a flat amount of pay that is payable to the tutor on the first day of
						the class. A fixed amount may be used to record an allowance that is
						provided in addition to an hourly or session based pay, or in the case of a
						short class where the tutor is paid a fixed amount. The fixed type of pay
						has no relation to the tutors teaching schedule in the class timetable, or
						number of students enrolled. A tutor who is eligible for a fixed pay type
						does not need to be assigned to any of the class sessions, but does need to
						be added to the class tutor tab. There is no multiplier for this pay rate -
						it is a once off payment.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Per session</emphasis></para>
					<para>A per session rate of pay is attached to sessions in the class timetable where the tutor
						is assigned. A per session rate of pay is payable regardless of the duration
						or payable time set for the session. A per session pay rate can not be paid
						in addition to a per timetabled hour pay rate for the same tutor involved in
						teaching a class. If more sessions are added to the timetable, the amount
						payable for the tutor will increase.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Per enrolment</emphasis></para>
					<para>A per enrolment rate of pay pays the tutor an amount multiplied by the number of active
						enrolments in the class at the time the payroll is run. A per enrolment rate
						of pay can be paid in addition to a per session, or per timetabled hour rate
						and may be used for additional allowances, such as an assessment marking
						allowance. Like fixed types, per enrolment types are payable on the start
						date of the class, and can be paid to tutors not attached to deliver any of
						the class sessions e.g. an assessor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Per timetabled hour</emphasis></para>
					<para>This is the most common type of pay rate used, and is based on the tutors attendance at a
						session i.e. the tutor is assigned to the session, and the session duration
						is 3 hours therefore the tutor is paid for their rate per timetabled hour x
						3 hours. There is also an additional 'Payable Time' field for each session
						that can override the session duration for payroll purposes e.g. to pay to
						an additional hour to allow for opening and closing a venue, or to pay less
						time than the session duration, to account for unpaid breaks. As the
						timetable is changed, the amount payable to the tutor will automatically
						increase or decrease. Fixed payroll wage types and per enrolment types can
						be paid in addition to a per timetabled hour rate to a single tutor in a
						class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Per student contact hour</emphasis></para>
					<para>This is a less frequently used type. It is a rate that is paid per student (active
						enrolment) per hour of delivery. A rate set for this type is multiplied by
						both the number of active enrolments at the time the payroll is run x the
						number of timetabled hours for each session. It is more commonly used for
						the provision of government funding than it is for payroll. Per student
						contact hour paylines are calculated as a single wage line due on the start
						of the class and can be used in combination with other pay types. The
						'Payable time' field in the timetable also sets the hours multiplier for
						this rate.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		<example>
			<title>How to create Tutor pay rates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>To open the window go to <guimenu>File</guimenu> >
							<guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem> > <guimenuitem>Tutor roles
						</guimenuitem>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select one of the existing wage types to edit and modify or create a new wage type
						by clicking the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/definedTutorRolesList.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Give a name and a public label to the wage role, for example 'VET Tutor Step 1'. The
						public label shows as the role in the class interface. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Set the expense account for the wage</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button within the pay rate window to add a
						payrate for this Tutor type.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_payrate_window.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the drop down sheet, define how this type of Tutors wage is calculated from the
						options available e.g. 'Per timetabled hour'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the <guilabel>rate</guilabel> field, define the dollar amount per your selected type
							the Tutor is to be paid e.g. $55 per timetabled hour. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>On-costs allows you to take into account any additional expenses related to employing
						these staff, such as superannuation, leave loading, payroll tax and workers
						compensation costs. A common on-cost used calculating additional employee
						costs in Australia is 20%</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setting the start date for this pay rate allows you to keep track of historical payrate
						increases, and ensures that if a Tutors pay calculation falls across a
						change in pay conditions, all sessions delivered before the change will be
						calculated at the old rate, with sessions delivered after the change in rate
						to be calculated at the new rate. By default this field is set to a
						historical date five years past for the first entry you create, but you can
						change it to the date of you choice. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click <guibutton>Ok</guibutton> and <guibutton>Save</guibutton> and close the
						record. You will be returned to the list screen where you can add or edit another pay rate.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/definedTutorRole.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<caution>
			<para>If your payrate doesn't start until today, but the class start date is prior to today,
				no automatic pay rate will be found when you add the Tutor to the class. You can still
				create a manual pay line in the class. Also, if the payrate changes during the class
				progress, i.e. class spans June and July, and at the start of the financial year a new pay
				rate applies, that class budget information will only show the original pay rate in the cost
				calculations, but the actual payslip calculations will be correct as to the timing of each
				session and the pay rate that applied as each session was delivered.</para>
		</caution>
	</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="payroll-classBudget">
		<title>Class budget with Tutor pay</title>
		<para>Once you have defined the default payrates for the various classifications of Tutors you
			employ, you can use these to automatically add wages costs to your class budgets. You can do
			this by adding Tutors to classes. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>If you do not know who the individual Tutor will be in advance to your class scheduling,
				we recommend you set up a Tutor named something like 'To Be Advised' whom you can assign to
				classes. This will allow you take wages into account in your initial class budget and
				viability calculations. When you know the name of the individual who will be running the
				class you can replace TBA with the actual Tutor, and make any changes to their pay rate as
				required.</para>
		</tip>
		<example>
			<title>Assigning a Tutor and payrate to a class in one step</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the class window, navigate to the Tutor tab. Here you can add one or more Tutors,
						Coordinators, Assistants or other staff to the class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> to add a new Tutor to the class or double
						click on a Tutor already added to the class to add a wage to their record.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the Tutor edit sheet, type in the surname of the Tutor you wish to add to the
						class. This field will look up Tutors you have already created in the database. You can
						not add new Tutors from here.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>When you select the Tutors role, the automatic pay rate set for this role will be
						added. You can override the wage at this point for this individual Tutor for this
						class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click <guibutton>Ok</guibutton> to add the Tutor to the class.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/addTutorToClass.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Continue to add additional Tutors to the class, and define their wages as required. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you have added a coordinator or other assisting staff member to the Tutor list of the
						class you can choose to remove them from publicity (printing in the brochure
						and showing on your onCourse website) by unchecking the option 'Show this
						tutor in class information'. You can also choose to uncheck the option 'add
						selected tutor to all class sessions' if the tutor being added is not
						expected to attend the class sessions.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you need to edit the Tutor wage once you have set it, you will need to go to the
						class budget tab to make changes. Double click on the wage you wish to edit and check
						the option 'override assigned role's pay rate'.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_wage_override.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once you have clicked on 'override assigned role's pay rate', you will then be able
						to adjust the role, account code and rate. <inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/editWageInClass.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you did not have a wage added when the Tutor was added to the class, e.g. for a
						historical class, you can add the wage on the budget tab. Go to <guibutton>+
							Add budget item...</guibutton> select from the list <guibutton>Wage
						</guibutton> and select the Tutor from the list.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can also add Tutors to the class directly from the timetable, during the session
						creation or edit process. If you add Tutors here, you can adjust the
						payline's in the budget tab in the same way.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<para>You can also add additional lines to the tutor payroll for other pay types. You are limited
			to one line per type (per timetabled hour, fixed, per enrolment ect) for each tutor.
			This allows you to add the standard tutors pay rate, and perhaps and assessment
			allowance per enrolment or a set up/pack up allowance per session. To add the additional
			pay rate type:</para>
		<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
				<para>In the class record, go to the budget tab and select the add budget
					item</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select add wage and select your tutor's name. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If this is the second or subsequent line for your tutor, you will need to
					select the 'override tutor wage' option</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Add the specifics for the new wage line item ensuring you choose a different
					type to any existing pay lines</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Unavailability bookings</title>
		<para>All bookable resources in onCourse, such as sites, rooms and tutors can be given
			unavailability rules. After you have created these rules they will be highlighted in the
			timetable with a warning if you try to book the resources in a way that conflicts with
			their unavailability. Double bookings receive the same warning i.e. when you try to
			assign a tutor to two classes whose sessions overlap. onCourse does not prevent you from
			making double bookings as their may be legitimate reasons for you to do this, it just
			brings them to your attention.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to record a Tutor as being unavailable</title>
			<para>Many colleges employee tutors on a part time or casual basis who also have commitments
				elsewhere that effect their availability to teach. Tutors may also take periods of
				leave which you may want to record in against their record so they aren't assigned
				to teach any sessions during that period. Whatever the reason, you can flag a Tutor
				as not available in the following way:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In onCourse, go to "Tutor"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Double click on a record to open a Tutor profile</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From here click on the "timetable" tab</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Click on the "list" option and in the bottom panel, there is the "availability rules"
						section (see screen shot)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the + sign on the top right hand side of the "availability rules" section and
						you can add the busy period as well as the option to select "all day" which,
						as the name suggests, will block the whole day for that Tutor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Where needed, this can be a reoccurring booking, such as a tutor who is
						never available on Wednesdays.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/unavailabilities.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="payroll-attendance">
		<title>Confirming Attendance and exceptions</title>
		<para>Not only is attendance used for students, it can also be used to record whether your
			Tutors showed up and if they stayed for longer or shorter than their rostered time. You do not
			have to use this function in order to pay Tutors, but it can be very useful. Tutor attendance
			can be set for each session on the class Attendance tab.</para>
		<example>
			<title>Setting Tutor attendance for Tutor pay</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open a class record and navigate to the attendance tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>For each session, click on the attendance icon and set the appropriate attendance.
						Click once for attended, twice for not attended. Three clicks will set the session back
						to unmarked.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_tutor_attendance.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set the attendance to partial attendance, or absent with reason, right click on
						the attendance icon and select one of these options. When you select one of these values
						a drop down sheet will appear with fields for additional information to be set. Either
						of these options need to be approved for Tutor pay in the window.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set partial attendance, you need to enter in the sheet how many minutes of the
						scheduled session minutes the person was in attendance for. You can enter
						more or less minutes than the session duration. Note that the session
						payable time from the timetable does not appear on this screen, only the
						duration. Approving this Tutor pay variation means the person will be paid
						for the payable time you have set as their override. Leaving it unapproved
						means they will not be paid for this session at all, unless you choose to
						check the option during the payroll export 'unapproved attendance' <inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_partial_attendance.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="payroll-payslips">
		<title>Generating Tutor pay</title>
		<para>onCourse generates Tutor pay records in bulk, for a given point in time, based on the
			attendance records for Tutor. While generating Tutor pay records the admin user is given
			choices as to whether unmarked or unapproved attendance should be included.</para>
		<para>Tutor pay is run for sessions up to your defined date, and will pick up all the unpaid
			sessions since last time the payroll was run and the date you nominate.</para>
		<para>It is best practice to select all classes when running a tutor pay so that the payroll
			run will pick up any new payable items that may have been added to a class and remain unpaid.<example>
				<title>Generating, editing and finalising Tutor pay</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Before Tutor pay can be created you'll need a fully setup class, with
							timetable, Tutors and wages.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open list of classes</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Highlight classes for which Tutor pay is to be generated. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select the "Generate Tutor pay for xx classes " menu item under the
							cogwheel icon<inlinemediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/generateTutorPayStep1.png"/>
								</imageobject>
							</inlinemediaobject></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Enter the date you want the payroll run to include sessions prior to.
							If you want the pay run to include sessions run on 1/3/2014, chose the
							day after e.g. 2/3/14</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select whether unmarked or unapproved attendance is to be taken under
							consideration when generating Tutor pay. This only applies to per
							session or per timetabled hour pay. Other types of pay (such as fixed
							rate) does not rely on attendance marking or approval at all. In those
							instances where a fixed rate is to be paid, a pay run can be generated
							anytime after the Class has commenced. <inlinemediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/generateTutorPayStep2.png"/>
								</imageobject>
							</inlinemediaobject></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Press save and wait until a new list view, showing all newly created
							Tutor pay records is displayed. They will have a creation date of
							'today' and will be marked with a status of 'new'.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If a payslip for a tutor has been created in error, while it has a
						status of 'new' it can be deleted using the garbage icon in the top
						right hand corner of the payslips window.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once Tutor pay records have been created they can be edited. Each
							Tutor pay record has a list of items grouped by class and based on the
							relevant attendance/wages/sessions for that class. Payslips can only be
							edited with they have a status of 'new'. Once you finalise or export
							them they become locked.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Unchecking an item in the list will remove it from being paid in this
							payroll cycle. The next time you run a payroll it will be add to the
							tutors payslip again. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Additional custom or manual Tutor pay items can be added to the payslip.<inlinemediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/editTutorPay.png"/>
								</imageobject>
							</inlinemediaobject></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor pay can be modified until its finalised, which happens once the
							record has been exported using <guimenu>File</guimenu> >
								<guimenuitem>Import/Export</guimenuitem> > <guimenuitem>Tutor pay
							</guimenuitem>.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Another way to finalise a Tutor pay record select it and choose
							"Finalise Tutor pay" from cogwheel menu. The finalised Tutor pay records
							display status "Paid/Exported"</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example></para>
		<caution>
			<para>Tutor pay can have following statuses: New, Completed, Approved and Paid/Exported. Only
				a status of "Paid / Exported" prevents the editing of the record. </para>
		</caution>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Payroll Questions and Answers</title>
		<qandaset>
			<qandaentry>
				<question><para>Can I have multiple tutors teaching, and being paid for the same session?</para></question>
				<answer><para>Yes, you can assign many tutors to a session. Each tutor is attached to the class with their
						own payroll type and rate, and this is the rate that will apply to them as
						they teach the session. Each tutor attached to the session will be paid
						their rate multiplied by the session's payable time, in the case of per
						timetabled hour payrates.</para>
					<para>If the tutors attached to the session have different payable times due to
						them i.e. only one of the tutors is paid an extra hour for opening and
						closing the venue, then use the tutor attendance function to vary the
						payable time for each appropriate session for that tutor only.</para></answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question><para>I have a five hour class, with one tutor teaching for the full five hours, and other teaching only for two of those hours. How do I record their different payable times?</para></question>
				<answer><para>There are a few options available here, depending on how you wish to present the class
						timetable to the tutors and students attending. One option is to break the
						single five hour session into a three hour and two hour session, and assign
						the five hour tutor to both, and the two hour tutor to their session only.
						The class budget will then show the correct expenses also. The benefit of
						this approach is that both tutors will see the times they are expected to be
						teaching in their timetable. Your onCourse website will slightly alter the
						display of the class details block when you have broken a day into multiple
						sessions so it is clear to potential students what the delivery structure
						looks like and what the class start and end times are.</para>
					<para>A second option would be to keep the single five hour session and have
						both tutors assigned. The two hour attending tutor, instead of having a per
						timetabled hour rate could have a per session rate, that you worked out to
						be the per timetabled hour rate x 2. This will give you the correct class
						budget payroll expenses, but the two hour tutor will see in their timetable
						that they are 'teaching' a five hour session. </para>
					<para>A third option would be to keep both tutors assigned as above, but use the
						attendance marking function for the two hour attending tutor to mark them as
						'partially attended' and their payable time to be 120 minutes only. This
						option will generate the correct payroll for the tutor, but the budget will
						show that you expect to pay them for five hours of attendance, not two, so
						will be overestimating the class costs. The tutor timetable will also show
						that the two hour tutor is 'teaching' a five hour session.</para></answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question><para>A tutor called in sick and was replaced by a casual. How can I reflect this so they are not paid for that class session?</para></question>
				<answer><para>You can either untick the tutor from the session who didn't attend or mark their attendance
						record with a red cross. Either option will prevent a per timetabled hour or
						per session payroll type being generated for them for that particular
						session.</para>
					<para>You can then add the casual who filled in for them to the class and just
						assign them to that session and ensure the appropriate wage line is added to
						the budget for them (it's best to untick the option 'add selected tutor to
						all class sessions' when you just want to add a casual replacement tutor to
						a single session)</para></answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question><para>Our award requires the tutors to be paid for a minimum of two hours per session, but the
						session is only one and a half hours long. How can I pay them
						correctly?</para></question>
				<answer><para>The payable time field in the session is the first option for overriding the payable time, so
						you could increase this from the default session time of 1 hr 30 mins to the
						two hours you want the tutor to be paid. This would then show in the budget
						the correct costs for the tutors wage.</para>
					<para>Alternatively, you could override the tutor payrate from the normal per
						timetabled hour option to a per session option where you manually worked out
						the 2 hour rate. This would also keep the budget accurate.</para>
					<para>The other option would be to use the partial attendance option, and increase their
						payable time from 90 mins to 120 mins, so the correct pay was generated, but
						it wouldn't affect the budget projection, which would keep their estimated
						pay amount being multiplied by 1hr 30 mins per session. This is a better
						choice if you had two tutors assigned to the session and only one of the
						tutors was affected by this award condition.</para></answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question><para>Our award requires tutors to be paid an additional 20% of their normal hourly rate when they
						work 4 hours or less. How can I calculate this?</para></question>
				<answer><para>There are a few ways you could approach this change of rate.</para>
					<para>One option would be two have two different roles which each had two
						different per timetabled hour rates e.g. Tutor Part Time, $40 per timetabled
						hour and Tutor Casual with a rate of $48 per timetabled hour. You would then
						choose the appropriate role and rate when you assign the tutor to the class,
						knowing it's daily session duration and if they are being paid at the Part
						Time or Casual rate.</para>
					<para>The second option is to use a single rate, but for the sessions with a 4
						hour or less duration, to add 20% more time than the session duration to the
						session payable time. 20% of an hour of payable time is 12 minutes, so if
						they are working for 3 hrs, you could pay them the Part Time rate for 3 hrs
						and 36 min payable time to get 3 hours of payable time at the Casual
						rate.</para>
					<para>Keeping in mind that a tutor in onCourse can has a role and rate which
						applies to all of their sessions for that class, using an increase in the
						payable hours is a good option if the session duration, and appropriate
						payrate, varies during the class. For example if the first 9 sessions of the
						class are 6 hours long, so the tutor is paid at the Part Time rate, but the
						last session is an exam and only 3 hours long, so the tutor should is paid
						at the higher per hour Casual rate for this session only. This is where
						changing the payable time to 3 hrs and 36 mins would be most
						appropriate.</para>
					<para>A final option, if trying to calculate the difference in payable time to
						arrive at the new rate is too complicated, is to add a second wage line to
						the budget for that tutor for a fixed rate of the extra amount they should
						be paid. In this example, for the final 3 hour exam session, the tutor would
						be paid an additional $32 on top of their normal hourly rate. Remember that
						if you choose this option, the fixed amount will show up in the payroll run
						for the first class session, as all fixed rate types are payable on class
						commencement. You can use the untick option for that line in the payslip to
						remove it on every payslip generated until the pay run when you want it to
						be paid, but this requires a little more manual intervention. </para></answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question><para>Out tutors are paid a fixed daily rate when they work between 6 and 8 hours. How can I set this up?</para></question>
				<answer><para>onCourse does not have a concept of a daily rate. A per session rate may be an appropriate way
						to express this provided your class timetable has only one session per
						day.</para>
					<para>If single day in the class timetable is often broken into multiple
						sessions, expressing the daily rate as a per timetabled hour rate would be
						more appropriate. For example, if the daily rate was $300, you may choose to
						express this as a per timetabled hour rate of $50 per hour, and you would
						then ensure all classes with a daily duration between 6 and 8 hours have the
						payable time per day set to 6 hours.</para>
					<para>If your teaching day started at 9am, finished at 4pm and the day was
						broken into 3 x 2 hour sessions with gaps between them for breaks, the
						default payable time would be the same as the session time, so you wouldn't
						need to alter anything and the daily rate would be calculated
						correctly.</para>
					<para>If your teaching day started at 9am and finished at 5pm with a single
						session having an 8 hr duration, you could adjust the payable time to 6 hrs
						so the daily rate would calculate correctly.</para></answer>			
			</qandaentry>
		</qandaset>
	</section>
</chapter>
