<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="processingEnrolments">
	<title>Processing Enrolments</title>
	<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-Definitions">
		<title>Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Quick Enrol:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Quick enrol is a tool available to you in onCourse, it allows you to
						easily enrol a student into a class in just a few steps. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Enrolment:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>An enrolment is an instance in which a person has elected to partake in a
						class for different reasons, they will supply their details and this will be
						stored in the onCourse database. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Invoice:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>An invoice is a record/document that represents income of some sort. This
						can be an enrolment into a class or other goods and services provided. An
						invoice is basically a bill. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Payment:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A payment is an instance in which money owing has been successfully taken
						from one party and transferred to another. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Student:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A student in onCourse is a type of contact, one who is currently or has
						previously been enrolled into a class and is being taught by another
						person/resource. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Payer:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A payer is someone who has personally paid an invoice for an enrolment in
						a class. It is important to note that a payer does not necessarily need to
						be the person taking the class, or even an individual for that matter. They
						can be a relative, friend, manager or company. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-quickEnrol">
		<title>Working with Quick Enrol</title>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>Quick enrol can be accessed through a number of methods</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>Clicking on the Quick Enrol option from the onCourse home or "splash"
					screen.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Selecting <emphasis role="bold">People</emphasis> from the top menu and then
					selecting <emphasis role="bold">Quick Enrol</emphasis> from the drop down menu.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> You can also bring up the Quick Enrol page if you hold down the command
					button on your keyboard and press the E button once, this is called a <emphasis
						role="bold">Keyboard Shortcut</emphasis>. Please note you can only issue
					this command if you are in an active window of onCourse, not any other program.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para> Quick Enrol is a tool in which you can enrol students into classes. Most of the
			fields have autocomplete functionality which means when you start typing, onCourse
			starts finding students that start with that name, and will display the results on the
			right hand side of the window.</para>
		<para>The following will identify the different elements of the Quick Enrol window, and what
			their purpose is, the left side of the windows allows you to search for previous records
			that are stored on your database, where the right side houses the fields and functions. </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>Navigating through Quick Enrol</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">CONTACTS</emphasis> button (left side of the
					window): This button allows you to review the contacts details.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Enter contact...</emphasis> field (left side of the
					window): This field allows you to add a new contact or search for previous
					contacts that are already stored on your database, they can be a student, a
					tutor or a company. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">ITEMS</emphasis> button (left side of the window):
					This button shows you the breakdown of the current tax invoice.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Enter course or item...</emphasis> field (left side
					of the window): This field allows you to search for a specific course or item
					that is already stored on your database, such items include membership number or
					names, vouchers codes, or products.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">PAYMENTS</emphasis> button (left side of the
					window): This button allows you to review and select which invoice/s you wish to
					debit the payment from.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Credit card</emphasis> button (left side of the
					window): This button allows you to choose the payment method along with the
					payer. Please note that the name of the button will change to what ever payment
					method is being used.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The <emphasis role="bold">Enter voucher or promotion...</emphasis> field (left
					side of the window): This field allows you to enter a voucher or promotional
					code and apply it to the payment.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-Creating">
		<title>Creating an enrolment with Quick Enrol</title>
		<para>This section will provide you with clear and concise instructions on how to achieve
			certain things within onCourse Quick Enrol, like enrolling a student.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<title>A few things to consider first</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>A contact can be a student or a payer, a company can be listed as a payer but
					can not be a student. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Student names can be entered in this fashion: "Smith, John". When you type a
					comma, the auto complete looks up all students with "Smith" as a surname. As you
					continue to type letters of the first name, the list is reduced. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>You can also type student names like this: "John Smith". When you do this, the
					auto complete feature will not start showing you choices until you have typed a
					few letters of the student's surname. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If the student you are enrolling has a contact record at your college, you can
					select them from the list on the right hand side of the window. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>When searching for a students record a list will appear on the right of the
					window, you will see their full name, suburb, date of birth and email address,
					to assist you in selecting the right record.</para>
				<note>
					<para>The USI field will be disabled along with you not being able to change
						student name of date of birth, in Quick Enrol, if the USI has been
						verified.</para>
				</note>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If the student you wish to enrol is new to your college, you can select the
					option "New contact…" which will appear on the right hand window when you click
					on the 'Enter contact...' field.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once you have selected your student, you will see their information in the
					Quick Enrol window, this is the same information you see in their contact
					record, you can then make changes to any of the contact details, notes or
					AVETMISS information as needed. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If there is a third party payer you will need to add them as a contact and
					create a relationship to the student. This can be found at the bottom of the
					page under the General tab in the contacts record, it will say 'Above contact is
					X of the payer'.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>When you complete the enrolment, the changes will be saved. If you cancel the
					enrolment, your changes will not be saved.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<section>
			<title>Simple enrolments</title>
			<para>The most important thing to remember about Quick Enrol is that all enrolments
				processed in a single onCourse Quick Enrol process generate one invoice to a single
				payer. This could be for one student enrolling and paying for themselves in one or
				more classes, or another contact enrolling and paying for one or more students to
				enrol in one or more classes. If two friends are enrolling in a class together and
				paying separately, you would process their enrolments as two separate Quick Enrol
				processes.</para>
			<para>Every Quick Enrol process generates an invoice, even if there is no payment
				involved. Sometimes, this invoice will be for $0.00, for example if there is no cost
				to enrol in the selected class. Sometimes the invoice will be paid in full on
				enrolment, and also be a receipt of payment. Sometimes the invoice will be partially
				paid or not paid at all. The default setting for Quick Enrol to default payments to
				full payment or no payment is set in the Financial Preferences window.</para>
			<para>When processing an enrolment via the onCourse client, it is possible to issue an
				invoice to the customer who won't be paying the course fee at the time of enrolment,
				even if your usual preference is set to pay in full. This is done by changing the
				payment method to 'no payment' from the default option 'credit card'.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open "Quick Enrol"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the "Enter contact..." field, type in a name of the contact you are
						trying to enrol. If the correct contact populates on the right hand window,
						then select them, if the person you need is not in the system, you can
						create their profile by clicking on the 'Select' button on the right hand
						side on the window next to the text 'New contact' and then complete their
						contact detail information.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/autocomplete.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Use the autocomplete to locate and select the student</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>After the contact is selected, click on the "Enter course or item" field
						on the left hand side.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From here input either a course code or course name, again these fields
						are autocomplete so if you were to type e.g "Comp", courses that begin with
						those letters, e.g. 'Computers for Beginners', 'Computers for Seniors' will
						be available to select. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once the course is located then selected, the classes will be presented to
						you in the "Choose a class" list view, highlight the class you want. By
						default, only current and future classes will be shown.</para>
					<para>The "Show finished classes" checkbox can be selected to include classes
						that are now past their end date, e.g "Computers - Beginners ABC-123" is
						scheduled to end on 24/11/13, and the date is 25/11/13, selecting "Show
						finished classes" ensures that "Computers - Beginners ACBC-123" is shown in
						the class list view and can be selected for enrolment.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can now add a MEMBERSHIP, VOUCHER, or PRODUCT, if other purchases are
						being made with this enrolment. This can be done by either searching for a
						membership number or name; voucher code; or a product name, or alternatively
						clicking on one of the 'Show all' buttons on the right hand side of the
						page.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you wish to review the invoice, you can so this by clicking on the
						'ITEMS' button</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you have either a voucher or promotion code you can input this into the
						'Enter voucher or promotion...' field, then click on the + symbol to
						apply</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can now review the invoice/s the payment will apply to by clicking on
						the PAYMENTS button on the left hand side of the page. This only is
						necessary if the student has previous invoices with balances outstanding.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Next, select the Credit card button from the left hand side to select the
						chosen payment method; the payment amount; and who the payer will be. Please
						note that the payer does not have to be the student, it can be any other
						contact added to the Quick Enrol process, including a company.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Finally, select save from the bottom of the window, a confirmation box
						will appear, form here select your methods of receiving the invoice and
						enrolment confirmation. That's it!</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Discounting the enrolment fee</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>When processing an enrolment through Quick Enrol, you can discount course
					fees by using:</title>
				<listitem>
					<para>Automatic discount – a discount automatically offered to people who meet
						pre-defined criteria, e.g. seniors, people who hold a certain membership,
						students re-enrolling within a defined time period or students enrolling in
						a defined date range</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Promotion – a special offer accessed through a one-time code, used as a
						marketing tool.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Manual discount - a once off discount that isn't part of a standard
						promotion or concession</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para> More about concessions and promotions can be found in <xref
					xlink:href="#discounts"/></para>
			<para> If an automatic discount has been created, the student meets the requirements of
				the discount and the class they are enrolling in has been set to allow that type of
				discount, then the discount will automatically be applied when they enrol. </para>
			<para>If a student is automatically eligible for more than one type of discount, the
				higher discount will be applied.</para>
			<para>You can also manually switch to a lower, eligible discount or override the
				discount amount applied.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/concessions1.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enrolment with an automatic discount applied for one class</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding a promotional code </title>
			<para>Promotional codes can be used by students enrolling over the web and by
				administration staff via onCourse Quick Enrol. In both instances, the code word must
				be supplied for the student to gain access to the discount. </para>
			<para> When processing an enrolment, enter the code in the 'Enter voucher or
				promotion...' field, and press the + button next to the field in Quick Enrol. This
				will then discount the eligible classes as appropriate. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Prom_code.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Quick Enrol promotional code field with the code "Green" entered,
						before adding it to the enrolment</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/Prom_code2.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>After clicking +, the name of the discount 'From tree to towel rack' has
						been applied to all eligible enrolments</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding information to invoices</title>
			<para>To review the tax invoice, you must click on the ITEMS button on the left hand
				side of the page. There are also a number of additional functions that you can do in
				this section of Quick Enrol</para>
			<para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you have more than one contact you can choose who is being invoiced
							to, therefore who the payer is going to be in the drop box under the
							ITEMS (TAX INVOICE) text.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you wish to create a reference for the invoice, such as a purchase
							order, this can be recorded in the 'Customer reference' field.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can also change the date that the invoice is due by change the
							date in the calender in the 'Due date' field.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Any enrolments or products you have already added to this Quick Enrol
							will be itemised automatically on the invoice, with any discount or tax
							applied.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>To add any additional charges you can do this by entering what they
							will be in the 'Additional charge...' field; then enter what fee this
							will incur; select what account; chose whether or not GST is added; then
							click on the "Add' button to include this in the invoice.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Any additional notes can be added in the 'Public notes' field at the
							bottom of the page. Text in the public notes field will print on the
							invoice.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Tax_invoice_image.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>An example of the tax invoice window in onCourse</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
				<para>If you are enrolling a student into multiple classes with one class having a payment plan,
				then you will end up with two tax invoices.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Tax_invoice_multiple.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>An example of the tax invoice window with multiple invoices</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Adding a 3rd party payer</title>
			<para>This part of the 3rd party payer topic only covers the steps to follow to add a
				3rd party payer. For more, read on to the section "3rd Party Payments". </para>
			<para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Add the student to the enrolment as per the usual process. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If the third party is already related to the student you have added,
							you can find them quickly by clicking on the down arrow next to the
							'Enter contact...' field and selecting them.</para>
						<para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/QE_related_contact.png"/>
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>There are two contacts already added to this Quick Enrol.
										From the related contacts list I can select any other
										contacts already related to either of these contacts.</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If the contact is not currently related to the student, to add the
							payer to the enrolment, add them as a contact in the same way as you
							added the student to Quick Enrol. You do not need to enrol them in any
							classes, however, if they are a friend or family member they may be both
							enrolling and paying. </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>You can create a relationship between contacts at this point, e.g.
							contact 1 (Jenny Smith) is the staff member of contact 2 (Computer
							Trainers of Hobart) by scrolling to the bottom of the student's general
							tab.</para>
						<para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
										fileref="images/3rd_party_payer.png"/>
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>The relationship option, click "select" to choose a type
										of relationship between contacts</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Set the classes for the student(s) as per the usual process.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Ensure you select the correct payer, the name of the payer will change
							next to the ITEMS button. Enter the payment details (zero payments are
							allowed – an invoice with an unpaid, partial or fully paid balance will
							be sent). </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select 'Email' and/or 'Print enrolment confirmation and tax invoice'
							as appropriate. The invoice will only go to the payer. The enrolment
							confirmation will go to the student(s) enrolling. </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolling multiple students in multiple classes</title>
			<para>Quick enrol can be used to enrol many students in many classes, provided they are
				all being paid for by a single payer.</para>
			<para>In this example, two students from the same company are each enrolling in two
				classes. Both students are attending one class together, and then they are each
				attending another, different class.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Add the students and their company to Quick Enrol</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the first class that the students are both attending. You will note
						by default both students are ticked as attending this class.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/QE_multiple_class.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Both students are selected to attend this class</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the second class one of the students is going to attend. Unselect
						the student who is not attending. Note that on the summary panels on the
						left, it shows that Jenny Smith is attending two classes, while Kieran Smith
						is only attending one, and in the Items list summary, two students are
						attending Accounting with MYOB and only one is attending Computers
						Beginners.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/QE_second_class.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Only Jenny Smith is selected to attend this class.</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Repeat this process, selecting the second choice of class for the other
						student.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the ITEMS button to show the invoice summary, and change the
						payer from the first student to the company. The invoice summary shows four
						lines, with two enrolments for each student.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/QE_invoice_summary.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The invoice that will be generated for the company, based on this
								Quick Enrol process.</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the 'credit card' default payment selection, and complete the
						payment process as requested by the company e.g. no payment for an invoice,
						or take a payment now</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Save and complete the enrolment. The tax invoice will be sent to the
						company, and two enrolment confirmations will be sent to each of the
						students. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enrolling a student in credit or debt</title>
			<para>To enrol a student in credit or debt basically means that the student (when the
				student is the payer) you are about to enrol owes your organisation money through
				unpaid or partially paid fees, or your organisation owes this student money via an
				onCourse credit note, perhaps because the student cancelled an enrolment in a prior
				class. To achieve one of these you would need to make sure the following:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>The student must have been previously enrolled in a class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The student must have accrued either credit or debit depending on their
						previous engagements with your organisation.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once trying to enrol the student, you will notice the amount either in
						"Previous owing" or "Balance outstanding". </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If the student has credit to their name, then the balance outstanding will
						be less than cost of the enrolment. The student may use all or some of their
						credit during this enrolment. If the student has insufficient credit
						available to cover the cost of this enrolment, they can pay the balance
						outstanding as per a standard enrolment.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If the student has a debt, and your financial preferences are to pay the
						enrolment in full, then the default payment amount will be the total they
						owe. As per the previous section 'How to review a contact's invoices', you
						can choose which, if any, of the outstanding invoices you wish to pay
						now.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Keep in mind the outstanding balance in any Quick Enrol will be the
						balance of the payer's account. For many enrolments, the payer and student
						are the same person. However, if the payer is another person or company,
						their credit can be used to pay for another student's enrolment. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-paymentOptions">
		<title>Quick Enrol payment options</title>
		<para>By default the first contact is nominated as the payer. If you wish to switch this to
			another contact, click on the payment button on the left and change the name of the
			payer in the field provided. You can also change who the payer is by clicking on the
			ITEMS button on the left side of the page.</para>
		<para>If a third party, such as an employer or agency are paying the fee, and if the payer
			has any amount outstanding, that information will be added to the total fee. You can
			choose to pay the full amount owing, zero, or a portion of the amount owing. </para>
		<para>If a voucher is being used to pay for an enrolment, you need to add the voucher before
			choosing how to pay any balance outstanding by an alternate method.</para>
		<para>If your financial preferences are set to pay in full, but you are taking a partial
			payment now, you can edit the amount the contact wants to pay at this time by clicking
			on the pen icon, changing to edit mode, and change the amount in the field.</para>
		<para>If you click the pen icon a second time, the payment amount will default back to the
			full amount payable. In the image below, you can see payment amount is in default full
			payment amount, as the value is slightly greyed out. When you are in edit mode, the text
			is in black and you can type into this field.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/QE_payment_options.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Payment options available via Quick Enrol</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>By default, the payment type will be set to credit card. You can change this to
			another payment type of your choice (or no payment, if the student is not paying right
			now). Anything you record as a payment at this point should only be a payment you have
			received right now - this is not the place to record the way the student is intending to
			pay at some point in the future.</para>
		<para>If you do not have a merchant account linked to your onCourse installation, selecting
			credit card will presume you have processed the credit card elsewhere and already
			verified it was successful e.g. through your own EFTPOS terminal or other payment
			gateway service.</para>
		<para>If you do have a merchant account linked to onCourse and you select credit card, a
			browser window will open and the details will be validated as you enter the information.
			The enrolment save process will not complete until the bank validates the card number
			(see below for more details on how this works).</para>
		<section>
			<title>Reviewing the invoice</title>
			<para>By clicking on the "PAYMENTS' button you can review any other unpaid invoice(s)
				that are connected the Quick Enrol invoice payer. The invoice being created as part
				of this Quick Enrol process is labelled 'This Invoice'. You can select or unselect
				any of the invoices the contact wants to make a payment against at this time, by
				clicking on the related check box. By default any invoices that have a due date in
				the future will be suppressed.<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Reviewing_invoice_image.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>An example of the window you see when you wish to review a contacts
							invoice(s)</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject></para>
			<para>If you are enrolling a student in more than one class, with one being a payment plan then
				you will end up with two invoices. Every playment plan class will get it's own
				invoice so if you enrolling a student into five classes, with two having payment
				plan and with the other three not, then there will be three invoices created.<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Reviewing_payment_plan_invoice.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>An example of the window you see when you wish to review a contacts
							invoices when they have enrolled in multiple classes, with one being a
							payment plan class</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject></para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Using a voucher for payment</title>
			<para>If the student or payer has a Gift Voucher or a Package Voucher they wish to
				redeem for this enrolment, then you need to record these details first.</para>
			<para>Enter the voucher code in the 'Enter voucher or promotion...' field. The balance
				available on the voucher will automatically be applied to any of the eligible
				enrolments in this Quick Enrol window. </para>
			<para>You can then proceed to take payment for any outstanding balance via an alternate
				method such as cash or credit card.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Recording a cash payment</title>
			<para>To record a cash payment simply select 'cash' from the payment type drop down
				menu, once you have confirmed the payment amount is correct, just click save to
				complete the enrolment.</para>
			<para>Any cash payments you make will be linked to your user location for your banking
				process. These cash payments will be need to be reconciled when you run 'Deposit
				banking' from your location. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Recording a cheque payment</title>
			<para>To record a cheque payment you will need to follow these steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select 'cheque' from the payment type drop down menu and the window will
						refresh to update the payment type</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the cheque bank, cheque branch and cheque drawer in the fields that
						appear. Note that these are required fields within Quick Enrol and you will
						be unable to complete the enrolment unless you enter the cheque details.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once you have confirmed the payment amount matches the cheque amount, just
						click save to complete the enrolment</para>
					<para>Like cash, cheque payments are linked to your user location for
						banking.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/QE_cheque_payments.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Cheque payment required fields within Quick Enrol</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title> Recording an EFT payment </title>
			<para>An incoming course payment may have been processed on an EFTPOS terminal external
				to the onCourse system, even though the payment has been processed, you will still
				need to record the fact that the payment has been made within onCourse. To do this
				you will need to follow these steps: </para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select EFT from the payment type drop down menu</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once you have confirmed the payment amount, just click save to complete
						the enrolment</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
		<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-creditCards">
		<title>Processing a credit card payment</title>
		<para>onCourse processes credit card payments via a secure web browser and verifies the
			credit card details in real time with the bank.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/QE_credit_card_payment_window.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Secure online payment window to process credit card payments</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para> To process a credit card payment via the secure payment gateway, you need to do the
			following steps:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select Credit Card from the payment type drop down menu within Quick
					Enrol</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Once you have selected that payment type, you no longer need to enter the
					credit card details into the Quick Enrol window, as a separate browser window
					will open to enable you to enter the credit card details directly into the
					secure payment gateway.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>To open up this new browser window and process the transaction, click on
						<guilabel>Save</guilabel> within the Quick Enrol window</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Enter the credit card details into the secure payment window and then click
					the <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> button to process the payment</para>
				<para>Whilst the secure payment is being processed, the Quick Enrol window will
					remain open with a processing enrolment message being displayed. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The payment will be processed and if successful, the payment gateway window
					will display the message <emphasis role="bold">payment was successful</emphasis>
					you can then close the payment browser window</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The Quick Enrol window will also update to show that the transaction was
					successful, you can then click OK and then send the enrolment confirmation as
					per the standard process. </para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Successful_CC_Payment_Message.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Secure payment browser window updates once transaction is successful</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/QE_Successful_CC_Payment_Message.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Quick Enrol window updates with the following message once the payment has
					been approved</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<note>
			<para>In the event that there is an outage with your internet connection whilst a credit
				card transaction is being processed, for example the separate secure payment browser
				window is unable to be opened. An error message will appear notifying you that the
				payment is unable to proceed. You will need to wait for that payment attempt to time
				out before re-attempting the process. Timing out of a failed transaction ordinarily
				takes approximately 20 minutes.</para>
		</note>
		<section>
			<title>Managing cancelled and failed credit card transactions</title>
			<para>This section outlines how you manage the cancellation process and how onCourse
				reconciles those cancelled transactions</para>
			<section>
				<title>How to cancel a credit card transaction</title>
				<para>To cancel a credit card transaction that you have commenced, you need to take
					the following steps:</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>To cancel a transaction that is underway, click on the
								<guilabel>Cancel</guilabel> button within the secure payment window.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The payment window will update to show the message <emphasis
								role="bold">this payment was cancelled</emphasis>. You can then
							close the browser window</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>In order to ensure that the invoice is reversed in onCourse, the
							system will automatically generate a credit note </para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>The Quick Enrol window will display the message <emphasis role="bold"
								>Payment is cancelled. A credit note has been
							created.</emphasis></para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<tip>
					<para>If you proceed with opening the new browser window to enter the credit
						card details, then find you need to cancel that transaction, always make
						sure that you click the <guilabel>Cancel</guilabel> button within the secure
						payment browser window.</para>
					<para>If you close the browser window by clicking on the close button, the QE
						window will lock and you will not be able to use QE until the transaction is
						timed out after 20 minutes.</para>
				</tip>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Cancelled_CC_Payment_Message.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Secure payment browser window updates once transaction has been
							cancelled</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/QE_Cancelled_CC_Payment_Message.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Quick Enrol window displays this message to notify the user of a
							cancellation and that it' has issued a credit note.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>How to manage transactions where the payment has failed</title>
				<para>The following section outlines what happens if the credit card number that has
					been entered is declined due to an invalid number, or the card has expired or
					insufficient funds are available.</para>
				<para>When a credit card payment has failed, the secure payment window will display
					the message <emphasis role="bold">This payment failed because the card was
						expired, invalid or does not have sufficient funds</emphasis> You will then
					be presented with three different options to complete the transaction. These
					options are clearly displayed within the payment window and you can hover your
					mouse over these options to view an explanation of each option, before making
					your selection. </para>
				<section>
					<title>Option 1: Abandon the Transaction - Keep the Invoice</title>
					<para>The payment will be marked as failed, but the invoice and enrolments kept.
						The debtor will be kept, owing you money for later payment</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/Payment_Window_Abandon_Keep_Invoice.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Option 1: Abandon the Transaction - Keep the Invoice</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Option 2: Abandon the Transaction - Reverse the Invoice</title>
					<para>The payment enrolments will be marked as failed and a credit note created
						to reverse the invoice.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/Payment_Window_Abandon_Reverse_Invoice.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Option 2: Abandon the Transaction - Reverse the Invoice</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Option 3: Try another card</title>
					<para>If the first card entered is declined, by clicking on <emphasis
							role="bold">Try another card</emphasis>, the payment window is refreshed
						and you can then enter a different card number to complete the transaction. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/Payment_Window_Try_Another_Card.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Option 3: Try another card</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
		<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-paymentIn">
		<title>Processing payments outside of Quick Enrol</title>
		<para>If an invoice is unpaid at the time of enrolment, or partially paid, at a later date
			you will need to collect the rest of the money owed to you. </para>
		<para>Until the balance of the invoice is paid, the payer will be recorded in the system as
			a debtor, and you can find them quickly in the invoice window.</para>
		<para>When a payment is made, you need to go to the Payment In window to record this, and
			reduce the balance of the debtors account.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Processing a Payment In</title>
			<example>
				<title>How to process a payment in</title>
				<para>Payments In can be accessed from the splash screen or from the <emphasis
						role="bold">Financial</emphasis> menu tab the top of your screen. To process
					a Payment In, follow these steps (assuming student has debt with you):</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Go the Payment In page either through the onCourse home screen
							Accounts > Payment In, or by selecting "Financial" from the top menu,
							then "Payment In"</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>From here click on the + (Add) symbol in the top right hand side of
							the window.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Type in the payer name in the "Payment from" field, remembering the
							field has autocomplete functionality. Only debtors who have a balance
							outstanding will be located in this field.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>If the debtor has more than one invoice with a balance outstanding, by
							default the payment will apply to the oldest invoice(s). The invoice(s)
							this payment is to apply to are ticked in the list. You can change the
							choice of invoice(s) as required.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select payment method and make sure all other details are in order
							before clicking the "save" button. You may take a full or partial
							payment towards their balance outstanding.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>After you complete this a email will be sent to the payer with the
							payment details and the payer record will appear in the list view of
							"Payment In".</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/Payment_In.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>A payment in for a debtor with multiple invoices with balances
							outstanding</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</example>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-invoicesAndEnrolmentConfirmations">
		<title>Sending invoices and confirmations</title>
		<para>At the end of the Quick Enrol process you can send email and/or printed tax invoices
			and enrolment confirmations.</para>
		<para>If the student(s) have provided email addresses, this option will be selected by
			default, and printing not selected. Select for each student if you would like this
			information emailed and/or mailed. </para>
		<para>The enrolment confirmation goes to each student who has enrolled in a class. The tax
			invoice only goes to the payer. For example, if two friends were attending a class
			together, paid for by one of them as a gift to the other, only the payer would receive
			information about the fees charged. The person receiving the enrolment as a gift would
			simply receive an enrolment confirmation with no information regarding the cost. </para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/QE_send_notifications.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Sending an enrolment confirmation and invoice through quick enrol</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="processingEnrolments-FAQs">
		<title>Quick Enrol FAQ</title>
		<para>If you have a question about Quick Enrol that is not answered by this chapter, please
			feel free to post a question in our forum or lodge an onCourse support request.</para>
		<section>
			<title>How do I manage an overpayment made by a student? </title>
			<para>onCourse does not allow overpayments of invoices. This is a deliberate design
				function to ensure data entry errors are not made. If a student presents a cheque
				made out for the wrong amount, so you can bank and process the cheque you can do the
				following:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create the enrolment as usual in Quick Enrol</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Add an 'other charge' to the enrolment, with a line item title like
						'overpayment'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Process the payment in Quick Enrol with the total balance of the cheque
						that has been presented.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Go to Invoices and create a manual credit note for the person who made an
						overpayment. This credit can then be used towards other enrolments or
						refunded. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>What do I do if I have recorded a payment (money) without any payment actually
				being made or I recorded the wrong amount?</title>
			<para>If for example a student has not actually made a physical payment on their
				enrolment, but an onCourse user recorded their enrolment in onCourse as paid, you
				will need to follow these steps to resolve it. Only unreconciled payments can be
				reversed.</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Locate the payment record in the 'Payment in' window and select it by
						single clicking it</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the to right hand corner or the window, go to the cogwheel and select
						the option 'Reverse payment'. This will reverse the payment against the
						invoice(s) where it was originally applied. Those invoices will now have a
						balance outstanding.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>When you complete the reversal process, the status of the payment in will
						change from success to reversed.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can now process the correct payment in method at the time the student
						pays or for the correct amount that was received. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reverse_payment.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Reversing an incorrect payment record</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I change part of an enrolment fee to a business, and part to a student? </title>
			<para>The best way to charge part of an enrolment fee to someone and another part to
				someone else would be to follow these steps. We will use an example of a $100
				enrolment where a student has paid half of an enrolment and the other half has been
				paid for by their job network agency:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a credit note for the student for $50 (half of the class fee). This
						will now drop their balance outstanding down to $50 (or $0 if they have
						already paid their half)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Create a manual invoice for the job network agency in the invoice window
						for the remaining $50.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Process the payment in for Job network invoice when they pay it. </para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>For an invoice, you can not record some of the payment coming from a person other
				than the payer (in this case the student). The reason you would use this method is
				so that if the student's enrolment is cancelled for some reason, they will only be
				entitled to a $50 refund, rather than the full $100. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>How do I provide an student with a discount after they have already
				enrolled?</title>
			<para>Invoices in onCourse are immutable, that is, you can't change them after they have
				already been issued.</para>
			<para>You can choose to either cancel the original enrolment and process it again
				correctly, with the discount or you can create a manual credit note for the
				student</para>
			<para>If the student has already paid the full amount, they will end up with credit that
				can be refunded or used towards another enrolment. If the student hasn't paid
				against the original invoice, they will now have a lower balance due, because of
				their credit note.</para>
		</section>
	<section>
		<title>How do I check to see if a student has been enrolled?</title>
		<para>You can go to the Enrolment list view window that will allow you to see basic information
				about all enrolments taken both in the office and on the web.</para>
		<para>If you require more information about an individual enrolment you can double click on an
				record; this will open a new window with additional information broken down into 4
				tabs. These tabs are General, Outcomes, VET FEE-HELP and Attachments</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/Enrolment_general_tab.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Enrolment General tab</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>What happens if a student doesn't meet the class age restrictions?</title>
			<para>If a class has a minimum, maximum or age range set for enrolment in the class
				general tab, then during Quick Enrol, each student attempting to enrol in the class
				will have their date of birth checked.</para>
			<para>If the student doesn't have a date of birth at all, then they will not be allowed
				to enrol until a valid date of birth is provided.</para>
			<para>If the student has a date of birth that means they do not meet the age
				requirements, they will not be able to enrol.</para>
			<para>If the student is enrolling via the office, then their date of birth can be
				modified. If the student is self enrolling on the website, and has previously
				provided their date of birth, they can not change their date of birth without
				contacting the office. If you approve and change their date birth in onCourse, they
				will then be allowed to enrol in this class on the website.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/QE_age_restriction_error_message.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Quick Enrol showing both types of age restriction error message</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
