<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="reports">
	<title>Reporting</title>
	<subtitle>Reports. Numbers. Charts. It's important to be able to see your data to make business
		decisions, and even more importantly, seeing it in a way that makes sense to you.</subtitle>
	<section xml:id="reports-printing">
		<title>Using reports</title>
		<para>onCourse comes prepackaged with a large range of reports. You can use them as is, or
			copy and modify any of them to suit your needs. You can also create brand new reports
			from scratch.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Printing Reports in onCourse</title>
			<para>The first thing to be aware of when attempting to print a report is that you must
				be in the right onCourse list view to print a report. For example, Class roll is a
				report available from the class list. You can not print this report from inside the
				class record, or from the general window. You must open the class window
				first.</para>
			<para>From each list window, you can select File > Print to see the list of available
				reports.</para>
			<para>All reports are printed to a PDF file which you can save to your computer, email,
				or print to a printer on your network. Your computer will need to have a PDF reader
				installed to create and view the report. Windows operating systems prior to Windows
				8 need to have this manually installed as one is not included as part of the
				operating system. OSX includes an embedded PDF reader called Preview. </para>
			<para> For exports to excel, XML or other formats, see the chapter <link
					xlink:href="#importExport">Importing and Exporting.</link>
			</para>
			<para>Before you print a report, you will usually need to run a query on the data first.
				For example, if you wish to print the class rolls for all the classes starting this
				week, you will need to do an advanced query for classes starting from today, to the
				last day of the week. For more information on queries, see the chapter Getting
				Started.</para>
			<para>The print dialogue box provides an alphabetized list of all reports available via
				the given window, simply select the relevant report and a summary description is
				provided of the highlighted report. This description will also clarify as to whether
				the report prints in Portrait or Landscape format.</para>
			<para>In the print dialogue, you will be asked if you want to print all, selected or
				highlighted records. A record count will be given for each option. Selecting 'all'
				will print the report for all records in the database. Choosing 'selected' will
				print the results from the query you have run. Choosing highlighted will print the
				report for the one or more records you have selected in the list. </para>
			<section>
				<title>Managing Print Backgrounds </title>
				<para>onCourse printed reports can be set up with a defined background or overlay
					allowing the user to utilise different backgrounds or headers dependent upon the
					particular report. These backgrounds can be set up as a PDF document that is
					then imported into onCourse via the report window. </para>
				<para>Generally, a college will have a standard 'letterhead' style background,
					available in both portrait and landscape modes that can be used as the print
					background to common reports like invoices, enrolment confirmations and class
					rolls.</para>
				<para>In addition, the college may have one or more background reports for their
					Qualification, Statement of Attainment, Transcript and Certificate of Attendance
					reports. These backgrounds will usually contain formal elements such the
					colleges contact details, RTO ID, the business logo, the AQF and/or NRT logos
					and possibly the certificate signatory details &amp; signature. They also may
					contain optional design elements such as borders, background images or
					watermarks.</para>
				<para>By using the background function for activities such as certificate printing
					design, with only the text based contents coming from the onCourse report, a
					college can modify their backgrounds at any time,without access to sophisticated
					software or report writing skills.</para>
				<section>
					<title>Setting Up the Report Print Backgrounds</title>
					<para>The following instructions outline how you can set up your report print
						backgrounds which will be overlayed with the report content:</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Create a new Microsoft Word or iWork Pages document and ensure
								that the page set up is set to Portrait.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Open up the Header for the new document and place the required
								logo and contact details you wish the report to display.</para>
							<tip>
								<para>Ensure that the elements that you place within the header do
									not exceed the dimensions of the report header space. </para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Once you have completed the set up of the page header, save the
								document as a PDF so that it is ready to be imported into onCourse
								as a background. Make sure that you clearly label within the name of
								the PDF whether the document is Portrait or Landscape format.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Reset the original Word or Pages document to display in Landscape
								format, then realign the elements within Header to ensure it fits
								within the dimensions of the Header.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Repeat step 3 making sure that you clearly label within the name
								of the PDF whether the document is Portrait or Landscape
								format</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Certificate Backgrounds</title>
					<para>The standard Qualification and Statement of Attainment reports include a
						second report, the transcript, as the second page.</para>
					<para>If you already have a certificate background you have had professionally
						designed, which you order from the printers, you can choose to embed this
						background in the report. You should request a A4 PDF of your backgrounds
						from your designers first.</para>
					<para>If you do not have a professionally designed background, you can easily
						create your own using a simple word processing tool. Keep in mind the <link
							xlink:href="http://www.asqa.gov.au/qualifications/issuing-qualifications.html"
							> ASQA guidelines for issuing certificates</link> and the appropriate
						use of the formal logos, when designing your backgrounds.</para>
					<para>You will also need a second page PDF background for the transcript
						report.</para>
					<para>If you create and upload a two page PDF, comprised of your Certificate
						design followed by your letterhead or transcript design, for example, these
						pages will be used correctly when printing the combined report from
						onCourse.</para>
					<para>When creating a background for a Qualification or Statement of Attainment
						report, onCourse will apply the first page of your PDF background to the
						first page of your report (the Certificate page), then apply the second page
						of your PDF background to each subsequent page of the Certificate report
						(the Transcript pages). </para>
					<para>If you are printing Certificates in bulk, onCourse will recognise when the
						student record has changed to the next student and therefore apply the first
						page of the PDF background again as this is a new Certificate. </para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Selecting a Background when Running the Report</title>
					<para>Once you have created the print backgrounds for your reports, you can now
						import those PDF backgrounds into onCourse and attach them to the specific
						report. You only need to import each report background once. </para>
					<para>Selecting the relevant background is managed via the print dialogue box of
						onCourse. The following instructions outline how you can apply the relevant
						backgrounds to your reports:</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>The first option within the drop down menu of available
								backgrounds is 'no background'. If you select this option it simply
								means that the header of the report will be blank (no logos or text
								will appear).</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>The drop down menu will also display any other backgrounds that
								you have previously imported into onCourse. As per the following
								example, this is where the naming convention of the backgrounds
								becomes very important, particularly with respect to whether the
								background is in Portrait or Landscape format. If you select a
								Landscape template for a report which is printed in Portrait format,
								the report will not work. </para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
										fileref="images/PrintBackgroundOptions.png"/>
								</imageobject>
								<caption>
									<para>Select the relevant print background from the drop down
										menu</para>
								</caption>
							</mediaobject>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>If you wish to import a new background PDF document, select
								'import from disk' from the drop down menu, this will bring up a
								dialogue box to allow you to select the background you wish to use
								for this report. Note also that the newly imported print background
								will be auto selected as the background for the Report you are
								currently running by default. </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Once you have either selected an existing background or imported a
								new one from disk, you simply run the report, which will generate a
								PDF output of the report with the specified background.</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<tip>
						<para>The chosen report will display the last background used as the default
							when printing that report. But you can simply select an alternate
							background from the drop down menu or import a new background if you so
							chose. </para>
					</tip>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Managing Print Backgrounds</title>
					<para>Once you have uploaded the PDF documents that become the print backgrounds
						for your reports, you can then manage these backgrounds via the Report
						window of onCourse.</para>
					<para>To access these backgrounds go to <guimenuitem> File - Preferences -
							Reports</guimenuitem>, highlight the report you wish to edit the
						background or backgrounds for then select 'Manage print backgrounds' via the
						cogwheel icon of the Report window.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
								fileref="images/ManagePrintBackgroundsViaCogwheel.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Manage backgrounds via Report window</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<para>A new dialogue box will appear, which allows you to either rename a
						background by double clicking on the entry, or to delete a background that
						is no longer being utilised. </para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
								fileref="images/ManagePrintBackgroundsDialogueBox.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Editing Backgrounds</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
					<tip>
						<para>You can only import new backgrounds via the Print dialogue box when
							printing a given report. This process cannot be done via the Report
							window of onCourse.</para>
					</tip>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Managing Backgrounds for Custom Reports</title>
					<para>The ability to apply a print background to your Custom Reports provides
						users with a much greater level of flexibility particularly in reference to
						generating Certificates. </para>
					<para>One example of this is that if your College has more than one entity such
						as a separate Business Training College, by setting up different print
						backgrounds for each of your entities, including logos and branding, you can
						manage the generation of certificates for both entities with ease. Whereas
						previously the images were embedded within the Custom Report itself, these
						images are now part of the print background. </para>
					<para>You can also apply new backgrounds to your Custom Reports without the need
						to contact ish to request changes to your Custom Report, you can simply
						manage this by updating the print background that is used for the relevant
						custom report.</para>
					<para>Further to this, you can update the signatory name for your Certificate
						reports via the AVETMISS tab / General Preferences settings of onCourse.
						Remember that this field will appear as one line on your Certificate report,
						so you would add the name and title of the nominated signatory name in the
						one line. Go to <guimenuitem> File - Preferences - General
							Preferences</guimenuitem>and click on the AVETMISS tab, the 'Full
						certificate signatory name' field you need to edit is under 'Optional' on
						this tab. Whatever content you add to this field, will appear automatically
						within your Certificate Reports, unless your custom report has this
						information hard coded into it.</para>
					<para>If you require a different layout for the signatory fields i.e. two names,
						name and title on separate lines or embedded digital signature, we recommend
						you put all this data in the background and remove the signatory details
						from the onCourse report template.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" 
								fileref="images/EditSignatoryNameViaAVETMISSTab.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Updating signatory name via General Preferences</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</section>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Financial Reports</title>
			<para>Please note some reports are listed more than once as they may apply to multiple
				areas of the colleges operation</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-BudgetDetails">Budget Details</link> Line by line details
				of class per page budgets</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Budgets">Budgets</link> Summary reports of class budgets,
				grouped by subject</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-BudgetSummaryBySubject">Budget Summary by Subject</link>
				Provides a summary analysis at course subject level of actuals against budget</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassInvoiceRecord">Class Invoice Record</link> Report that
				summarises by Class a list of all students, payments made, fees owing and name of
				payer for the given enrolment</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Banking">Banking Report</link>This report shows payments in
				and is designed to take along to the bank when you deposit your cash and cheques. </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Payslip">Payslip Report</link>This report allows you to
				print the payslips for error checking prior to exporting them to your payroll system </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassTutorList">Class Tutor List Report</link> Scheduled
				tutor hours for each class, useful for pay claim verification</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassTutorPaySchedule">Class Tutor Pay Schedule
					Report</link> Provides the detail of the expected payslip lines that will be
				generated for all tutors attached to a class with wages in the budget</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-DebtorsandCreditors">Debtors and Creditors</link> Aged
				debtors and creditors</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-EnrolmentLiability">Enrolment Liability Report</link>Report
				showing the breakdown of the outstanding liability held on each enrolment,
				(enrolment fee component not yet posted to the defined income account). </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Invoice">Invoice Report</link> Invoices supplied to
				debtors</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-CorporatePassList"> CorporatePass List Report</link>List of
				CorporatePasses</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-CorporatePassDetails"> CorporatePass Detailed Report</link>
				Detailed information regarding CorporatePass usage</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-PaymentIn">PaymentIn</link> Line report of all payments
				in</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-TransactionDetail">Transaction Detail</link> Detailed
				report displaying transactions made to and from each general ledger account over a
				specified period of time.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-TransactionSummary">Transaction Summary</link>a more
				general overview of transactions made over a specified period of time. This report
				is not based on cash positions, but invoices created and is used by most book
				keepers to provide their accountant with a record of assets, liabilities and
				income.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Reconcile">Reconcile</link> For reconciliation with banking
				deposits</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Statement">Statement</link> Summary of all debits and
				credits for a contact </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-TrialBalance">Trial Balance</link> The opening balance,
				closing balance and movement of account transactions in your onCourse chart of
				accounts for a specified time period </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Course and class management reports</title>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassBySubject">Class by Subject</link> An overview of all
				the classes, grouped by subject, including enrolment numbers and enrolment
				targets</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-FundingHours">Class Funding</link> This AVETMISS based
				report is useful for keeping track of the hours of funded delivery you have provided
				against each qualification</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Sales">Sales Report</link>This report provides a
				comparative analysis of sales figures from one College site to the next.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-SalesByCourseLocation">Sales By Course Location
					Report</link>List of the number and monetary value of enrolments categorised by
				Course and College Site.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-CancelledClasses">Cancelled Classes Count Report</link>List
				of the number and monetary value of enrolments as they existed in classes before
				they were cancelled</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-DiscountsByClass">Discounts by Class</link>List of all
				discounts for a given Class and their take up value.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Classes">Classes Report</link> A summary list of classes,
				similar to the classes list window, showing dates and enrolment numbers</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassTutorList">Class Tutor List Report</link> A <emphasis
					role="italic">useful</emphasis> report for payroll purposes, this shows, grouped
				by tutor the hours of scheduled delivery they have for each class</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Courses">Courses</link> A printed list of the courses
				window</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-AllClassDetails">All Class Details</link> Detailed report
				of all information for a given class, including enrolment numbers, session details
				and course details and directions.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-StudentSpecialNeeds">Student Special Needs</link> Provides
				a report of any students that require assistance with completing or accessing a
				class or classes</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassBySite">Class By Site</link> Summary of all classes
				against a given site or sites. Report includes summary enrolment information and
				Male Female breakdown.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Rooms">Rooms List</link> List of all rooms and their
				related sites and seating capacity </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-RoomTimetable">Room Timetable Report</link> A report that
				allows users to print the details of all sessions that are scheduled for a
				particular room, for a particular date range</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-SiteDetails">Site Details</link> The details of a
				particular site as it has been set up, including directions, room listings and
				capacity.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-SiteList">Site List</link> A list of all the sites and
				their addresses</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassTutor">Class Tutor List</link> List of all Tutors by
				Class, includes site information and start end times for sessions.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-TutorDetails">Tutor Details</link> The contact details and
				scheduled sessions for a tutor</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Tutors">Tutors Report</link> A list of tutor names and
				addresses</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassSign">Class Sign</link> Report that can be printed out
				and used as a sign / label on door of Training Room.</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Marketing reports</title>
			<para><link linkend="reports-MailingList">Mailing List Report</link> Contact details of
				all people on a mailing list</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-WaitList">Wait List Report</link>List of all current wait
				list entries received. </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-DiscountTotal">Total Discounts</link> Details of all
				discounts given for a range of classes, grouped by discount name and class. </para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Information for students</title>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassDetails">Class Details</link> The information for each
				session of the class is listed on this report</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-CourseDetails">Course Details</link> This report provides
				all the detail of a course, including it's description and scheduled classes</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-EnrolmentConfirmation">Enrolment Confirmation
					Details</link> about course content, time dates and locations for sessions of
				the class a student has enrolled in</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassInformation">Class Information</link> Class
				information for the enrolling student</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Invoice">Invoice Report</link> Invoice showing GST and
				non-GST fee components, plus balance outstanding.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Statement">Statement</link> A list of all transactions made
				by a contact</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-CertificateAttendance">Certificate Attendance</link>
				Certificate to certify that a student has attended a non VET short course</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-StudentTranscript">Student Transcript Report </link> A
				transcript showing all enrolments and outcome results for a student for all classes
				they have enrolled in at your college</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Information for tutors</title>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassRoll">Class Roll</link> Session by session grid
				created for marking student attendance, including tutor sign off on attendance
				sheet. </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-classRollSingle">Class Roll - Single Session</link> A
				standard document that lists all the students in a class, tutors return this roll
				each session or week. Users need to print multiple copies of this roll if they
				require one for each session of a class.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-SimpleClassRoll">Simple Class Roll</link> Session by
				Session grid created for marking student attendance.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-classTimetable">Class Timetable</link> allows the user to
				select multiple classes and print a date-range specified timetable of sessions to
				show the students when and where to turn up to class.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-classTimetableplanning">Class Timetable Planning</link>
				this is an alternate version of the class timetable report which includes the
				session private notes field. when and where to turn up to class.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassContactSheet">Class Contact Sheet</link> Contact
				details for students in a particular class</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-StudentContactList">Student Contact List</link> Contact
				details for all students across a range of class groups</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-studentdetails">Student Details</link> A useful educational
				report showing an overview of all units a student has undertaken at the training
				organisation and their outcomes </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassRollContactNumber">Class Roll Contact Number</link> A report
				that provides a list of all students, their contact phone number, can be printed out
				and used for roll call. </para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-AssessmentOutcomeReport">Assessment Outcome Report </link> Provides
				a printable template for the Tutor to enter assessment outcomes for each unit of
				competency for students in a given class.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-EnrolmentSummary">State Based Enrolment Summary</link> A list of
				contact enrolments by state</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassRollAge">Class Roll - Age</link> A class role with the
				students ages</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassRollUSI">Class Roll - USI</link> A class role with the
				students ages</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>VET/AVETMISS reports</title>
			<para><link linkend="reports-Qualifications">Qualifications</link> A list of the
				training.gov.au qualifications available within onCourse</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-StatementOfAttainmentPageOne">Certificate Statement of
					Attainment</link> Report that generates a Statement of Attainment for partially
				completed qualifications.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-QualificationPageOne">Certificate Qualification</link>
				Report that generates a Qualification Certificate for students that have completed
				all requirements for a given Qualification.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-TrainingPackages">Training Packages</link>A list of all
				Training Packages available within onCourse.</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-TraineeshipTrainingPlan">Traineeship Training Plan</link>
				Provides an outline of the required units of competency within an overall
				Traineeship Training Plan for a given student.</para>
			<para>
				<link linkend="reports-TrainingPlan">Training Plan Report</link> ASQA compliant RTO
				Training and Delivery Plan</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-FundingHours">Class Funding</link> For keeping track of
				delivery hours for different funding groups</para>
			<para><link linkend="reports-ClassHours">Class Hours</link>A summary of the classroom,
				nominal and reportable hours for each class.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="reports-existing">
		<title>Existing reports in onCourse</title>
		<para>onCourse includes a range of printed reports as part of the standard software. These
			examples list the reports available and their purpose. Additional reports can be quoted
			and built on request if you do not have the in-house IT skills to build or modify your
			own reports.</para>
		<section xml:id="reports-BudgetDetails">
			<title>Budget Details</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Budget Details Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain a detailed print out of the budgeted and actual income and expense
				lines, one page per class. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenuitem>Class</guimenuitem> menu, select
					<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and choose <guimenuitem>Budget
					Details</guimenuitem>. You can print all available records, listed records
				(based on a query you have run) or the highlighted records. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/BudgetDetailsByClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Budget Details</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Budgets">
			<title>Budgets </title>
			<subtitle> onCourse Budget Details by Subject </subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain a detailed print out of the budgeted and actual</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenuitem>Class</guimenuitem> Menu, Select
					<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose <guimenuitem>Budgets</guimenuitem>.
				You can print all available records, listed records (based on a query you have run)
				or the highlighted records. You can suppress the class lines, to provide a summary
				for each subject only, or show each class.Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>In the example below, the classes are listed with the actual figures displayed. As
				detail has not been entered for the budget fields, the budget amounts are all listed
				as $0. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/BudgetDetailsBySubject.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Budgets Details By Subject </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-BudgetSummaryBySubject">
			<title>Budget Summary by Subject </title>
			<subtitle> onCourse Budget Summary by Subject </subtitle>
			<para>Use: Enables Colleges to monitor budget against actuals at the summary level,
				includes details by subject on the number of enrolments, income generated, expenses
				and the resulting variances.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenuitem>Class</guimenuitem> window, select the
				specific classes you wish to run the budget analysis for. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then choose <guimenuitem>Budget Summary by
					Subject</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/BudgetSummaryBySubject.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Budget Summary by Subject</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassInvoiceRecord">
			<title>Class Invoice Record </title>
			<subtitle>onCourse summary by Class of all payments and fees owing </subtitle>
			<para>Use: Invaluable as a method of cross referencing incoming payments for a given
				Class. the report lists the names of all enrolling students, Invoice No, fee
				charged, fee paid and any outstanding balances. As well as the name and contact
				number of the payee</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenuitem>Class</guimenuitem> window, select the
				specific classes you wish to print the details for. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then choose <guimenuitem>Class Invoice Record
					Report</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu of reports.Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/ClassInvoiceRecord.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Class Invoice Record</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Banking">
			<title> onCourse Banking Report </title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Banking Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain a report of all cheque, cash and credit card payments processed
				since the last bank, to assign the money to the appropriate general ledger income
				accounts, and to generate a printed report, where necessary to provide to your bank
				with the cash and cheque deposits. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenuitem>Financial</guimenuitem> Menu, select
					<guimenuitem>Deposit Banking</guimenuitem>. In the window that opens, you can
				see a summary of the cheques, cash and credit card payments collected since the last
				processed bank. You can check the option, <guimenuitem>Print Report</guimenuitem>,
				for a hard copy, as displayed below. The report can also be re-printed for only
				payments in or payments out from either of these menu options, for the date range
				you specify. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run
				the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/BankingReport.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Banking Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Payslip">
			<title> Payslip Report </title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Payslip Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This allows you to print the payslips for error checking prior to exporting
				them to your payroll system </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenuitem>Financial</guimenuitem> Menu, select
					<guimenuitem>Tutor Pay</guimenuitem>. In the window that opens, you can see the
				full list of Payslips. Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then choose <guimenuitem>Payslip Report</guimenuitem>
				from the drop down menu of reports.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
						fileref="images/reports/payslips_report.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Payslips Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassTutorList">
			<title>Class Tutor List Report </title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class Tutor List report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain an overview of classes scheduled for each tutor. This report also
				provides the total hours the tutor is scheduled to teach for each class, which can
				be used for payroll purposes. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as a particular date range. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				Report <guimenuitem>Class Tutor List</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/ClassTutorListReport.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Class Tutor List Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassTutorPaySchedule">
			<title>Class Tutor Pay Schedule Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class Tutor Pay Schedule report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This report provides the detail of the expected payslip lines that will be
				generated for all tutors attached to a class with wages in the budget, allowing you
				to confirm that the correct details have been entered at the class level prior to
				generating the tutor pay. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as a particular date range. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				Report <guimenuitem>Class Tutor Pay Schedule</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
						fileref="images/reports/class_tutor_pay_schedule.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Class Tutor Pay Schedule Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-DebtorsandCreditors">
			<title>Debtors and Creditors Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Debtors and Creditors Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain an aged debtors and creditors report for all unbalanced
				invoices</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Invoice</guimenu> window, select
					<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose <guimenuitem>Debtors and Creditors
					Report</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate background for this
				report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/DebtorsAndCreditors.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> A Debtors And Creditors Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-EnrolmentLiability">
			<title>Class Prepaid Fees Liability Report</title>
			<subtitle>Report showing the breakdown of the outstanding liability held on each
				invoice linked to the class, for both invoices generated on enrolment and manually linked invoices</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This Report identifies how much of the invoice value is currently held in the Pre Paid
				Fees Liability Account and is yet to be transferred to the defined Income Account.
				This report is grouped by Class and sorted by Date</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Classes</guimenu>window, highlight the classes you wish
				to run the report against. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenu>Print</guimenu>and
				select the Class Prepaid Fees Liability report from the drop down list. Remember to
				select the appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>		
<mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
		<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/reports/PrepaidFeesLiability.png" format="png"/>
	</imageobject>
	<caption>
		<para>Excerpt of Enrolment Liability Report</para>
	</caption>
</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Invoice">
			<title>Invoice Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Invoice Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To supply hard copy Tax Invoices to students and other debtors.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Invoice</guimenu> window, find the invoices you
				wish to include in the report, such as a particular date range. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				Report <guimenuitem>Invoice</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: When a student is enrolled, and provides an email address, a tax
				invoice will be emailed to the payer, along with an <uri>enrolment
					confirmation</uri>, sent to the student enrolled. Often this will be the same
				person. </para>
			<para>Other invoices, not relating to enrolments, can be manually created and printed
				via the invoices window. </para>
			<para>As seen below if you have enrolled into a class using a payment plan the Tax invoice will
				show you the next payment due dates and the amounts payable.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
						fileref="images/reports/Invoice.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> A Tax Invoice Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-CorporatePassList">
			<title>Corporate Pass List Report</title>
			<subtitle>List of Corporate Passes</subtitle>
			<para>Use: List of all current CorporatePass records.This report prints in Portrait
				format.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>CorporatePass</guimenu> window, find the
				Corporate Pass records you wish to include in the report. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and choose
				report <guimenuitem>Corporate Pass List </guimenuitem>from the list of available
				reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run the
				report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/CorporatePassList.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Corporate Pass List Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-CorporatePassDetails">
			<title>Corporate Pass Detailed Report</title>
			<subtitle>Detailed information on Corporate Pass Usage</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Provides detailed breakdown of usage of Corporate Pass records, including
				invoices generated against each Corporate Pass.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Corporate Pass</guimenu> window, find the
				Corporate Pass records you wish to include in the report. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and choose
				report <guimenuitem>Corporate Pass </guimenuitem>from the list of available reports.
				Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run the
				report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/CorporatePass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Corporate Pass Detailed Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-PaymentIn">
			<title>Payment-in Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse PaymentIn Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain an overview of payments processed, declined or rejected, processed
				through either your office or over the website.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Payment In</guimenu> window, find the payments
				you wish to include in the report, such as a particular date range. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				Report <guimenuitem>Payment In</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: All payments made, or attempted, as part of the enrolment process
				will created a Payment In record. You can also manually create payments in from this
				window, against any outstanding invoice.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/PaymentIn.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> A 'Payment In' Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TransactionDetail">
			<title>Transaction Detail</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Transaction Detail</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To provide a detailed report displaying transactions made to and from each
				general ledger account over a specified period of time.</para>
			<para>Report Location: To access this report you must first be in the "Accounts" section
				of onCourse, you can access this through a number of ways. From the splash screen or
				from the top menu Financial > Accounts. Once in "Accounts" click on "Account",
				there's a subtle difference. Once in "Account" (under "Accounts") you may select
				(from the top menu) File > Print then select Transaction Detail from the list of
				available reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report
				then run the report. You can also set the date far back so that you may include more
				records that have occurred over time.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/TransactionDetail.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> A Transaction Detail Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TransactionSummary">
			<title>Transaction Summary</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Transaction Summary</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To provide a more general overview of transactions made over a specified period of
				time. The date selector field for the print engine is a date time field so you can
				clearly see the start and end of the data you wish to collect. By default, the start
				and end date will be 12am. To print all data for the range 1/1/2014 - 31/12/2014
				enter the date range 1/1/2014 12.00am to 1/2/2014 12.00am. This report will provide
				you with for example; Student Enrolments overall rather than each individual
				student</para>
			<para>Report Location: To access this report you must first be in the "Accounts" tab of
				onCourse, you can access this through a number of ways. You can print this report in
				both the Transaction the Account windows which can be access from the splash screen,
				or from the top menu by Financial > Transactions or Financial > Accounts. Once in
				either "Transaction" or "Account" (under "Accounts") you may select (from the top
				menu) File > Print then select Transaction Summary from the list of available
				reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run the
				report. Be sure to adjust the date and time to suit your requirements. Remembering
				you can highlight multiple records in these windows. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/TransactionSummary.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> A Transaction Summary Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Reconcile">
			<title>Reconciliation Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Reconciliation Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To reconcile payments in and out with banking deposits.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Financial</guimenu> menu, Select
					<guimenuitem>Reconcile Statement</guimenuitem>. Check the payments you wish to
				reconcile, and select <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem>. A summary of the reconciled
				and unreconciled payments are displayed in this window. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ReconciliationReport.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Reconciliation Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Statement">
			<title>Statement Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Statement report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To print a list of all transactions (both debits and credits) for a
				particular contact</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Contact</guimenu> menu, Select
					<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				<guimenuitem>Statement</guimenuitem>. You can select to print the entire transaction
				history, or define a date range. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/Statement.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> A Statement Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-CertificateAttendance">
			<title>Certificate Attendance</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Certificate Attendance Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Report is generated at the conclusion of any non VET short courses to verify
				that the student attended all of the required number of classes.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Enrolment</guimenu> window, select the specific
				students you wish to print the certificates for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and then choose <guimenuitem>Certificate Attendance
					Report</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/Certificate-Attendance.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Certificate Attendance </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-StudentTranscript">
			<title>Student Academic Transcript Report</title>
			<para>Use: To provide students with the information retained in onCourse regarding each
				of their enrolments and current status of their outcomes</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Student</guimenu> window, select the specific
				students you wish to print the transcripts for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and then choose <guimenuitem>Student
					Transcript</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select
				the appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/AcademicTranscript.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Student Academic Transcript </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassBySubject">
			<title>Class by Subject Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class by Subject Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain an overview of all classes status within a given time period, such
				as a term. Classes are grouped by their Category/Sub Category tag. Useful for
				holistic planning processes and work flow activities such as confirming course go
				ahead or managing cancellations. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as a particular date range. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				report <guimenuitem>Class by Subject</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: M/F column: If a student's gender is not set within their details,
				they will not counted for either M or F; thus M + F does not necesarily equal to the
				total number of enrolments. Target column: This is the number of enrolments to reach
				the target for this class, ie: -3 means 3 more enrolments are required to meet the
				target, 3 would means that there are 3 enrolments more than the target.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassBySubject.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> A Class by Subject Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-FundingHours">
			<title>Funding Hours Report</title>
			<subtitle>Keeping Track of Funded Delivery</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To keep track of delivery of funded program Student Contact Hours over a
				particular time period. This report shows a summary of each qualification and the
				hours delivered against each of the national funding types.</para>
			<para>Report Location:From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as the current years English classes. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and choose
				report <guimenuitem>Class Funding</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: This report may be of particular interest to colleges who deliver
				programs with a range of funding sources and who are required to report the delivery
				of these hours. By regularly running this report, the year to date delivery can be
				checked and be used to assist with program planning. More information about how
				student contact hours are calculated is available <uri>here</uri></para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassFunding.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Funding Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassHours">
			<title>Class Hours Report</title>
			<subtitle>Tracking of class hours</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A summary of the classroom, nominal and reportable hours for each class, for
				use in the administration of VET / AVETMISS courses.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the classes you
				wish to track hours for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Class Hours</guimenu> from the
				drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this
				report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassHours.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Class Hours Report</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Sales">
			<title>Sales Report</title>
			<subtitle>Keeping track of Sales Figures</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This report provides a comparative analysis of sales figures (shown as number
				of enrolments and monetary value) from one College site to the next.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Enrolment</guimenu> window, select the specific
				enrolments and classes you wish to run the analysis for. Select
					<guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Sales Report</guimenu> from the
				drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this
				report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/SalesReport.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Sales Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-SalesByCourseLocation">
			<title>Sales by Course Location</title>
			<subtitle>Keeping track of Sales Figures</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Provides a summary list of the number of enrolments and monetary value of
				sales for each site, with further detail regarding number of enrolments and monetary
				value listed by Course.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Enrolment</guimenu> window, select the specific
				enrolments and classes you wish to run the analysis for. Select
					<guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Sales by Course Location
					Report</guimenu> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/SalesByCourseLocation.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Sales by Course Location Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-CancelledClasses">
			<title>Cancelled Classes Count Report</title>
			<subtitle>Analyse the enrolments and income lost from cancelled programs</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Provides a summary list of the number of enrolments and monetary value of
				those enrolments for classes which have been cancelled and the students transferred,
				refunded or credited. This report can be useful for deciding if that type of class
				should be offered in the future, based on it's level of previous student enrolment. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Classes</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to run the analysis for. This report only prints data from classes
				which have a cancelled status. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Cancelled Classes Count</guimenu>
				from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background
				for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/CancelledClassesCount.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Cancelled Classes Count Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-DiscountsByClass">
			<title>Discounts by Class</title>
			<subtitle>List of all Discounts for a given Class</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Report generates a list of all discounts that apply to a given Class. As well
				as a summary of the number of enrolments and the discounts taken up.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Classes</guimenu>window, hilight the specific
				Classes you wish to run the report for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then choose the <guimenu>Discounts By
				Class</guimenu>from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/DiscountsByClass.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Discounts by Class Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Classes">
			<title>Classes Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Classes Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To obtain an overview of all classes status within a given time period, such
				as a term. Useful for holistic planning processes and work flow activities such as
				confirming course go ahead or managing cancellations. Classes are reported in the
				list order you have sorted the window data e.g. class name alphabetical order, start
				date order or code order.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the courses you
				wish to include in the report, such as a particular date range. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and choose
				report <guimenuitem>Classes</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: The information available in this report is also available grouped
				by subjects in the <uri>Classes by Subject Report</uri>.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/Classes.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Classes Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Courses">
			<title>Courses Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Courses Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To create a print out of the list of courses</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Course</guimenu> window, find the courses you
				wish to include in the report, such as all courses tagged as 'business'. Select
					<guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and choose
				report <guimenuitem>Courses</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/Courses.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Courses Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-AllClassDetails">
			<title>All Class Details</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class Details Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Detailed report of all information for a given class, including delivery
				mode, minimum and maximum places, enrolment numbers, fees and discounts, session
				details, course description, tutor information and directions for getting to the
				campus.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and then choose <guimenuitem>All Class
					Details</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/AllClassDetails.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> All Class Details </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-StudentSpecialNeeds">
			<title>Student Special Needs</title>
			<subtitle>Reference for students requiring assistance. </subtitle>
			<para>Use: Used as a reference for any special needs such as wheelchair access, dietary
				requirements and provides an indicator as to whether the student and or tutor has
				been contacted to confirm or follow up this information.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Student Special Needs
					Report</guimenu> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report. </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/StudentSpecialNeeds.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Student Special Needs </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassBySite">
			<title>Class By Site</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class information site by site</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This report provides a list of all current and future classes assigned to a
				given site. Information includes, course and class name and code, start and end
				date, fee charged, enrolments (against target) and statistics on Male Female
				breakdown.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and then choose <guimenuitem>Class By
					Site</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassBySite.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class By Site Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Rooms">
			<title>Rooms List</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Room information by site. </subtitle>
			<para>Use: List of all rooms and their related sites and seating capacity.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Rooms</guimenu> window, select the specific
				rooms you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Rooms List</guimenu> from the drop
				down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report
				then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/RoomsList.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Rooms List </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-RoomTimetable">
			<title>Room Timetable Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Room Timetable Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: The purpose of the report is to allow users to print the details of all
				sessions that are scheduled for a particular room, for a particular date range. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the "room" window, highlight the room in question and go to
				File > Print choose "Room timetable" from the drop down menu in the top right hand
				side. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run the
				report. In the example below, there are some classes with and without tutors, to
				give you an idea of how it will come out for you.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/RoomTimetableReport.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Room Timetable Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassTutor">
			<title>Class Tutor List</title>
			<subtitle>on Course Tutor List by Class</subtitle>
			<para>Use: List of all Tutors by Class, including site information and start end times
				for sessions.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				details you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Class Tutor List Report</guimenu>
				from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background
				for this report then run the report. </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassTutorListReport.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Tutor List Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-SiteList">
			<title>Site List</title>
			<subtitle>List of onCourse sites</subtitle>
			<para>Use: List of all sites and their addresses</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Site</guimenu> window, select the specific
				records you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Site List</guimenu> from the drop
				down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report
				then run the report. </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/SiteList.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Site List Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-SiteDetails">
			<title>Site Details</title>
			<subtitle>Details of onCourse sites</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Detail of all each site, venue information, rooms and each room capacity for
				the site</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Site</guimenu> window, select the specific
				records you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Site Details</guimenu> from the
				drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this
				report then run the report. </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/SiteDetails.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Site Details Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TutorDetails">
			<title>Tutor Details Report</title>
			<subtitle>on Course Tutor Details Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: The contact details and scheduled sessions for a Tutor</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Tutor</guimenu> window select the Tutor(s) you
				wish to view the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose the Report entitled <guimenu>Tutor
					Details</guimenu>. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report
				then run the report. </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TutorDetails.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Tutor Details Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Tutors">
			<title>Tutors List Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Tutors List Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A list of tutor names and addresses</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Tutor</guimenu> window select the Tutors you
				wish to view the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose the Report entitled
					<guimenu>Tutors</guimenu>. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TutorsList.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Tutors </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-EnrolmentSummary">
			<title>State Based Enrolment Summary</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse State Based Enrolment Summary Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A list of contact enrolments by state</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window select the specified
				classes you wish to print details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>State Based Enrolment Summary
					Report </guimenu>from the drop down menu. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
							fileref="images/reports/Enrolment_summary_by_State.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> State Based Enrolment Summary </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassRollAge">
			<title>Class Roll - Age</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class Role - Age Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A class roll with the students ages</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window select the specified classes you
				wish to print details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Class Roll - Age </guimenu>from the drop down menu. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
							fileref="images/reports/class_roll_age.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Roll by Age </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassRollUSI">
			<title>Class Roll - USI</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class Roll - USI Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A class roll with the students USI status and the course qualification and unit of competency information</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window select the specified classes you
				wish to print details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Class Roll - USI </guimenu>from the drop down menu. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="50%" contentdepth="50%"
							fileref="images/reports/class_roll_USI.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Roll - USI </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassSign">
			<title>Class Sign</title>
			<subtitle>Label for Training Room for given class</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Report that can be printed off and used as a sign or label on door of
				Training Room</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window select the specified
				classes you wish to print details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Class Sign Report </guimenu>from
				the drop down menu. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report
				then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassSignForDoor.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Sign </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-MailingList">
			<title>Mailing List Export</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Mailing List Export Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Contact details (first name, last name, email) of all people on a given
				mailing list. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> or <guimenu>Contact</guimenu>
				window, select the contacts you wish to run the report against. Select
					<guimenu>File</guimenu>, <guimenu>Print</guimenu>and choose the <guimenu>Mailing
					List Export</guimenu>Report. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report.</para>
			<para> </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/MailingListExport.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Mailing List Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-WaitList">
			<title>Wait List Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Wait List Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: List of all current wait list entries, including name of course, name of
				student, client, and site where course is held. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Wait List</guimenu> window, select the specific
				entries you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Wait List Report</guimenu>from
				the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report. </para>
			<para> </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/WaitingList.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Wait List Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-DiscountTotal">
			<title>Total Discounts</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse report for uptake of discounts</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To confirm uptake and cost of discounts across a selection of classes</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Classes</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to include in the report. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Total Discounts</guimenu>from
				the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report. </para>
			<para> </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TotalDiscounts.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Total Discount Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassDetails">
			<title>Class Details Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Class Details Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use:To obtain full list of one or more classes scheduled sessions. This is a list
				view of the timetabled sessions. Useful information to provide to venue
				coordinators, tutors and students. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as all current classes at a particular venue.
				Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				Report <guimenuitem>Class Details</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassDetails.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Details Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-CourseDetails">
			<title>Course Details Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Course Details Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To create a print out of the full course information including scheduled
				classes. Can be used to create print copies of all the web information to mail to
				students without web access. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Course</guimenu> window, find the course(s) you
				wish to include in the report, such as all courses tagged as 'sport and fitness'.
				Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Choose
				Report <guimenuitem>Course Details</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/CourseDetails.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Course Details Report</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-EnrolmentConfirmation">
			<title>Enrolment Confirmation Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Enrolment Confirmation report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To provide students with details of their class once they have
				enrolled.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Enrolment</guimenu> window, select the
				enrolments you wish to print enrolment confirmations for, Choose
					<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and Select the Report <guimenuitem>Enrolment
					Confirmation</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: During the enrolment process, if the student provides an email
				address, an email confirmation of enrolment can be selected. It is not necessary to
				provide hard copy enrolment confirmations for these students.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/EnrolmentConfirmation.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Enrolment Confirmation Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassInformation">
			<title> Class Information Report</title>
			<subtitle>Class Information for enrolling students</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Class information that can be provided for the enrolling student including
				course details, information about the Tutor, directions on where to go and the
				individual session details.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Class Information</guimenu> from
				the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for
				this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/ClassInformation.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Class Information Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassRoll">
			<title>Class Roll</title>
			<subtitle>Attendance record keeping</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To create a list of students enrolled and columns for each of the scheduled
				sessions, used to mark attendance. The report will automatically re-size to fit the
				number of students and session conditions. Hard copy rolls are often distributed to
				tutors before classes commence, or PDF copies emailed to tutors or
				coordinators.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as all current class taught by a particular
				tutor. Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and
				Choose Report <guimenuitem>Class Roll</guimenuitem>. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: Given that tutors may pass rolls around the room for students to
				initial their attendance, to comply with privacy legislation, there are no student
				contact details on the class roll. If the tutor requires the student's contact
				details, a <uri>student contact list</uri> can be printed. The roll is marked by
				session and will show "Y" if attended; partial attendance, "N" for absent; absent
				without reason and no value for unmarked attendance.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="60%" contentdepth="60%"
							fileref="images/reports/class_roll.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Roll Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-classRollSingle">
			<title>Class Roll - Single Session</title>
			<subtitle>One session class roll</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To be used for classes where the tutors need to return a student-signed copy
				of the class roll back to the college administration office after each week or
				session. Users need to print multiple copies of this roll if they require one for
				each session of a class.</para>
			<para>Report location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window and highlight the
				records you wish to print a Class Roll for. Go to
					<guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then select <guimenu>Class
					Roll Single Session</guimenu>from the drop down list of available reports.
				Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run the
				report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/ClassRollSingle.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Class Roll - Single Session Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-SimpleClassRoll">
			<title>Simple Class Roll</title>
			<subtitle>Marking sheet for student attendance</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Session by session grid for marking student attendance</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu>window, select the Class you
				wish to generate an attendance sheet for. Go to
					<guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then select <guimenu>Simple
					Class Roll</guimenu>from the drop down menu of available reports. Remember to
				select the appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/SimpleClassRoll.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of the Simplified Class Roll Report </para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-classTimetable">
			<title>Class Timetable Report</title>
			<subtitle>A timetable with a date range</subtitle>
			<para>Use: The purpose of this report is to allow the user to select multiple classes
				(which may contain the same students e.g. those doing a Diploma may undertake 4
				classes simultaneously) and print a date-range specified timetable of sessions to
				show the students when and where to turn up to class. Useful for both students
				attending classes or could also be printed for all classes for a tutor who teaches
				multiple classes. </para>
			<para>Report location: To print this report go to the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window
				and highlight the class(es) you wish to run the report against. Go to
					<guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then select <guimenu>Class
					Timetable</guimenu> from the drop down list of available reports. Remember to
				specifi the date range and select the appropriate background for this report then
				run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/class_timetable_report_dates.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Options for the Class Timetable Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/ClassTimetableReport.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Class Timetable Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-classTimetableplanning">
			<title>Class Timetable Planning Report</title>
			<subtitle>A timetable with a date range</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This is an alternate version of the class timetable report which includes the
				session private notes field in the last column. </para>
			<para>Report location: To print this report go to the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window
				and highlight the class(es) you wish to run the report against. Go to
					<guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then select <guimenu>Class
					Timetable Report - Planning</guimenu> from the drop down list of available
				reports. Remember to specifi the date range and select the appropriate background
				for this report then run the report.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/reports/class_timetable_report_planning_dates.png"
						format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Options for the Class Timetable Report - Planning</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="70%" contentdepth="70%"
						fileref="images/reports/class_timetable_planning_report.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para> Class Timetable Planning Report</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassContactSheet">
			<title>Class Contact Sheet</title>
			<subtitle>Student Contact Details</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To create a list of students enrolled and the phone numbers and email
				addresses for those students. Hard copy lists can be distributed to tutors before
				classes commence if you wish them to have this information. Tutors can also access
				this information via their web portal if you organisation has enabled it.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the "Class" window, find the classes you wish to include in
				the report, such as all current class taught by a particular tutor. Select File,
				Print and Choose Report"'Class Contact List". Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: Given that tutors may pass rolls around the room for students to
				initial their attendance, to comply with privacy legislation, there are no student
				contact details on the class roll. If the tutor requires the student's contact
				details, a <uri>student contact list</uri> can be printed.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassContactSheet.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Class Contact List Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-StudentContactList">
			<title>Student Contact List</title>
			<subtitle>Name, Address, Phone and email</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To export the contact details provided for students enrolled in a
				class.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, find the classes you
				wish to include in the report, such as all current class taught by a particular
				tutor. Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and
				Choose Report <guimenuitem>Student Contact List</guimenuitem>. Remember to select
				the appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: This report may be used to accompany the Class Roll</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/StudentContactList.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Student Contact List Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-studentdetails">
			<title>Student Details</title>
			<subtitle>Overview of all units undertaken by a given student</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A useful educational report showing an overview of all units a student has
				undertaken at the training organisation and their outcomes.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the classes and
				students you wish to include in the report. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose <guimenu>Student Details</guimenu> from the drop
				down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report
				then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/StudentDetails.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Student Details Report</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-ClassRollContactNumber">
			<title>Class Roll Contact Number</title>
			<subtitle>Useful information for tutors</subtitle>
			<para>Use: Report that provides a list of all students, their contact phone number, can
				be printed out and used for a roll call. Can also be used to contact students who
				are not in attendance at their enrolled session or class.</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to print the details for. Select <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>Print</guimenuitem> and and then choose <guimenuitem>Class Roll Contact
					Number</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/ClassRollContactNo.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Student Details Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-AssessmentOutcomeReport">
			<title>Assessment Outcome Report</title>
			<subtitle>Assessment Outcome Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: For use by the College Tutor to mark the assessment outcomes for each student
				studying a VET class. As well as enabling the Tutor to sign and date the entries
				prior to sending back to College Administrators for entering onto onCourse. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu> window, select the specific
				classes you wish to print the required assessment outcomes for. Select
					<guimenu>File</guimenu>, <guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose the
					<guimenu>Assessment Outcomes</guimenu> Report from the drop down menu. Remember
				to select the appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/AssessmentOutcome.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Assessment Outcome Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-Qualifications">
			<title>Qualifications Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Qualifications Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A list of the all the data downloaded from NTIS which you can use to start
				building courses. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Qualifications</guimenu> window, select the
				qualifications you wish to run the report against. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose the <guimenu>Qualifications</guimenu>
				Report. Remember to select the appropriate background for this report then run the
				report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/Qualifications.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Qualifications Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-StatementOfAttainmentPageOne">
			<title>Certificate - Statement of Attainment</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Statement of Attainment Certificate</subtitle>
			<para>Use: onCourse includes AQF recommended templates for full Qualification
				Certificates, Statements of Attainment and transcripts. Certificates can only be
				generated from units that are recorded as part of onCourse enrolments. If you wish
				to include Credit Transfer units, you will need to add these outcomes to the
				students record before you create the certificate. For detailed information
				regarding VET Certificates, refer to the RTO Guide Chapter of the User Manual. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Certificate</guimenu> window, select the
				student(s) you wish to run certificates for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose the <guimenu>Certificate</guimenu> from the
				drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this
				report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: The resulting report (Statement of Attainment or Qualification) is
				dependent on how you have set up the Certificate record.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/StatementOfAttainment.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Statement of Attainment Page One</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/StatementOfAttainmentPageTwo.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Second Page of Statement Showing Academic Transcript</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-QualificationPageOne">
			<title>Certificate - Qualification</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Qualification Certificate</subtitle>
			<para>Use: onCourse includes AQF recommended templates for full Qualification
				Certificates, Statements of Attainment and transcripts. Certificates can only be
				generated from units that are recorded as part of onCourse enrolments. If you wish
				to include Credit Transfer units, you will need to add these outcomes to the
				students record before you create the certificate. For detailed information
				regarding VET Certificates, refer to the RTO Guide Chapter of the User Manual. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Certificate</guimenu> window, select the
				student(s) you wish to run certificates for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>,
					<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and choose the <guimenu>Certificate</guimenu> from the
				drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the appropriate background for this
				report then run the report.</para>
			<para>Report Notes: The resulting report (Statement of Attainment or Qualification) is
				dependent on how you have set up the Certificate record.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/CertificateQualificationPageOne.png"
							format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Qualification Certificate Page One</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/CertificateQualificationPageTwo.png"
							format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Qualification Certificate Page Two Showing Academic Transcript</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TrainingPackages">
			<title>Training Packages Report</title>
			<subtitle>onCourse Training Packages Report</subtitle>
			<para>Use: A list of all Training Packages available within onCourse. </para>
			<para>Report Location: This report is accessible via the <guimenu>Courses</guimenu>
				menu, <guimenu>Training Packages</guimenu>. Remember to select the appropriate
				background for this report then run the report. </para>
			<para> </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TrainingPackages.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para> Training Packages Report </para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TraineeshipTrainingPlan">
			<title>Traineeship Training Plan</title>
			<subtitle>Outline of requirements for Trainee</subtitle>
			<para>Use: This report provides summary information on the required units of competency
				that need to be completed for a given student. As well as provision of signatures
				and sign off on the Training Plan by the student's employer, the trainee themselves
				and the Registered Training Provider (RTO)</para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Enrolment</guimenu> window, select the specific
				students you wish to run the training plan for. Select <guimenu>File</guimenu>
				<guimenu>Print</guimenu> and then choose <guimenu>Traineeship Training
					Plan</guimenu> from the drop down menu of reports. Remember to select the
				appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TraineeshipTrainingPlan.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Traineeship Training Plan Page One</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/Traineeship Training PlanPageTwo.png"
							format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Traineeship Training Plan Page Two</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TrainingPlan">
			<title>Training Plan Report</title>
			<subtitle>ASQA compliant RTO Training and Delivery Plan</subtitle>
			<para>Use: ASQA compliant report that provides a detailed outline of the units of
				competency for the given Course/Class, as well as the start and end date for each
				unit. The report also includes a Delivery Plan which outlines as to when each Unit
				of Competency are taught within the overall Class schedule </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Class</guimenu>window, select the Classes you
				wish to generate <guimenu>Training Plans</guimenu>for. Go to
					<guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenu>Print</guimenu>and then select <guimenu>Training
					Plan</guimenu>from the drop down list of available reports. Remember to select
				the appropriate background for this report then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TrainingPlanPageOne.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Page One of Training Plan Report - Outline of Units of
							Competency</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TrainingPlanPageTwo.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Page Two of Training Plan Report - Outline of Delivery Plan</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section xml:id="reports-TrialBalance">
			<title>Trial Balance Report</title>
			<subtitle>Transaction management report for time periods</subtitle>
			<para>Use: To report on the opening, closing and movement of the onCourse chart of
				accounts during the time frame you define. It shows a summary of the credits and
				debits in each account, which will indicate if there is a error in the ledger should
				the accounts not balance. Note that onCourse may not include all your business
				accounts, as you may have selected to set up only some of your accounts from the
				range available in your primary accounting system. </para>
			<para>Report Location: From the <guimenu>Financial</guimenu>menu, select the option
					<guimenu>Summary Extract</guimenu>. Then select <guimenu>Trial
				Balance</guimenu>, and enter the date range you wish to report on. Select the
				appropriate landscape background for this report, then run the report.</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/reports/TrialBalance.png" format="png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Sample Trial Balance Report</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
