<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="tagging">
	<title>Tags and Tag Groups</title>
	<section xml:id="tagging-usingTags">
		<title>Tags in onCourse</title>
		<para>Tagging in onCourse is a powerful tool that allows you to add additional hierarchical
			information to records in a way that can be easily used for searching and grouping
			records. When specifically related to Course records, tags are flexible ways for you to
			categorise your data and organise the navigation of your website. </para>
		<para>Tag groups applied to other record types can be used for internal navigation and
			grouping, but will not affect the website.</para>
		<para>Tags can be created and edited by navigating to "File" -> "Preferences" -> "Tags". This will
			bring up a list of Tag groups. By default, onCourse will have a special tag group called
			Subjects that exists in your new database, whose name can not be changed.</para>
		<section><title>The Subjects tag group</title><para>The main tag group, used to drive your website
				and in the export of courses and classes for print production and many standard
				reports, is the "Subjects" tag group. You can create the categories that are
				appropriate for your organisation, and any sub categories that are needed.
				</para><para>Tag data is hierarchical so for example, under the category 'Computers'
				I might find tags with names like 'Microsoft Office', 'Adobe Creative Suite',
				'Tablets &amp; Smart phones'. There are no limit to the number of levels of
				hierarchy you can create, but from a user and navigational perspective, generally
				three levels are more than sufficient to represent the range of data you are
				tagging.</para><para>Any course tagged with a sub tag like 'Microsoft office' would
				also be visible if I clicked on the parent tag 'Computers'.</para><para>As a general
				rule of thumb, a website visible tag should apply to a minimum 3 to 5 course
				records, and a maximum of 10 to 15 to give the website visitor a useful and workable
				group of courses to browse.</para><para>For each tag group, you can decide if applying a tag from the group is mandatory or optional.
				A mandatory tag may make sense if you want to ensure your staff always tag every
				course in your database with a website navigation tag. You can also choose whether
				the tag can be applied an unlimited number of times, or only once.</para><para> You can also decide if records can have more
				than one tag from the tag group. Giving courses multiple subject tags mean they can
				be listed in multiple places on your website. For example, an MYOB course could be
				tagged with both 'Accounting' and 'Computers'.</para><para>You can add any number of
				tags by clicking on the "+" icon. To add a subcategory tag, first click on a tag to
				select it and then click once again on the "+" icon.</para><para>By default, tags
				will be sorted by alphabetical order. The tag edit view also allows you to apply
				your own sort order to the tags. Highlight a tag in the list then drag and drop a
				given tag item within the group to the place in the hierarchy you wish it to go.
				</para><para>This tag display order will also be mimicked on your onCourse website
				for tags under the "Subjects" tag group</para><mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/adjustment_of_tag_weighting.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Adjusting the tag weighting via tag group edit view</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section>
				<title>Understanding tag hierarchies and relationships</title>
			<para>When setting up your subject tags, it is advisable to only apply
				these subject tags to Courses and not to classes or other types of records. The
				reason for this relates back to the hierarchical nature of the database the
				information that is connected back to a course.</para><para>For example, a Course
				within the database will have classes, and within a class tutor(s) will be assigned,
				room(s) allocated and students enrolled. From a filtering perspective, by applying a
				subject tag to a Course, when you select the subject tag filter within any window,
				e.g. contact, the related information such as student enrolled in a class from a
				course with the tag, or tutor teaching a class from the course with the tag, will be
				displayed.</para><para>If you apply the tag directly to contact records as well as Courses, the meaning of the filter
				will change to also include the meaning above "AND show me all the contacts tagged
				with" which can lead to a returned results list that doesn't make much sense to the
				user. </para>
			<para>In the following image you can see
			in the class window. The information has been filtered by the "Business" subject tag.
			Even though the classes listed are not tagged with the "Business" subject tag, but the
			classes all relate to a course that has the '"Business" subject tag, they will display automatically.</para>
				<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/filtering_class_by_course_subject_tag.png" format="png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Filtering Classes by a Course subject tag</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
	</section>
	</section>
		<section>
			<title>Tags on your onCourse website</title>
			<para>Course tags, beginning with the Subject tag group, define your website user
				navigation experience. Any new tags you create, or changes you make to any existing
				tags will update automatically on the website. By default, all tags within a tag
				group are set as 'show on website' by default. If you uncheck this option, the tag
				will no longer show on the web, but will still be visible inside the onCourse
				application for your own internal filtering. This can be a better option than
				deleting a tag and all it's relationships to historical records, if the tag is not
				currently in use for active courses.</para>
			<para>If you have two onCourse websites for two arms of your business, each website may
				be driven by it's own tag group. For example, a site for open enrolments might be
				driven by the subjects tag group, where the corporate site might be driven by a
				different tag group called 'corporate'. If this is the case, every course that you
				want to show on each website, must be tagged by a tag from the defined website tag
				group, even if that tag is not currently shown on the website. In this multi site
				situation, a course tagged with a non-visible tag will still be accessible via the
				course URL if you wish, while not being accessible via the navigation structure.
				Without a tag from the defined website group, the URL will return 404 not
				found.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Tagging and the website URL</title>
			<para>The URL for the subject tag group is /courses/subjects. This URL will contain any
				information that has been added in the 'Detail' field for the Subjects root tag. </para>
			<para>If you set up a first level tag within the subjects tag group which is entitled "Arts", the
				URL for that tag on your website would display as /courses/arts.</para>
			<para>You can also display second and third level tag hierarchy within the URL, here is an
				example of a second level tag entitled "Photography" under the Arts tag:
				courses/arts/photography.</para>
			<para>Whilst the default tag structure for website URLs are set to recognise tags under the
				Subjects tag group, you can also show other tag groups for Courses on the web, as
				long as you define the tag group as being <guilabel>web visible</guilabel> by
				clicking the Visibility field, then selecting 'Show on website'. An example of
				utilising a different tag group within a URL would be as follows:
				/courses/demographic/return-to-work for a tag group called 'Demographic'.</para>
			<note>
				<para>Within the tag group edit view window, you can change the URL path of the tag name. To
					change the default URL path, simply click on the padlock next to the field
					<guilabel>URL path</guilabel> then edit what you want the URL path to be. So
					in the example below the URL is being changed from /courses/Creative+Arts to
					/courses/Arts.</para>
			</note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/abbreviated_tag_name.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Example of the URL path which can be set within the tag preferences of onCourse</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		<section><title>Adding tag web descriptions</title><para>Tags can contain rich text descriptions,
				including images and video or other html content, which will display on your website
				at the top of the course list results for that tag.</para>
			<para>In order to display the
				web description and any images you may attach, you need to do the following:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Flag the tag as <guilabel>web visible</guilabel>within the tag set
						up.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Using rich text, enter the information, description of the tag into the
							<guilabel>detail</guilabel>field for that tag.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can also add images to the tag web description by uploading the image
						to onCourse via the <guilabel>Resources > Attachments</guilabel>menu. </para>
					<para>For more information about rich text and adding images, refer to the <link
							xlink:href="http://www.ish.com.au/s/onCourse/doc/web/richText.html">rich
							text</link> chapter of the User Handbook.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/tag_description_on_web.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>An example tag description showing text and an image</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
			<section>
				<title>Using multiple tag groups for website navigation - faceted search</title>
				<para>The special Subjects tag group is just the starting point for website navigation using
				tags, and can be thought as the equivalent of the dewy decimal system of course
				grouping. However, you may wish to build a website where there are multiple ways a
				potential student can browse through your course offerings if they don't know 'what'
				they want.</para>
			<para>Some examples of other types of course tags in use by onCourse customers include
				'who' (or demographic) type tags, 'where' (location, term/holiday program) or 'how'
				(delivery mode, duration or level).</para>
			<para>It is important to consider at this point, before you decide to create multiple
				tags groups to record all this additional data, if the information you want to
				navigate by is a 'saved search', as in, onCourse already has this data stored in the
				class information, or a tag - new information about a course onCourse doesn't store
				anywhere else. The location of a class can be found via a saved search as the site
				address details are stored in the database already. The information about a course
				being a 'workshop', 'short course' or  'program of study' is a user defined
				definition that is best added to the course by a new tag group.</para>
			<para>Both tags and saved searches can be used to navigate the website on their own, or
				in combination with other tags. This kind of navigation is called faceted search and
				needs to be carefully and considered and designed to meet your particular business
				needs before being implemented by the creation of and application of new tags to
				your onCourse data.</para>
			<para>Faceted search allows users to see a pre-count of available class information as
				they refine their search options. In this example, a two tags called 'Who' and
				'What' combine to form a faceted search across a large data set, to allow website
				visitors to drill down and find the course and class they are looking for as quickly
				as possible.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/tag_faceted_search.png" format="png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Configuring a tag and what it will be applied to within onCourse</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
		</section>
	<section xml:id="tagging-creatingTags">
			<title>Creating a new tag group</title>
		<para>To create a new tag group, begin by going File > Preferences > Tags and clicking the +
			button in the top right hand corner. </para>
		<para>Begin by giving your tag group a name and deciding which part of the onCourse database
			you want this tag group to apply to.</para>
		<para>A tag group can apply to multiple record types, but can not be applied to record and a
			record sub set. For example, you can not apply a tag to both 'contacts' and 'students'
			as students are a type of contact. For the same reasons, a tag can not apply to both
			'courses' and 'classes'.</para>
		<para>Only tags which apply to 'Courses' will be available for display and navigation on
			your onCourse website. Tags which apply to other record types are for internal filtering
			only.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/tag_application.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Configuring a tag and what it will be applied to within onCourse</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Begin building your tag structure by using the + button. The first time you click + in a new
			tag group, that will create the parent tag. Each subsequent click of the + button will
			add a child tag underneath the parent.</para>
		<para>If you wish to adjust the tag structure, you can also drag and drop the ordering from
			the default alphabetical sort order.</para>
		<para>You also have the ability to make changes to the root tag, however you won't be able to add
			a sibling or delete the root node. In the case of the special Subjects tag, you can not
			change the root tag name.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/root_tag.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>The name for the root tag 'subjects' can not be edited.</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<title>Tags as a filtering tool within the onCourse application</title>
		<para>All tags groups you create will be available as filters within the relevant onCourse
			list views. The tag groups shown are based on the record type the tag is related to, and
			then the records related to that record type.</para>
		<para>For example, a tag group applied to Courses will also be available as a filter in the
			related windows of classes, contacts and enrolments.</para>
		<para>In the course window, checking the filter means 'show me course records tagged with
			this tag'. In the class window, checking the same subject filter means 'show me the
			classes for the course tagged with this tag'. In the student window it displays as
			Subjects (enrolled), and means 'show me the students enrolled in classes linked to
			courses tagged with this tag'.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/tag_subject_enrolled.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>A contact filter using the subjects tag to show students enrolled into classes joined to
					courses tagged with the subject 'Creative Arts'</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>The tags that display within the left hand pane of a given window, provide you with a
			number of different options in terms of searching and sorting of information. Tag groups
			and components of tag groups can be expanded and collapsed to create your preferred
			window layout. You can utilise the tags within the a window in a number of ways: <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
						<para>Expand and collapse a given tag group within the left hand pane by clicking on the name
						of the tag group (show / hide will display on hover)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Expand and collapse tags within a tag group by clicking on the arrow that
					indicates a tag contains sub tags</para>
				</listitem>	
					<listitem>
					<para>Use the tags to filter records within a given list view by checking the tick box next to
						the tag name. Ticking a tag that contains sub tags will select all the tags
						beneath it.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Selecting multiple tag check boxes within the same tag group to create an OR search. e.g.
						selecting 'Business' and 'Writing' from the subjects tag at the same time
						will find results tagged with Business OR Writing. </para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Use a tag filter in conjunction with a core filter or saved search. This will create and
						AND search. E.g. current classes AND subject 'Writing'.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Use the advanced search parameter of "tagged with" or "tagged with (including
						children)". This means the search will include any records which have been
						tagged with second or third level tags within the hierarchy, also known as
						"children".</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem><para>Use a combination of advanced search, tag filter and core filters. The advanced search
					will operate within the filtered set of results your checked options will limit
					the list of results to.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		</section>
	<section xml:id="tagging-filter">
		<title>Creating an advanced search filter instead of a tag </title>
		<para>Sometimes, creating a tag group to add information to a record is not the best choice
			for your needs. If the data already exists in the database, you could use a saved search
			to achieve the same result.</para>
		<para>The benefit of a saved search is that it works automatically, as opposed to a tag that
			needs to be added to a record, and if the properties of the record changes, you don't
			need to remember to change the tag.</para>
		<para>An example that could be a tag or saved search is the class concept 'Term'. A term is
			a date range that represents group of classes that start within that range.</para>
		<para>You can create Tag Groups and sub-tags to achieve this, however you can also achieve the
			same result with less work with advanced search. Both options will deliver you a check
			box style filter in the classes window to use to locate records quickly.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a Filter using Advanced Search: </title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> Click on the magnify glass in the top left-hand corner </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> In the Advanced Find window; - choose to Find records matching ALL of the following -
						Start date/time : after and on: [The first day of term 1] - then click "Add
						Search Line" and set Start date/time : before and on : [The last day of term
						1] </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Click on the Cog Wheel, then choose Save Find, name the Find to "2017 - Term 1". You can
						choose to make this filter visible to yourself or, to all staff using
						onCourse, then click Save.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>When you next open the class list view, you will see your saved find as a
					check box in the window.</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>
			Adding and removing tags from records
		</title>
		<para>After you have created your tag groups and their structures, you need to assign these tags to your records.</para>
		<para>This process can be done record by record in the edit view, or in bulk from the list view.</para>
		<para>To add a tag to a record, open the record and click on the icon which looks like a
			luggage tag. This will show you all the tags available for that type of record.</para>
		<para>You should always choose the tag furthest out in the tree - you don't need to add a
			tag from each level. In the example below, we are adding the tag 'computers' to the
			course record. You shouldn't add the tag 'Computing, Business &amp; Professional' to
			this record.</para>
		<para>You can remove a tag by clicking on the minus symbol on the tag name that is visible
			when you hover over the tag name.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/tag_adding_to_record.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Adding a tag to a course record</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="tagging-bulk">
		<title>Tagging and Untagging multiple records</title>
		<para>A great feature in onCourse is bulk tagging. This is just like regular tagging except you
			are applying this tag to multiple records at one time.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to bulk tag</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>First, make sure that you have tags created, if not go to File > Preferences > Tags and
						set this up (see above for more on this) and ensure it is set as 'available
						for' the correct record type e.g. tutors.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open up the list view of records where you wish to apply the tag in bulk, like
						"Tutors"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Highlight the tutors records you want to apply the tag to by selecting them in the
						list</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/multiTag1.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Multi selecting the records to tag</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>On the left, go to the tag you want, e.g; "Subject > Baby Boomers" and right click on the
						tag name (be careful to avoid clicking the check box)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once you right click on the tag you want you have two options: add or remove the tag from
						the selected options.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/multiTag2.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>The Add/Remove options when you right click on tags</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>After you select your option click on "continue" and the tags will be added.</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
								fileref="images/multiTag3.png" format="png" />
						</imageobject>
						<caption>
							<para>Confirm your tagging selection</para>
						</caption>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Once this process is finished, the records you have highlighted will be tagged. You can double click on the record to open the edit view and see this.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>	<para>To bulk remove tags from records, simply follow the steps above but choose "Remove this
				tag from X highlighted records " instead of "Add this tag to X highlighted records"</para>
		</example>
	</section>
</chapter>
