<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="tutors">
	<title>Tutors</title>
	<section xml:id="tutors-termsAndDefs">
		<title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Contact</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A person or company in onCourse is called a contact. Contact can be set as a
						Student, Tutor or Company, none of these or a combination of these.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Tutor</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A tutor is a type of contact. A tutor is anyone who teaches a class for, or on
						behalf of, your college. They may be an employee or a contractor, and could also be a
						student of your college who is enrolled in classes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Student</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A student enrols in classes. A contact or tutor who enrols in a class will
						automatically be set as a student (in addition to being a tutor).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Company</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A company contact is a business, not an individual. Companies may also be set as
						tutors, for example, you may contract to have ACME Tennis Coaching teach classes for
						your business. You can assign the company as the tutor of the class.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Relationship</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Contacts can be related to each other. For example, a company that delivers courses
						for your college, may also have individual contact records set up for their staff that
						teach or assist with the sessions. These contacts would be set as employees of the
						company. By doing this you could advertise the class as being taught by the company,
						which would be the information that displays on your ish website, while also internally
						managing the individuals that would be booked to deliver each class session.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="tutors-workingWith">
		<title>Working with Tutors</title>
		<para>To access the tutors records go to the Dashboard and type Tutors into the Find Anything
			search. The Tutors window is just the Contacts window with the Tutors filter
			pre-selected. It operates exactly the same as the <link
				xlink:href="contacts.html#contacts">Contacts</link> window does.</para>
		<para>You can open a tutor record by double clicking on it in the list view window.</para>
		<section xml:id="tutors-recordTabs">
			<title>Tutor Record Tabs</title>
			<section>
				<title>General</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/tutor_record_general_tab.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>The general section is an important section that holds a lot of information about the
					tutors. Once in the general section, you will be able to edit things
					like:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Name</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Address</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor phone and fax numbers</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor email</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Message (alert for operator)</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Date of birth</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Gender</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Memberships</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor Honorific</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Relation Window - From this window, you can set relationships to that
							tutor</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/tutor_general_relation.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "relation" window in the tutor general section</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Financial</title>
				<para>This section is a view only screen and shows you the financial transactions your company
					has with the selected tutor. Here you will see invoices issued or received and
					payments made to the tutor listing all the relevant information and providing
					links these records. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Messages</title>
				<para>This section lists all messages sent to the tutor from onCourse via email, SMS and post </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Notes</title>
				<para>This section keeps a list of all notes you have relating to the tutor and any web visible
					or private documents like resume, certificates and references.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Documents</title>
				<para>This section is where any documents from the onCourse document management
					system have been linked to the record. </para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="tutors-Resume">
				<title>Resume</title>
				<para>This is where you store the bio information about the tutor you wish to
					publish to your ish website</para>
			</section>
			<section xml:id="tutors-Tutor">
				<title>Tutor</title>
				<para>This section shows a list of the classes the tutor is scheduled to teach. This section
					will also information about the working with children check. The Children Check
					number is required when expiry date is specified and vice versa. A warning gets
					shown when adding a tutor with status 'Barred' or 'Interim barred' to a class. </para>
				<para>There is also a Timetable button in this section. This button opens the
					timetable window and shows all the sessions for the selected tutor in a calendar
					layout. You can <link xlink:href="timetable.html#timetable">read more about the
						Timetable section here</link>.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
							fileref="images/wwcc.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The "relation" window in the tutor general section</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Timetable</title>
				<para>This button opens the timetable window and shows all the sessions for the selected tutor
					in a calendar layout. You can <link xlink:href="timetable.html#timetable">read more
						about the Timetable section here</link>.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="tutors-Creating">
		<title>Creating Tutors</title>
		<para>You will need to keep your tutor's contact details on file and what classes and
			sessions they are scheduled to teach each term. If you are an RTO you will also need to
			keep copies of their resume and qualifications on file. onCourse allows you to do this.
			Each tutor has their own personal file in onCourse which is easy to access and update. </para>
		<para>If you have a large number of casual staff who work at a variety of different venues,
			it can be difficult to manage communication with them as you might not see them in
			person very often. Tutors listed in onCourse can be emailed or SMS'd easily and all
			messages sent out of the system are tracked in the tutors record helping you to keep all
			communications listed and organised. onCourse is designed to help you manage your staff
			records with ease. </para>
		<example>
			<title>How to create a new tutor</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>With the Contact window list view open, click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button in
						the bottom right hand corner of the screen. A new contact screen will open. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Set the contact as a <guibutton>Tutor</guibutton>. You will see that an additional
						section for tutor resume is added to the record.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>First Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Last
							Name</guilabel> of the tutor.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Enter the <guilabel>Address</guilabel> and other contact detail for the
						tutor. If you add an <guilabel>Email</guilabel> address, your tutors can log
						into your ish website to check their class schedules and you can email them
						directly from onCourse. If you enter a <guilabel>Mobile phone</guilabel>
						number, you can send SMS to your tutor from onCourse.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>For each contact method (mail, email and SMS) you have the option to opt the contact out
						of marketing communication. The default setting is to "accept marketing
						material," so when you click on the cog wheel above these fields, you will
						see this option is highlighted with a tick. This means that when you have
						marketing mail outs, this address will be on the mailing list. To change
						this setting simply click on the cog wheel and select the option "opt out
						from postal marketing material" if the person dosen't want to receive
						marketing communication from you. The other option is "undeliverable",
						meaning that no mail is to be delivered to this address because it is
						incorrect, or in the case of an email address, has received an undeliverable
						response from the mail server. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The field <guilabel>message (alert for operator)</guilabel> is for any
						special notes that are important or relevant to this contact for eg. they
						might allow their phone number to be given to students.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Use the resume section to create a publicly listed biography for the tutor. This screen
						shows that information which is displayed on your website. Be aware that
						this is an automatic function. For example, you might post a brief
						description for this particular tutor, their background and experience and
						how it relates to the courses they are teaching. As this information will be
						visible to students and general public on the website, it is recommended
						that you obtain permission from the tutor to publish this information. You
						can enter the text directly into the screen or cut and paste from another
						source. The text in the field can be formatted using Rich text. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Move to the Notes section to add attachments or other notes to the tutor record. The text
						in the <guilabel>notes</guilabel> field is private. Attachments can be
						public (on the website) or private (only available in onCourse).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> To attach documents in the Notes section, click on the + sign on the right hand side of
						the screen. This will open up a drop down screen "attachment (new)". Click
						on <guibutton>import</guibutton> to open up your files. Select the file you
						wish to attach and enter You can then select the "available on web" box if
						you wish to publish the document on your website. Click
							<guibutton>ok</guibutton>. This will close the attachment screen and
						return you to the notes screen. Here you will see a list of the attached
						files. You can delete any files by clicking the - sign.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<note>
			<para>By creating a new tutor record and entering the email address for that tutor, the
				system will automatically create a new account for the Tutor to access the
					<guilabel>Skills onCourse</guilabel> Portal. You can then instruct your tutors
				to go to the <guilabel>Skills onCourse</guilabel> log in page and enter their first
				name, last name and email address and click on the <guilabel>Forgot
					Password</guilabel>link. They will then receive an automatically generated email
				with their new password. </para>
			<para>Admin staff of the College are not able to view or update the Tutor Portal
				password via the onCourse Client, this must be done via the <guilabel>Forgot
					Password</guilabel>link on the Skills onCourse home page.</para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="tutors-contactingTutors">
		<title>Contacting tutors by email or SMS</title>
		<para>You may wish to notify individual tutors if their course is running or cancelled, or groups
			of tutors with information about activities and event at the College. If you create and
			send the message from onCourse, the history of the message is stored within the tutor's
			record on the messaged section.</para>
		<para>You must have set up an SMS and email gateway with ish to use this feature. For
			information on how to do this, read the General Preferences documentation. </para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Open the tutor window and search for the tutor/s you're after using the search
					functions.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Highlight the tutors you wish to contact in the list. To do this select the first contact
					name, hold down shift then select the last contact name and click on the cog
					wheel icon on the bottom right hand side of the window.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Choose "send message" and the messaging window will open.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Choose the template you want to use - the type of template determines whether you're
					sending an email or SMS.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Fill out the fields. The fields required will be defined by the template you
					select. You should see a preview build in the right side of the window as you
					type.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Check the number of contacts being sent to. You can send to suppressed contacts also by
					clicking the checkbox under the student count.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Press <guibutton>send</guibutton>.</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/sending_message_to_contact.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Sending a message to a Tutor via the cogwheel function</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="tutors-Payroll">
		<title>Tags specific to Tutors</title>
		<para>Tutors have some specific tags that can be added to their records relating to pay periods
			and their tutor status. You will see a + button just below where you set the contact as
			a Tutor. Click on this and a drop down menu of different tags will display, among the
			selections is "payroll wage intervals" and "tutors." These aren't required but can be
			useful when used.</para>
		<para>Payroll wage intervals - Gives you a choice of weekly, fortnightly and monthly payment
			schedules. Select one. </para>
		<para>Tutors - offers you the choice of : contract tutors - those tutors who will invoice
			your business pending tutors - those tutors who are not yet working for you vet tutors -
			vocational education and training tutors</para>
		<para> Make your selection and the tag will appear on the record. </para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="tutors-Attachments">
		<title>Contacts and Documents</title>
		<para>Documents provide a way of adding web visible or private documents like resumes,
			certificates and references to a contact.</para>
		<section>
			<title>To add a document to a contact</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the contact you wish to add the attachment to then find the Documents section</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select the "+" button to bring up the documents pop over window</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From here, if you've already uploaded the file and given it a name, type
						it here, or click 'browse' to browser your computer for the location of the
						file. Once you have located the file you wish to attach, select it and click
						"Open"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You'll be prompted to give it a name and to set the access level required to view it.
						Once done, click 'Add'</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>To open or view a document</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the contact you wish to view the document for then scroll to the Documents
						section</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>When you find the document you wish to view from the selection available, click the
						document record. it will open a pop over showing both the document name,
						attached tags, access rights and a description.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click the file image in the left of the pop-over. It will open up the
						selected document.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>To remove an unlink a document</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open the contact you wish to unlink the document from then scroll to the Documents
						section</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click the 'x' button that appears next to the document record you want to
						unlink. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Alternatively, double-click the record then click the Unlink button.
						You'll be asked to confirm. Cancel to cancel, Agree to unlink and
						save.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
