<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="usi">
    <title>Unique Student Identifier (USI)</title>
    <section xml:id="usi-whatIs">
        <title>What is the USI?</title>
        <para>On 1 January 2015 the Australian Commonwealth government introduced a Unique Student
            Identifier which will be issued to every student undertaking vocational training. Once a
            student has been issued a USI, they will supply this number to any RTO where they
            undertake training, be they short one day courses like First Aid, year long full
            Qualification programs or anything in between. The training they undertake will be
            reported back to government through mandatory AVETMISS reporting and a combined training
            transcript created for the student showing all training attempts and completions
            undertaken throughout their life. If the student declines to provide their USI, the RTO
            is not permitted to issue their Statement of Attainment or Qualification on completion
            of training.</para>
        <para>Eventually a USI will be issued to every child starting primary school and every
            student at university. The USI is similar to existing identity systems already in place
            in Australia: medicare number, tax file number, driver's license, etc. but it is not
            printed on an identity card and it is illegal for RTOs to print them on student cards or
            certificates.</para>
        <para>The USI can only be issued in an automated fashion by the USI agency in response to a
            request from a student who comes with certain identification papers. Medicare cards,
            driver's licenses, birth certificates and passports are probably the most common forms
            of identification which can be used. Students without any official identification papers
            can be issued a USI though a manual request process.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="usi-Requirements">
        <title>Requirements and limitations</title>
        <para>The USI legislation puts certain limitations on how the USI can be used and how it
            must be reported.<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The USI cannot be printed on certificates. None of the default
                        certificates or transcripts in onCourse include the USI.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The USI must be verified by the RTO. onCourse has a special feature to
                        automate this process.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You may not issue a certificate to a student until you have their USI and
                        have verified it. onCourse will allow you to create Certificate records but
                        not print them until the USI is verified. You can override this behaviour
                        with the appropriate administrator rights, but you must then ensure you have
                        implemented another verification process in your RTO.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>If you are creating a student's USI on their behalf, you can not store the
                        identity documentation on a student's record permanently. You must discard
                        it once you have successfully obtained the USI.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The USI data is exported in all AVETMISS 7 flavours.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>
        <section xml:id="usi-onCourseProcess">
        <title>The onCourse USI process</title>
        <para>Our primary goal is to make obtaining and verifying USIs the responsibility of the
            enrolling student to minimise the data entry and management effort required by your
            office staff. </para>
        <para>If a student enters their USI online, or you enter it manually in onCourse the USI
            will automatically be verified against the USI Agency system. In order for this process
            to work we will require a special authorisation key called an AUSkey that has been
            linked to your RTO. </para>
        <para>The verification system is not available to onCourse community edition users who don't
            have a support agreement with ish. You can still capture the USI within onCourse and
            report it for AVETMISS but you will not be able to take advantage of the online student
            self-service process or the automatic verification process. Community users can verify
            their student's USIs manually using the USI Agency RTO portal.</para>
        <section>
            <title>How onCourse automates the USI process</title>
            <para>We know that many organisations who use onCourse deliver a mix of accredited (VET)
                and non-accredited training, and that the USI requirements will not apply to their
                non-accredited students. We also know that some 75% of students who have ever
                enrolled via onCourse either have enrolled online or have provided an email address
                during the enrolment process, so can receive emails from us and access websites to
                complete web forms. </para>
            <para>First of all, when a student enrols in a course which is identified as a VET
                course, their enrolment confirmation will include some additional text explaining
                what a USI is and why they need to tell you theirs. This email directs them to a
                special onCourse portal page (no log in required) requesting they supply their USI
                or go through the process to create one. </para>
            <para>Most students will be going through the process of creating a new USI. Once they
                complete this part of the process, we will then take that new USI and verify it
                against their first name, last name and date of birth as supplied on enrolment. If
                the USI doesn’t validate (possibly because the student used a dummy date of birth on
                enrolment, or a shortened version of their first name) then they will be prompted to
                update the incorrect data in onCourse to match their USI, so we can pass the USI
                validation process. </para>
            <para>Every Monday morning, all recently enrolled VET students who have not supplied you
                with their USI will be sent an automatic reminder email on how to complete this
                process and why it is important they do so. There is a customisable and that runs
                this process which you can edit to meet your preferred business requirements. A
                student who doesn't complete this process or can not validate their USI will be
                flagged in onCourse for you to follow up. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title> What you need to do enable the USI validation service in onCourse </title>
            <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Obtain an AUSKey from the <link xlink:href="https://abr.gov.au/AUSkey/"
                            >Australian Business Registry</link>, If your organisation lodges tax
                        electronically to the ATO you may already have an AUSKey. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Create a device AUSKey and send it to ish to upload to your onCourse
                        server. Step by step instructions are available at <link
                            xlink:href="https://ish.com.au/oncourse/auskey"/>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Register your AUSKey with the USI Agency using <link
                            xlink:href="https://forms.business.gov.au/smartforms/servlet/SmartForm.html?formCode=USI-SysAccess"
                            >this form</link>. If you don't get an email confirmation, follow it up
                        with the USI Agency directly. Only once your AUSKey is registered can you
                        use the built in validation tools in onCourse.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Customise the onCourse enrolment <link xlink:href="#emailTemplates"
                            >template</link> and USI reminder template and <link
                            xlink:href="#scripts">script</link> so the wording and frequency of the
                        reminders is suitable for your business.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Obtain a USI for yourself and test that it validates in onCourse.</para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            <para>Please contact your onCourse account manager if you need any assistance with this
                process.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="usi-selfService">
        <title>Student self-service</title>
        <para>On enrolment through the office or the web, onCourse will send an email enrolment
            confirmation to the student. If the course is VET flagged, the confirmation template
            will include some text directing the student to obtain and supply you with their
            USI.</para>
        <para>Another default script in onCourse can be enabled to send a reminder email to students
            every Monday at 9am until the class is complete or the USI is entered. You can modify
            these templates or alter the script which determines when and how often to send these
            emails. </para>
        <para>Note that students are only sent this email if they are enrolled in a VET flagged
            class, to avoid bothering your students engaging in non-VET training, however by default
            VET flagged courses without qualifications or units will also trigger this email as they
            are usually reported via AVETMISS for funding arrangements. You may wish to alter the
            scripts to only send the email when the course has a qualification record
            attached.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_email.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>An example of a confirmation email with USI information</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/usi_followup_email.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>An example of a USI reminder email.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>Once the student gets the email requesting their USI, they will be able to click on a
            link which takes them directly to a page within the skillsOnCourse portal. They will not
            require a password and the link will be valid for 7 days from the email being sent. The
            URL is cryptographically signed so that they will not work after the expiry date and
            they will not be transferable between students.</para>
        <para>You can change the default 7 days expiry to any number of your choosing by editing
            your enrolment confirmation and USI reminder email templates.  </para>
        <para>The skillsOnCourse portal page will explain the USI to the student and give them a
            convenient link to create or recover a USI if they don't have one or have forgotten it.
            This has been optimised so that it can be used on mobile and tablet devices. The student
            will be able to enter the USI and onCourse will handle the verification process
            automatically.</para>
        <para>The student will be asked to complete three steps: first supply their date of birth
            (if not supplied on enrolment) and USI, then the standard AVETMISS questions which are
            not mandatory, and then to supply any data for CMS mandatory fields that were not
            supplied on enrolment, like their address. If the USI agency reports back that the
            student's name is wrong (for example, they enrolled in onCourse with their maiden name
            but their USI is issued in their married name) then onCourse will give them the
            opportunity to fix this.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_mobile_start.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 1: This is the screen the students will arrive at. The date of birth
                    field will only be shown if it hasn't already been supplied.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_mobile_verifying.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 1 in progress: While the USI is being verified they will see this
                    window.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_student_name_mismatch.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 1 failed: The student's name doesn't match the USI Registry data. They
                    have the opportunity to correct the data in onCourse.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_mobile_success.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 1 complete: The student's USI has been successfully verified. Now they
                    move on to step 2.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_portal_step2.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 2: The student completes the AVETMISS questions.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/usi_complete_blank_fields.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 3: The student completes an missing personal data. No previously provided
                    data is shown, only empty fields marked as mandatory in your website CMS.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/usi_mobile_update_details.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Step 3: If the student has already supplied all the necessary contact data,
                    they are shown this information about how to update their details.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/usi_mobile_complete.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>USI portal complete: If the student has completed the USI data and clicks on
                    the link again, they are given the opportunity to review their AVETMISS question
                    responses only.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="usi-Capturing">
        <title>Capturing the USI in onCourse</title>
        <para>The USI does not need to be captured at the time of enrolment, but typically you'll
            want to have it entered and verified before the class is completed in order to not delay
            issuing of certificates.</para>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a USI for a student</title>
            <para>Some students will not be able to navigate the USI portal to obtain their own USI,
                in which case you are able to do this on their behalf in the onCourse student record
                VET tab.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/usi/create_a_USI.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para> When there is no USI supplied, you can click on the link to open a web
                        portal and create a new USI.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>If the USI field is blank you will see a link next to the field to create a USI.
                Clicking on this link will open a web portal where you can complete the student
                details and identity document information. You will need to declare that you have
                obtained permission from the student to complete this process on their
                behalf.</para>
            <para>An AusKey is not required to create a USI using the web portal. After creating the
                USI, you need to enter it into onCourse and the verification process will
                run.</para>
            <para>We do not recommend you copy or store the student's identity documentation in
                their onCourse record as this is in breach of the USI legislation.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Manual entry of a USI</title>
            <para>When you create a new student or update an existing one, you can type the USI
                directly into the field available on the VET tab in their contact record. This can
                also be done directly within the Quick Enrol process. The USI will be checked for
                validity (it is the correct length and matches a checksum) and then verified against
                the USI agency.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/usi/invalid_USI.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>What you will see if the USI has not been entered correctly. This USI is
                        invalid as it doesn't meet the character length and checksum. It can't be
                        validated and the record can't be saved.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>If you have an onCourse support contact, have supplied us with your AUSKey and
                    <link
                    xlink:href="https://forms.business.gov.au/smartforms/servlet/SmartForm.html?formCode=USI-SysAccess"
                    >registered your AUSKey</link> with the USI Registry System the USI validation
                system in onCourse will be enabled.</para>
            <para>Once a complete USI is entered in the student record, the background validation
                process with the USI Registry System will run automatically. The validation process
                is checking that the student's first name, last name, date of birth and USI match
                the data held by the USI Registry System.</para>
            <para> If it succeeds the USI will be marked as verified with a green pill next to the
                USI field and the student's first name, last name and date of birth will become
                locked.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/usi/verified_USI.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This USI has passed verification and the record has been locked.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>If the one of the fields do not match e.g. the student's first name in onCourse is
                a shortened version of their legal name, then the USI verification process will
                fail. Hovering over the information icon next to the USI field label will show the
                reason why the verification process failed. You can update the non-matching data in
                onCourse and the verification process will run again, automatically, when you change
                one of the first name, last name, date of birth or USI field's data.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/usi/USI_verification_failed.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>This USI has failed verification. The data can be corrected and the
                        verification attempted again.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Editing a locked student record</title>
            <para>After successful USI validation, the data that was matched with the USI - the first name, last name, date of birth and USI of the student, becomes locked. </para>
            <para>On occasion, a student may inform you that they created their USI with the wrong
                name details and wish to update their records. To do this, they need to contact the
                USI Agency by logging into their own portal and completing the process to make the
                change. Once the USI Agency has the details of the change, you can go ahead and
                update their onCourse records to match.</para>
            <para>Click on the padlock symbol next to one of the locked fields in their record and a
                new sheet will open. This will allow you to edit one or more of the fields.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/usi/USI_edit_sheet.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The fields have been unlocked for you to edit</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
            <para>After editing, click on Verify USI and the SOAP call process will run and confirm
                if the students details with the USI agency match with the change you wish to
                make.</para>
            <para>If your change matches, the student record will return to it's locked state
                showing the new data that has been verified.</para>
            <para>If the student has not successfully updated their USI Agency record, your attempt
                to verify will fail and an explanation will be given when you hover over the
                exclamation icon.</para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                        fileref="images/usi/USI_edit_name.png"/>
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>The USI details have attempted to verify with the new data, but have failed on the surname.</para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="usi-certificatePrinting">
        <title>Certificate printing and the USI</title>
        <para>The USI legislation requires that RTOs only issue formal certification to students who
            have supplied a USI which has passed verification.</para>
        <para>From 1/1/2015 all certificate record print attempts will check the student USI status.
            A warning will show for any certificate print or reprint where the student doesn't have
            a USI. A certificate created after 1/1/2015 will not print without a verified
            USI.</para>
        <para>A range of warnings and errors will appear based on your onCourse access rights. By
            default, all non admin users do not have permission to print certificates for students
            without verified USIs. </para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_cert_print_fail.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>This certificate can't be printed as the user does not have permission to
                    print without a USI.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>All admin users will see the warnings if a student doesn't have a USI or verified USI,
            however they will be able to proceed to print for all certificates if they
            choose.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_cert_print_warn.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>This is a warning only. You can still proceed by selecting print.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>All access roles have two optional levels of access - print certificate without
            verified USI (this means they student has supplied a USI that meets the checksum
            requirements, but for whatever reason it hasn't passed verification with the USI
            Registry System) and a higher level of permission, print certificate without USI.</para>
        <para>We do not recommend that you allow staff permission to print certificates without
            verified USIs.</para>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/usi/USI_certificate_print_permissions.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>This access role does not have permission to print certificates without a
                    verified USI.</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="usi-FAQs">
        <title>USI FAQ</title>
        <qandaset>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para>Why are all my USIs failing to verify with the error message saying the
                        USI agency can't be contacted?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>For all the customers that <link
                            xlink:href="https://forum.ish.com.au/discussion/276/preparing-your-rto-for-the-usi-implementation-in-2015#latest"
                            >followed the instructions we provided on our forum</link> about
                        creating an AUSKey, sending it to us to upload to your server and completing
                        the USI Agency Access request form, it seems the last step went pear shaped
                        for some and the AUSKey wasn't linked to your RTO Id, making the whole
                        automatic verification process fail.</para>
                    <para>Complete the <link
                            xlink:href="https://forms.business.gov.au/smartforms/servlet/SmartForm.html?formCode=USI-SysAccess"
                            >System Access Request Form</link> again and wait for an approval email
                        before trying to verify USIs.</para>
                </answer>
            </qandaentry>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para>How do I make the USI validation process run in onCourse?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>When onCourse detects you have entered a USI in the USI field on the
                        Student VET tab, it will check that you have an RTO ID entered in your
                        general preferences, and a First Name, Last Name and Date of Birth entered
                        in the student record. If all these fields are complete, the USI Validation
                        process will run automatically in the background.</para>
                    <para>If it fails, and you need to change some of the data to make it try again,
                        make the change, click out of the field (use tab on your keyboard, or click
                        into any other field) and the process will run again. If you don't need to
                        change any data, just click in the USI field and click out and it will try
                        again. You can do this as many times as you like - the validation check is
                        quite fast, less than 3 seconds in most instances, and there is no limit to
                        the number of times you can try to validate a USI.</para>
                </answer>
            </qandaentry>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para>How can I test that my onCourse USI portal access is working as
                        required?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>Go and <link
                            xlink:href="http://usi.gov.au/create-your-USI/Pages/default.aspx">create
                            yourself a USI.</link> Then you can use your own details to create a new
                        student contact and test the USI verification. Try without a date of birth
                        or misspelled name to see the error responses you'll get in onCourse. You
                        can discard the contact instead of saving it onCourse after sufficiently
                        testing the verification process.</para>
                </answer>
            </qandaentry>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para>What should I do when the student has created their USI in a name
                        different to the name they enrolled with?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>Commonly, students will enrol with the name they prefer to use e.g. Bob
                        rather than Robert, but their USI will be issued in their legal name. When
                        you try to verify the USI they supply against their name, an error will be
                        returned telling you that the first name (or last name, or date of birth)
                        doesn't match the USI you supplied. In that case, you can change the data in
                        onCourse and the verification process will automatically run again. </para>
                    <para>If the student uses the USI portal to supply you with their USI, then they
                        can correct their name spelling themselves. You might need to call the
                        student to get their correct name spelling if you are collecting and
                        verifying USIs via an office based process.</para>
                    <para>Of course, we have also had instances of students whose name is spelt
                        incorrectly on their ID and therefore the name linked to their USI has the
                        wrong spelling, or students who have enrolled using a married name, when the
                        ID they used to create their USI was in their maiden name. You'd need to
                        enter their name into onCourse as an exact match as their USI name to make
                        it validate, but you probably don't want to do this as then their
                        certificate will be issued in the wrong name too. For the time being, leave
                        it as an invalid USI.</para>
                    <para>In these instances you need to get the student to log into their own <link
                            xlink:href="https://portal.usi.gov.au/student">USI Agency Portal</link>
                        and make the change there, and advise you once this has been done. Then you
                        can try the validation process again, and it should pass with the right
                        spelling.</para>
                </answer>
            </qandaentry>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para> How can I find out which students USIs have failed to pass validation in
                        onCourse?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>In the contact advanced search options, you can search for USI status =
                        not verified. You can then work through the list of returned to results to
                        check the error messages, contact the students and make the appropriate
                        changes. As you change the data, the verification process will run
                        again.</para>
                </answer>
            </qandaentry>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para>How can I find out which students need USIs but don't have one recorded in
                        onCourse?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>Using the class window, locate all your VET classes that are running
                        during 2015 and highlight them all. Use the cog wheel to find 'Enrolled
                        students' related to the highlighted classes.</para>
                    <para>In this new window of students, use the advanced find to search for USI
                        status = not set. Once you have this list of students, you can then manually
                        follow them up with phone calls or find their enrolments to send them the
                        USI reminder email.</para>
                    <para>To send the reminder email, select all the students and use the cogwheel
                        to find related enrolments. When the enrolment window opens, check the
                        filter options 'current active' and 'completed active' to remove any
                        cancelled or failed enrolments from the list. Then highlight all the
                        enrolments and from the cog wheel choose the option 'send emails from
                        template' and select the template called 'USI reminder email'.</para>
                </answer>
            </qandaentry>
            <qandaentry>
                <question>
                    <para>What happens when merging contacts with USIs?</para>
                </question>
                <answer>
                    <para>You cannot merge two contacts with different verified USIs. If you attempt
                        a merge, a notification will be displayed informing you that you can't do
                        this.</para>
                    <para>If only one of the contacts has a USI, then they can be merged, but their
                        First/Last Name and date of birth can't be changed during this
                        process.</para>
                     </answer>
            </qandaentry>
        </qandaset>
    </section>
</chapter>
