<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="Vouchers">
    <title>Vouchers</title>
    <para>Voucher products can be created in onCourse, and then offered for sale either via the
        College website or through the office via Quick Enrol. These vouchers can be gift
        certificates, a way to sell a bundle of enrolments as a set fee, or as a method of issuing a
        student with a credit, allowing them to apply that credit to an open or restricted range of
        courses.</para>
    <example>
        <title>Voucher Use Cases</title>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product for sale for a user specified dollar value. Redemption value
                    is the same as the purchase price and has a fixed redemption period e.g. 12
                    months. This type of voucher is typically known as a gift certificate.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product for sale for a different redemption price to the purchase
                    price. e.g. purchase price $100, redemption value $120. This type of voucher can
                    then be used as credit to purchase enrolments or other products.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product offered for sale for a fixed fee, redeemable for a single
                    enrolment in a course or set of courses </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product offered for sale for a fixed fee a fixed number of
                    enrolments from a set of one or more courses. For example 4 enrolments from one
                    course (a year's worth of enrolments in a course) or 4 enrolments in 4 courses
                    (one enrolment in each of the four courses).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A way to sell a bundle of enrolments to a company for a fixed fee, for their
                    staff to enrol in a class of their choice from a course, e.g. 10 enrolments in
                    your choice of class for the course Computers for Beginners. This type of
                    voucher would send the invoice on redemption to the nominated company contact,
                    rather than to the student.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </example>
    <section>
    <title>onCourse Terms and Definitions</title>
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Voucher Type</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher is a product which can be sold and later redeemed for other
                    purchases or enrolments. Vouchers can be redeemed for a monetary value or
                    for a fixed number of enrolments in a set range of courses. The voucher type
                    describes how much the voucher costs to purchase, how long it is valid for
                    and what it can be redeemed for.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Voucher</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>Vouchers are the list of purchased voucher type products. Vouchers can be
                    purchased and redeemed through Quick Enrol. This list shows who purchaed the
                    voucher, who it is redeemable by and what the remaining value of the voucher
                    includes. Every voucher has a unique code that must be quoted for
                    redemption.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>
    <section>
        <title>Issuing a Voucher</title>
        <para>For most cases when a user wants to buy a voucher, they will nominate the price they
            wish to purchase the voucher for, and that the price will also be the redemption value
            of the voucher. (Type 1) This type of voucher product will be created by default for all
            onCourse instances and be called "Gift certificate". It will only be enabled if the
            College has the right license that enables this feature. </para>
        <para>In addition, colleges can create other types of voucher products that are linked to
            enrolment permissions and these will have purchase prices fixed by the college. Some of
            these types of voucher products may also be available for sale on the website.</para>
        <para>A voucher may be sold as part of the existing QE process or it may be given away for
            free (sold with 100% discount). Either way, an email is sent to the payer with the
            details of that voucher (not the student since it may be a gift, if the student and the
            payer are different people).</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Redeeming a Voucher</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A student can click on the link in the voucher email (the URL contains the
                    voucher code) www.collegeurl.com.au/enrol?voucher=[voucherproduct.code]</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the voucher is linked to the student, then it will be visible in their
                    portal</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A student can type in the voucher code in the payment window (as part of the
                    redesigned enrolment page). </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                    fileref="images/voucher_email.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption>
                <para>Confirmation message after purchasing voucher online</para>
            </caption>
        </mediaobject>
    </section>
    <section>
               <title>Voucher Type</title>
        <section>
                <title>General</title>
                <para>To view, edit ot create a voucher type you can go to either the splash screen
                    and click on Voucher type box in the Marketing tab or the onCourse menu File →
                    Preferences  → Voucher type.<mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/Voucher_Type_General.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab in a new voucher type record</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <para>There are a number of fields in this tab, they are:</para>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>SKU - this refers to a stock-keeping unit, a unique identifier for
                                each distinct product and service that can be purchased. You can
                                create whatever product code you want for this voucher.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Name - allows you to name the voucher.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Liability Account - allows you to choose the liability account you
                                want to be used.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Expiry date - this allows you to create a expiry date for the
                            voucher for the date of purchase e.g. 365 days.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Options for redeement - you can select whether you want the
                            voucher to be able to be redeemed for an enrolment/s, for the purchased
                            price or for different price.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/Voucher_Type_General_Enrolment_In.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab if the option for redeement is left with
                                the default option "enrolment in"</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <para>By clicking on the + button you open up a window thats gives you three
                            options to choose what course/s the voucher can be redeemed against,
                            they are:</para>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Course - allows you to choose a specific course that the voucher
                                can be redeemed against</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>All courses tagged with - allows you to choose a group of courses
                                that have the same tag</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>All enabled courses - allows you to use this voucher for any
                                course available</para>
                            <note>
                                <para>If you want to apply a voucher to more than one specifc course
                                    then you can use the first option "Course" one by one for each
                                    course.</para>
                            </note>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/Voucher_Type_General_Courses.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the three options you can apply the voucher to.</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/Voucher_Type_General_Purchase_Price.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab if the option "purchase price" is selected
                                from the drop down box</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                                fileref="images/Voucher_Type_General_Price.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                        <caption>
                            <para>View of the general tab if the option "price" is selected from the
                                drop down box</para>
                        </caption>
                    </mediaobject>
                </para>
        </section>
         <section>
                <title>Web</title>
             
                <para>This tab allows you to choose if this voucher is available to be purchased, by
                    what methods, and if you wish to include any text on your website about it.<itemizedlist>
                        <para>There are two checkboxes on this tab, they are:</para>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Can be purchased online - allows people to to buy this voucher on
                                your website</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Is on sale - means this is now avaiable to be purchased</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <note>
                        <para>If only the "Is on sale" checkbox is selected then the voucher can
                            only be puchased via the phone or over the counter.</para>
                    </note>
                </para>
                <para>You can also add a more indepth description that will be displayed on the
                website (as long as both checkboxes are selected) in the Web desciption
                field.</para>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
                            fileref="images/Voucher_Type_Web.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>
                        <para>View of the web tab in a new voucher type record</para>
                    </caption>
                </mediaobject>
            
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
