<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0" xml:id="Vouchers">
    <title>Vouchers</title>
    <para>Voucher products can be created in onCourse, and then offered for sale either via the
        College website or through the office via Quick Enrol. These vouchers can be gift
        certificates, a way to sell a bundle of enrolments as a set fee, or as a method of issuing a
        student with a credit, allowing them to apply that credit to an open or restricted range of
        courses.</para>
    <example>
        <title>Voucher Use Cases</title>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product for sale for a user specified dollar value. Redemption value
                    is the same as the purchase price and has a fixed redemption period e.g. 12
                    months. This type of voucher is typically known as a gift certificate.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product for sale for a different redemption price to the purchase
                    price. e.g. purchase price $100, redemption value $120. This type of voucher can
                    then be used as credit to purchase enrolments or other products.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product offered for sale for a fixed fee, redeemable for a single
                    enrolment in a course or set of courses </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A voucher product offered for sale for a fixed fee a fixed number of
                    enrolments from a set of one or more courses. For example 4 enrolments from one
                    course (a year's worth of enrolments in a course) or 4 enrolments in 4 courses
                    (one enrolment in each of the four courses).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A way to sell a bundle of enrolments to a company for a fixed fee, for their
                    staff to enrol in a class of their choice from a course, e.g. 10 enrolments in
                    your choice of class for the course Computers for Beginners. This type of
                    voucher would send the invoice on redemption to the nominated company contact,
                    rather than to the student.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </example>
    <section>
        <title>Creating a voucher product</title>
        <para> Step by step examples and screenshots. 2 x voucher types</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Issuing a Voucher</title>
        <para>For most cases when a user wants to by a voucher, they will nominate the price they
            wish to purchase the voucher for, and that the price will also be the redemption value
            of the voucher. (Type 1) This type of voucher product will be created by default for all
            onCourse instances and be called "Gift certificate". It will only be enabled if the
            College has the right license that enables this feature. </para>
        <para>In addition, colleges can create other types of voucher products that are linked to
            enrolment permissions and these will have purchase prices fixed by the college. Some of
            these types of voucher products may also be available for sale on the website.</para>
        <para>A voucher may be sold as part of the existing QE process or it may be given away for
            free (sold with 100% discount). Either way, an email is sent to the payer with the
            details of that voucher (not the student since it may be a gift, if the student and the
            payer are different people).</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Redeeming a Voucher</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>A student can click on the link in the voucher email (the URL contains the
                    voucher code) www.collegeurl.com.au/enrol?voucher=[voucherproduct.code]</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the voucher is linked to the student, then it will be visible in their
                    portal</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>A student can type in the voucher code in the payment window (as part of the
                    redesigned enrolment page). </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
</chapter>
