<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="waitingLists">
	<title>Waiting Lists</title>
	<section>
		<title>Enabling waiting lists</title>
		<subtitle>Enabling waiting lists:</subtitle>
		<para>In the onCourse client, each course can be individually enabled to allow waiting lists.</para>
		<para> On the general tab, tick the box “Allows waiting lists” and your students will see on your website, listed below all of the
			available classes, the text “If there isn't a class to suit you, you could join the waiting list.”</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/beaded_jewellery.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Student web subscription to waiting lists</title>
		<subtitle>Student web subscription to waiting lists:</subtitle>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/sub_waiting_list.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>When students click on the link in a course to the waiting list, they will be prompted to enter their contact details and any
			particulars about when and where they would prefer to attend a class for this course. </para>
		<para> If students are new to your college, by adding themselves to the waiting list, a contact record for them will be created within
			onCourse. If they are existing students, the information they provide will be added to their existing student record. </para>
		<para> When a student is logged in to your website, they are able to manage their waiting list subscriptions, removing them from any
			courses they are no longer interested in.</para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="waitingLists-General">
		<title>Managing waiting lists within onCourse</title>
		<subtitle>Managing waiting lists within onCourse:</subtitle>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
					fileref="images/man_waiting_list.png" format="png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Staff within your college can also add and remove students to waiting lists. Students
			need to be set up as contacts before you can add them to a waiting list. </para>
		<para> Go to the menu People and select Waiting lists. This window will show you all the
			students currently on waiting lists for various courses. You can add a student to the
			waiting list by clicking the plus + symbol. </para>
		<para> In the general tab you can record the details about the student and the course, and
			select any venues they may particularly prefer. On the notes page you can enter other
			details such as time of day, day or week or any other preferences. </para>
		<para> From the waiting list window you can also remove students by clicking the minus –
			symbol. </para>
		<para> In the contact record you can see if a student is on any waiting lists, and in the
			course record, you can see how many students are on the waiting list. </para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Advising students on waiting lists that a class is available </title>
		<subtitle>Advising students on waiting lists that a class is available:</subtitle>
		<para>You can also search from the waiting list for all students waiting for a particular course, and use the cogwheel function to send
			a message to the students selected. More about using messaging<uri>here</uri></para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="images/advising_student.png" format="png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Enrolling students on waiting lists</title>
		<para>When a student on a waiting list enrols in a class from the course they wait listed, their
			waiting list entry is automatically deleted.</para>
		<para>You can also enrol a student directly from the waiting list by highlighting their
			entry and going to the cog wheel and choosing 'enrol'. This will pre-populate the quick
			enrol window with the student's contact details and the course information, you just
			need to select which of the available classes they would like to enrol in.</para>
		<para>Students can also choose to remove themselves from a waiting list via the onCourse
			student portal</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
