<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	version="5.0" xml:id="payroll">
	<title>Tutor pay</title>
	<para>In this chapter, we cover how to set up standard rates of pay for your Tutors, how to
		include Tutor costs within the overall class budget, confirming Tutor attendance / hours worked
		and how to generate Tutor pay from onCourse. </para>
	<para>Before you work through this section, you need to ensure you have already set up a class
		with a timetable. You will also need to ensure you have created a Tutor record. </para>
	<section xml:id="payroll-payRates">
		<title>Setting standard pay rates</title>
		<para>onCourse allows you to map standard pay rates to Tutor types. These are used by default,
			but can be overridden per class as needed. Some standard Tutor type names are included by
			default, but these can be changed or deleted as needed.</para>
		<example>
			<title>How to create Tutor pay rates</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>To open the window go to <guimenu>File</guimenu> >
							<guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem> > <guimenuitem>Tutor roles
						</guimenuitem>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Select one of the existing wage types to edit and modify or create a new wage type
						by clicking the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/definedTutorRolesList.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Give a name and a public label to the wage role, for example 'VET Tutor Step 1'. The
						public label shows as the role in the class interface. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Set the expense account for the wage</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> button within the pay rate window to add a
						payrate for this Tutor type.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_payrate_window.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the drop down sheet, define how this type of Tutors wage is calculated from the
						options available e.g. 'Per timetabled hour'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the <guilabel>rate</guilabel> field, define the dollar amount per your selected type
						the Tutor is to be paid e.g. $55 per hour. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>On-costs allows you to take into account any additional expenses related to employing
						these staff, such as superannuation, leave loading, payroll tax and workers
						compensation costs. A common on-cost used calculating additional employee
						costs in Australia is 20%</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Setting the start date for this pay rate allows you to keep track of historical payrate
						increases, and ensures that if a Tutors pay calculation falls across a
						change in pay conditions, all sessions delivered before the change will be
						calculated at the old rate, with sessions delivered after the change in rate
						to be calculated at the new rate. By default this field is set to a
						historical date five years past for the first entry you create, but you can
						change it to the date of you choice. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click <guibutton>Ok</guibutton> and <guibutton>Save</guibutton> and close the
						record. You will be returned to the list screen where you can add or edit another pay rate.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/definedTutorRole.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<caution>
			<para>If your payrate doesn't start until today, but the class start date is prior to today,
				no automatic pay rate will be found when you add the Tutor to the class. You can still
				create a manual pay line in the class. Also, if the payrate changes during the class
				progress, i.e. class spans June and July, and at the start of the financial year a new pay
				rate applies, that class budget information will only show the original pay rate in the cost
				calculations, but the actual payslip calculations will be correct as to the timing of each
				session and the pay rate that applied as each session was delivered.</para>
		</caution>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="payroll-classBudget">
		<title>Class budget with Tutor pay</title>
		<para>Once you have defined the default payrates for the various classifications of Tutors you
			employ, you can use these to automatically add wages costs to your class budgets. You can do
			this by adding Tutors to classes. </para>
		<tip>
			<para>If you do not know who the individual Tutor will be in advance to your class scheduling,
				we recommend you set up a Tutor named something like 'To Be Advised' whom you can assign to
				classes. This will allow you take wages into account in your initial class budget and
				viability calculations. When you know the name of the individual who will be running the
				class you can replace TBA with the actual Tutor, and make any changes to their pay rate as
				required.</para>
		</tip>
		<example>
			<title>Assigning a Tutor and payrate to a class in one step</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the class window, navigate to the Tutor tab. Here you can add one or more Tutors,
						Coordinators, Assistants or other staff to the class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the <guibutton>+</guibutton> to add a new Tutor to the class or double
						click on a Tutor already added to the class to add a wage to their record.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the Tutor edit sheet, type in the surname of the Tutor you wish to add to the
						class. This field will look up Tutors you have already created in the database. You can
						not add new Tutors from here.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>When you select the Tutors role, the automatic pay rate set for this role will be
						added. You can override the wage at this point for this individual Tutor for this
						class.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click <guibutton>Ok</guibutton> to add the Tutor to the class.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/addTutorToClass.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Continue to add additional Tutors to the class, and define their wages as required. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you have added a coordinator or other assisting staff member to the Tutor list of the
						class you can choose to remove them from publicity (printing in the brochure
						and showing on your onCourse website) by unchecking the option 'Show this
						Tutor in class information'</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you need to edit the Tutor wage once you have set it, you will need to go to the
						class budget tab to make changes. Double click on the wage you wish to edit and check
						the option 'override assigned role's pay rate'.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_wage_override.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Once you have clicked on 'override assigned role's pay rate', you will then be able
						to adjust the role, account code and rate. <inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/editWageInClass.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>If you did not have a wage added when the Tutor was added to the class, e.g. for a
						historical class, you can add the wage on the budget tab. Go to <guibutton>+</guibutton>
						<guibutton>Wage </guibutton> and select the Tutor from the list.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>You can also add Tutors to the class directly from the timetable, during the session
						set up of edit process. If you add Tutors here, you will need to manually add the Tutor
						pay rate from the budget tab.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
		<para>You don't need to do all the above if you already have the Tutor added to the timetable in
			your class. Instead you can go directly to the Budget tab and add a new budget line, filling
			out the relevant Tutor pay details as you go.</para>
		<para>You can also add additional lines to the tutor payroll for other pay types. You are
			limited to one line per type (per timetabled hour, per session, per enrolment ect) for
			each tutor. This allows you to add the standard tutors pay rate, and perhaps and
			assessment allowance per enrolment or a set up/pack up allowance per session. To add the
			additional pay rate type:</para>
		<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
				<para>In the class record, go to the budget tab and select the add budget
					item</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select add wage and select your tutor's name. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If this is the second or subsequent line for your tutor, you will need to
					select the 'override tutor wage' option</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Add the specifics for the new wage line item ensuring you choose a different
					type to any existing pay lines</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<example>
			<title>How to record a Tutor as being Unavailable for a Given Class</title>
			<para>Sometimes Tutors cannot make it to their classes, whatever the reason, you can flag that
				Tutor as not available in the following way:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>In onCourse, go to "Tutor"</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Double click on a record to open a Tutor profile</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>From here click on the "timetable" tab</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Click on the "list" option and in the bottom square, there is the "availability
						rules" section (see screenshot)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Click on the + sign on the top right hand side of the "availability rules" section
						and you can edit the busy period as well as the option to select "all day" which, as the
						name suggests, will block the whole day for that Tutor.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
						fileref="images/unavailabilities.png" format="png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="payroll-attendance">
		<title>Confirming Attendance and exceptions</title>
		<para>Not only is attendance used for students, it can also be used to record whether your
			Tutors showed up and if they stayed for longer or shorter than their rostered time. You do not
			have to use this function in order to pay Tutors, but it can be very useful. Tutor attendance
			can be set for each session on the class Attendance tab.</para>
		<example>
			<title>Setting Tutor attendance for Tutor pay</title>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open a class record and navigate to the attendance tab.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>For each session, click on the attendance icon and set the appropriate attendance.
						Click once for attended, twice for not attended. Three clicks will set the session back
						to unmarked.<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_tutor_attendance.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set the attendance to partial attendance, or absent with reason, right click on
						the attendance icon and select one of these options. When you select one of these values
						a drop down sheet will appear with fields for additional information to be set. Either
						of these options need to be approved for Tutor pay in the window.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>To set partial attendance, you need to enter in the sheet how many minutes of the
						scheduled session minutes the person was in attendance for. Approving this Tutor pay
						variation means the person will be paid for the full session. Leaving it unapproved
						means they will be paid only for their time in attendance. <inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/payroll_partial_attendance.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject></para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</example>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="payroll-payslips">
		<title>Generating Tutor pay</title>
		<para>onCourse generates Tutor pay records in bulk, for a given point in time, based on the
			attendance records for Tutor. While generating Tutor pay records the admin user is given
			choices as to whether unmarked or unapproved attendance should be included.<example>
				<title>Generating, editing and finalising Tutor pay</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Before Tutor pay can be created you'll need a fully setup class, with timetable,
							Tutors and wages.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Open list of classes</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Highlight classes for which Tutor pay is to be generated</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select the "Generate Tutor pay for xx classes " menu item under the cogwheel icon<inlinemediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/generateTutorPayStep1.png" />
								</imageobject>
							</inlinemediaobject></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Select whether unmarked or unapproved attendance is to be taken under consideration when
							generating Tutor pay. This only applies to per session or per timetabled
							hour pay. Other types of pay (such as fixed rate) does not rely on
							attendance marking or approval at all. In those instances where a fixed
							rate is to be paid, a  pay run can be generated anytime after the Class
							has commenced. <inlinemediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/generateTutorPayStep2.png"/>
								</imageobject>
							</inlinemediaobject></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Press save and wait until a new list view, showing all newly created Tutor pay
							records is displayed.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Once Tutor pay records have been created they can be edited. Each Tutor pay record
							has a list of items grouped by class and based on the relevant
							attendance/wages/sessions for that class.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Additional Tutor pay items can be added, they will be listed in at the bottom of
							the list.<inlinemediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/editTutorPay.png" />
								</imageobject>
							</inlinemediaobject></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tutor pay can be modified until its finalised, which happens once the record has
							been exported using <guimenu>File</guimenu> > <guimenuitem>Import/Export</guimenuitem>
							> <guimenuitem>Tutor pay </guimenuitem>.</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Another way to finalise a Tutor pay record select it and choose "Finalise Tutor
							pay" from cogwheel menu. The finalised Tutor pay records display status
							"Paid/Exported"</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example></para>
		<caution>
			<para>Tutor pay can have following statuses: New, Completed, Approved and Paid/Exported. Only
				a status of "Paid / Exported" prevents the editing of the record. </para>
		</caution>
	</section>
</chapter>
